Chapter 666

“Was our information faulty?”

“That’s a possibility or…”

“Or they lied to us? They wouldn’t have the balls to withhold information from the Long Clan, it must be something else…”

“Maybe those United Element bastards were smart enough not to trust them? This could explain why they were doing something idiotic like creating a fort.”

“That’s probably it, they might still be hiding here or chose a different area to occupy. We will have to search for clues but don’t forget your other duties.”

“Yes, Elder.”

A group of old men were standing around a map of this area. When talking they looked to the nearby settlement which was a city in which millions of people lived. They had interrogated some of the clans living there and managed to get some information. Apparently, a small unit of cultivators from their enemy had chosen to appear but no signs of them could be found. There wasn’t really a place to hide, the forests around here weren’t that dense.

They were quick to send out a scouting party to scour the area and wait. Thanks to the map they knew where the best spots for setting up a temporary stronghold would be. Apparently, their enemies were trying to create a stronghold in this area. To the people from the Long Clan and their affiliates, this was a strange tactic. It would have been much easier to just occupy the nearby city instead. Their presence here was a fact and defeating them with their larger numbers would be easy.

Yet they would soon have a rude awakening. As the group of cultivators was getting ready to go for another search their enemies weren’t that far away. To be exact they were right next to them, shrouded by the veil of the night. After their scouting party was marked by their leader, it was child's play to arrive at this base.

“The Elder was right, they can’t see us at all…”

“This opportunity is not something we can squander, get ready, and don’t embarrass our sect in front of the new elder.”

Zhang Teng called out to the other core formation experts that were behind him. Their group would form one attacking and one defensive formation in this battle each consisting of six core formation cultivators. The foundation establishment soldiers would be in the rear and help with the small fries that attempted to escape. It looked like they were outnumbered about two to one but with the element of surprise on their side, their morales were high.

“Elder Yinglo, everyone is ready, please give us the order to attack.”

Zhang Dong nodded while scanning through the enemy encampment. They had borrowed an abandoned mine and placed an illusory formation to hide the entrance. This world was vast, and finding such a location would have been quite a time investment. Even if they discovered it later he expected their opponents to be on the move. Their leaders weren’t stupid, everyone knew that creating a base wasn’t such an easy task.

He could feel two nascent soul masters on the inside along with around thirty core formation experts. The rest weren’t worth mentioning but one thing was apparent. These people did not belong to the Long Clan, only one person fit the bill and he was just a core formation expert. Both the nascent soul master on the inside was from other sects or clans that he wasn’t that familiar with.

‘They won’t even send out a master to guide their moves and leave it to other sects with promises of power. I guess we are doing something similar but not quite the same.’

Hiring mercenaries wasn’t anything new but he was sure that the Long Clan wasn’t paying these people much in return. They were probably strong-armed into complying with the superpower that was the Azure dynasty. Most of the oldies would not side with the new upstarts and probably hoped to gain an easy victory. Even if they wouldn’t be getting anything in return from the Azure Emperor, they could pillage whatever their enemies left behind.

‘A never-ending battle for cultivation resources to expand one's life and power… but is it really worth it in the end if immortality is impossible to grasp?’

He wasn’t sure if he had the right to ask that question. He had already reached the maximum level of power that this world allowed. Even without doing anything, he would be able to at least live a thousand years. Perhaps death seemed scarier to people that lived for longer than to ones whose lives ended rather fast. Without having a way of prolonging it, they needed to just accept the investable. Yet for a cultivator that was able to get to a thousand years there might have been a way.

“Elder, Yinglo…”

“Ah yes, we shall begin with the assault, leave the two nascent soul masters to me, I’ll be sure to remove them from this encampment.”

Lan Fei interrupted him while he was thinking things through. Even now he was not that keen on killing people. Yet after going through many battles there was one thing that he understood. These people might have not wanted to make this choice but they were hurting others by this choice they made. There was no reason for this war other than the Long Clan’s scheme and they were probably hoping for a reward after all the blood had dried up.

A darkened blade appeared in his hand and was pointed toward the enemy encampment. The element of surprise was on their side so he could take care of many of the enemy combatants on his own. The faster this was over, the less people needed to die. Thus he aimed for one of the nascent soul masters that was there.

“Huh?”

The old man was just walking through one of the mine shafts when he felt something coming. There was not enough time to evade, he could only look up and put his guard up. A massive black and purple energy strike pierced through the rocks above and collided with his chest. Even with all of his magical trinkets and powerful treasures, it went right through like a knife through butter.

“W-we are getting attacked!”

Zhang Dong moved his hand back after thrusting his sword forward. A torrent of sword energies that contained some of his Dao pierced through the ground and connected with the weaker of the two nascent soul masters. The strike went right through his chest and was an instant KO. With the infusion of his own Qi, the man was incapacitated and his life was now dangling on a thread.

‘One down, one to go…’

He flew forward as the vanguard at the remaining master that was quick to abandon the mine to intercept him. Even though he was much stronger than his opponents he was worrying about other things. This fight was different from the ones that he had in the previous few years. He wasn’t fighting demi-humans or creatures from the treacherous seas. His opponents were now just regular humans that inhabited this empire. While he had gotten somewhat used to delivering killing blows by now, if he could save some people by not having them die through collateral damage, then he would.

“Follow after Elder Yinglo, for the United Element Sect, and for the Patriarch!”

Zhang Teng, who was the second in command, raised his own sword at the enemy. All of the core formation experts assembled to create a massive water dragon and turtle. These elemental entities made from their Qi pushed into the mine in hopes of collapsing it and bringing death to the people in it. While their leader was against pointless killing, they weren’t as lenient.

“Ack, the walls are coming down, quickly evacuate outside! Activate the defensive formations! ARGH!”

Zhang Dong identified the nascent soul elder who fled outside instantly after his initial sword strike. The man was a great circle master and the one he defeated was in the later stage. These two probably never expected to get this much resistance with the amount of power they should be capable of producing.

“Who are you? How can you wield so much power?”

“Surrender and I might tell you.”

“You want me to surrender? You might have gotten a lucky strike on my junior but I’m not as weak!”

It didn’t seem that the man was capable of judging the true power of his enemy. A large number of spears along with a soul beast that looked like a giant with eight arms appeared. There was some circle of fire spinning behind this beast and his feet along with his hands were clad in fire energy as well. This being was also holding multiple weapons of various types like axes, swords, and even a hammer.

“You shall be defeated by this Xiuo H… huh?”

The man was trying to pronounce his name but before he could finish a shadowy figure appeared right before him. The vast quantity of spears that were part of a formation of flying weapons was somehow miraculously seen through and dodged through.

“Ugh…H-how…”

A metallic taste entered the man’s mouth as a palm connected with his chest. It send an ungodly amount of spiritual energy into his solar plexus along with his other organs. All of them started rapturing in a moment and even before he could call his massive soul beast for help.

“My apologies but I want to end this fight fast, you won’t be able to cultivate anymore and your life will be short… but this is the price that you’ll pay for taking part in all of this…”

Zhang Dong looked at the old man’s body crumbling as his Qi started going berserk. Ending a fight between nascent soul masters fast wasn’t that easy. This was even harder when one of the combatants didn’t truly want to destroy their enemy. It was possible for him to go for the kill shot instantly but instead, he decided to crumble the man’s dantian to destroy his cultivation.

“N-no… I will not… it… it can not end here… ugh…”

The man retreated while throwing all of the flying spears his way. Zhang Dong moved his body in strange, incomprehensible ways to evade everything. He could not let up, the man was in possession of a teleportation talisman. Before it could be activated he slashed forward with his black sword. Instantly the man’s arm had been severed but to his surprise, the talisman that was in that hand was still activated.

‘Am I still too soft?’

Zhang Dong remained in the skies while looking at the falling hand. The man was able to escape and even if he was heavily injured he still posed a future threat to his people. If anyone died by his hand in the future then it would be on his continence.

‘I should return to the mine and stop the fight…’

Yet now was not the time to deliberate this, the fighting below was still ongoing and now that the other nascent soul masters were gone he could just end it.

Chapter 667

“I want this place to be empty within the hour, take everything, grab the spatial rings, and don’t leave any stone untouched!”

“Yes, Senior Brother!”

The battle was over and Zhang Dong was looking at a particular scene playing out. The foundation establishment juniors were ransacking the entire mine and even taking some of the wooden beams that supported some of it. It seemed that there had been an order to not leave anything with spirit energy inside left.

‘I did say to bring any and all resources… I guess they are keeping true to my order.’

With the recent recruitment drive, his army was steadily growing. This meant that they needed to provide everyone with weapons, good robes, food, and even pills. The conflict had just started and they were going against a behemoth in the form of the Long Clan. Their opponent was well connected, no one stood in their way, and would offer up all their resources without a second thought.

His sect on the other hand had existed only around for ten years. While they were now famous it would take a lot more time for everyone to accept them as the new giant. Each time they went into new cities they had to jump through certain hoops to get the people's support. Some even tried to resist as they did not believe in their might.

Thanks to Zhang Dong’s system it was possible to recycle almost everything that was considered a crafting material. Thus his people were tasked with even stripping the floors of tiles which could be then reassembled into something workable. Even now they were scraping everything from this temporary enemy encampment to send back to later send back to the main sect.

“Take the prisoners away, they shall work at the mines.”

“Unhand me, I am a member of the Long Clan! Do you know who my uncle is? When he finds out, all of your descendants will be killed!”

“Shut it you old fart, they have special places at the mines for people like you!’

The man that belonged to the main Long Clan and was a core formation expert was apprehended. Even though their side had lost he was still complaining as if expecting to get returned to his family. It seemed that these people weren’t taking this war as seriously as his side was.

‘Hm… It's always better to go against a foe that underestimates their opponent, I hope there are more fools like this one out there.’

He could see victory on the horizon if they were up against self-absorbed idiots like this person. Considering that the Long Clan had been at the top for more than a hundred thousand years, they had no reason to doubt their victory. Perhaps they expected their outer clan elders and disciples to take care of everything.
‘How did that saying go? Hard times create strong men, strong men create good times, good times create weak men, and weak men create hard times. They had been on top for so long that they had probably weakened to a degree. They rely on other sects and branch clans to do the dirty work for them while they hide out in the middle region in that flying castle.’

Zhang Dong nodded at his assessment, when considering this truth things didn’t look that bad. However, the longer this exchange took the more his enemy would grow. Just like with the other empires he needed to continue pushing and the end would appear.

“Is everything fine?”

“Hm… Can you give me a report?”

He nodded while turning his head over to Lan Fei who had become sort of a secretary. The battle was over and he was done with suppressing the lesser cultivators with his aura. Without another nascent soul master to block it out, there was no way for them to fight back.

“We suffered no casualties thanks to Elder’s magnificent battle. Only a few injuries here and there but nothing a few pills can’t fix.”

“Mmm, and what of their side?”

“Around a fifth of their people had been slain in the attack the rest have already surrendered.”

“Is that so, you don’t seem happy Elder, is there something wrong?”

“No it’s nothing, help the others handle the prisoners and transport them to our stronghold. Then prepare them for transport after the gate is finished.”

“Of course.”

Lan Fei nodded her head and slowly retreated towards her sect brothers and sisters. She recalled the old days where this man had helped her out. Even though his face was rugged and unmoving it was obvious that he was feeling compassion for the deceased warriors from the other side. That someone like him existed in such a world felt strange but it also brought a smile onto her face.

‘I’m not sure what to do to minimize the deaths… These people aren’t participating entirely of their own free will. They can’t go against the Long Clan, even a random core formation elder is getting the royal treatment.’

The battle was won and the prisoners were getting taken away. The bodies of the defeated foes lay down on the ground while covered by thin cloth. The only thing he could do for these people was to take their remains into his medallion and then send them back to their clans. The least he could do was give their family members some closure.

‘They might hate me for it but… there are too many things at stake here for me to stop now.’
Killing regular human beings was a lot different than demi-humans. Even though this wasn’t the first time something like this happened, he could never get used to it. Soon the mine area was cleaned out and they returned to the stronghold where they were greeted by a few remaining sect members.

“Everyone, you did well. You are allowed to rest for the rest of the night, we will continue tomorrow at dawn.”

His people were tired, even if they were cultivators he knew that sooner or later their bodies would break. It was up to the commanding officer to keep his troops well prepared and resting was one way of sustaining morale. He could already see some of the soldiers smiling and commenting on the first real battle. All of them would start forming bonds with each other which would just solidify their integration into this company.

‘I wonder how the others are doing. Bob show me the report.’

‘Affirmative.’

While the others rested he wasn’t done with his duties. As the only nascent soul master here it was his job to keep everyone safe. His spiritual sense could spread out far into the distance. If someone got too close to their stronghold he would know.

He took a seat in his own private chamber that was devoid of any furniture. The castle had been assembled but it only created foundations of cold rock and steel. People would actually have to assemble other necessities that could be more easily transported through spatial rings.

For the time being he pulled out a chair along with a table onto which he superimposed a holographic image of the entire western border. The Long Clan was right in the middle and didn’t really control that much land compared to his sect or the one to the east. Even without any land, they were still considered to be the strongest superpower in the world.

‘Due to their concentration in the middle, it might be hard to drive them back, their protective formations could be as powerful as the ones from the Emerald Phoenix empire which shouldn’t be that much of a problem. What I really need to watch out for is that flying city and that Goliath thing Long Qing spoke about.’

The name reminded him of something like a giant golem or colossus from various legends. It was possible that this Long Clan he was going up against had a huge trump card. While this thing was supposed to help him against the other empires, now that he was going against his previous allies, it could be the reverse. It was possible for the scenario to change as he had a suspicion that the Overseer had something to do with it.

‘Perhaps if things get too one-sided, the Overseer has to level the playing field?’

He asked himself while staring at the map on the table. His forces were slowly assembling close to the border cities and assembling large castles. They weren’t just large structures of stone that could take a beating, there was a further purpose to their creation. After assembling a formation would be created, this one was quite special and could connect to other similar ones.

‘This is quite the undertaking, we need to assemble over a hundred of these to even have a chance to connect them.’

The plan wasn’t that simple. All these formations were supposed to connect to each other to form a giant wall between the center and the west. This is why they were trying to hide these buildings and create them before their enemy knew of their true purpose.

‘We have about one-fifth of them assembled, it’s going nicely but the Long Clan won’t remain passive.’

He recalled the elder that escaped from the battle. The man would probably make a full report to the Long Clan that might return with reinforcements. When the time came he needed to be ready to defend this place but he was not alone. Thanks to their teleportation gates, reinforcements would be able to arrive.

Even now some of his sect members were working tirelessly to assemble the first of these gates. Once they were finished more scientific staff could make their way over to help outfit this stronghold with weapons. Within a few days, he expected it to have many spirit canons, and protective shields to stem the tide.

‘I guess it’s up to them now, I’ll just need to protect them if those reinforcements arrive… I just hope they won’t be too hasty.’

This was an opportunity to test his enemies. Would they release the danger that was before them or would they ignore it? There were a lot of politics involved in the cultivation world. It wasn’t that easy to assemble new armies and get other elders to move. Without a proper leader or some structure, their response would be sluggish.

‘Well, I can only hope that they aren’t prepared for what’s to come, if this goes well, we will be able to push in for an offensive sooner than I anticipated.’

Chapter 668

‘They are really making me work… I wonder if someone suspects something by now…’

Zhang Dong looked at the passed-out man in his grasp. Just a moment ago the two had been exchanging blows in the air but now the previously strong man looked like someone’s grandpa. This was already his tenth battle at the border region and the enemies weren’t really letting up.

Just as he previously expected, the man that escaped had called for some reinforcements. Even though their counterattack was quite sloppy it wasn’t the end of it. A full-on war for the control of the border was now raging in the empire. The other forts and strongholds didn’t go unnoticed and within a week's time, the Long Clan had sent out their troops to stop the creation of these castles.

Their enemy seemed to have less manpower than their side on the surface but this was nothing more than a pretense. The Long Clan’s roots ran deep, a lot deeper than he anticipated. It wasn’t just the fear of the royal family that drove them, a lot actually believed that they were part of it all. For others, this was the chance they were waiting for, with enough merits they could be promoted to proper clan members.

However, his side was still managing to hold out. One of the reasons was that he was taking it a lot more seriously than his competition. Even now, not many of the nascent soul masters from the main sect showed themselves. This was the key to their victory, an unorganized opponent that lacked a proper structure in their army.

The battles he was going through were actually easier than the ones against the Phoenix emerald empire or the demi-humans. Those people actually had one central figure leading them, even the demi-humans that were divided into tribes had more control over people. They at least didn’t mix their tribes up together too much which lessened their need for cooperation.

Here on the other hand it was a mix-up of various clans and sects together. This was a recipe for disaster as cultivators were very headstrong and didn’t really like to cooperate with outsiders. Without a proper divide between officers and soldiers there was bound to be problems. No one wanted to be the vanguard and suffer casualties and even now during his battle, there were similar problems.

‘They tossed this elder at me just so they could get away…’

It was actually a tactic that worked. The time it took him to take out this nascent soul master, his friends had managed to escape. They weren’t faster than him nor were they stronger but still they got away. All of this was due to one thing, strange teleportation talismans that somehow every master above the core formation level was equipped with.

‘I guess this is what the Long Clan thought up to conserve their forces… but not sure what they will do with all those demoralized nascent soul masters…’

The whole thing was somewhat annoying. Whenever there were more than one nascent soul master on the battlefield, they would run the moment they realized there was no way of winning. Sometimes they would even do it before he could initiate combat. His fame of being a powerful master at the great circle level was spreading through the front like wildfire. The legend of the dark master Lei Yinglo was already reaching the middle regions.

“Elder Yinglo, thanks for your work!”

“Ah? Make nothing of it, just doing what I was hired for.”

He waved his hand while dangling a passed out late stage nascent soul master in his other arm. The people that were bowing in his direction were people from his own sect. He had taken the recently created teleportation gate in his fortress and traveled to this location as a backup elder. After the Long Clan figured out that these structures were being assembled they sent out many soldiers to sabotage the endeavor. Now he was swapped with more work as he showed everyone how competent of a fighter his alter ego was.

“Elder, we need you at the gate.”

“Again? What is this, the eleventh time?”

“My apologies but our base in the north is getting attacked by a unified force, they brought siege weapons and our sect members are having a tough time holding out.”

“Ah… fine, show me the way, you can take care of this guy without my help, right?”

“Thank you, great elder!”

He grumbled while flying towards the other castle that was identical to the one his group assembled. While they were taking a break without any problems he was here working overtime. Luckily with his help things were progressing rather smoothly and he hoped to have this wall assembled within the designated time window. With it up there would be no way of the Long Clan getting through without heavy weaponry or many nascent soul masters.

The passed-out nascent soul maser was thrown to the side and would be later questioned by his people. However, there was probably not much that he knew, all of these people were outsiders that didn’t really know what the Long Clan was up to. Their mission was to run interference while his sect tried to assemble a defensive wall in the west.

‘We should have started this sooner while the relations were a lot better between us…’

Zhang Dong regretted that in the past he didn’t push for setting up stronger boundaries but there wasn’t really that much time to take care of everything. His sect was brand new and there were many middle-sized sects in the area that didn’t take them quite seriously. Some time was spent on convincing them that they were really the replacement for the Soaring Dragon Sect.

If they attempted to send out their armies to the borders it would have probably not gone well with their previous peaceful approach. His motto was to use more of the carrot than the stick in these situations. Yet this required a lot more time than showing the others a large fist and ordering them to submit.

‘Being a dictator has its pros during times like these…’

After giving out a small sigh he departed towards the teleportation gate and his next destination. Peace gained through warfare and oppression never lasted long and that was his main reason for doing things like he did. It would only last as long as his sect remained in power. He could actually see something similar happening now. With each new loss, the Long Clan was hemorrhaging followers.

They were believed to be an unmoving titan that had existed since time immemorial. Everything thought that they couldn’t be moved or defeated by anyone. Even though the soldiers they sent were from branch families and people interested in gaining fame, a loss was a loss. This started to make people think, there was a possibility that the old behemoth had lived too long.

‘Perhaps that’s why they are using outsiders for the current push, if they fail they can blame them for everything… Maybe they are underestimating us more than I previously anticipated… good.’

When he arrived on the other side of the portal a battle was taking place. In the sky, he saw many flying barges made of wood. They were firing their guns at the defensive formation of this fortress. His sect was returning fire and even managing to give the others a run for their money. It was mostly a stalemate without much progress from the other side but now that he was here, it would change.

“We greet the Elder, we have been…”

“No need for pleasantries, I’ll take care of their leader so just keep firing back, this won’t take too long.”

Just like that he was gone and floating above the castle. Thanks to the structures being all the same it made maneuvering around the corridors a lot easier. While this was risky as their enemies would eventually get their hands on the plans, it made things easier for the people working there. It would be easy to train anyone and then send in a replacement.

“S-stop him!”

“W-who is he… oh no, it’s that man!”

It seemed that these branch members knew about him. The moment he appeared between the flying vessels they started pelting him with spirit cannons. It seemed that he was a more important target than the whole stronghold. However, this meant that they would be getting bombarded back by the members of his sect.

The explosions covered the sky and turned it black. Yet even if one of the spirit cannon shots collided with his body, there would be no damage to his enhanced body. Body Refining made anything below the great circle level of power ineffective. He wouldn’t even get scratched if he remained in one spot and became a target dummy.

Soon his target came into view, the largest ship from the group with its master on board. He could feel three people of the nascent soul variety on board. They were all sitting together and powering up their defensive formation while using their cannons to shoot. Hitting such a small target in the air wasn’t an easy task so they found themselves with an old man ramming their flying ship.

Splinters flew everywhere as he burst through the side and collided with their main engine. It took one hit and then promptly exploded. A cascading effect was soon created as the whole giant boat blew up with the people in it. To his surprise, the three nascent soul masters that were inside didn’t really do much to protect the crew of the ship. Instead, they used the smoke and blast to hide their presence in an attempt to attack him.

Yet this didn’t matter, he had grown too powerful already. Even when three of them worked in unison they were just not fast enough to land any blow. Instead, they suffered a counterattack that sent them flying in three different directions and into smaller flying vessels that were on their side.

“We must escape, he is too powerful for us!”

“Yes brothers, we must retreat… huh?”

“What is it?”

“The talisman… it’s gone?”

“Gone? Wait… mine isn’t here either.”

“Are you looking for these?”

After so many run-ins with these nascent soul masters, he knew that they would try to escape the moment they had the chance. To keep them from it, he decided to strip them of their teleportation talismans that he managed to pinpoint with the help of Bob and the system.

“You three aren’t going anywhere but into the spirit stone mines, now surrender and I might show mercy…”

Zhang Dong smiled while giving Bob another mission. With these three talismans in his possession now he had something to work with. Now what he needed to do was find where these people were escaping to and give them a visit…

Chapter 669

‘Just as I expected, good job with the analysis Bob. Now, how do I handle this…’

Zhang Dong had returned to his own fortress after things had cleared up. After helping his sect push the enemy soldiers away he had some time to wind down. The respite would probably be short and he expected the next charge soon. Now that the cat was out of the bag and his enemies knew about the strongholds, they could send in a more organized force.

Thus he focused on a way of sabotaging his enemies. This he could achieve thanks to these talismans that he had grabbed of the other nascent soul masters. After so many of them got away he developed a way of getting to these items. Then it only took Bob a little bit of time to pinpoint the location where users of these talismans were taken.

It was just one location within the Long Clan’s region. It wasn’t that far off from his own lands and was probably the area where they had their base. The city near it was populated by many people and a lot of powerful branching families of the Long Clan lived there. It was a good spot for a well-defended base.

‘All of the talismans trace back to the same location, so I can assume that all of the nascent soul masters that escaped me are probably there… now what to do with this information.’

This was a war, his enemies wouldn’t give him any mercy while he was still somewhat restrained. The easiest tactic here would just be to teleport himself to that location by using one of the talismans. Once there he could toss out a bomb to blow up their escape route and render the escape system useless. Now here came the problem and once again, Zhang Dong’s moral compass got in the way.

‘What if it’s close to a residential district and kills some bystanders?’

There were multiple ways for him to get people killed if he sent out a bomb through the talisman. If he was less merciful he wouldn’t bat an eye, it would be easy to just blow up the entire city with all the enemy cultivators stationed there. It was a decision that a leader trying to lessen the casualties on his side should take. Yet he couldn’t, the thought of blowing up unsuspecting residents that had nothing to do with this struggle, was not something that he could stomach.

‘I at least have to stay true to my way of life… otherwise, I’ll not be any better than the murder hobos I made fun of in the past. There is luckily another way of going over this, the location isn’t that far off… I should be able to get there within a few hours…’

Luck was on his side with this one, instead of using the teleportation talisman to go there himself he could just use his system. During his trip to the central region in the past he did create a save point for teleporting. It was made outside the main Long Clan city in another location and he could still go there.

‘I just need to sneak in, get in there and disable the formation…’

He wanted to go there and examine their base of operations before going with the nuclear option. Perhaps he was worrying too much and the area was away clear of any non-combatants but he didn’t want to risk it. It was impossible to pinpoint the locations due to how the talismans worked. He was given an area of about a hundred kilometers with the city in the middle for the potential drop.

‘Should I use some type of remote camera first and then use another medallion right afterward? But they would just turn off the formation if something strange appeared…’

For a moment he considered sending in an automaton that could forward him some information. Yet it would probably cause his enemies to become more cautious. If he wanted to keep the casualties of innocent civilians to a minimum, there wasn’t really any other way. The main reason he forced everyone to create these strongholds was to not involve regular people in the fight with the Long Clan.

‘We aren’t that far this time, so the spirit point usage won’t be that bad…’

“Lan Fei.”

“Yes Elder, can I help you with something?”

After making up his mind he called out to his current secretary. The woman entered the room slowly while swinging her hips from side to side. Her body had matured with the use of the sect's body refining technique which made it hard to focus. It became clear that she was trying to entice him with that voluptuous form, just like in the past. When interacting with other people her walking cycle wasn’t this overblown. She even made sure to wear a more revealing robe and the constant bending over didn’t help either.

“I might be gone for a while, I need you to keep it a secret.”

“A secret? But what should we do if the enemy appears? We aren’t ready to activate the ultra wall formation.”

“Don’t worry, just use this.”

“This is?”

After walking over he handed Lan Fei a small item. It was just a plate with a red button on it. Under the button, there was a short sentence ‘Press to get help.’ It wasn’t really much, it was just something that would inform him about them having trouble. There were several ways of tackling this depending on the magnitude of the enemies that could arrive.

“It’s a panic button, use it when you think the enemies will get through the shields but if it’s possible to last out, refrain from using it.”

“I see.”

The chesty woman nodded but could see that her bouncing mounds of flesh weren’t as effective as in the past. She could tell that the man that had been so shy all those years ago had changed. Yet this was her only chance to get herself into a higher position, thus her little ploy continued to Zhang Dong’s dismay.

“That will be all, I shouldn’t take that long to come back.”

“I’ll take my leave then~”

So she did while continuously swaying her hips in an over-the-top manner. Even someone like him was having trouble looking away which she somewhat noticed. After she was finally gone, Zhang Dong pulled up his map and pointed at the teleport location.

‘If Liena was here she would have my head… better never mention this…’

His wife was somewhat of a jealous type. Even though he didn’t show that much interest in other women, his family had a history of fooling around. While this was somewhat annoying, it was understandable with someone like Zhang Jin around. It was the same for all the other men in the world, he was the oddball out that practiced monogamy.

“Let’s go then… but first.”

The face that belonged to the demon hunter started shifting around into something older. His body size and musculature decreased as he changed into a lanky-looking old man in a flowy robe. This person was one of the cultivators that he managed to defeat in the last confrontation that took place not that long ago. The battle was still fresh so there were ways for him to explain his late teleportation escape.

After putting on the robe of the man he defeated and feeling somewhat dejected by the old man's smell, he was gone. His body turned into blue particles and within a fraction of a second, he was at the old save point he created. In the distance, he could see a large city that had brought him to his older brother.

It brought back a few old memories. Long Qing didn’t seem like a bad person, he had a somewhat laid-back personality. It seemed like he wasn’t taking this world that seriously but sooner or later the two would have to confront each other. The problem was his wife whom he adored and who was his true target. There would probably be no way of explaining to him that she wasn’t truly a cultivator of this world.

‘I don’t really know what she is… That Demon Lord didn’t feel like a real person either, more like a defensive program that activates when something breaches the protocols.’

It wouldn't be strange for the woman to behave normally when they met again. It was possible that she might have not even known of the Overseer's existence. It could be some sort of parasitic existence that took over whenever it wanted. Yet, it could be the other way around and the Empress had never existed in the first place.

‘Hmm… They don’t seem that bothered for people that should be at war…’
Thanks to his shadowy form he was able to quickly sink behind some shade in the clouds. From there he had a nice view over these lands. His mind was sharp and he remembered how this place looked in the past. Not much had changed and people were just going around as if nothing was wrong. It was as if they didn’t believe that the war could reach this far here.

‘We are really getting underestimated, it can’t be the same inside the Long Clan. They would have never pulled that stunt otherwise…’

It seemed that the Long Clan’s branching families weren’t taking this seriously. They were potentially fed the wrong information while working for the Long Clan. Perhaps they even thought that they were winning. If that was true then this strange behavior could be explained.

‘Are they actually sending these people out to get slaughtered, could they be planning something?’

Zhang Dong didn’t expect a sight like this so he didn’t even bother investigating this spot beforehand. It was possible that the Long Clan was just trying to gather more information about their new enemies. Sending in waves of moderately strong branch clans would give them the information that they wanted and none of their core members would lose their lives. Then after it was all done, they could move in to claim victory.

‘Hm… what if I show these people the true potential of their enemy… Would they start deserting?’

A thought crept into his mind. Cultivators were people that weighed their decisions. If something was very disadvantageous they would even abandon their own sects. Their loyalty to the Long Clan was merit-based and if they figured out that there was no way of gaining those. Then perhaps they would start fleeing.

‘I wonder…Well, first let me check out that base of theirs, maybe if I cause some havoc there…’

Soon he departed with a thought in his mind. Perhaps if he scared the allies of his new enemies enough, the war could be shortened exponentially.

Chapter 670

‘I made the right choice of not using that talisman. There are a lot of people here, old and young…’

Zhang Dong was in his shadowy form looking from afar. When searching for the place the teleportation talismans led to, a large settlement popped into view. There were at least a hundred thousand people here and all of them seemed to belong to various other clans and sects.

‘There are a lot of various banners. Bob, can you analyze them and give me their point of origin.’

‘Scanning, please wait…’

In under a minute he had the result posted up on his system window. There he could see the names and locations of each group that was in this city. To his surprise, they were quite spread out throughout the empire. Some of them came from his territories, others from the east side where the Heavenly Crane Sect resided, and others from the edge of the central region.

‘Now what should I do about this, there are multiple masters here, we didn’t even manage to get half of them and they will continue to teleport here to run.’

The Long Clan was using guerilla tactics. Even though he managed to protect multiple strongholds, some of them had fallen. There were people from his side that had given their life for this war and it would continue to happen as long as the conflict lasted. Ending it as fast as possible with limited casualties was his main goal but how to tackle this problem was the big question.

‘Is there no other way besides massacring them all to send a message?’

In reality, he knew of a somewhat surefire way of getting some branch clans off his back. Cleansing sects and cities was the normal way people did things in this world. When one large group attacked another they usually made sure to eradicate their opponents. In a world where one person could reach the apex of power and seek vengeance, it was imperative to root out any potential disasters. Only if the opponent was astronomically more powerful than another faction would people not seek vengeance.

‘There are downsides to this method, it requires a lot of resources and continuous search for any potential survivors.’

It was quite hard to eradicate sects and clans that had thousands of members. They would join up with rival sects and bolster their power. With more battles, the list of enemies continued to increase. Sooner or later a sect that lived by the sword also died by it. The Long Clan was smart, they let others do their dirty work and could shove the blame elsewhere. There was probably a reason why they survived for so long.

‘So how do I turn these people against the Long Clan without killing everyone in this city…’

A thought crept into his mind for a moment. He knew how a lot of the Long Clan elders looked. It would have been easy to impersonate one of them to destroy this place. He could even make it look like some demonic ritual that the Long Clan was part of. Human sacrifices were a common occurrence, making it look like his enemies lured people here to perform occult magic could work.

‘No, there must be another way… I could do it like this… but it will take some preparation. I should be able to fit them all into the medallion for the time being…’

Zhang Dong asked Bob about the logistics of his current plan. Before attempting it he needed to make sure that he had enough time. After the analysis was done and he got a good result it was time to sneak towards the city to perform a nice theatrical play. For this to happen he would need to first prepare the stage.

……

“This is all wrong, how will we explain this to the main clan elders?”

“We must push and destroy those strongholds before they create more.”

“Do we know what they are even making?”

“The scouts weren’t sure but a formation is being formed and a large one by the scope…”

A group of nascent soul elders was sitting around in a circle while discussing their recent battles with the United Element Sect. They weren’t too happy about their progress as they had assumed this to be a chance to stand out. If they could grasp this opportunity for themselves then their clans would gain the full backing of the Long Clan. With something like this, there would be no one who would dare to stand in their way.

“It all started with that man… who would have thought that they were hiding such a master? Who is this Lei Linglo?”

“He was apparently a demon hunter a few years ago but he suddenly resurfaced…”

“Could he be their Patriarch’s secret backer? This would explain some things… but perhaps it’s Wang Long, how can we believe that he killed him in the demonic region! I bet the two were working together from the start and this man knows some strange shadowy arts.”

“That seems plausible, that young man was powerful and demonic arts would explain his rise to power!”

The United Element Sect was a new powerhouse. More than ten years had passed since they started baring their teeth to the empire and now people had become informed about their past. On the surface, it seemed that they originated from an unsuspecting clan in the lower western regions. No one believed this to be true as it was impossible for a group with not even one nascent soul master to have become this successful.

Many better theories started floating around. Some believed that Long Dong had been someone at the level of the Emperor for many years and used the Zhang Clan as some type of cover. They painted Zhang Dong as a mastermind that plotted to overthrow the Azure Dynasty. It was him that destroyed the Soaring Dragon Sect along with Wang Long and now were dead set on taking over the entire Empire.

“I bet all of those demi-humans were just demonic cultivators from the island, it’s all lightning up… we must stop them before this empire gets overrun!”

“That is the truth but why isn’t the main Clan sending us reinforcements, if this continues we will lose the border.”

“We should not say such things, what if someone from the main clan is listening in?”

“... Haha, you’re right, I’ve spoken out of line, forgive me. I bet the Azure Emperor has a plan, we should trust in him.”

“Yes, we should.”

The group started laughing weakly while looking around. Speaking out against the Long Clan was something that was frowned upon. All of them here were in the same boat and wanted to prove themselves to the Azure dynasty. If they could have some of their children marry into the clan after this was over, their future was as good as secured.

“Now then, we must prepare a tactic for that Lei Yinglo and expose him as the demonic cultivator that he is.”

“Yes, if we get some proof then even more people will join our cause!”

“Proof?”

The group started chuckling at one of their younger members claiming this idea. Even without having any proof in their minds, there was no problem in pronouncing this fact. The Long Clan would probably agree with them and was already using the demonic cultivator angle themselves. It didn’t really matter to these people though, as long as they were able to gain merits for their own factions it was enough.

“Hm… hasn’t it gotten darker?”

“Now that you mention it… the moon, why is it there?”

“Careful, this isn’t something natural!”

“Are we getting attacked? But the defensive formation hasn't been activated?”

“Why would something that I created activate?”

“Huh? Is that… Is that the Azure Emperor?”
The group of around twenty nascent soul masters glanced up toward the sky. There they could see a man slowly floating in their direction. All of them knew who this was, his face, voice, and demeanor were of Long Qing, the man known to the world as the Azure Emperor.

“We greet the mighty Azure Dragon!”

All of these old masters started bowing almost instantly. Yet there was something fishy about all of this. Why would the mightiest of them all come to this remote region without even accounting for his arrival? Normally, if the need arose for him to travel a whole group of masters would make way. Days before his coming they would make sure that everything was in tip-top shape.

“W-what do we owe this honor? Lord of the Azure?”

After a moment of uncomfortable silence, one of the oldest members of this group spoke out. The whole city had become quiet as the voice of this Azure Emperor was quite chilling. There was a sense of danger that everyone was feeling as if the man that they regarded as their leader would actually bring harm to them.

“...”

“...S-senior?”

“BE QUIET!”

A massive surge of energy blasted forth from the sky and pushed down on everyone in this city. Instantly they could feel some of the junior members from their clans and others succumbing to this massive pressure. It wasn’t just a simple aura attack, a strange vile energy was mixed into it all.

“D-deminic Qi? It must be an imposter!”

“An imposter? Do you really think so?”

“What … are those the Supreme and Grand Elders from the Main Clan?”

“Why are they all here…”

Before the cultivators could ask more questions they realized that they were surrounded. Many nascent soul masters that only resided at the sky city were here. They could even see all three children of the Azure Emperor there. They were all powerful masters close to the apex and each and every one was radiating demonic Qi.

“I would like to thank you for your cooperation in coming to this place but your role ends here.”

The whole city started glowing in a dark purple hue. It became clear that this whole city was encased in some sort of demonic formation. The powerful masters that were from the branch families noticed that their qi was being suppressed and also drained by something demonic.

“You shall become nourishment for the dynasty and my idiot brother will take the blame for it!”

“Was the Azure Emperor the real demonic cultivator? How could this be?”

“It’s too late for you to figure it out now, all of you shall perish here and add to my power!”

With that proclamation, all hell broke loose, all the powerful elders from the Long Clan turned into strange beings similar to demi-humans and charged. A fight for their survival started, their only hope was escape but would they be able to run from the greatest force in the empire?

Chapter 671

“No please, No!”

“S-show mercy, Aaaa…”

Screams of thousands of people echoed through the city. Even if they attempted to run there was nowhere to go. A giant black shroud surrounded the whole city and whoever got close was shredded by unspeakable shadow horrors that resided in it. There was no escape and soon only a handful of nascent soul masters remained.

The crunching of bones and flesh being devoured by strange beasts was everywhere. Even when some of the demonic creatures were defeated they were quickly replaced by a new one. Soon even the stronger experts were starting to fade away, even without the Demonic Emperor’s involvement there was no way for them to survive.

“H-how could this be possible?”

“Was the Azure Dynasty infested by demonic cultivators from the start?”

“This can’t be happening, please Emperor show mercy… I’m willing to submit!”

The group of masters were unwilling to die, even if they were backed into a corner they grasped for any possibilities. Perhaps if they became slaves of these demons here they would be able to survive. It was better to join up with a demonic cultivator and form a slave contract. To these people that wished for immortality, survival was at the precedent of their existence.

“Hm… you wish to surrender and become my slave?”

“Yes, Honored Azure Dragon!”

“What are you…”

“Shut up, we must submit! Do you want to die like the rest?”

“Our brother is right, our allies are all dead, only we remain, if we perish here then how will our families survive?”

All of the survivors had one thing in common, they were all leaders of their own clans or sects. If they were not around to manage their factions they feared that they would crumble instantly. Their families and lines could be usurped by other branches which would make this whole undertaking a huge mistake. Perhaps they would have to perform some vile acts for these demonic beings but it was better than death.

“Please Emperor, we submit!”

The group shouted out while bowing. They were surrounded by a swarm of strange creatures. Some of them had huge mouths lined up with teeth the size of swords. Others were made out of a tar-like substance that consumed all it touched. It was as if every person that was devoured caused a multiplication of these horrors and now there was nowhere to hide.

“Do you wish to submit? Very well, offer up your souls to me for the binding contract!

“Of course…”

The old man that convinced the others to submit floated up into the sky with his guard wide open. Long Qing who had long revealed his demonic appearance, smiled widely. His large clawed hand moved forward while he performed some sort of demonic technique.

“Wait, that’s not a soul-binding art… what is he doing?”

One of the other elders that was somewhat aware of demonic arts noticed that something was off. Before he could shout out to warn his current ally it was already too late. The large demonic appendage shot out at the elder’s chest and pierced right through it. Soon all of them were looking at the man’s vitality being sucked away.

“H-he is devouring him…”

“Honorable Emperor, why?”

“What do you mean, why? I don’t need your loyalty, the only thing you are good for, is to be sustenance for my immortality! How do you think this dynasty has survived for over a hundred thousand years!”

“It… it couldn’t be… You’ve been robbing people of their longevity and adding it to your own?”

“I see that at least one of you has some intelligence but it’s already too late. Your life is forfeit and not even by stupid brother will be able to save you now.”

“Brother? The Golden Dragon?”

“Yes, he has been a thorn in my side for a long time. Luckily people like you exist, willing to do anything just to get some crumbs from me.”

The cogs in their brains started turning as they all realized that they joined the wrong side. It seemed that Long Dong, the current Emperor’s younger brother, had actually rebelled against the demonic beings. Either this or they were both evil cultivators just having a spat. The truth was unclear but if they ever wanted to figure it out, they needed to free themselves.

“No please, we don’t wish to continue, there must be another way…”

“Truly pathetic, even in your last moments you still wish to bargain but you will not talk your way out of this predicament, your death is all that matters… Die!”

Long Qing who had turned into a strange dark blue demon with webbed wings and glowing eyes pointed out. A massive aura that none of these people here could fathom pushed them down into the ground. There was nothing they could do, their Qi was being blocked by the overwhelming demonic energy. Even if they managed to escape from this area they would soon succumb to the thousands of demonic beings everywhere.

With indignation in their eyes, they could only look up at the massive surge of energy coming their way. The Emperor that they wished to gain favor with started turning into an even uglier being with tentacles on his face. It didn’t seem that he was even human at this point and soon they would become part of this mass of evil.

“Don’t fall to the demonic corruption, stay strong and never surrender!”

However, before they gave out their last breath something magical occurred. An opening in the shroud from the top was blasted through. It was followed by a torrent of golden light that descended down into this place. The light pushed the darkness away and allowed them to see the well-lit blue sky before.

“T-there is someone in that pillar of light…”

“Could it be?”

The nascent soul masters that didn’t pass out yet could see the descent of a might master. He was clad in golden armor and surrounded by strange angelic beings. The warmth that his spiritual energy emitted tickled their beards as they felt power returning back to their bodies. The evil energy was being driven back and even the demonic creatures were running to not get engulfed by the radiant light.

“So… You have come, my brother! Do you pity these idiots so much just to come here? They betrayed you, why would you aid such trash?”

“They had made the choice only due to faulty information, if they knew the truth, they would have never joined you, my brother!”

“Hah, are you sure? If I offered them their lives now, they would instantly stick their swords into your back! You are too gullible and that’s why you will never win, my younger brother!”

“We shall see! Not everyone is as power-hungry as you! There is still a goddess in people's hearts and I will help it blossom!”

“Pathetic words, only the strong will survive, compassion is just a way for the powerful to feel better about themselves! It’s a luxury of the strong!”

The group of masters started to get off the ground while listening to the two masters have a strange conversation. The whole battle was stalled but not like they could interrupt the only person that was willing to help them. As it continued, they started to feel immense shame at trying to form a contract with the demonic cultivator.

It was true that to conserve their lives and prestige they would have no trouble stabbing their current savior in their back. While some of them were about to turn over a new leaf, others just looked for the best moment to escape. With the holy energies filling the air and the decline of demonic Qi, they could feel their power resurfacing.

“We are done talking, do you really wish to help these fools that would not thing twice of betraying you? Then, protect them with your life!”

“Stop!”

Yet before they could initiate their escape all hell broke loose. In just a fraction of a second, the Azure Emperor pointed his many tentacles at the group on the ground. A massive surge of demonic energies appeared along with a strange phantom of a monster behind the Emperor. It was probably his soul beast that looked like a humanoid with webbed wings and the face of a squid.

A ball of hateful energy was sent flying in their direction and they were far too weak to defend themselves against it. But right as they were about to die, their savior appeared. The man known as the Golden Dragon put himself in the middle of the attack and took the brunt of it. Everything went black as a giant explosion rocked the entire city turning it to ash. Soon all of them started passing out with the only thing remaining in their minds being the gallant image of Long Dong, their protector.

……

“Hey, watch it, if you drop them they might wake up!”

“Forgive me senior sister, this one elder is surprisingly plump…”

A strange scene was taking place as a group of passed-out people was getting dragged onto a teleportation gate. Some were being flown out with the help of flying swords, others were getting carried manually by members from the United Element Sect. It was quite the undertaking and only possible due to one man that was hovering up in the sky.

Zhang Dong was rubbing his eyebrows as he was finally able to dispel the illusion that he created. Thanks to techniques from this and the other world he was able to pull the residents of this city into a grand play. The whole massacre wasn’t real and everything that transpired had happened inside of these people’s minds.

No one had died and most of the commoners had been moved into his medallion for the time being. They would need to be transported into the real dimensional regalia to let others think that this city had actually been destroyed. Some of the cultivators would be left alone and freed to go spread the word.

‘I hope this works, as long as these people believe that their lives are at stake, they will not work with the Long Clan.’

The perception of these people had been that he was in cahoots with Wang Long. Now on the other hand they would be convinced otherwise. Without any help from these masters, his borders were secured and the Long Clan would need to move in, otherwise, the war would quickly snowball into something they can no longer control.

Chapter 672

“Huh? What? I’m alive?”

“Oh, you are finally awake.” Please your wounds haven’t healed yet but thanks to the honorable Golden Dragon, all of the demonic Qi has been removed from your body.”

“Demonic Qi? Golden Dragon… now I remember…”

An old man rubbed his head that felt like it was on fire. Around him, he could see a few other familiar faces that had stood by him during the last battle. All of them were confused as they found themselves in an undisclosed location without knowing how they got here. The people around them didn’t seem too strong or like they belonged to any of their allies.

“I remember now, both the dragons fought each other and there was a large wave of spiritual energy, we must have lost our conscienceless at that time.”

“Elder, you managed to survive?”

“Yes… who would have known that the Emper… no, I won’t call him that anymore, that bastard tried to kill us all!”

Of the twenty or so nascent soul masters that were there, only four were in this room. It seemed to be some type of large hospital with some other survivors here and there. Some were walking around and chatting, while others were still sleeping. One thing that was of note, was that all of them were fine. None had any deep wounds and radiated strange divine energy.

“This spiritual energy…”

“I see that you have noticed, honored elder. It’s all thanks to the Golden Dragon.”

“Yes… it is very reminiscent of his energy, he must have used his healing arts on all of us…”

Soon the group of survivors started getting together. It didn’t take them long to realize that they were now in a nearby city, just a few hours of flight away from their old base. Apparently, after the battle was over, the angelic beings that were flying around with Zhang Dong carried them over to this city. They were all placed in the city hospital and finally woke up after a day or two had passed.

“This can’t be real… was the dynasty build on demonic practices?”

“It is the truth… I woke up half a day before you and made my way to the city. Nothing remains of it, it turned into nothing more than a giant hole…”

“This is indeed troubling, what should we do? Will the other branch families believe us?”

“What if they knew this?”

“You don’t mean?”
“I’m afraid that might be the case…”

The four let their heads down while trying to figure things out. It was possible that the other branch families were working together with the Long Clan and had left them all to die there. However, it was also possible that no one actually knew the truth. If nothing had gotten out for a hundred thousand years, it could mean that the Long Clan’s demonic background ran deep.

“Could Long Qing truly be immortal?”

“I don’t know but that form and demonic Qi, he must have lost his mind a long time ago… no one can live that long and retain their sanity.”

All of them nodded and also found themselves referring to the Emperor without his title. After what he had attempted to do, they wanted to distance themselves from him as much as it was possible. If what they saw was the truth then all of their clans were in danger.

“What should we do? That monster will probably silence our families, while both of the brothers are fighting, we must escape…”

“Escape where? Should we seek shelter in the West or the East?”

“I for one trust in the Golden Dragon…”

“I’m not sure, he might be the same as his brother but… at least it’s better than dying.”

“I’m not sure if the Heavenly Crane Sect can defend itself against something like that… the United Element Sect on the other hand…”

All of them started nodding and agreeing. When they needed help only one person reached out to them and was able to survive. They didn’t really judge Zhang Dong on the basis of his virtues but by his strength. With that amount of power that he had shown them, it was possible to fight against that monster. They were masters at the apex and couldn’t even lift a finger. To survive this along with their families they needed to hug the thighs of the only person capable of standing up against the evil emperor.

“We must act swiftly.”

“Aye, I have some family in the West region, I’ll contact them and ask for a way in…”

“I don’t think they will allow us into their midst without a binding contract but that’s better than working with that monster.”

“I agree, we must depart!”

The four elders found all the survivors that belonged to their factions before departing the city. After discussing the situation they turned into streaks of blue light in the sky. The only thing on their mind was survival which could be only achieved by quickly leaving the middle regions.

“Are they finally gone?”

“Yes sir!”

“Good, we shall return to the extraction point, be sure to remove the traces of us ever being here!”

Unbeknownst to the elders that flew away, the hospital staff in the city started acting strange. They quickly exchanged their white robes for dark ones and their faces became covered by masks. Their leader removed a strange medallion from his neck which he pointed at the hospital area. It soon started glowing and within a flash, a group of passed-out people appeared.

They were wearing the exact same white doctorly robes this group was before. Without saying much they soon disappeared after their part of the mission was complete. Now that the nascent masters had taken away everyone that was involved in the illusory formation their job was done.

…….

“When you said to let those people go I wasn’t sure what to think of it, but now I understand. Will they not see through the illusion eventually?”

“Perhaps but a mind is a fickle thing, it will show us what we want it to show. As long as they believe that there is something unnatural to the Emperor’s power, they will not be able to see through the deceit.”

“It does seem so, their branch families are in an uproar, the spies that we planted are only fanning the rumors and the elders we released will just confirm it…”

“As long as it gives us some time, it’s enough the wall is almost finished and the attacks have ceased.”

“That is true but what should we do with the others?”

“We’ll have to have them stay in the Dimensional Regalia for now, we can’t have people that have perished from demons appearing again.”

“Haha, they did seem confused at first but after getting some free pills and accommodations they turned over a new leaf.”

“How reasonable.”

Zhang Dong chuckled while talking with his grandfather. Other elders were here as well and they were all discussing the recent event. After assembling the large illusory formation some things had changed on the battlefront. A lot fewer branch families from the Long Clan were taking part in the offensive. After word got spread that the Azure Emperor was a demonic cultivator and it was confirmed by some reputable elders all hell broke loose.

After the little trick he pulled on the nascent soul masters they did all the work for him. He had been able to judge their personalities with the illusory formation and also the system. They were in a way the most gullible and distrustful ones from the bunch. He was sure that they would start spreading rumors about Long Qing’s true demonic form.

At first, he wasn’t sure if it was a feasible plan but he made it into a possibility while avoiding too many deaths. Perhaps the residents of that city were now stuck inside a pocket dimension but it was better than getting killed in a war. He was able to reduce the size of his enemies and also spread discourse in their ranks.

Even if someone examined if these elders had their memories tampered with, no one would find anything. The illusion was so real that it was indistinguishable from reality. All of what they saw was real to them and this was enough to help spread the rumors. Some people were already rushing into the Western region after their belief was shaken.

‘There was no trust between them in the first place so this isn’t that strange.’

The branching families of the Long Clan didn’t really know their Emperor. He was like a god living on Mt. Olympus, there was nothing tangible in their relationship. They had been always treated as second-rate citizens by the main family. The only reason that they continued their alliance was due to the difference in power and the possibility of advancement. Now that they were offered nothing more than death, they could only turn to their recent enemy.

“What should we do with the refugees, some of them are powerful but I’m unsure where their loyalties lay…”

“As long as it's not with Long Qing it will suffice, we can’t just have them on our side unmanaged…”

“We will use the ankle bracelets to keep track of them.”

“Ah yes, the slave bracelets!”

Zhang Jin nodded at the mention of this device. It was similar to a slave collar but was placed out of sight on a person’s ankle. It would let the cultivators retain some amount of dignity. If they were forced to wear collars around their necks it could complicate things.

“Well then, things are progressing smoothly…”

“Is something wrong?”

“Not really but usually when things go too well…”

“You worry too much, after the activation there will be no way for those Long Clan bastards to sneak into our lands! This will give us enough time to reinforce our borders and finally, we will be able to go on the offensive!”

Zhang Dong nodded while looking at the map before him. The first part of the plan was almost over but this was just the beginning. Without having to worry about their borders they would be able to strike back. Amassing a greater force to conquer was the next step that he was not that willing to take.

Yet to end this conflict sooner he had to strike the iron while it was hot. The Long Clan was probably ill-prepared for an internal revolt that had now started. This was a chance for his side to take over, waiting too long would only allow his enemy to take control of the chaos, and this was something that he couldn’t allow.

Chapter 673

“Don’t let them activate it!”

“It’s too late!”

A blue shield of light pushed up into the sky. Instantly it stopped many projectiles that slammed against the protective energies. The tremendous explosions would have leveled any average building in one hit. Yet, the barrier of light stood strong without buckling under the pressure.

With the shield standing strong the ships firing could not get to the generators on the other side. Soon the people that were ordering the bombardment realized that it was over. Their projectiles couldn’t make it over to the other side but they, on the other hand, could be hit.

Large cannons on the walls of the stronghold they were trying to besiege took aim. Previously they had been almost successful in clearing them all out but some were still operational. With the blue shield between them, even these damaged cannons would be able to give them hell.

“R-retreat!”

It was too late, some of the blasts connected with the ships that had their own barriers already depleted. This army had given it all to shut off these structures before it was activated and had lost their wager. Now they were unable to cause any harm to their enemies but the other side could blast them to Kingdom Come.

“They are retreating! Should we form a pursuit unit?”

“No, we have achieved our goal, the great wall has been created and it will never fall!”

People on the other side cheered while watching the mass of ships retreating. The great wall of spiritual energy could be seen on both sides and reached deep underground as well. There was only one way to get in and that was through a stronghold and destroying one would probably not be enough. As long as the other castles remained intact the great formation would persist. Only after multiple ones fell would it be possible to get through.

‘At least that’s the theory, I am not sure how strong the Azure Emperor is or what their real trump card is…”

Zhang Dong in the disguise of Lei Yinglo was floating up in the sky. He helped defend this location while Zhang Zhi and Huo Qiang were doing the same in other regions. This was a combined attack of the branching families performed at multiple fronts. After his last ploy, the enemy army had lost a lot of good soldiers.

The infighting helped them tremendously and now the barrier was there. Anyone that wished to travel to the central region would have to go through one of the strongholds which his sect controlled. It worked both ways, all trade routes from the west that existed were now removed. Even though the central region was one of the most lush in the Empire it imported a lot of resources from the larger regions.
‘If the Heavenly Crane Sect decided to cut them off, we could slowly squeeze them dry… but those guys could see it as a chance to strike a deal with the Long Clan, that is if I let them…’

The Eastern region was supposed to be natural during this conflict. If they started aiding the Long Clan they would automatically become the enemies of the United Element Sect. Zhang Dong hoped that he had shown enough of his hand for them to reconsider.

‘I don’t think they will make any decisions unless I or the other side sends them an ultimatum. They should also realize that if they try to curry favor with the Long Clan, they will be used as replacements for these branching families…’

After seeing how the Long Clan does things it was obvious that they didn’t like to get their hands dirty. Their branching families were in an uproar after the news of the Emperor being a demonic being had started spreading. Some recordings of his illusion were skillfully pushed to some of the intelligence agencies working there. He was convinced that it would not go anywhere but thanks to this little trick he was finally able to create his great wall.

‘They should remain neutral but perhaps I need to send them a warning.’

Even if he was on good terms with the Heavenly Crane Sect, it was important to make them aware of the line they should not cross. If they aided the Long Clan in any way, they would be considered enemies. In the north as well as in the south regions of the empire his clan’s borders connected to the Heavenly Crane Sect. The Emperor resided in an oval region in the center that didn’t stretch out fully to the north and neither the south.

If the Heavenly Crane Sect decided to become his enemy, then he would need to fight them in those two regions. This was also why this wall was created, now even if the two teamed up, they would be able to easily get into his lands. Then there was also the hidden ally that was down in the south.

Argus and Lucius were still searching for parts of their holy equipment. They would not shy away from entering the central region to do so. The West was already opened to them and they were also allowed to search the East. Some new parts were discovered but with time they would have to move towards the central region.

‘They will be a good distraction when the time comes…’

While his mind was torn with ways of winning this war he was brought back to reality by the victorious shouts of his sect brothers and sisters. They were cheering as their mission was now done and they had been victorious. Everyone was going to get some merits that could be turned into cultivation resources. All of them took one big step towards immortality and more power.

‘I wonder what these people are really fighting for… for their families or just for selfish gain of power?’

Even after spending more than ten years in this world he still didn’t understand these people. To this day, gaining more power was only a means to an end. If he could just relax in a normal-sized home with his family and was left alone, then he would stop fighting. He didn’t even know if he wanted to provoke the one that created this world out of fright.

What if fighting was meaningless and he would just lose the short time he was given in this world to spend with his family? What if it was better to just live out his days and perish like everyone else? Maybe dying wasn’t the end and his life would continue in another strange world filled with adventure. However, what would a place like that be without his wife or children?

‘I must get around that time-stopping ability before it’s too late…’

Thus as his work was done, Lei Yinglo disappeared from the battlefield. Perhaps if he needed a secret identity again, his old persona could appear again as he was now considered an ally of the sect. Zhang Dong in his true form on the other hand returned to the dimensional regalia to ponder the elements and time. When the time for the last battle came he needed to be prepared.

Soon days turned into weeks and those into months as another year went by. A lot of changes took place after the appearance of the great wall which was named the Elemental Barrier after their sect. Many people were enraged by its appearance as they weren’t able to reach their families in the central region. They weren’t given a choice to complain as anyone willing to join the Long Clan was not allowed out.

No one expected such a drastic split to occur and neither that the Unlimited Elemental Sect was capable of producing such grand structures. It had become painfully obvious that the Golden Dragon was not in any way inferior to the Azure one. Soon more people started congregating in their cities and the armies continued to grow.

The Heavenly Crane Sect was put in a bad spot but it managed to remain neutral. They had been sent an ultimatum from both sides and decided to not join up with anyone. This of course soured their relations with the Long Clan but allowed them to conserve their forces. The East side was forced to create its own barricades in case of an invasion and thus weakened the central region even more.

No one knew who would attack who. Only the masters of the Western region could relax as their barrier could not be broken. A few attempts of bombarding or slamming powerful techniques at it were taken. Yet with the possibility of boosting the defenses in a desired location through the faction system and also teleporting, it was impossible for the Long Clan to get through.

It seemed that neither side was able to produce any substantial damage. The United Element Sect remained passive while the Long Clan even started sending out some of their own troops to test the defensive formation. No one knew what would happen but rumors of a counteroffensive were spreading. Sooner or later one side would complete their preparations and break this stalemate.

When this happened, all hell would break loose. The borders were devoid of life and the cities were deserted by their inhabitants. No one was willing to live close to the strongholds on either side. They knew that something was coming, two dragons could not exist so close to each other. This stalemate was nothing more than two giants throwing small jabs at each other before finally going in for the haymaker.

‘Warning warning, large structure approaching…’

“So it begins… I will have to work with what I have…”

Zhang Dong brought up his map as Bob informed him about the movement near the border region. Previously small skirmishes took place with the Long Clan’s flying armada being forced to return. Yet he knew that it was all just a test. They were trying to figure out the defensive limitations of the great elemental barrier. Several key strongholds were being approached by a swarm of large flying ships. It was a united attack bent on getting this large wall down.

“I bet they intend to push forward here after the barrier breaks… Well, I better not keep my brother waiting then…”

Chapter 674

“Open up the gates! The Emperor has made a verdict. The one called Long Dong has brought great shame to the Azure dynasty and needs to be punished for his actions. He is guilty of colluding with demonic cultivators that have sought to destroy peace in these lands!”

A loud voice echoed throughout all the lands as a man spoke out. Long Shen was his name and he was the oldest of the three children from the royal line. Behind him stood Long Fengge the youngest son and Long Yanyu the middle child. All of them had gathered for this announcement before the great shield behind which the United Element Sect forces were gathered.

“It is an undeniable fact that he worked together with the Demonic Cultivator known as Wang Long. The Emperor has deemed him guilty of treason but sees it fit to give his brother a way to defend himself! As long as he relinquishes his title of Golden Dragon and submits himself to the Empire’s forces, we shall guarantee the life of anyone that was bewitched by his techniques!”

The speech was quite long and painted Zhang Dong as a demonic cultivator without mercy. His name was associated with the likes of Wang Long who was known to have been responsible for destroying the Soaring Dragon Sect along with performing other atrocities while fleeing to the northwest demonic island.

“Do those idiots actually think that we believe any of that hogwash? The Patriarch isn’t a demonic cultivator at all. The fight against the Demon Emperor Wang Long was well documented!”

While the one-sided speech continued the people on the other side of the large barrier started complaining. Some of them had even been during the fight in the demon city, others were there when the Demi-Human Emperor and his forces attacked. The Long Clan wanted to pin all the deaths on their Patriarch and the people here weren’t taking it well. All they wanted to do was fire back but had to wait for their leaders to make a decision.

“That is why we urge you to stop this facade and open the gates! We will swiftly deal with the evil demonic cultivator referred to as the Golden Dragon and see to it that he doesn’t harm any more innocent people!”

The more the speech continued the more the people on the other side of the barrier got angrier. The man that was being discussed could hear everything that was being said. He along with a few others were looking at a holographic image in the middle of the table that represented the oldest son of the Azure Emperor. The man was wearing a very traditional-looking armor set composed of shiny blue scales.

“What are they trying to achieve with this statement?”

“Maybe they want to assess our troops? The Emperor’s name carries a lot of weight even to this day… It hasn’t been long since we grasped enough power to suppress them, some of our people might not be able to refute their claims…”

“Destroy their dantians if such people appear! How could we allow those kinds of individuals inside our sect!”

“Now calm down Liena, no one is breaking ranks yet.”

Zhang Dong calmed down his wife while Zhang Jin chuckled. The three along with a few other elders like Feng Maling were all gathered here. Huo Qianf and Zhang Zhi on the other hand were directly at the area where the speech was taking place. If an attack occurred they would be there to counter the armies with their own power.

“Dong’er is right, these are just standard tactics to lower the morale of the opposing troops. They probably hope for someone on the inside to revolt and perhaps disable the barrier for them. However, do you think our people are so weak or dumb to trust in them?”

Liena along with the others nodded and looked to the hologram. There they could see that the speech was ending but no one paid much attention to it. Instead, the troops that were stationed there started shouting profanities at the man in the armor.

“Go screw yourself and bring your daddy here!”

“Yeah, is the Emperor too scared to face us?”

“He isn’t our Emperor! Zhang Dong is the true leader, stop lying the demonic cultivators are you!”

“The great sect leader would never do such a vile act, It’s all lies and you shall pay for them!”

“Yeah! They must pay! Down with the tyrant!”

“The Azure Dynasty deserves to crumble!”

Everyone on the side of the Western region started shouting. They weren’t taking any of their rhetoric, not even one person paid attention to the sweet words and promises of treasures. The Long Clan tried to entice them with various boons if they decided to make way for their armies but at this point, no one could believe the Azure Dynasty anymore. Their movements had been erratic during the large crisis and the opinion of the people had shifted.

‘They won’t be able to get in through the front door… will they commence with their siege then?’

While the others were looking at the holographic image of the enemy army, he was examining his own system map. Thanks to it he could see the entire border region along with the placement of the enemy armies. While Long Shen and the siblings were at the central stronghold other forces were moving to other locations as they spoke. It was clear that they were all waiting for a signal to attack.

It wasn’t that hard to figure out how this defensive formation worked. It operated on the same principle as any other similar formation. While it stretched through a large area with many strongholds generating power to keep it running, there were a few core regions. To destroy this the Long Clan wouldn’t need to destroy all the castles, they just needed to contend with a handful.

‘I guess they figured it out before even giving it a first try, this is disheartening.’

Zhang Dong frowned as he hoped to at least waste some of the Long Clan’s resources during a prolonged defense. This formation had five core locations that needed to be protected. If they all were captured and disabled by the enemy, the entire structure would collapse. A core location could be swapped out but would require some time to recalibrate the barrier.

Thus he expected his enemies to attempt to capture a few of the strongholds first before discovering this fact. As it stood now they had successfully identified the correct locations and were waiting. If they managed to weaken all five of them at the same time, then the wall would collapse.

“This is all just a distraction, their true aim is to get to the key locations. During the speech, their forces have been trying to approach us… I guess we shouldn’t keep them waiting.”

He stood out from his seat which was somewhat more extravagant looking than the others. Even though he didn’t wish for it his wife forced him to distinguish himself from the other elders. Perhaps if it was in the past he would have disagreed with her but at a critical juncture where he was going against the Azure Emperor, his image also mattered. If he was to replace the old leader then he needed to also act one. After all of this was over and people settled down, then he could try introducing some slow changes.

“Where are you going?”

“Hm? I’m going to go join the others?”

“You can’t!’

“I can’t?”

“Listen to your wife, it’s too soon for the Patriarch to show himself. You could be walking right into their trap.”

Before he could take his leave to aid his soldiers he was stopped by his significant other. She wasn’t alone as his grandfather also stepped up to go against his decision. When looking at some of the other elders they averted their gazes but also seemed to agree with the two.

“You don’t want me to participate?”

“That would be the correct decision, you can’t risk your life at this stage of the conflict. The Azure Emperor hasn’t even appeared.”

“Dear, as the sect leader you must limit your actions, let the other warriors gain the glory while you prepare yourself for the real enemy, the Azure Emperor.”

“I see… and all of you agree with them?”

After hearing his wife also being against his involvement he turned to the other elders. All of them nodded and were in agreement. This was not the time to push their trump card onto the battlefield. Zhang Dong was the strongest weapon that they had. Someone as strong as him should not act unless it was truly necessary.

“Patriarch, it’s too dangerous. Our enemies know of your ways, this could all be an elaborate trap. We can’t ignore the Long Clan’s craftiness, they have existed for hundreds of thousands of years. The Golden Dong Palace that is now in our possession was once in theirs.”

“That is a good point…”

No one really knew what the enemy's true trump card was. The Azure Emperor was still a mystery and some caution was advised. Even though some of his forces were sacrificed to the war effort it was better than having him go down during the beginning phases of this war. There were many nascent soul masters willing to prove their might and letting them pave the way was something that he needed to contend with. It was impossible to save everyone and going off by himself would eventually get him killed.

“If everyone thinks so, then for now, I’ll return to my cultivation chamber, I’m sure my grandfather and my lovely wife will be enough to lead the attack.”

“I’m glad that you understand.”

Liena was happy and relieved that Zhang Dong decided to go with their advice. However, to their dismay, he was already thinking about potentially getting out there in his previously retired persona. The last time he went outside no one discovered his trick and thus had no reason to doubt in his words. As long as Zhang Dong the Golden Dragon didn’t appear on the battlefield, the Long Clan would have no reason to implement any potential grand traps. This would allow him to minimize the casualties while also helping him keep an eye on the enemy movement from a closer location.

‘I guess it was a good moment to revive Lei, there will be more work for the demon hunter…’

Chapter 675

“So you have chosen to stand with the demon? Are there no honorable warriors left? Will you all just stand by while our Empire crumbles in a mindless sea of carnage?”

Long Shen who was acting as the leading general proclaimed after his long speech had ended and no gates were opened. The other side wasn’t budging at all, no one was willing to join their side. Usually, the name of the Azure Emperor was enough to open all doors before them but this time around, they were getting nothing else than animosity.

“Stop babbling nonsense, if you cared about the Empire you’d have helped us against the demi-human scourge!”

“That’s right, where were you and that Azure Emperor of yours when our family members were being devoured by those monsters?”

“My entire family was killed by blood-sucking monstrosities and you did nothing! Now you want to spout some nonsense about honor? Go screw yourself!”

“Screw the Azure Emperor and the Long Clan!”

“Yeah! Screw them!”

A large number of angry voices echoed back at the end of the speech. Many people that were here were ones that joined up with the United Element Sect after losing their loved ones to the other invading Empire. Before Zhang Dong interfered in the city raids, millions of people had already perished. At that time there just wasn’t enough manpower to defend the whole western region.

The only one that could have pulled it was the Long Clan and they had ignored the plight of the people that were now blaming them for the deaths. The United Element Sect’s chosen method was impeccable. People that could betray them would not be allowed to participate in the border defense. There was no possibility of their own forces joining the other faction but this was not set in stone for the other side.

Long Shen’s speech was interrupted by the shouting and the sound magnified in various ways. The Long Clan was still only a clan and not a sect, they did not really allow outsiders to be part of their inner core. They still somewhat relied on forces from branching clans to assist them in large skirmishes like this. Their rule had been unopposed for millenia and thus they had grown somewhat ignorant.

“The Azure Emperor is a monster and so is anyone who follows them!”

“No one wants an incompetent leader to rule over us, now is the time for change. We need someone like the great leader Zhang Dong who actually cares about us instead!”

“Yeah, down with the tyrant the old dynasty needs to end for the Empire to be reborn!’

While this didn’t sound like anything new and the members that belong to the Long Clan didn’t take it to heart, some of the people there did. Branching families had heard about the accusations of demonic origins. A secret investigation had also been launched into the debacle with the secret base. It had vanished just like some of the surviving elders had said and was filled with a strange veil of darkness.

Some believed it to be trickery, others to be the truth. Now that they had all gathered here for another confrontation, it was hard to distinguish who was in the right without proper evidence. Yet the seed of doubt for their overlords had been already planted and by the looks of things, they were still getting pushed around like slaves. Even now their formation had the branch families in the front while the main Long Clan was sitting in the back inside massive aerial vessels.

“Very well, in the name of the Azure Emperor, you will all be punished! If you won’t listen to reason then you will be forced to yield!”

The speech was over and no resolution had been reached. The large armada that was on the other side of the barrier advanced forward while the flagship remained behind. This flying fortress was more similar to the golden palace in size. It wasn’t as bulky but seemed to possess a large number of cannons and space for the Long Clan members to reside on. Many nascent soul masters were residing there along with the Emperor’s children.

Soon the battle would commence and to no one's surprise Long Shen along with his siblings wouldn’t be taking part. After the attempt at opening the gates had failed the oldest son was replaced by an elder of equal strength. While the Long Clan wasn’t as big as a large sect, it made up the numbers with quality. There were multiple such masters gathered here and they would not go down easily.

‘Hm… they started advancing on the other fronts too, they are going for the joint attack.’

Zhang Dong was looking at his system map while residing at another location. Long Shen’s speech had been broadcasted everywhere and also to this stronghold he was now residing. He had been told by his wife and grandfather to remain in the dimensional regalia. Instead of listening to their plea, he had decided to join the border defenses as his alter ego, Lei Yinglo.

‘The main base is being defended by Huo Qiang so it should be safe, at his level he won’t go down to anyone besides the Azure Emperor himself. Zhi might be a bit weaker but he should be fine too and Liena is also there, she should be fine…’

He was the only one that was getting left out of the picture. His position on the chessboard was that of a king. A king should not move too willingly to expose himself to the enemy as if he died, then it all would just crumble. While he felt bad for deceiving his friends there was no danger of this happening if his enemies didn’t actually know who he was.

‘They would certainly pile up here if they knew about it but, they won’t know or even think that I’d pull a stunt like this…’

From his perspective, the Long Clan probably thought of him to be similar to their leader. An Emperor did not put themselves in danger if it wasn’t necessary. The thought of endangering their lives just to save some extra lives was preposterous. No Emperor or king would care about their subjects to this extent. Some even believed that they were the main focal point of their own country. What was the point of protecting it, if the Emperor got killed?

Thanks to the common sense of this world he had been given a safety net. No one would think that he was the Patriarch but just a regular elder that happened to be on the level of the others. His position was still a bit special and not everyone trusted the man called Lei Yinglo. After his work during the establishment of the other stronghold, he gained some fame but there was still some work left until he was seen as a core member of this sect.

‘I can keep watch over everything here and transferring my voice through the faction system won’t be a problem, no one will realize that I’m at this location.’

Thus began his plan of helping his sect to win this battle. Yet this would not be one of those quick battles that he was used to, instead, a prolonged siege was taking place. Both sides started pelting each other with various attacks from a somewhat safe location. It was a trial of attrition that continued for many hours until turning into days.

Even though the spirit bullets were flying back and forth, nothing else but the ground below them was taking damage. Both sides had very strong protective barriers and could not break through them. The flying ships had the advantage of being able to move so each time they had become low on energy, they were just swapped out for new vessels. The side with the strongholds on the other hand was just constantly receiving attacks. It seemed that the enemy’s tactic was quite easy.

“Elders, if this continues we might not hold out for that long…”

“It does seem so, where there any orders from the supreme elders?”

“No, they told us to hold out for now until they gather enough information for a counter-attack.”

After a few days of the continued siege, a problem arose. Most believed that the grand barrier was big and strong enough to last through any attacks even if they took weeks or months. Yet their enemy was the Long Clan, their flying ships were a lot more powerful than they had anticipated and one major flaw in this type of defense arose. As long as the other side could circle out their weaponry, sooner or later this side would become overwhelmed. Unless they supplied the shields with unlimited energy, it just wasn’t sustainable.

“Do they at least know how much time we have?”

“Some say, that we have around a month's time until the shields become too weak to hold, writhing that time we must come up with a solution.”

The Long Clan was in a more favorable location with a giant spirit vein inside the central region. They could route all that spiritual energy into their flying armada to replenish its energy. With a constant stream of new flying monstrosities on their side, the energy resource they were using was practically unending. If something wasn’t done about it, then soon one of the core points of this formation would break and then they would lose their advantage over their enemy.

‘It’s good that they don’t know who I am…’

Zhang Dong thought to himself while coming up with a solution to the problem. His side didn’t want to give up the defensive advantage by sending in their own ships to chase the Long Clan armada. Their side was probably already waiting with a counter-offensive if they attempted to push in. While throwing everything into the battle could produce results, a lot of lives would be lost. The only other option would be to somehow cut off their enemy's supply lines.

“Could I propose a solution to our problem?”

“Elder Yinglo? Could there be something that we missed?”

He was not alone in this place and this time around he wasn’t playing on going in solo either. While it was possible for him to just teleport behind enemy lines, battling all those nascent soul masters by himself would be draining. It was possible for the Azure Emperor to be waiting for such a tactic.

“What if I told you about a way of getting around their defenses? If all goes well, then we will be able to strike at their backs when they least expect it.”

“Oh? Such a way exists?”

“Yes, what we can do is…”

Thus he started explaining his new battle plan, while it had some problems it was better than just waiting here. Before their defenses became overrun by their enemy cannon fire, they would cut off their never-ending supply of energy.

Chapter 676

“I still can’t believe we are doing this… can they really not see us?”

“Would they let us be here if they did?”

“Hey, shut up you two, and get a move on, it’s no time for chatter! We need to complete the mission, place the devices in the correct locations just like the elders told us!”

“Forgive us, senior sister!”

A small group of hooded figures were sneaking around the ground. Above them, the loud explosions of spirit cannons were successfully masking their speech as they maneuvered around the raging battlefield. Sparks of leftover spiritual energy rained down on them like drizzle but they were well protected by their clothing and special hiding technique.

They were all shrouded in some sort of darkness, as long as they kept to it, there was no way of them being discovered. The man responsible for this was hidden away somewhere in the middle and concentrating. Thanks to his technique many core formation warriors were able to move around this place freely and were about to finish their mission.

‘They won’t know what hit them.’

Zhang Dong thought to himself while looking up. There right above him was the colossal fortress in which the Long Clan was hiding. After realizing that the shield they assembled wouldn’t last the continued blasting, he came up with a solution. Instead of pushing in with the sect's limited forces, he decided to create a funnel of energy below the armada. His teleportation feature allowed him to create a smaller temporary teleportation gate on the other side of the shielding formation. Through it he moved in some of his troops that were now setting up their counter.

‘I don’t feel the presence of the Azure Emperor nor that of his wife… though she was previously able to hide her true form from me, so I have to take that into consideration.’

When he was in the Azure Palace, his older brother showed some mild care for his children. While he was allowed to teach them a lesson, their relations weren’t that bad. If he managed to capture them alive, then they could probably act as a bargaining chip to hasten their surrender. Yet, he couldn’t see those old elders give up their position in the Empire. Playing second fiddle to a sect of upstarts was not something they would do. Long Qing was still part of the Long Clan and probably carried the same sentiments.

‘He acted very relaxed and confident back then, but that could have been before he identified me as a threat to his position. I don’t think he will step down without putting up a fight but perhaps if I have his children, he’ll back away.’

His current intention was not necessarily to win this conflict, at least not at this very moment. His life would be long and he had not aged a day since arriving in this world. He had a good five hundred years in him until his body would start showing signs of aging. His brother on the other hand didn’t have that much time as long as a non-involvement agreement could be established, it would be fine.

What he needed now was just more time to master his strange cultivation realm and for that he needed the Long Clan to back away. There were a lot of holes in his plan as he wasn’t sure how deep those family ties were. Then he also needed to catch at least one of those kids before he could start bargaining with his current enemy.

‘For all I know they might not even be inside that flying fortress, it wouldn’t be strange for them to have teleported back to their main city to seek shelter.’

His thoughts continued to bug him while this area was being outfitted with traps. Two other regions had been worked on beforehand and now he found himself together with Huo Qiang against the main fortress. His identity remained hidden for the time being and his wife wasn’t here. Liena was probably the only person that would be capable of reading his mannerisms but she was further to the north protecting one of the other core structures.

“Elder, we are done.”

“Good, let us return before they realize.”

Finally, after days of preparing all the traps were ready. Soon their plan could bear fruit and the joint operation could commence. Thanks to Bob who could forward all information almost instantly to everyone at the same time, it was easy to start the push. He and the other cultivators that took part in the initial mission moved back to look at the fireworks.

The unsuspecting people from the Long Clan and their branch families had a rude awakening as they saw a light show from down below. First, all the devices that were placed and looked like boxes covered in magical runes started glowing. They connected to each other with glowing straight lines to produce a giant magical circle underneath. A purple glow encompassed multiple regions as the first effect took shape.

Something akin to a gravity field was formed that started to pull all the flying vessels down toward the ground. Thanks to Zhang Dong’s knowledge of the Dao of gravity and the inclusion of magics from another world, it was possible to trap his enemies here. Now that this magical trap had been activated it wouldn’t be easily destroyed. It was powered by the large defensive formation and directly connected to it.

“Now is the time, give it all you got, brothers and sisters, to me!”

Huo Qiang led the vanguard forward as they burst forth from the main defensive stronghold. Previously they would be unable to chase down the attacking armada that could easily outrun them while pelting them with a mass of spirit bullets. Now while they were trapped in the gravitational trap, they could not move and were also being pulled in the direction of the stronghold which was in possession of many large cannons.

Zhang Dong wasn’t far behind but his main role was protecting the gravity trap which he was the focal point of. If he strayed too far then it would lose some of its pulling force. This was required to affect the large Long Clan flying stronghold that was slowly being yanked over in his direction. It was their main priority and after the other side was caught in the trap, their side began to charge.

Zhang Dong tried to help as best as he could while protecting the formation from various energy blasts. Many large formations taking the forms of turtles to defend him were also in the way. Getting through all of it would take some time and this was not something the Long Clan had plenty off. Their ships could not move at all, they were like sitting ducks just waiting for their shields to be blasted through.

On his system map, he could see the same actions being taken at the other locations. There weren’t any huge flying strongholds like the one here. Even without his help, his people were able to keep at it. This didn’t mean that there weren’t any casualties along the way. It was a war between two powerful factions and no one was willing to give their enemy an inch.

For him who could see his faction population on the system window, it was maddening. He had to sit there without being able to do much while his people were being killed or injured. Before the massive fortress in the air was breached he couldn’t really move. Huo Qiang, Zhang Liena, and Zhang Zhi were battling it out on their own fronts and needed to contend with their own powers.

He had to somewhat stay true to his promise of not getting involved in the border dispute. If he just activated his full power the Long Clan would more than likely target his position. Having a clear shot at the enemy leader was not something they could ignore. Perhaps they would even use this massive fortress of theirs as a battering ram, however, as it looked his involvement wasn’t needed.

‘It seems that they really weren’t expecting this turn of events, just a bit more and we can blast through their defenses.’

While the huge formation that was around the borders was being boosted by various treasures and even somewhat by a spirit vein, the other army wasn’t. They only had flying ships with engines that were not built to get bombarded by countless spirit blasts from cannons. Now that they were forced in range of them, they were getting blasted to smithereens and soon some of them started to crash down to the ground.

“That’s it, they are faltering don’t let up, focus fire on the main stronghold, pull the Long Clan bastards out of there!”

Even now the enemy clan was using the branch families as cannon fodders. A regiment of their ships was creating an axillary defensive formation. They were taking the brunt of the attacks while the people from the Long Clan tried to pull away from the gravitational attack. All their cannons were aimed directly at the ground but it wasn’t that easy to get rid of the magical lines. Zhang Dong was keeping his shadowy techniques alive which made it quite difficult to pinpoint the true location of the weak points.

‘Are they going to use their large cannon?’

As a last-ditch effort to get out of there, the large castle-like structure transformed some of its towers into a massive cannon. The sound of it powering up produced a lot of static noise and was hard to miss. It was pointed directly down and at his immediate location. Clearly, his enemies had pinpointed the man responsible for it all and were dead set on killing him.

‘Oh?’

‘Protect the Elder, don’t let them destroy the gravity trap!’

Before he could do something about it, a large group of flying ships gathered around him. There were various models that he remembered drawing up in his spare time as well as some that he had never seen before. These probably belonged to some of their allies from other sects that decided to join them in this defensive battle.

They were all there ready to take the massive cannon blow by themselves. They all knew that if the elder controlling this grand magic fell, then their plan would go up in smoke. The other side on the other hand didn’t look that united. Some of them were trying to escape to the sides while others continued with the battle. There was a stark difference between the leadership of these two sides and soon it would be made obvious which had the advantage.

Chapter 677

A blast of swirling light shot forth and collided with a large blockade of defensive formations. It looked like a giant snapping turtle with a spiky shell after multiple smaller such formations connected with each other. Even though the creature looked massive it started crumbling under the pressure of the spiritual energy.

“We have to hold!”

“Give it your all, even if it kills you!”

Some of the cultivators inside the formation cried out in pain. Others spit out a copious amount of blood while trying to remain conscious. Nevertheless, none of them relented and even if their bones were broken or cultivation was shattered, they would not let this attack get through to the elder down below.

The man they were trying to protect was shrouded in a sphere of dark purple light. He was the central node of the whole trap formation that was created under the Long Clan’s flying stronghold. If his technique was interrupted then their plan would quickly go up in smoke. The warriors of the sect fighting this war knew the stakes and they were unwilling to give in while victory was at their fingertips.

Yet, it didn’t seem that they would be able to last through this massive blast of energy. This flying fortress was massive and so was the main cannon it wielded. The energy it produced was far outside what a group of cultivators creating defensive formations could combat.

“It won’t hold…”

The nascent soul master that was the focal point of this large turtle caught up some blood while speaking. He and a handful of other early-stage nascent soul masters had recently been able to push into this realm. This was only possible thanks to their sect and mostly the Patriarch who was able to push people through the threshold through a strange cleansing technique.

All of them felt grateful and wished to repay the kindness that was given to them. In their minds, there was no reason for their leader to do such a thing. Other masters in larger sects usually kept such techniques hidden and only aided their closest aids or even took them to the grave. Even if they were in the same faction, it was hard to trust anyone. Only after this sect was established were they able to look past such things, to the point of sacrificing it all.

The crumbling turtle gave out a massive roar as everyone inside of it pushed themselves further. Some were even able to advance through the threshold of their previous cultivation realm in a last-ditch attempt at victory. Their struggle bore fruit as somehow they were able to last through the blast that left a giant gaping hole in the glowing turtle's spiky shell.

“It didn’t go through, the trap persists!”

They cheered when they realized that they had managed to last through the blast of energy without affecting the elder's concentration below. Their voices quickly went quiet as they saw the massive cannon charging up again. It was already a miracle that they managed to block the first one, a second one would cleanly go through the damaged defensive formation.

They turned to the sky to see if some help was coming. Their biggest asset, Huo Qiang, was already being contested by ten nascent soul masters. His soul beast was tussling with a mass of others. It would be impossible for him or any other to make it in time. It would take several minutes to restore the gap in the shell but they only had a few seconds of time before the cannon recharged.

The cannon fire from their own stronghold wasn’t able to get through the flying fortress's defenses. It looked bleak for the people below, if they didn’t move out of the way then their lives would be forfeit. There was not enough energy to block another shot. If they moved from this spot, their elder that was concentrating below them would be hit instead. He was known as a strong man but even he wouldn’t last through it. When he died or got injured their trap would be gone and the counterattack of their enemies would shred them.

A decision was made by the people inside. They would sacrifice themselves for the cause. Even if they saved themselves, the enemy armada would be unleashed and their back would be open while they fled. Either they died, or everyone else would. There was a slight hesitation at first but in the end, they all came to the same conclusion. It was better to die for the sect that treated them well than to live as ants as they did before joining up with them.

“Remember us!”

“For the sect and for the future!”

“Take care of my family…”

All of them were resolute and gathered their energies for one last blast. Perhaps this would give the other elders enough time to do something about this cannon, each second mattered and they were convinced of this worthwhile sacrifice. However, something threw a big wrench into their plan and it was in the form of a giant beam of light coming from the side of their own fortress.

“Huh?”

They all gasped as they saw something drill itself against the protective barrier of that massive fortress. The beam that was charging up started faltering as the owners of the floating castle needed to reroute all energy toward their own defensive formations. Even with that they were unable to fully counter this massive attack that continued to blast away.

“Is that?”

“Did the Patriarch come to aid us? But he was supposed to remain at the sect…”

“No, it’s not the Patriarch… it’s his soul beast!”

A large golden dragon appeared out of nowhere and passed through the barrier. It was clearly Bahamut, the beast that belonged to the United Element Sect’s leader. The people here didn’t really know that the dragon had become its own being that could act independently. To their knowledge, it would be impossible for these soul beasts to form at such a large distance from their main sect.

Yet, their leader was not there and his spiritual essence was missing. How he was able to control this creature at this distance was unknown to them but now they were saved. The golden dragon tossed itself into the battle as it continued to blast the enemy fortress with forceful ranged attacks. It had more firepower than the average flagship of a grand sect and much more maneuverability.

The course of the battle shifted almost instantly as the dragon arrived. The tired soldiers that almost died while protecting the gravity trap now had enough time to regain their footing. The large turtle that they previously formed was restored. After using some recovery pills on the injured members inside, all was well again and the counter-offensive began.

‘Good that I called Bahamut over, no one said that he couldn’t help out with the cause.’

Zhang Dong was still sitting below in his lotus position. He had predicted that something could go wrong and had his familiar wait in hiding. Thanks to the sudden attack some of the cannon had been damaged. It was time to push through and board the main structure of the Long Clan.

‘I must pull them in a bit closer, those other ships don’t matter, all I have to do is to get into that thing before they run away…’

The battle continued and for the time being he had to remain on the ground. The closer the enemy armada got to the center of the formation, the greater the gravitational pull became. Soon they were forced to move away from their ships that became nothing more than unmoving targets for the spirit cannons.

‘They really don’t care about those branch families, do they?’

To no surprise, the cultivators that belonged to the branching families attempted to retreat into the largest fortress. It at this point in time had not yet fallen and was the only thing that could protect them from the cannon fire. Yet, when they approached it, their bodies were repelled by the defensive formation. It seemed that the only people that could go through it were members of the main Long Clan.

Such behavior was something that he expected but their using their allies as meat shields blatantly was not something that even Zhang Dong expected. The Long Clan leaders probably had their reasons for it but it made them look immoral and instantly lowered everyone's morale.

“T-the main clan has abandoned us!”

“How could this be? After all we sacrificed for them?”
To a lot of people here fighting for the Long Clan was their ticket to immortality. They knew that there were no guarantees given and that the road would be bumpy, but they at least expected them to give them some aid in a situation like this. Now it became clear that the Long Clan only acted tough when they were greatly superior to their opponents. In a case like this where things were more disadvantageous they would retreat.

‘Here they come, time for phase two!’

Zhang Dong watched his people fight for the future of their sect with their lives on the line. On the other side, the Long Clan and their branching families could not be any more divided in their goals. Thanks to such a disbalance he would be able to achieve victory here as now he could activate the true trap.

As he was sitting there the purple light expanded in the form of various shadowy and purple tentacles. These were thicker than trees and numbered in the thousands. They quickly wiggled up to grasp the flying fortress that had arrived before him. Incorporating some techniques from his old enemies was quite handy and even though this made him look like some kind of demonic cultivator, it was needed to disable this flying fortress.

“Just like we planned! Board their fortress!”

Huo Qiang, the acting general shouted out. In both his hands he had a charred corpse of a nascent soul master. After tossing them to the side he turned into a shooting star. To someone like him that liked to battle strong foes, there was almost no greater gift than the Long Clan. His aim was the oldest son of the Emperor whom he considered to be the number two of that faction.

Yet before he could storm the castle a massive surge of azure flames exploded from within this structure. It brought with it a surge of unprecedented spiritual energy that forced even someone like Huo Qiang to back away. Soon the flames were followed by a beastly roar that sounded similar to that of a dragon…

Chapter 678

“Has the Azure Emperor come himself?”

“Why would he appear here now, is it to protect his children?”

The people from the united element sect were stunned at the scene that was playing out before them. Just a moment ago it looked like they would be able to board the inside of this flying fortress and get to the Long Clan members hiding inside. The gravitational formation had spawned some dark tentacles that clung to the huge structure and pulled it down to the ground. Escape was now impossible, or so they thought.

Almost at the same time as the defensive shield wavered a spike in spiritual energy occurred. They all backed away out of fright of an explosion happening but instead were greeted by a ferocious draconic roar. From within the fortress, a large blue dragon emerged that was around the same size as its golden counterpart that belonged to the United Element Sect’s Patriarch.

It was preceded by an azure column of flames that reached the sky and created a fiery twister. This surge of energy started pushing everything away while creating a momentary safe spot in the middle. Even when someone like Huo Qiang who practiced the dao of fire tried to get closer, he was burned by these strange flames. No one could get close and had to watch the giant dragon rise up while spreading its wings.

‘These flames aren’t regular flames, they affect the soul as well…’

Zhang Dong, who was below the large fortress, started analyzing the situation. The draconic beast that he was looking at was more than likely the soul beast of the Azure Emperor. While he had not seen it before, the spiritual energy signature that it was giving off, was identical to the Emperor’s.

‘I don’t feel his presence, did he just send out his beast instead of coming here himself?’

Most people were starting to panic. No one expected Long Qing’s soul beast to appear and it wasn’t even the only one there. Right behind it was a smaller version of the blue dragon that had one person standing on top of its head. It was the oldest child of Emperor Long Shen. The other three that had previously been here with him were missing.

‘They are either attacking the other locations with their armies or returned home before this battle started…’

He had to at least give it to Long Shen. The man had stayed together with his troops without running away. For a moment he expected to see an elder replacing his position while he fled even before the whole battle started. Instead, he was together with his father’s beast that looked only similar to his own.

‘They must somehow force their soul beasts to look the same through their cultivation technique, maybe that’s why they also confused me with being part of their clan.’

Bahamut the golden dragon looked somewhat similar to the azure being. They weren’t a palette swap but were both western dragons with wings coming out of their backs. Both of them were staring at each other as the battle was paused. The azure flames that were swirling around were making it troublesome to move forward as they burned more than just flesh.

Luckily, the golden dragon that was on the side of the United Element Sect was similar. Its master had mastered the Dao of the souls which meant that it was capable of contending with these strange flames. It gave out a loud roar as it produced a counter technique. A lightning storm of pale golden light was formed in an instant and it flew at the swirling inferno.

These two spiritual forces collided with each other while everyone else just watched. A shower of lightning bolts descended on the entire fortress that was being shrouded in blue flames. The Azure beast on the inside opened up its wings to rouse the flames. They engulfed the entire space and became thicker but it was not enough.

“The lightning attacks, they are erasing the flames!”

One of the elders participating in the battle shouted out. After a moment the enraged flames started vanishing. With each strike of lightning and thundercrack, they were thinning out. The whole golden storm moved over the stronghold to engulf it and the battle raged on.

‘They are about equal…’

While the other sect members couldn’t really see what was going on, Zhang Dong could tell that Bahamut wasn’t truly winning. Both forces were canceling each other out, for every bolt that landed on the flames more were born to counter it. The two massive dragons were now in a bout of endurance and nothing else. Their powers were suspiciously equal and even after a prolonged exchange a victor was not arising.

‘Wait, what is that Long Shen doing? Is he trying to escape?’

In the turmoil, he could see the smaller dragon move somewhere. He finally left his position as the trapping formation had done what it was created for. However, it was already too late. When he arrived behind his golden dragon the other side was already activating a teleportation technique. They were using the Emperor’s beast as a distraction while escaping along with the other Long Clan members.

‘I should have acted sooner, they are actually doing the sensible thing and escaping…’

It seemed that his enemies weren’t as stupid this time around. The moment they were convinced that there was no way of winning, they started escaping. Various teleportation talismans were being used and to his surprise, they weren’t being blocked by the formation he created. It was created with the talismans the branch families were using in mind. This was a new batch and they were clearly superior in all aspects.

‘They just left them all here…’
While the main Long Clan that was stationed on the stronghold escaped, the branch families that were stranded in the flying ships weren’t as lucky. They were in possession of the older version of the talismans that could be blocked. They could only look from the sidelines as their allies fled and they were left here at the mercy of the United Element Sect.

“Don’t think that this will change anything. Your deeds will not go unpunished! The whole Empire will know of your demonic nature!.”

Long Shen’s voice echoed through the whole battlefield before he vanished. His soul beast disappeared along with him but the flames that were being produced by the larger azure dragon were still there. It was staying there to act as a distraction and a shield. Even though Bahamut was close to breaking through, he would be unable to shatter the flames in time. Their main foe had managed to escape but this wasn’t all.

“My brother, I might have underestimated you but… this won’t happen again! I will see you soon, so until then, please try to stay alive, Ha ha ha!”

Zhang Dong that was still in the form of Lei Yinglo was stared at by the Azure dragon. The beast started to suddenly talk in the voice of his older brother, Long Qing. He was somehow able to see through his disguise while no one else could. After a few words the being he was controlling also started to fade away but before fully leaving it did leave a parting gift.

“Everyone, retreat, that stronghold is going to explode!”

He quickly shouted at everyone as he noticed an internal problem with the fortress. It was self-destructing and it wouldn’t take more than a few seconds for the engine to blow up. Everyone retreated at the call out from the elder. Some nascent masters moved forward to shield their weaker juniors and it was the same for Bahamut. His wings spread to all sides as it began producing a massive shield to protect everyone that was behind it.

The fortress that was brought down to the ground exploded with a resounding boom. It was as if they had expected this outcome beforehand. Perhaps while their stronghold was under the gravitational pull, they had already evacuated their soldiers. This explained why the teleportation talismans were used in unison.

Yet not everyone was saved, the people belonging to the branch families that were behind this blast were getting burned alive. His forces were defending against the blast that was before them, there was no time for anyone to look at what was happening behind this evaporating stronghold.

‘Hold it together…’

Zhang Dong strained his power as he tried to contain the blast together with Bahamut. Both of them were the closest to the initial detonation with Huo Qiang up in the air where he previously slaughtered a few nascent soul masters. Everything was quickly swallowed up by the bright blue explosion of azure flames that attempted to burn through the souls of everyone here.

‘I need to protect their souls or they will all die, the spirit energy contained in this blast is just a distraction.’

The real attack was hidden inside of the explosion and loud noise. Normally everyone would protect themselves from the overloaded Qi but not be aware of the underlying soul attack. Luckily for everyone here, Zhang Dong was a specialist when it came to souls. Thanks to his quick reaction he was able to douse these azure flames that were trying to burn through.

They didn’t seem to discriminate between anyone. The leftover branch family members belonging to the Long Clan could not protect themselves from this strange attack. For a moment he expected them to have some sort of shielding that would allow them to persist but they started dropping like flies.

‘Damn bastards don’t even care about their allies!’

He was enraged at the sight of people losing their lives. His side was safe from the adverse effects of the soul attack and only suffered some minor cases from the spike in spiritual energy. The branching clans on the other hand were getting wiped out. It was so bad that for a moment Zhang Dong wondered if his older brother was trying to eradicate these side clans and then pin it all on his faction.

To protect his own people his form expanded into a golden haze. His true form had to be exposed as without it, using his holy energies would be impossible. The light surrounded everything and pushed the flames away to cancel their adverse effect. Soon the area returned to normal but the sight that remained was anything but regular. A large hole where the stronghold was pulled down was now there and large groups of collapsed cultivators were everywhere.

‘...’

He was speechless at the sight of the soulless husks on the ground. The inclusion of soul arts complicated things but it was also too late to turn back. Now that such a large number of his foes had perished, his side had an advantage that needed to be used.

Chapter 679

“Hey, there are some survivors here!”

“How many are there?”

“Not that many, not more than ten made it out alive…”

“If it wasn’t for the Patriarch, a lot of us would have perished with them.”

“So this is how the Long Clan does things?”

“Yeah and still those idiots flock to them … “

Two soldiers were pushing some rubble out of the way to get to the survivors. What they found was not for the faint of heart. The people that were within the blast zone of the explosion had their souls destroyed. Their bodies looked like dried-up husks and several of those were on top of one survivor here.

“The people on top must have used something to protect this person…”

“Family?”

“Perhaps…”

One of the soldiers noticed a medallion around the woman’s neck that had survived the explosion. Three other people with similar accessories were on top of them. It seemed that they tossed themselves on top of her to protect her soul from getting devoured.

“Could have been their child or perhaps a sibling?”

“Such a terrible fate to be betrayed by your allies… will the world finally listen?”

“What do you think? They’ll try to pin the blame on us, I bet they’ll say that our Patriarch did it all just like the last time!”

“They have no honor or pride.”

One of the soldiers spit to the side while the other gently carried the survivor onto a floating platform. This platform produced a blue shield of light to protect the injured woman. It was a special stretcher that on the inside also produced golden light of healing to stabilize this patient. In the distance, similar devices were used to carry out the handful of survivors that could perhaps give some insights into the current Long Clan strategies.

Even though they were being rescued their status was still that of a prisoner of war. Perhaps after the betrayal from their side, it would be easier to convince them of the Long Clan’s devil-like nature. Yet, the fear of the old monster that had ruled over these lands for millenia was strong. It wouldn’t be that easy to change the mind of the citizens that grew up on the fact that the Long Clan was the strongest of them all.

“That is true but will anyone believe us?”

‘That’s a good question…’

Zhang Dong hovered up in the sky while looking around the area. His attention focused on the conversation of these soldiers. He was far up in the air but this didn’t stop him from using his senses to listen in. It brought a question to the forefront about how others would see this confrontation. Would they believe that the Long Clan abandoned their branching families or not?

‘Our side recorded the whole exchange but they’ll just say that we tempered with it or created some type of illusion. There are many ways of spinning it but one thing is clear, they have lost this battle and were forced to retreat…’

Although the Long Clan would probably deflect all accusations of their cowardly behavior, one thing could not be denied. The Behemoth that towered over the Empire for countless ages had been vanquished in an open field. Even though most of their army was made up of branching clans and mercenaries willing to risk their life for resources, they had lost.

‘Those clans will think twice about involving themselves in this conflict now.’

Zhang Dong knew that the people from this world were not that brave. Cultivators calculated their chances of victory and usually only engaged in combat if they were confident in winning. The ones that arrived at the pinnacle of power were not there due to their bravery but their caution. This war which was supposed to be an easy victory had become a lot messier.

‘The Emperor’s dragon was seen by everyone, they probably won’t be able to deny that.’

With the appearance of the Azure Dragon beast, it was clear that this was not an easy battle. If the Emperor had to get involved to save his children, the sides had to be somewhat equal. Most of the experts would take this time to reevaluate their decisions and steps. Siding with the United Element Sect had become a valid tactic that could prove very profitable.

In the end, the cultivators just wanted one thing, more cultivation resources to fuel their neverending desire for power and immortality. If the Long Clan actually fell during this conflict, the rewards that could be gained would be massive. They had hundreds of thousands of years to reach this point and were probably hiding a lot of secrets.

The ancestor of the Azure Emperor was supposed to have been a true immortal that ascended. To push into that fabled realm a lot of people would risk their lives. Masters that were close to their death could see this as a chance for them to live a bit longer.

‘It will take a bit longer for those old hidden foggies to come out, one won battle won’t change much, this war is only beginning…’

Zhang Dong brought up his system window and clicked over to his map. There he could see the entire wall that was created on the western border. It was mostly in a shade of green with a few spots being orange and the spot he was in now, was the same. The color represented the damage that the formation suffered. It shifted to yellow from green and then over to orange with red being the last one. If the fight continued for longer then red would be all that was left.

‘It held up and they have all retreated after their main fortress fell…’

After analyzing some combat data it was revealed to him that this area was a decoy. They were probably expecting to pull most of the defenders out from the other regions here. With most of the firepower drawn in the direction of their flying fortress the other ship fleets would have time to blast through one of the other walls.

However, after it was destroyed the other ships in the other areas started to retreat. There were probably many reasons for the retreat, one of them perhaps being the betrayal from the Long Clan’s side. The more the trust wavered, the better it became for his side of the equation. Now it was up to him to decide on the next step. Would they give their enemies time to recover or push in while they were winning?

‘If I wait too long they will eventually recover and the next time it might not be as easy…’

Information was key and now the Long Clan had a lot of it. The next time they came here they would probably expect him to be somewhere on the battlefield. He had hoped to remain hidden as Lei Yinglo but could not keep his form during the explosion. The soul energy and aura of golden thunder clearly belonged to him. Perhaps even the Azure Emperor would be there to catch him when he revealed himself.

‘They certainly don’t care about their soldiers as much as I do. Launching a sneak attack during the confrontation could work and they probably do something about the gravity trap the next time around.’

He could not count on the same tactic working twice. Now that his enemies knew about the gravity energy and also about his shadowy technique that he implemented into it, they would certainly try to do something about it. Zhang Dong was not out of options though. They had no idea about his system and he could use it to create better-placed teleportation spots at the border region. Defending this area for some time was possible and perhaps he wouldn’t even need to participate.

‘Hm… what should I do…’

“Senior brother, watch out!”

“Huh?”

“I tried to stop her but she came through!”

“Uh…”

His thoughts were interrupted by Huo Qiang who shouted in his direction. The person he was pointing to was flying his way and she didn’t look happy. Those furrowed brows made her usually cute face look ferocious. It was like a demon was coming his way and he had no place to run.

“How dare you lie to me!”

“I uh… please calm down my wife we are still out on the battlefield, what if there are any Long Clan survivors…”

“Then they will have to wait for you to explain yourself.”

Zhang Dong started backing away while Liena flew over to his location. The other sect members bowed their heads at the arrival of their matriarch and soon started listening in to the conversation. When arriving she was screaming out at the top of her lungs which made things somewhat obvious. To not have their private life be exposed, Zhang Dong quickly created a barrier to block out sounds from getting out.

“You were supposed to remain at the sect, what were you thinking? Disguising yourself as an elder? How long have you been doing this for?”

“I uh… it wasn’t that long…”

“It wasn’t? So if I look up your fake name in the records, I won’t find anything interesting?”

“Why would you do that dear… How about you calm down and we discuss things somewhere private.”

“Calm down? You want me to calm down?”

He had made a grave error in his wording. His lovely wife, who was usually calm, collected, and cute, started shouting at him. It was hard to refute her claims as he had done the things that she mentioned. Without telling anyone he endangered his life but the biggest problem was this, it was the lack of trust.

“Do you really trust us this little?”

“No, I was just worried that more people would die… please understand.”

After a little back and forth the shouting stopped. The crux of the issue was his lack of trust in his people that usually depended on his overwhelming might to get things done. He had come here to finish the battle faster and to conserve lives. While his plan had worked, if his enemies were able to figure out his true identity, this whole thing could have ended with a tragedy.

“No more lies from this point on, will you promise me this?”

“Of course!”
Liena squinted while Zhang Dong tried to put on his poker face. Her face moved in quite close to look for nervous ticks but there were none. Even though he just went through a large-scale battle, the fear he felt now was greater than he had when the flying stronghold was exploding.

‘I’ll be sleeping on the couch for a while…’

Chapter 680

“What are those bastards thinking? Let me go there and I’ll knock some sense into them, brother!”

“No, we must minimize the infighting, this is what got us in this situation in the first place…”

“Those blasted United Element Sect bastards are turning our people against us! Who do they think they are?”

Long Fengge shouted angrily while looking at his older brother Long Shen. To the side, Long Yanyu was looking at a holographic depiction of the central region that looked somewhat similar to what Zhang Dong was using. It was color-coded in the same way and showed which places had been damaged or taken over.

“I say we hang the traitors to make an example, how dare the branch families second guess our orders? Something like this had never happened before! They actually demanded that our father join the battle.”

“Preposterous, just because that fool took part in the battle they expect father to do the same, they need to be shown some manners!”

“Will you two quiet down, they will be punished with time but first we need to drive these invaders out of our lands. You have already seen their capabilities, that man is the real deal…”

“Do you actually think that we might lose?”

Long Fengge asked his older brother with a surprised expression on his face. After the last battle, the oldest started acting strange, it was as if he was afraid of their so-called uncle. During the siege, they had seen a glimpse of his power. He was able to deflect the destruction of the flying fortress that should have been enough to blast the whole region into nothingness.

That he was able to defend himself and his people against the soul attack was also not something they calculated in. What they were expecting was a victory while suffering a small number of casualties from their side. The branching families weren’t really considered part of the main clan so they didn’t care that much about them. Yet even after using their last trump card the damage they sustained was far greater than they anticipated. Their enemies were untouched and now quickly pushing in on the border region.

If this wasn’t bad already, there were more troubles brewing. The branch clans were now unwilling to cooperate with their forces. Some masters had already taken their disciples and vanished from the central region. Most of them hid away within the central region but some were escaping to the east as the western region was sealed off and unsafe.

People had become aware that this was not a one-sided conflict. Everything that transpired during the first confrontation confirmed the old rumors. The United Element Sect was not an easy opponent and they were not to be underestimated. Even if all the conflicts in the Western region were fabricated, it didn’t matter anymore. They were able to push back a direct attack from the Long Clan. It didn’t matter that the forces were mostly made up of branch families, no weak sect would be able to achieve a victory over their forces and do this without suffering many casualties themselves.

“We won’t lose but the real question isn’t that.”

“Then what is it, elder brother? If you are so sure of our victory, why did you order everyone to retreat? We lost a lot of people there, perhaps it would have been better to at least try?”

“Sister, are you questioning your eldest brother’s decision?”

“Me? Questioning his decision? I did no such thing, I’m just talking aloud as always you may ignore my ramblings~”

Long Yanyu posed the question while looking at the red marks on the map. Long Shen was supposed to inherit the mantle of Azure Emperor in the future so his words counted for a lot. During the confrontation, he decided to retreat instead of confronting their uncle. She considered this decision to be somewhat cowardly in nature. It was an opportunity to prove himself as the rightful owner of the title but now bad rumors were spreading that he was not suited for it anymore. The Golden Dragon’s name was on everyone's tongues and she hated it.

“We didn’t have enough information, the fake was a lot more powerful than what we were led to believe. This battle was nothing more than a test and we had gained precious information.”

“Precious information? I hope it was worth it.”

“I was, now we know what he is capable of, here take a look.”

While talking the oldest sibling pointed out with his finger at the holographic map. It flicked and started changing into the shape of a person. It was clearly the man known as Zhang Dong and the fake Emperor that he referred to. There were various words written to the side and pointing to his body and even the sword that he recently used in the confrontation.

“Dao of Heavenly Lightning, Soul Arts, gravitational techniques … is he capable of doing all of this?”

“Indeed, he has mastered various types of Dao and they seem to have increased since he entered our city. He was not in possession of all of this… either he learned them recently or was able to hide them when he was here…”

“How would he be able to learn all of this in a measly ten years? That’s impossible.”

“I agree, he must have found a way to hide his strength even in front of our father, we must consider his equal and stop playing around. If we continue like this, we will all die…”

The younger sister and brother went quiet as they finally understood what their eldest brother was getting at. Even if they remained on the battlefield and fought, their uncle would have defeated them all. He was far stronger than every one of the elders that were there to protect them. Just like their father who could defeat multiple nascent soul masters, they needed to consider him to be his equal. If not, their demise would come swiftly.

“Will Father need to move? Will it be impossible for us?”

The youngest sibling asked while looking at Zhang Dong’s holographic image. His appearance seemed more ferocious now than it was all those years ago. It was now clear that he had been hiding most of his power and still was able to easily trump their skills.

“I’m not sure, we will not be able to kill him with a brute force approach like last time. If we are able to lure him into a trap of spiritual weakening then we would stand a chance.”

“I didn’t think he would be so ferocious but I still can’t see him defeating Father.”

Long Fengge said out in anger while slamming his fist on the machine producing the holographic image of their enemy.

“Nevertheless, we must account for everything, just like before they will attempt to lure us in. With the current information, we can develop the proper countermeasures.”

Long Shen managed to remain calm, he was not as assured as his younger brother of their father's victory. He had seen the man close up and his presence was very similar to the Azure Emperor’s. It was impossible to come to a conclusion as neither of them had shown their true fighting prowess. Before it came to a confrontation they needed to figure out the strengths and weaknesses of this man. If they didn't, Long Shen felt that even his father could be in trouble.

“How did they manage to sneak up on us? If not for that gravitational trap we would have been able to safely retreat.”

“That’s a good question and our people have found the answer, take a look at this.”

Long Shen made the hologram shift to represent the previous battlefield. He then pointed to an area that was behind their flying fortress.

“Our experts discovered a strange fluctuation of energy in this area, they have come to the conclusion that it was some type of teleportation technique.”

“Teleportation technique? Did our formation fail?”

“It is so, the technique was strange but they have informed me that they will be able to discover it if they ever use it again.”

Long Shen smirked slightly as he was convinced that his enemies wouldn’t be aware of this fact. Similar techniques had already been used around their region and were being analyzed. The next time their enemy arrived they would become aware of their presence.

“Surprisingly it’s a strange unorthodox art, we won’t be able to block it with our formations but they won’t be able to use it for subterfuge.”

“He must have had a fortuitous encounter… maybe it’s an ancient art of a long gone immortal.”

“Perhaps, we must account for everything so that Father…”

“Oh, what are my cure children up to, and why is it so dark in here?”

“Father?”

Before Long Shen could finish the sentence he heard his father’s voice echo through the room. It took the three a moment to find their parent that was seemingly just sitting there in the corner. It looked like he had been there the whole time without them noticing. They all went pale as they had been insinuating that he might have been weaker than his younger sibling, Zhang Dong.

“What’s with those faces? Do you think I’d be mad? Nothing of the such, this is rather exciting don’t you all think?”

“Exciting?”

The three looked at each other without knowing how to reply. The fate of the Long Clan was at risk. Their people were at the apex of the empire for hundreds of thousands of years. If their line would to end when they were in charge, then they would be the biggest shame of the Long Dynasty.

“Ha ha, long have I waited for a worthy opponent, my little brother, the Golden Dragon! Our Clash will be legendary!”

Long Qing was all smiles while his children were sweating. They haven’t seen their father so excited in a long time. Usually, he just lazes around the whole day while resting his head on their mother’s lap. It was clear to them that he was itching for a fight and it was up to them to pave the way.

They knew that he was not much of a planner and had no inclination toward making strategies. Even the help from his soul beast was gotten by a request from Long Shen that had not trusted the other elders that were downplaying the danger that the United Element Sect posed. It would probably be up to them to set the stage for their dad but with him around, they felt that there was no wall they couldn’t get over.

“Now, I’ll leave the rest up to you, Long Shen! Call me over when you need me.”

“Of course, father.”

The Emperor was not one to partake in long strategic meetings. Leaving it all up to his oldest son was the best plan in his mind. Instead of wasting time here, he could train up for the clash with his brother. When the time came he would give it all and prove once and for all that he was the world's strongest expert.

Chapter 681

“How have things been progressing? Has the Long Clan responded to anything?”

“No Patriarch, they deny all claims and still persist with the false claim.”

“I see, that is troubling.”

Zhang Dong nodded at the officer from his sect that brought him the bad news. The last battle had left a bad aftertaste but life needed to continue. Instead of pushing in instantly, he decided to parley or at least make an attempt at it. The Long Clan did not wish to talk and stuck to the fake narrative of them being a demonic sect. Thankfully not many people believed this as the western region saw a boost in quality of life improvements.

Thanks to his system's faction option, he was able to get spirit points for keeping his citizens happy. Even if on the outside it looked like he was wasting resources by helping the poor. In actuality, he could exchange the later gained spirit points for various other things. One of them was his angelic automatons that could be further upgraded into a powerful force. When looking at things with the future in mind, he was better off investing in the vast western region.

‘It doesn’t seem like they are willing to talk on neutral grounds. It was at least worth a try.’

Zhang Dong wanted to sigh but decided to stop himself as he was not alone in this meeting room. He had attempted to stop this pointless war with his brother. If they were able to make some type of binding contract like the previous sects then lives could be saved. Yet the Long Clan was unwilling to give them a millimeter of space. They even asked for them to hand him over as he was assumed to be a demonic cultivator.

It made sense in this world where one person could decide the fate of many. Zhang Dong was too much of a risk for anyone to allow him to run free. The Long Clan wanted to prove that they were the supreme faction with no one above them. One of the biggest issues was the potential legality that he had to the throne. At least the Soaring Dragon Sect had no claim to it which lowered their danger level.

Zhang Dong on the other hand could potentially with time split the Long Clan into two factions. Not everyone liked the Azure Emperor, there was a possibility for an internal struggle if he continued to rise in power. Long Qing wouldn’t last forever and then Long Shen was supposed to be his successor.

However, after a certain lightning cultivator arrived, the man was not the best prospect for the position anymore. His short arrival at the city sent out waves of opposition. If the Azure Emperor started aging the much younger brother had proven himself to be his equal. Would the weaker son be able to take out the mantle or could the Golden Emperor rise in his place?

At the time he didn’t really have anyone attempt to contact him. He had been stuck in the golden palace and trying to restore it before vanishing. If it was possible to take over the empire through politics and diplomacy then he would be all for it. Yet perhaps the elders that opposed him saw the writing on the wall and decided to remove this option as if it was some growing tumor.

‘I guess I have grown too dangerous to be left alive. I endanger their dynasty just by existing…’

He stood up from his seat and moved forward on the podium. This platform was floating in the middle and contained him along with his wife, Huo Qiang, and a few other elders from his sect. They were not alone here as there were many other cultivators everywhere. The robes they were wearing varied in shape, size, and color as they were not part of the United Element Sect.

“First of all, I would like to welcome you all on behalf of the United Element Sect. You all have traveled from far-off reaches and for that I am grateful.”

The people on the sides started nodding while being somewhat surprised. To them the man that was talking to them was an enigma. His power was real and this whole meeting seemed pointless. Why did he bring them here if he could have just ordered them to go into battle without even giving them a reason?

The Long Clan had done it with all their branch families and was even pulling some uninvolved sects into their army. The war was quickly progressing into the second stage where everyone scrambled for potential resources and warriors. They expected to be given a battle plan that they were unable to refuse but instead, they were greeted with respect by a man that should be above such things.

“I have gathered you here all to discuss the future of our western region and also the Empire in its entirety.”

After the last battle, one thing became clear, his side didn’t truly have enough manpower and support for a longer conflict. The wall that they amassed would eventually break if it wasn’t supported by others. He wanted to get through this without involving all the other people but it might be impossible.

The enemies he was facing were sitting on a giant spirit vein and their region was deeply protected. While these people didn’t all have to directly help his armies in battle, they could be used as sideline supporters. Delivering resources where they were needed and also offering up some was needed.

“While I know what you might be thinking, I will assure you that I don’t wish to send your people to the battlefront, you all will have a choice to make but some will be more lucrative than others. Now please, you should have all received special jades with the merits, please take some time to process the information.”

Zhang Dong returned to his seat while Zhang Jin took over the rest. While he could force these people to do his bidding this would adversely affect their happiness rating in the faction system. To not shoot himself in the foot he made a decision to implement the usual merit system. These people carved special techniques and cultivation resources. With all the spirit points he was earning, it was quite easy to offer them enhanced cultivation manuals.

“Does anyone have any questions? I’ll try to answer them to the best of my ability.”

“If I may?”

“Ah, you come from the Green Serpent Sect, please go ahead.”

Zhang Jin started taking questions from the people gathered there. In the jades, they were given the potential rewards they would receive for their services. One, in particular, was an interesting one and would be the least cost for the United Element Sect.

“You are capable of enhancing our cultivation techniques and spiritual arts?”

“Indeed, It’s a simple process for our masters and it will be possible for you to come into possession of immortal grade manuals, depending on your contribution to the cause.”

“Immortal grade?”

Everyone started whispering around as they could not fathom someone giving up an immortal-grade treasure or cultivation method. This was the pinnacle of their world, something that could potentially turn people into future Emperors and immortals. Why would a sect give up such knowledge, in their eyes it was probably a hoax.

“You do not believe that we possess such manuals?”

Zhang Jin turned towards Zhang Dong who just nodded. Soon he produced a manual from his spatial ring that his grandfather held up high.

“This is an immortal grade technique, I would like for all your leaders to inspect it.”

Everyone’s eyes bulged out as even without coming too close to the booklet they could feel a strange spiritual energy from it. All the nascent soul masters that represented their sects and clans quickly rushed to the central stage while almost forgetting that they were in the presence of the Golden Dragon. Their eyes focused on the first page that was presented to them and they instantly knew, this was an immortal grade treasure worth dying for.

“It’s an immortal rank technique… I can hardly understand the first page…”

“Hey, stop hogging it by yourself, let me see…”

“What is this knowledge… is there more? I have to know!”

The old masters that were all over five hundred years old started acting like children. They were pushing each other out of the way while trying to read the page that was being held by Zhang Jin. Yet this was all that they would be receiving, a little taste to urge them forward. Instead of forcing the other sects to comply they offered rewards in return. While some would still remain skeptical after receiving some rewards or seeing others get them, they would change their tune.

“Please calm yourselves, it is unbecoming of your position.”

Zhang Jin was forced to yank the booklet out of reach as some of the masters started reaching for it. They quickly retreated in fright as they noticed what they just attempted to do. Even though a lot of them were ready to fight with their life on the line for treasures like this, they were not stupid.

Zhang Dong was here and so was Huo Qiang whom they knew were above their skill level. Even if the whole group tossed themselves into battle at once, they weren’t confident in winning. This was exacerbated by the rise of lightning and fire energy within this large hall. Everyone involved in the potential tussle started shrinking back and returning to their seats soon after.

“As you have seen, it’s the genuine article but it’s not the only one you may receive, it will all depend on the merits you gain in the future. How our merit system works is included within the jade which you may take back to your clans and sects. Now, I will answer your questions.”

Soon the meeting continued and Zhang Dong decided to leave it up to his grandfather. They started asking about the basics and if they were obliged to participate which they weren’t. This was a strict merit-based system that was supposed to push them to do better. There were many ways of gaining these merits and calculating for specific rewards was possible.

While they were discussing the future war venture he was already thinking about the coming battle. His brother was going to face him sooner or later and he had to get ready. Before he could tackle the woman that was behind him, the Azure Emperor needed to be dealt with first.

‘I need to be ready when the time comes and expect her to get involved as well… this is quite troublesome but I’ll get through like I always did…’

There were too many people at stake. He was not alone anymore and he would do his utmost to defend the family that he had built.

Chapter 682

Time continued to pass as both factions rallied their forces. With the Long Clan’s reputation constantly falling in the wake of their actions, they could no longer rely on branch families and side sects living in the central region. The consensus that the Emperor was just using them as meat shields had become a reality.

Going against the United Element Sect was not an easy task. Previously everyone expected them to fall within a few weeks. They had proven to everyone that they were here to stay, but multiple battles later they still stood strong and it was the Long Clan that had to retreat. The western side of the empire was never this strong. Previously it was even considered to be the weakest of the big three and now it was potentially the strongest.

People from the central region found themselves fleeing there. Even though massive barriers were created to keep anyone from that side outside, there was a way to get in. After going through several checks it was possible to head inside. Hidden spies were apprehended at a staggering rate without anyone knowing of the system’s involvement. It was impossible for anyone from the Long Clan to get through without being discovered.

Within a few months, a battle zone had formed and constant barrages of spirit blasts continued to rain each day. The massive formation could not be breached and the Long Clan forces could not muster enough forces for another big push. Their reputation continued to plummet until they finally had to dip into their own pockets. For people that had remained at the top for so long, this was a hard pill to swallow.

“I didn’t expect their armies to collapse this fast…”

“Perhaps we got lucky, the central region had been mismanaged for a long time. They have grown fat and lazy, unable to function without their pawn.”

Zhang Dong nodded at Zhang Jin. The two were looking over a holographic map of the border region. Their victories were piling up and it didn’t seem like they would be slowing down anytime soon. The support of their armies was almost unanimous after a few battles went their way. The middle-sized sects had started to see the spirit stones waiting for them and were now fully invested. Their unease was now gone as the Long Clan was getting pushed back and forced into a more defensive position.

“Even though their clan has many elites, they had never gained the skills required to lead just like the last time, some of them started fleeing at the first sight of defeat.”

“They are truly spineless, without the branch clans to act as meat shields they are incapable of risking their own life.”

Zhang Jin replied to Zhang Dong’s point while everyone else nodded. It was as if their entire army was composed of young master types. They were unable to produce any victories and were prone to blaming their fellow clan members. There was no unifying hand guiding them as the Emperor continued to hide away at the flying castle in the sky. Without a proper leader, the others continued to push their own agendas and usually step over each others toes while doing it.

“And that’s why we will win!”

Said Huo Qiang who could not wait to join the fray. The battles at the borders were losing steam and if this continued there was a possibility of pushing towards victory. With their formation standing strong, there was nothing to worry about anymore. Entering the lands of the Long Clan would be the next obvious step.

‘Everyone is getting pumped up, I’m not sure if I like this…’

Zhang Dong was aware of how their people felt. Most of them had come from smaller clans and sects. They had attained newfound power through hardships but also luck. They wanted to prove to the world that they were worthy of keeping all the blessings that they were given. There was no better way of showing the world this other than taking the spot of the current dynasty.

His name had become a problem as he could make a legal case for the throne. Perhaps if there was a democratic vote to attain this position he would have been able to win it. The Azure Emperor was an obscure being that never showed himself, even after all that had happened the man didn’t appear. It seemed that unless they traveled to the capital city of Azure, there would be no resolution.

“What of the recent movement in the region, are they really retreating to the spirit vein?”

“Yes, I wanted to bring this up, our intelligence agents have confirmed this by traveling to various cities in the central region, the Long Clan has been given an order to retreat.”

“Hah, the cowards are running, we should push in and end it all!”

Huo Qiang called out to the people here and his father nodded in agreement. It looked as if the enemy was trying to concentrate their forces in one region and defend it. In the eyes of many this was only what an injured beast would do and they wanted to quickly put it out of its misery.

“End it all? I don’t think it will be that easy Qiang. They recalled all of their main clan members which means that all their nascent soul masters will be in one place.”

“So? This just means that we can vanquish them all at the same time!”

“That’s why muscle brains like you are… “

“What? Everyone knows that only cowards run!”

Zhang Liena gave out a sigh while fanning herself with one of her emerald fans. She knew that it was one thing to defend themselves against a few branch families and another to fight the true Long Clan. Their numbers were low but they made them up with quality.

“The Matriarch is right, the number of their nascent soul masters greatly outnumbers ours. Their lands have never suffered a defeat, many have tried to topple the Azure dynasty but they have all failed. Please take a look, this is as much as we have gathered.”

Zhang Jin tried to ignore Huo Qiang and Liena’s disagreement while bringing everyone's attention to the holographic map. There he presented a circular area surrounded by steep mountains and something that looked like a flying city of massive proportions.

“This is the capital city, if we compare it to the Golden Palace then you will see one of the problems that we will face.”

“It’s so much bigger?”

The Golden Dong Palace had been upgraded multiple times and was the size of a giant castle. Even with its own massive size, it looked like a pebble next to the mountain that was the Azure Dragon city.

“This city has been able to keep itself afloat for thousands of years, we believe that it's taking vast quantities of spiritual energy to achieve this. Part of the main spirit vein in question is directly under it.”

Everyone knew of this already but this presentation brought everyone up to scale. Previously Zhang Dong along with a few of his family members were able to visit the large city. Thanks to this they were able to gather some information about the size and some of the main defensive structures.

“While we might have a general layout of the main city, we don’t really have much about the surrounding area. We were unable to peek through their grand formation and arrived through methods of teleportation. Even though we witnessed some of the outsides, it was shrouded with something.”

“Could it have been an illusory formation?”

“That’s a possibility, it wouldn’t be strange if they hid a trump card within this center shroud.”

The elders nodded again. It was possible for something to be in that empty zone. To their knowledge, there were no cities built there or at least that is what the Long Clan wanted everyone to know. They always held people up at the mountain range and whoever was allowed to go through, could only through one of the teleportation gates. It was a big unknown what truly waited for them inside and preparing for the unknown had to be accounted for.

“What of the Heavenly Crane Sect, have they decided to take a side?”

“No, they are remaining neutral and have started to amass more forces around their own borders.”

“That doesn’t bode well, did they make a deal with the Long Clan?”
“That probably isn’t it. It’s actually favorable for us if they do so.”

“Do you expect them to create another barricade like we did?”

“Something like that, they aren’t much different than any other sect. They will wait and if the Long Clan tries to flee, they will see it as an opportunity to attack.”

“I see, they are opportunists to the end.”

Zhang Dong answered Liena while nodding. The Heavenly Crane Sect wasn’t a great ally. Instead of helping anyone they would just stay there and wait. It was in their best interest for both sides to weaken each other as much as possible. Then if they deemed it possible, it would be their time to rise, and going up against weakened enemies was their plan.

“I just hope they don’t expect things to remain the same after we win.”

“I agree, having such snakes around would bode badly for the future of the new dynasty.”

Zhang Jin responded to Liena while Zhang Dong frowned at the choice of wording. To him, this was a battle against whoever created the scenario but for them; it was more about gaining more resources and land. They all wanted to create a new world order with their names being immortalized for future generations. It would be a great honor to pave the way for their offspring and become ancestors worthy of praise.

“Continue to monitor their movements, we shall push through with the next stage of our strategy as soon as it’s possible, does anyone have any grievances to voice or do we all agree?”

Zhang Dong stood up and asked the elders, experts, and also his friends if they really wanted to push through with this war. Now was the time to take their chance, people were quickly revolting against the old royal family. If they waited too long then the Emperor would probably regain his foothold. The longer the Long Dynasty lasted, the more the whole empire would push into chaotic times.

Some criminals were already seeing this as a chance to ransack various cities and smaller lesser protected areas. The longer this took the more collateral damage would occur and as always the less fortunate would be affected the most.

“I will take the silence as your answer, very well. We shall rally the troops and push in. We will take the central region over and drive the Emperor out of his hiding place…”

Chapter 683

“Drop your weapons and surrender, in the name of the Golden Dragon we guarantee your lives, stop this pointless conflict!”

“You’ll guarantee our safety? How can we trust someone like you, weren’t you the ones that started this dispute?”

“That is incorrect and you probably know it already. The Long Clan attempted to assassinate our Patriarch, they did nothing to protect us when the monstrous beings appeared and even now continue to deny all allegations like the cowards they are!”

“P-preposterous, the Long Clan wouldn’t do such a thing!”

An elder shouted in anger at the accusations that were being presented. Their group of warriors had barricaded themselves inside a large structure. It was their last bastion that was protected by a few layers of formations.

“It wouldn’t? Then where are they? Why did they leave all of you here? They certainly didn’t believe that you could hold us back. Look at the facts, they left you all here to die.”

On the outside, there was a large group of cultivators. They were formed up in several formations that created water serpents and other creatures. All of them had stopped the siege as they didn’t want to waste their time on such a matter. This battle was already over and the people inside were just postponing the inevitable.

“That’s impossible they would never…”

“Never? Why do you still deny the truth? We offer you a way to save your life, the ones you serve would never give such an opportunity to their enemies! Do you wish for more lives to be lost? You might hold out for a few days at most and then what?”

“T-the Long Clan will surely send help…”

“Oh? They will? That’s not what our scouts reported.”

“What do you mean?”

“Have you not realized yet? You all have been abandoned, your governor who was a member of the Long Clan left before the battle even started. Do you think it was us that blocked the teleportation gate from working? No, they destroyed it by themselves so that no one else could follow after them.”

The elder on the inside couldn’t muster up any words as he knew that something was wrong. When the large armada was seen approaching their leader suddenly vanished without a trace. The teleportation gate was activated once and then stopped working as some other people were trying to escape. Their group assumed that the enemy did something to block their escape device as some of the other teleportation talismans they had weren’t working either.

“H-he really abandoned us?”

“Yes, that’s how the Long Clan does things, haven’t you heard already?”

“So it was true, they don’t care about us at all! We are just a branch family …”

“No you must not give in to their words, we should wait …”

“Wait for what? Do you think the Azure Emperor will appear to save us when he has not been seen anywhere for hundreds of years?”

The people inside the structure started arguing with each other. Some had heard the news about branch clans being offered up for slaughter and also the rumors of dealings with demons. Both sides were throwing these accusations at each other so most people assumed that it was just the usual tactic. Placing themselves on the moral high ground was a standard tactic for war. It gave people the excuse to slaughter their enemies if they were vile monsters in the eyes of others.

“Maybe it won’t be so bad? Why are they even asking us to surrender…”

“What do you mean?”

“They should be able to break through our defenses soon… why are they offering us a way to survive?”

“Because they are liars and they won’t be able to get in?”

“Do you really believe that? All of you know that we have been abandoned, I for one would like to survive…”

One of the men that was talking looked to the side where his wife and child were huddled up with others. The attack had not come as a total surprise but they were not able to evacuate people from the city. One of the reasons was due to the governing member from the Long Clan. He had forbidden anyone from leaving the city and many here had already realized why. With their families stuck inside the city walls, they would do a better job at defending the Long Clan’s investments because if they fell, their family members would be next in line.

“If we just wait, help will come…”

“Are you sure? Wouldn’t it be better to at least try, is there something besides our lives that we can lose?”

The group stopped arguing and instead began to think. What were the realistic chances of their side turning it around on the enemy combatants? Their city was not that much of an important location in the grand scheme of things. It was a city meant for leisure without any strategic meaning. What these people from the United Element Sect were doing was just passing by.

Their leaders had probably all escaped to the next city that was entrenched in a mountain region and would pose a bigger threat. There was no reason for them to come back as they would only risk losing their combatants. These people were probably on the way over there so it was better to wait and fight at a more favorable location. This of course meant that they would all die instead as no help was coming.

“I heard that the Golden Dragon is righteous… what if the rumors were true? What if the Long Clan was the aggressor all along?”

“I would rather live with disgrace or as a slave than see my children die here…”

“But what if they use us for demonic rituals?”

“Will it change anything if we don’t surrender? Do you think we can beat them? You’ve seen their might…”

The people on the inside started to consult each other for more input. It was clear that they didn’t know what the right choice was. Their will to live was strong but they didn’t want to be labeled as traitors. The people on the other side continued to wait patiently but they didn’t have time to wait forever.

“Have you decided?”

“What will you do with us if we surrender? Will you kill the men and take in the children?”

“Kill the men? We are not barbarians, in the name of the Patriarch you will be detained and taken to a temporary settlement. There you will live until this war is over.”

“A temporary settlement?”

“Yes, you will not be permitted to leave but fear not, your families will not be mistreated or used for slave labor.”

The conversation continued as the people painted a picture of what the other sect had in store for them. Normally prisoners of war would either become slaves or just be killed outright. Any cultivator in the world had the potential to grow powerful and then seek vengeance. Thus the winning side usually performed a cleansing by either killing everyone or destroying their cultivation base.

Due to these facts, the people that were on the losing end had trouble trusting their potential captors. What if they all get sent out to some type of cleansing facility instead of the promised temporary settlement? To some of them, it was better to at least try to fight if they were just going to get massacred. Scattering in all directions was also an option, perhaps a handful of people could survive and to some, this was a valid option.

“W-what if we just run? At least some of us should be able to escape?”

One of these people proposed to flee. Yet when looking at the other people in here, they didn’t seem to be of the same mind.

“Are you crazy? Did you see the flying ships they have and those trapping formations? None of us will be able to leave the city. They already blocked off all the secret escape tunnels.”

All escape attempts have been thwarted. It was as if their enemies had information about their escape routes. Many had already tried to escape and they were forced to retreat to this place to seek shelter. It was a temporary solution and within a few days their enemies would probably make it in.

“So what then, do we trust them? What if they skin us alive?”

“You believe those rumors too much.”

“Yeah… Did you all notice? They didn’t seem as ferocious as those rumors were saying…”

“The might actually let us live…”

Some of the people here were there when the fighting started. During a war when an enemy went down, they were given a death blow but these United Element Sect people didn’t seem to follow through. It was as if they were given the order to conserve lives. Due to these facts, the group finally started giving in to their fears and made a decision.

“We will surrender, just swear on your honor that you will uphold the things that you said to us!”

“We of the United Element Sect don’t lie, I swear on the entire sect and the Patriarch’s good name that you will not be harmed.”

Finally, the defensive formation was disabled and the cultivators from the United Element Sect rushed in. The people inside were scared but just as they promised their weapons landed on the ground. If the other side betrayed them this would be the best opportunity but no carnage came, instead they were guided outside where some other city residents were.

“Brother, I thought you were dead?”

“I thought so too… it might take some time for my cultivation base to recover… but they didn’t kill me.”

People that were left on the outside were mostly here. There were some deaths but a lot of the soldiers actually managed to survive and were being detained instead. It seemed that what the people from the United Element Sect said was true and they would all be able to survive.

Soon all of them were being guided towards a circular gate. It was one of their own teleportation devices that had been seized by the other forces. There were some strange metallic parts on the sides applied to it that the people here didn’t recognize. As it churned to present them with a path forward they steeled their nerves as what awaited them at the end could be their undoing.

“Oh, you finally made it through?”

“Uncle? Huh? Didn’t you perish a week ago … “

“Perish, nonsense! The lies of the Long Clan have spread too far! Come, let me fill you in on what has been happening lately…”

When on the other end they arrived at a strange place. It looked like a new world with a different sky and some of the people they knew from other cities that had been previously captured were also there. Soon they would realize that a lot fewer deaths occurred in the recent push of the United Element Sect…

Chapter 684

“...”

A shiny orb made from silver descended quickly to the ground before suddenly slowing down to a halt. A pale blue glow glazed over it as the sphere started to travel up into the air. It traveled upwards where it came from but right at the top, the energy around it burst into many tiny fragments.

“Shit…”

Zhang Dong saw the orb that weighed around a kilogram crashing down to the floor. While normally he would have no trouble manipulating this amount of weight with his spiritual energy, it was different in this case. The metal ball was not forcefully lifted up, instead, time was being slowed down around it and then reversed. He was able to momentarily affect a small area around the object but his stamina wasn’t quite there.

“This is a lot harder than mastering the other energies, even soul power isn’t as difficult… But I’m actually getting somewhere…”

There weren’t many things in this world that could tire him out. His body had become superhuman with massive reserves of spiritual energy that grew larger each day. Even with all of that, he could barely use the Dao of Time to use this simple technique. Yet, there was hope for him now. He had managed to push through one of the hurdles and was now able to affect time in close vicinity to his body.

“Reversing time is a lot harder than fast-forwarding for some reason… Perhaps it goes against the fundamental rules of the world?”

Next to the ball, there was a withered plant. Previously he had used the Dao of Time to age a flower. Before him, it bloomed and then withered away into the state it was now. The process was a lot easier to produce than the reverse as bringing it back to life via a time technique was quite strenuous. He came to the conclusion that the passage of time was considered more natural than winding back the clock. Going faster was still within the rules of this world.

“I can’t really affect much of an area though… I can’t imagine how much power you’d need to reverse the time on the entire planet or the universe…’

The Overseer managed to stop time but they were not reversing it. Perhaps this was all that he needed, if he pushed time forward he might be able to move. If he failed, however, it would turn him into a dried-up raisin in a matter of seconds. Without being able to reverse the process he would need to be careful.

“Maybe becoming a true immortal is required to manipulate time. If you have unlimited time, then perhaps it is possible to affect it?”

He glanced within himself to the white seed that had begun opening slightly. Even now he had no idea what this thing would turn him into. Would it allow him to reach the immortal stage or something in-between? As things stood now he was unsure of his chances against the final opponent. With his current mastery of the Dao of Time, it might not be possible to even land in one hit before he was disabled.

‘The noose has been slowly constricting around the Long Clan, they don’t really have anywhere else to run…’

To take his mind off his training he decided to glance at the map. A lot of months had passed since the battle at the wall. His armies were performing rather well and constantly producing victories as they pushed into the central region. Most of this could be attributed to the bad handling of their people by the Long Clan and also their limited numbers.

They had decided to keep themselves small and constricted to one major city right in the middle. Everything around them was run by weaker branch families and smaller sects. They had a lot of masters that if the need arose would be able to wipe out those branching families. However, these same masters were hard to move and control. All of them lived at the apex of the empire and thought fighting was beneath them.

Due to a mindset like this, the United Element Sect could prosper. Before the Long Clan realized this, they were on the defensive. They had lost the first line of defense that were the branch families. Without the lands they occupied resources became limited and even when the stronger masters began their move, it was already too late.

‘They all fled to the capital, soon it will be the last thing that remains… but I don’t like it, what is he thinking…’

Zhang Dong didn’t even need to participate and within a short amount of time, his forces surrounded the dividing mountain. It was as if the Long Clan was beckoning them inside, the probability of a trap existing inside was great. There were a few options that he could go with, one that involved risking his own life or his soldiers.

‘Should I send in a scouting party first? There are a few elders that are good at sneaking in but none of them is better than me at it. The only problem would be to explain it to everyone…’

After using the demon hunter persona his wife had become quite mistrustful. He couldn’t blame her as she was afraid of him getting into trouble as he always did. With his position becoming so high as to rival the Azure Emperor so did his importance. If it became known that he had perished or gone missing, then the Long Clan would probably launch a full-blown assault. It wouldn’t be strange if their current allies turned on them if he disappeared either.

When taking everything into account, it wouldn’t be great to move in by himself. Launching a similar mission when he headed out into the ocean was a better solution to the problem. They actually had more information about their opponent now than when they visited the Cerulean Empress.

‘Bob, how long will it take for another palace upgrade if you use the current spirit points we are getting.’

‘Calculating… it will take approximately 4 years, 34 days, and 5 hours.’

‘That’s what I thought, I kind of reached the point of diminishing returns here…’

The palace had gone through another upgrade since the time he visited the underwater Empress. It was now larger, sturdier, and more mobile than ever. It could not be compared in size to the flying city of the Long Clan but its capabilities should not be below it that much. Even after receiving spirit points from the entire western region, it would take years for the next upgrade.

‘It’s also four years if I don’t use the points on anything else, upgrading the angel army takes a big chunk out of it and can easily double the time I’ll need to wait.’

Unless he wanted to conquer the Eastern region, he would probably not be able to upgrade the fortress for at least another five years. After all that time some momentum would be lost and his enemies would become even more entrenched. As it stood now he believed that the Long Clan’s defenses wouldn’t be up to par. They had remained on top for so long so he expected them to be sloppy just as they have continued to be throughout this whole war.

‘I can’t have them start doubting their power, they will make a lot more mistakes now than in the future where they have some time to cool their heads.’

It became clear that for his battle with the Azure Emperor, he would need to come to him. Perhaps the region surrounding the whole capital would become a ring for their massive conflict. No maps existed of that region and it was rumored to just be an area filled with precious resources. Many other sects in the past had attempted to push into it but no one was able to return alive.

‘If I can get past the first hurdle there, then victory won’t be impossible. It could also be possible that they want us to push in…’

While finishing up his training he started moving outside. The whole dimensional regalia had become filled up with people. There were now millions of war prisoners living here but they weren’t really doing anything. Some were used for spirit herb farming while others were for mining. This immortal treasure was a small world of its own and also had its own resources.

He took some time to fly over one of the encampments that was filled out with swarms of tents. The other elders didn’t like how he brought this idea up to them. Instead, they wanted to place everyone into harsher concentration camps where they would be taught a lesson. Yet, he understood that the vast majority of these people had nothing to do with the Long Clan. They were unable to refuse their overlords and a lot of them were non-combatants who were just trying to live out their lives.

‘Not all of them look happy about this but at least the kids are enjoying themselves.’

This encampment was surrounded by a large formation that acted like a fence. There was more than enough space to fit everyone in but his people controlled the traffic that was going in and out of here. These people outnumbered the warriors from the sect and thus they needed to be controlled. It was always possible for a revolt to be launched if enough of them got together.

‘As long as the conditions don’t go out of control, they should remain docile but the longer they stay here the more they will want to return to their old lives.’

All of these people previously lived in the central regions. They weren’t receiving much compared to what they were used to. The concentration of Qi in the Dimensional Regalia was high but not high enough for people that grew up around the central spirit vein.

‘Even if they tried to revolt they wouldn’t really be able to get out…’

He was more afraid that people would lose their lives and not about them potentially breaking out of this place. His sect members were training and living here as well, so they needed to be prioritized over everything else. This continued to push him to a faster resolution to the Azure Emperor issue.

With the issue in mind, he vanished from the area and appeared outside. There he looked out the window to take in the view of what he had created. A city stood tall with millions of people living in it. A statue resembling him along with his wife and best friend was there. People regularly visited it to bow in an attempt to get some good fortune and blessing.

‘I need to preserve the peace here but what will it cost…’

Zhang Dong asked himself while bringing up the system window that pointed him toward the Golden Palace. Soon the final push would commence and he needed to assemble his army. Only one enemy remained and it was finally time to end it all.

Chapter 685

“What’s troubling you, I know that look.”

“Oh sorry, I spaced out for a moment. It’s just… It seems too easy.”

“I agree, the mighty Long Clan should have done a better job at defending their borders….”

“Hey, what are you two worrying about? Our Sect is just this strong, this is the obvious result! Now let’s go pull that little emperor out of his castle!”

Zhang Dong along with his wife Zhang Liena looked to their friend Huo Qiang that interrupted their conversation. All of them were standing on a large golden balcony and before them was a wide mountain range. The size of the mountains was truly tremendous as they pierced the clouds.

There was one opening exactly a kilometer in width. A giant gate stood there, its columns made from azure jade. Two large eastern dragons were etched into the columns with their mouths open and pointing at the potential visitors. It was a one-of-a-kind entrance through which their sect wished to traverse through.

“Gramps, what do you think?”

“I think that we need to be careful but…”

“But?”

“I also think that Elder Qiang isn’t wrong, our sect is strong and we have already gone through many hardships to arrive at this point.”

“So, you are feeling confident.”

Zhang Jin nodded while looking with the others at the giant gate being pulled apart. Many large cables were attached to it and on the other end they connected to massive flying ships. Ten of these ships were pulling slowly from each side and the gate started to open. A strange current was exposed and filled the area with spiritual energy.

“They really like to monopolize that spirit vein, don’t they?”

He commented while feeling a substantial increase in this energy. It was the most universal power source in this world and caused countless massacres. The old text proclaimed that the Long Clan had settled down here many thousands of years ago. This mountain range along with the gate was said to not have always been there. It was created to separate the central-most region from all the others.

The Heavenly Crane Sect and the late Soaring Dragon Sect had limited access to this bountiful resource but they were not allowed to cross the mountain path. The same vein crossed into their lands but its power was diminished. The United Element Sect had recently been able to claim the vein for themselves but something was wrong.

A spirit vein should not have been able to try out. They were like natural power plants that circulated spiritual energy from the entire world. When energy was spent by a cultivator it would return to the world. After transitioning through the planet it would soon be attracted to the vein that spat it back out into the environment. It was a renewable process that would continue as long as there was life in this world.

Yet something went wrong and the spirit vein that previously belonged to the Soaring Dragon Sect had started to be drained fast. It was as if something or someone was redirecting the energies elsewhere and after opening this gate, Zhang Dong had an idea where it all went.

‘They always had the capabilities of limiting the spirit vein output. There could be a few reasons for it…’

Zhang Dong knew about the logic behind spirit energy returning to the world and being constantly recycled. However, this could potentially be all hogwash. The laws governing this world were created by a superior being and they could probably also be changed at a drop of a hat. It was possible that the Long Clan had lied about the true form of the main spirit vein that they were monopolizing. If it was a natural phenomenon then they should have been unable to halt it.

‘Either it’s not natural or that Overseer got involved…’

One of the reasons he decided to continue with the push was the drying up of spiritual energy. At this moment the concentration just went down by a couple of percent which wasn’t yet noticeable. If it continued, then they would probably be playing into the Long Clan’s tactic.

Spiritual energy was used to perform all sorts of techniques and to make treasures work. The more the concentration fell the longer it would take anyone to cultivate and recover. A Cultivator converted spiritual energy and circulated it around their body to make it stronger. The more enhanced their bodies became the better they got at absorbing the ambient energy from the world. If it suddenly vanished then their power would start to decline and this was probably the next plan that the Long Clan came up with.

‘They really don’t want to leave their region. They offered up all of their cities and branch families for slaughter and never moved. This is some sort of obvious trap…’

The fact was brought up to the other elders but the consensus was the same. It was better to push in now while the spiritual energy was high before it was too late. Even though they had their own spirit vein to allow their main city to prosper it would not be enough for all the other sects. The more they waited the more the public opinion would start to shift. They had to use the temporary unity of all the sects to their advantage and finish this quickly, if they waited too long the rope around their necks would start to constrict.

“There is no one to welcome us? Well, that’s boring.”

“I for one welcome boring, ho ho.”

Huo Qiang was ready to charge in instantly as the gate had opened but to everyone’s surprise, there was no counter armada of ships waiting for them. It was actually quite silent with nothing in view.

“It’s just an empty plain? Where are all the beasts or animals?”

Liena wondered while trying to peer through the threshold of the gate. Even when everyone craned their necks and strained their eyes there was nothing to see here. The grass was long and bountiful but something was lacking. It was as if someone forgot that they needed to customize this area for something.

“It is indeed strange, I don’t like it… I can feel something, a formation. The moment we go inside we will be under it.”

“A formation? What kind?”

“I’m not sure, it’s hard to understand but… it has some similarities to the one we saw in the ocean…”

“Is it a space-warping formation?”

“I might be…”

Zhang Dong wasn’t sure. When they all visited the Cerulean Empress’ domain they had been transported to a new area without even knowing. When they entered the chasm they were already under the influence of a formation and the fish that swallowed them was just the icing on the cake. When taking that into consideration, it was possible that when they crossed this area they would arrive at another location or perhaps in a pocket dimension like before.

“It doesn’t seem to be a trap, the formation won’t kill us but I have no idea where it will take us…”

“If it’s the same, then we must have the warriors retreat to the palace.”

Zhang Jin nodded and quickly gave the order for all the outside soldiers to gather together. Some went into the large flying ships that were capable of producing a large protective shield. Others awaited the golden palace that had become a floating stronghold of massive proportions.

They had been preparing for many months for this push but Zhang Dong was not sure if they were going into it for the best reasons. He was just trying to protect his family and friends while also discovering the truth about this world. If his brother gave him a good offer then he would probably ask for a ceasefire. Yet all the attempts to get in touch with him didn’t work and the war just continued.

“Everyone is waiting for your word.”

“... I don’t think this is a good idea…”

“You wish to stop the advance?”

He was unsure of what was to come. Everything here looked like another trap, it was one thing if he pushed in by himself but another if he got the people here killed. Before going in he had to be sure that it was safe.

“No, but I want to test something, Bahamut.”

The large golden dragon had shrunken down to his cute form and quickly reacted to his master's call. His body shot up into the sky and he quickly transformed into the massive winged form that everyone knew him by. Bahamut was a special being, he originated from a part of his soul and would not die unless Zhang Dong perished with him. His death would also not cause a giant backlash as it did when a soul beast was defeated.

Everyone nodded and looked at the large dragon flying toward the opened gate. His frame was quite large but even he looked like a small lizard with wings when compared to the giant columns and gate before him. His speed started increasing the closer he got to the threshold and finally, as he was before it a strange phenomenon started.

“Bahamut, he vanished?”

Liena leaned forward as she saw the large dragon just vanish into nothingness. The air around the gate rippled a bit as if a rock was thrown into water. It took a few seconds for it to calm down but one thing became clear, what they were seeing before them wasn’t real.

“So as expected, it’s some type of portal.”

“Is it a massive teleportation gate? But our sensors didn’t detect anything…”

Zhang Jin was the next one to ask the question. Zhang Dong on the other hand brought up his system window to see where Bahamut was being taken to. What he witnessed was somewhat interesting as instead of the dragon’s location just changing to another one, a path was seen. His speed was much faster to what should be possible by the rules of this world which only made sense if one thing was true.

“It’s not a portal gate, it’s a formation that warps space around it.”

While rubbing his chin he continued to monitor Bahamut’s location. When focusing he could actually see what his familiar was witnessing through his eyes. The space around him was quite queer as it was lighting up in various colors but just after a few seconds had passed some type of exit appeared through which Bahamut was able to come outside.

“Why is that room all white… and is that a person there?”

His dragon appeared in a spacious room with nothing in it and in front was a platform. There he could see a person sitting on something that looked like a throne. His clothes were blue and his face was quite familiar.

“Is that the Azure Emperor? What is he doing … ”

Before he could answer that question himself a red window popped up.

Error, Forced Teleportation initiated.

Chapter 686

‘Hey Bob, what’s happening? Can’t you do something about this?’

‘Error error, unable to block, forceful teleportation will commence in 5…4…3…’

‘God damn…’

“What’s wrong?”

Zhang Liena turned to Zhang Dong who was flailing his arms around in an uncharacteristic manner. Usually, he would remain mostly silent in the background while only talking when he had to. His strange outburst could only mean that something was wrong and soon she realized that his body was getting surrounded by blue energy.

“It was a trap, I’m getting pulled in, don't try to…”

“Wait what is happening!?”

Before she could grasp his hand it disappeared into blue fireflies. His last sentence was not finished but one thing was clear, this was not one of his strange games. The performance didn’t feel as forced as usual. Something had gone wrong with Bahamut that had been sent to scout out the way for them.

“Where did the Patriarch go?”

“Was there some type of trap in there, was he pulled away through his soul beast?”

The other elders that were in the room saw their somewhat panicked leader vanish from the spot. While they knew that he was in possession of various teleportation techniques this one seemed different. The way how it activated right after the large dragon vanished through the gate was suspicious. Without their leader around they found themselves asking all sorts of questions.

“How did they do this? How did they activate the technique inside of the Golden Palace, there should be no way of something like this happening!”

“Could there be some type of bloodline magic at play? Perhaps the Patriarch’s strong ties to the Long Clan allowed them to do so?”

Some of the theories made some sense as bloodline bonds in the cultivation world were not just biology. There was a mystical power integrated into each bloodline and the stronger the ancestor who was the origin point of it, the more powerful the descendants became. It was possible that through such arts their leader was yanked into an unknown location.

“Be quiet, that’s not what we should be arguing about!”

“Elder Jin is right, we must send out our soldiers to investigate that gate!”

The people in the golden palace looked at the strange gate and the grasslands past it. Without their leader, they found themselves in a strange place. Should they push forward and figure out the extent of the trap or would waiting be the better option?

Their Patriarch had always managed to come back from these kinds of situations, even if it took him years most of the people here believed that one day he would be back. Thus soon they started to calm down, this was not the first time that something unexpected happened. What they now needed to do was figure things out and the first step would be to see if they could get through this gate. The whole palace was almost a kilometer in diameter by itself so pushing it through was an option and probably their next move if their Patriarch did not return.

While everyone was calming down from losing their glorious leader, the man in question was appearing in a room of white. He was overtaken by a strange teleportation spell that felt strange. It was as if he was not the one being teleported but somehow the area around him was forcefully switched out to this location. It was some type of higher version of teleporting

‘Bob, where am I? This looks like some type of pocket dimension.’

‘Unknown space detected, location unknown, trying to calculate.’

When he arrived here he was sure to activate all of his spiritual senses. He was either inside of the formation that created a separate dimension or was transported into an entirely new location. During Bahamut’s descend into the gate he tracked his location that was going all over the place but suddenly it vanished after arriving at the centermost region. This meant that more than likely he was transported near the capital city and perhaps he was right as he was not alone.

“My Brother, you have arrived!”

“Long Qing? Did you do this? How were you able to pull me in here…”

“Oh, this place has a special connection to our bloodline, after you sent in your soul beast it was quite easy.”

Long Qing shrugged while smiling. Bahamut that was sucked in first was also here and was growling at a blue beast. Another dragon of comparable size was at Long Qing’s side and it looked like battle was imminent. However, after looking around Zhang Dong started asking himself a few questions.

‘Is this really a trap? I don’t see anyone else, if he wanted to kill me, then would other masters be here with him?’

This didn’t make much sense, where were the experts? Was Long Qing so assured of his strength that he didn’t think that bringing over help was needed? Was it possible that he didn’t actually want to fight but talk instead?

‘I don’t see the Empress anywhere but I can’t pierce through those strange white walls, are they made from the same material I encountered at the spawn points?’

The whole area was rather large, in the middle there was a sizable platform with a gazebo on top. His so-called brother was floating right above the roof with a shit-eating grin of unprecedented proportions. Ever since he started interacting with this person his strange deposition of not taking anything seriously had become apparent.

Even now it looked like he was in the middle of playing a prank of his but this one involved the lives of billions. With the future of the entire empire at stake here, this did make Zhang Dong’s blood boil. Why was this war even continuing if his brother didn’t seem to care about anyone?

‘I need to calm down before I smack him right in that perfect jawline… maybe if he doesn’t care that much about the empire… I could convince him to form a pact of non-aggression.’

While usually, the old monarch needed to be forced down from the throne, this didn’t mean that he couldn’t remain here in the central region. The biggest problem was access to the main spirit vein which was causing a decrease of spiritual energy in the western regions. They would need to be given access to it. A promise was not enough but this would mean that his forces would need to be stationed here and occupy it. The Elders from the Long Clan would not stand for it but perhaps there was a chance.

‘As long as it limits the deaths and keeps everyone safe…’

Zhang Dong nodded to himself and moved his arm up to call Bahamut back. The two dragons were eyeing each other while hissing. If he didn’t do something about it, then a fight would instantly break out.

“I see that you wish to have a chat?”

“Yes, I presume that this was why you brought me here, to have a talk?”

“You are correct! Now come, let us talk!”

If it was possible then handling this predicament without a fight would be optimal. This strange meeting he was having with the enemy leader could be a good sign. Even after arriving at this strange location, he was not getting attacked from all sides. This didn’t mean that there was no danger as he knew a trope that went along with this scenario.

“Little Brother, why don’t you stop this little temper tantrum and return to the Clan?”

“Temper tantrum? I’m not sure that I am following?”

“You don’t have to say a thing, I understand what you are feeling but fear not, I’ll talk to the elders about it, I’m sure they will forgive your little game.”

“Game?”
Zhang Dong was confused as his ‘older brother’ was throwing out some strange words. It was as if he was saying that the whole war was just an emotional outburst of a younger sibling.

“Do you believe that I did this just to impress the elders?”

“Why yes? Didn’t you do it to prove your position inside the clan? I’m sure they will accept you as the leader of the West now! It was quite the ingenious plan to use the old prophecy against them!”

“I see…”

Long Qing started going off-script to a place that he didn’t expect. From his standpoint, it seemed that Zhang Dong used the other Empires to show off his might. The possibility of him orchestrating the other empires by hiring mercenaries was also brought up to the front. It was as if the Azure Emperor didn’t even pay attention to the chaos that was spreading through the empire while it was happening.

“Great, so you agree. I will have to make an example of a few of your elders, like that Huo Qiang fellow. He had killed a couple of prominent elders and young masters so I’m sure that you’ll understand.”

“You want to do what?”

“Is there a problem? The face of the clan needs to be kept, if we don’t keep on appearances then the people might think that we are weak. Do you have a better solution? Oh I know, you have a daughter and a son.”

“Huh? What are you…”

“I understand, my sons are a bit old and my daughter too… but if we bonded our children with each other, then no one could complain!”

He wanted to lean over and give the Azure Emperor a smack for just suggesting something like this. His kids were way older than the father of the children he was trying to give away. From his short visit to the capital city, he also discovered that the two sons were already wed to multiple women. Having his only daughter be just another notch to one of those idiots was not something that he could stomach.

“So let me get this straight…”

Zhang Dong had enough of the one-sided conversation. It was as if Long Qing thought he had all the cards on his side. The time to turn this around had come and he had to list a few of his own dealbreakers.

“You wish to kill one of my elders, that also happens to be my good friend and also offer up my children to bargain?”

“Well, if you say it like that then it sounds bad but I’m sure you know how it is.”

“Oh, I know how it is… so let me give you an offer. I want the remaining grand elders to be brought to me, their cultivation base will be stripped and you will make an apology.”

“Me, apologize, for what?”

“For starting this war when you could have ended it…”

“My dear brother, your joke is going a bit too far.”

Long Qing started chuckling but soon realized that his white-haired brother was not responding in jests. His face remained unmoving as he stared with deep conviction. The rise in spiritual force in the area was also a sign for how serious this issue was and that he would not go back on it…

Chapter 687

A surge of spiritual energy slithered through a white room. It took the shape of multiple lightning bolts that clashed with blue flames. Both energies filled out half of the space and continued to push against each other in a shoving match. The sources of these strange energies were sitting on a pure white gazebo that at this point in time was becoming ripped apart by these two colliding powers.

“I don’t think you understand my little brother…”

“Oh, I understand and I refuse your proposition. If you think I’m incapable of backing up my words with force, you are gravely mistaken.”

The whole space started to warp as Zhang Dong exerted more spiritual force against the Azure Emperor. Long Qing was visibly stunned by the display of might, his face switched through varied emotions before settling down on a smile.

“I’ve underestimated you, my brother, I didn’t believe that you were hiding this much from me.”

“You think this is much?”

“Is that so? It doesn’t look like that to me…”

The Azure Light started glowing brighter and pushing back at the golden lightning. Zhang Dong had to give it to the Azure Emperor, he was no weakling. If he had to compare it to all the other Emperors that he had faced, then perhaps he did have a bit more spiritual energy than them. It was somewhat comparable to the Emerald Phoenix Emperor. Considering that the two were just straining their spiritual energy against each other, the Azure Emperor probably had some more to give.

While for a moment the blue energy seemed to be winning soon it was stopped. A different type of glow was mixed into the golden hue as purple light slipped in. The Dao of gravity made it in to push against the azure flames and equaled out the exchange. Soon after more lights were added as Zhang Dong utilized various other greater Daos that he had acquired throughout his many travels.

The Azure Emperor was in possession of an enhanced Dao of Fire. It was similar to his golden heavenly lightning and not enough to push against his younger brother. The whole white area started shaking and the gazebo was being shredded to pieces by these two pinnacle cultivators. Soon an explosion rocked the entire area as the two bounced back.

‘Hm… There is something more than that one Dao of flames, is it the Dao of the sword?’

A longsword appeared in Long Qing’s hand right before he was about to overpower him. It was a very nice-looking blade with an azure hilt and long silvery edge. An illusory dragon was swirling around this blade. After using the system he became aware of its grade going over heavenly.

‘It’s not quite an immortal grade weapon, a quasi-immortal item, this might be a problem…’

This was perhaps the ace in the hole that Long Qing was hiding away. With this weapon in his hand, he was able to equal the playing fields. When it came to pure Qi and the number of Dao’s then Zhang Dong was superior. His own sword that he had created from the best available resources didn’t come close. It would probably be impossible for him to break that strong item without offering up some blood.

“I did not expect this, my little brother has large fangs.”

“I also didn’t expect that the great Azure Emperor would hide behind a sword.”

“You insult me, brother. This is part of my strength just as that immortal heritage you have been lucky enough to unearth.”

“Immortal heritage? What do you mean?”

Zhang Dong asked as he was a bit confused about the accusation.

“How else would you be able to rise to these heights? Do you want me to believe that you’ve done it all through hard training and skill?”

“...”

He could not really say anything back against the accusation. In reality, all that he was today had been throughout the system. It was used by him to quickly push into the nascent soul level and then to gain his new mysterious cultivation base. If Long Qing was relying on treasures then so was he. Without the system, he would have been unable to even have this conversation here.

“Your silence says it all. There is no shame in it, we use what we can that has always been the way!”

Long Qing raised his quasi-immortal sword up into the air with one hand and quickly slashed forward. In an instant, a blue wave of flames was created and burst forth. The power was astonishing and not something he could block. Yet, the person that was using this weapon was not as strong. As long as he could read through the movement, there was a small window that he could react to.

Remaining passive in this situation was not wise. His brother was trying to get a feel for his capabilities and how much wiggle room he had. To not disappoint, Zhang Dong pointed out with his finger. Even when some of his white locks got severed by the sword slice he counter-attacked instantly.

A ray of golden energy formed in front of his finger and flew forward. It was timed to shoot out at the same exact moment as he dodged the azure energy. Long Qing who was attempting to launch a follow-up attack was forced to change the trajectory of his blade. His blade slashed in a horizontal fashion to block the beam attack but even when he did, his frame was pushed back by a few steps.

‘That sword…It’s not really what it seems to be… ‘

After this exchange Zhang Dong noticed something, there was a light at the end of the tunnel. When he assumed that he was going up against a quasi-immortal weapon, his victory chances plummeted. Now on the other hand, after Long Qing received the concentrated beam with that weapon, one thing became clear.

‘This must be the weapon of the old Emperor, it must be ancient.’

He was not sure how old this sword was but it had to at least be a hundred thousand years. It was possible that it was once an even more powerful fully immortal weapon. However, even these were susceptible to the passage of time. Even though it was called an immortal item it didn’t mean that it would last forever.

After the hit connected, he could sense a strange resonance within this weapon. He was one of the better craftsmen in the whole empire. Making a heavenly sword had become as easy as breathing. Through his experience, he could feel that this sword had begun to lose its luster. The more the fight continued the more it would deteriorate and eventually shatter by itself.

‘So I need to drag this thing out until it breaks, the more he uses it the more damage it will suffer. If it was not an immortal weapon it would have probably already collapsed on itself.’

This ancient weapon had a limited amount of uses and the Azure Emperor probably also knew this. If it was at its full power then producing more of those azure shockwaves could become troublesome. Yet instead of pushing forth with the sword raised he was taking his time and conserving its power.

‘His probably going to conserve it and only use it when he has to… so I actually have to give him a reason to defend himself.’

It was easier said than done. The blade was still a weapon that could damage his body that was immune to almost all heavenly weapons. If he got too close then his head could fall off. The man he was facing seemed to be focused on the Dao of the sword a lot more than he ever was so staying at range was perhaps the better solution.

Thus before attempting anything, he decided to keep some space and barrage him with a few well-placed bolts of lightning. A shower of golden light descended from the heavens onto the Azure Emperor that had led him here. The wight chamber filled out with various bright colors as various techniques descended toward the man with the blue sword.

This mass of energy would cause any normal nascent soul master to sweat and panic. The Azure Emperor on the other hand remained in place and just moved his blade forward. With one thrust he produced a torrent of unimaginable power that pierced through all the various pinnacle techniques Zhang Dong could produce. While they weren’t quite focused, not even someone like the demi-human Emperor who possessed a body unmatched by anyone would remain uninjured.

‘Damn, are you serious? Isn’t this cheating? Hey Bob, can you calculate how many more times he can do that with that thing?’

‘Calculating… insufficient data, can’t measure…’

His Ai failed him as he could not present him with a number. Without knowing the amount of power the Azure Emperor needed to use it was impossible for Bob to make the calculations. Zhang Dong did notice one specific thing, something that his enemy probably tried to hide. A small tick appeared for a fraction of a second in his body. It was as if something had happened after he cleared out the space with his blade, perhaps Long Qing knew that he didn’t have much time and that if he couldn’t end it fast, it could be his downfall.

‘His pushing, this might confirm it…’

Long Qing was now on the attack for the first time and so was his large Azure Dragon. It collided with his golden counterpart which was called Bahamut. Their draconic might exploded and caused whatever was left from the little platform in the middle to evaporate into nothingness.

The speed at which the four beings were clashing with each other generated sonic booms everywhere. It was the battle of an epoch taking place but no one was here to notice it. Other cultivators would give away their limbs to be able to analyze the various battle techniques that were clashing against each other.

For the moment the tide was turning and the Azure Emperor was on the path of victory. His weapon was able to slice through all of Zhang Dong’s defenses and calling forth his golden armor for help did not do him any good. Swipe after swipe the spiritual metals continued to be shredded to pieces and even his body was becoming injured.

Yet he prevailed, with each injury he received his blows rained back. Even if he was able to just tear through the emperor's clothes and give him a little nick, it all counted for something. These tiny scratches started piling up as the seed inside of his body started reacting. All the years of training didn’t go to waste as the Emperor’s Dao of the sword began getting infused into his body by the ferocious attacks. He was slowly learning, even without absorbing it through the system his own Dao of swordsmanship was starting to evolve…

Chapter 688

“How are you able to defend for so long…”

“Wouldn’t you pick up a few tricks if you fought people at your level? But perhaps you never really had to struggle before in your life?”

For a while it seemed that he would lose, the quasi-immortal weapon that his opponent was using had shredded through his armor and continued to be a problem. Even though his spiritual energy was higher and he possessed more insight into various Dao’s, he was still getting pushed back. The only reason he could last through everything was due to Long Qing's supposed lack of experience.

The Azure Emperor was at the pinnacle of this world. The only people that could challenge his might were the other emperors that had all been defeated by Zhang Dong. Throughout his life there was no one that could pose a real threat to his position. From what he knew, Long Qing was an only child. The Long Clan would not allow their future emperor ever to suffer a setback.

Zhang Dong could imagine his older brother being surrounded by yes men all his life. He was given the best cultivation materials, the best techniques, and the best training that was possible. He obviously developed into a strong fighter but there was something lacking, something that could not be given by training alone. This something was experience gained only by a near-death battle with an equal or slightly stronger opponent.

Even though Zhang Dong was a lot younger and relied on the system to gain a lot of his power, he still faced competent opponents. He had risked his life the moment he arrived in this strange world and had even almost died when defending others. Long Qing never had a worthy opponent that would push him to his extreme. His sense of superiority made him believe that he could not be defeated.

However, now he was having a rude awakening as some droplets of blood appeared on his cheek. During their last exchange, Zhang Dong was able to predict the path of the quasi-immortal weapon and delivered a well-placed counter. After throwing in a few fakes here and there his opponent had to retreat.

“You cut me…?”

“Oh, that little nick? It was a bit shallow but I think I’ve gotten the hang of you and that blade… Now we can start for real.”

Long Qing touched his cheek with two fingers and quickly examined the red liquid on his fingertips. He could vaguely recall Zhang Dong swinging his sword that had been dulled by his own. It looked more like a saw with all the broken-up parts but was somehow being held together by his Qi instead. It made the edge retain a lot of sharpness that somehow made it through his defenses.

“A lucky cut!”

“We will see in a moment if I was lucky or not, won’t we?”

The two men charged at each other without using any grand techniques. Long Qing still expected to have the all-around advantage but soon he realized that something was wrong. Zhang Dong started to anticipate all of his sword strikes before he could pull them off. His weapon was superior and could not touch his body which was constantly recovering from any damage.

To make things worse he even needed to defend himself. It didn’t end at the shallow cut on his cheek, soon his royal robes were being torn through. Long Qing was so confident in his victory that he didn’t even change out of his baggy royal robe. It had become a negative factor in this fight when his opponent turned up the pace.

“Why you…”

“Oh, it stings, doesn’t it? But this is only the beginning…”

Zhang Dong had managed to figure out Long Qing’s fighting style. It was very proper and orthodox. It lacked any weaknesses but it also didn’t possess many strengths. The limitations of it started shining through as he was unable to react to the unorthodox sword style he was fighting against.

“Ugh…”

During their duel, the Azure Emperor started faltering. His rage built up and resulted in wider swings that had more power behind them but were also easier to predict. Zhang Dong’s palm managed to find its way toward Long Qing’s torso. This clean hit sent the leader of the Long Clan flying into the distance. His body collided with the edge of this wide chamber and produced an imprint that started cracking.

‘So this wall is destructible?’

For some reason Zhang Dong expected this room to be locked away from the outside. The attacks that the quasi-immortal weapon produced had been slamming into the walls constantly without producing any damage. To his surprise it cracked almost instantly the moment Long Qing collided with it. There could be only one reason for this happening.

‘There is some sort of invisible barrier over those white walls but Long Qing can pass through this invisible barrier.’

He was sure that this was the trick behind it. This whole area was probably attained to the Azure Emperor in a similar fashion as his own Golden Palace was to him. Perhaps right outside of it there was some type of power source that these walls were tapping into. It was probably a defensive formation or something similar that recognized Long Qing as the owner.

‘Hm, this smells like a bloodline technique…’

A small amount of the Azure Emperor’s blood remained on the tip of his damaged sword. While his opponent was quickly recovering from the hit, he was far away. The Azure Dragon that was fighting to the side with Bahamut was already charging to protect his master. Landing a follow-up attack was improbable so instead he decided to go for the nearby white walls.

‘Hah, like through butter…”

The tip of his sword that had broken in a few places had somehow made it through this white coating. After pulling it out he could feel some air being circulated through. These walls were rather thin and mostly for show, the thing keeping the whole place together was an invisible formation that he only now started to see through.

‘Hey Bob, can you tell me where I am?’

‘Attempting… map has been updated…’

‘Well, this is surprising…’

Zhang Dong was able to finally activate his map. The small hole that he lodged his sword through allowed him to connect with the outside. Just as he had thought his location was deep into the enemy lines. If what he was seeing was correct then he was directly under the floating capital that he once visited.

‘Bob, where am I exactly?’

After some calculations were met he got his answer. The floating city that only Long Clan members lived in was around thirty kilometers above him. He on the other hand was somewhere underground five kilometers deep from the surface. The reason he was unable to teleport out became apparent as a large black hole appeared in the middle of his location. He was in a previous player spawn point that didn’t let people use their system map.

‘I need to get out of here, that quasi-immortal blade is tougher than it looks, it will take more to break it and even if my skills are getting sharper, so will his…’

Zhang Dong knew that for the time being he had the advantage but things could change rather fast. Long Qing lacked the experience when fighting opponents with more spiritual energy but he was getting it the more they fought. Just like he surprised his older brother with the cut to the cheek, the same thing could happen to him. It was more important for him to get out of this trap and reach his people as victory was murky.

‘There are other people outside, I can feel it… even if I back him into a wall, I will not win.’

His mind was made up after realizing that this was not a fair fight, to begin with. Their clash was being watched from outside. It was probably members from the Long Clan there. If their Emperor started losing they would surely charge in to stop him. Before they got involved he needed to get out of here and with Bob’s help and these few drops of Long Qing’s blood his escape became possible.
With a slight tap, he managed to expand the area of the hole to the side of a manhole cover. With a quick swipe of his blade, the white wall was sliced into a perfect circle that slowly started falling into the room he occupied.

“Bahamut, to me!”

“Wait, what are you doing? You can’t leave!”

“Sorry, but my sect members are worried about me!”

Bahamut’s form exploded into a million golden particles that blinded the Azure Emperor for a moment. Now in the form of a tiny baby dragon, he appeared on Zhang Dong’s shoulder. Both of them quickly slid through the hole in the wall to arrive outside of this cage. Now the true form of all of this came to light and it included many nascent soul elders crawling out of the woodwork.

“Stop him, he must not escape.”

‘This looks like some strange filming set…’

His body blurred as he dodged a few of the nascent soul masters trying to attack him. The white room that he left behind was inside a large circular cavern. It was made from some sort of gray stone that was very similar to cement. The whole area was very well lit and it was possible to look into the huge white room inside. For the entire time that he was in it the people here were able to look at the confrontation.

‘So, these guys were his backup. I never really stood a chance even if I continued to fight…’

There were far too many people guarding this place for him to ever come out victorious. Without reaching something like a quasi-immortal level himself there was no way of him winning. Luckily he did not use all of his energy while battling his older brother. The people coming after him were not prepared for his escape so evading their tackles was rather easy.

His gaze fell on the environment that looked out of place. The whole place was lit up as if he was in some kind of secret underground facility. It looked sterile and more modern compared to the capital city that was directly above. Considering that one of the ancestors of the Long Clan was part of the system users it made some sense. It was possible that he built up this spawn point to be a secret lair to help his descendants after they left.

Before him was a giant gate before which something like an elevator was waiting for him. It was the only way out as the walls were probably enhanced by the otherworldly material that was unbreakable. His push for survival was on, getting out to get some assistance from his sect was necessary and he would show that it was a mistake for the Long Clan to ever bring him here.

Chapter 689

“How was he able to escape through the ancient formation and the mystical chamber?”

“It doesn’t matter, don’t let him escape from here!”

“Agh…He’s too strong, where is the Emperor?”

“Release the seal of the mystical chamber!”

A group of people started panicking as they saw the white-haired Zhang Dong speed throughout the area. His body was surrounded by golden lightning and with each movement he created a sonic boom. Even though there were many late-stage and great circle realm nascent soul masters around, none of them could even touch him.

They did not understand how their Emperor was even able to last against such a monster for this long. The two dragons were on another level and all the elders here quickly realized that they were like little children compared to them. It would take their leader a moment to get here so it was up to them to stop this person from escaping. If they were able to block him for a few seconds, then it would be their victory.

“Get out of my way if you don’t want to die.”

However, their opponent would not go down without a fight. All the people that were trying to block his path were trampled through. The walls of spiritual energy were shattered, their soul beasts destroyed and their own bodies battered. The once mighty nascent soul masters could only look on with horror as a human inside a giant bolt of lightning collided with the exit gate.

“Fool, only the Emperor can activate the grand gate you shall not escape!”

“Only the Emperor? Thanks for the tip, idiot.”

“Huh?”

One of the elders shouted out to spite the man that had shoved him out of the way and took his arm along with it. The way outside could only be opened by the Azure Emperor himself without their leader they would be unable to leave themselves. Only one person from the royal family had access to this area at a time and currently, the Emperor had managed to emerge from within the white chamber.

The flesh wounds that were on his body had healed up thanks to his own body-refining technique. People from the Long Clan wanted to cheer but before they could give their leader some words of appreciation the whole place started rumbling. Something connected with the large gate before which an elevator was placed.

“How?”

“What are you looking at, stop him!”

The usually calm and collected Long Qing shouted at his followers. His voice carried with it an uncanny amount of animosity that they had never witnessed before. The Azure Emperor that they knew was more relaxed and never took things too seriously. Yet, at this moment the air around him had become different. It could only mean one thing, the opponent that they were facing was on a level that could make the world's strongest angry.

“The gate, it’s opening? Is his bloodline this strong…”

One of the elders here had to bite his tongue before saying something that he couldn’t take back. Everyone here assumed that only the Azure Emperor could use the large gate as he was of the line of Azure. They had forgotten that Zhang Dong here was supposed to be his brother from a very close bloodline to his. Normally this wouldn’t be a problem but their ancestors were close brothers and probably twins. It was possible for his bloodline to activate the opening mechanism and apparently, it was.

The large gate started opening and just as soon as the opening was big enough for a person to slip in, he was out of there. To make things worse, the gate started closing itself back behind him and left the nascent soul masters trapped on the other side. Even when the Azure Emperor approached to activate it, it wouldn’t budge.

“What did he…?”

It seemed that somehow Zhang Dong’s bloodline had overpowered Long Qing’s and the gate identified him as the new master. Even after their leader moved his hand forward to activate the opening mechanism there was no response. In the case of a bloodline overpowering another, the previous owner would lose all of their rights of ownership. This sight caused a silence in this area in which the group found itself trapped now.

“M…my Lord? Maybe if the young lords come together the lock will open…”

Finally, the highest-ranked elder from the group decided to speak up. In the case of the bloodline weakening it was possible to boost it with the help of more direct descendants. This included all of Long Qing’s children and perhaps a few other elders that were at this time in the city. It was a shameful act to ask for but as it stood, this was the only way for them to get out of there as the walls were too sturdy to break through.

“Hah, you want to involve my children? A shame like that is unbecoming of an Emperor!”

Instead of calling for help, the man raised his blue blade forward. It started radiating a blue flame that expanded forward to take the shape of a dragon’s head. This head shot forward while accompanied by a massive roar. With shock on their faces, all the elders quickly retreated to make way for the dragon made of Qi and sword energy.

After it collided with the gate a massive explosion shook the entire place but still it wasn’t budging. The Emperor didn’t falter as he held his azure sword forward and continued to push the technique against the cold rock. Within a few seconds, an audible cracking sound was heard by everyone here. Finally, the protective structure gave in to the quasi-immortal weapon that was able to create a small hole to the outside.
“It’s small but now you will be able to use our teleportation techniques to get out, follow him, and don’t let him escape!”

“You heard the Emperor, follow me!”

The old men initialized their talismans to vanish from within this area with only one remaining for a moment. It was the leader of those elders and the strongest person here before the Emperor. Most of them didn’t hear it but there were two cracking noises at different locations as the attack connected.

“What are you waiting for, I gave you an order.”

“Of course, Azure Emperor!”

The man quickly left while looking over Long Qing’s tired expression. This attack he performed had taken a lot out of him and was probably the reason why he wasn’t chasing after the man that got away himself. It was better to keep this realization to himself as mentioning this to his clan members would only cause a lowering in morale. All of them needed to focus on this enemy, if they could take care of the usurper then it would all be over.

…

‘This tunnel looks like an old subway… who made this?’

Zhang Dong with the help of Bob had managed to hack into the opening mechanism. Luckily this world saw him as the Long Clan’s ancestor’s descendant. His bloodline resembled the Azure Dynasty’s and through it he was able to gain ownership over it. It was a temporary solution as he expected Long Qing to get out of there sooner or later but by that time he would be long gone.

When outside he entered something that looked like a subway tunnel. There were cables and lights at constant intervals here and also something that looked like a monorail. The platform that was before the gate probably moved through this modern-looking tunnel system. Perhaps if he visited this place a few years ago he would be surprised but after getting to the truth of the system the veil was already torn from his eyes.

‘Did the person that created this really come from Earth or from somewhere similar?’

The way things looked here was almost identical to the stations he remembered from his old life. It was quite eerie to fly through this place that reminded him of his old world and the lack of any side tunnels only made it creepier. However, before he could focus on this feeling a red window appeared before him.

“Hm? Did they get through the gate already? It should have taken him at least a couple of hours to reset the bloodline… Did he use the quasi-immortal weapon?”

After taking a glance he knew that Long Qing was not able to use his bloodline to get through. This left one other option which involved the powerful blade that he was using. During his confrontation with the Emperor, he realized that it would be impossible for him to beat it. If he was not getting chased by an angry man with that blade then he needed to increase the pace.

‘Can’t that blasted thing just shatter already… I guess it’s not an almost immortal blade for nothing, I also can’t exclude the possibility of him having other weapons like that.’

His speed increased as he did not wish for the battle to continue in this small area. There was no way to evade and these walls were as strong as that gate that he left behind. Luckily it didn’t seem that anyone predicted that someone could get through it. There were no checkpoints that stopped him or blockades. Probably when he arrived at the top one last area waited for him before he could escape.

‘I should be able to teleport back to the golden palace after I leave this place. Bob, use the function instantly when you are able to, we can’t take any chances.’

‘Affirmative’

His system was powerful but also quite rudimentary. It had the basis of an old operating system that he was familiar with. To activate anything he needed to click through many prompts and windows. Thankfully, with Bob’s help who could access functions with his approval, it was possible to go around these limitations.

Only a couple of kilometers remained and when he got outside he would be back with his allies. With the help of the Golden Palace, he hoped to counter the quasi-immortal blade. It had gone through a lot of upgrades and could dish out a lot of damage. Yet, the finishing blow would probably need to come from him but as long as he had some backup then everything was possible.

‘Wait… someone is there…’

A strange light appeared at the end of the tunnel as he arrived. Something was wrong which caused him to surround his whole body in a layer of protective spells and techniques. The moment he arrived at the exit area he was bombarded by a barrage of spiritual energy. All the nascent soul masters that he saw down below were here to receive him, things looked grim but for some reason, the Azure Emperor was not here…

Chapter 690

“Give it your all, he might still be alive!”

A group of old men and women along with various large creatures behind them continued to barrage a specific spot with all their ranged techniques. They stood before a large ancient gate with many chains attached from all sides. It was the only exit from this area and required a pure Long Clan bloodline to open.

It was a spot where they could teleport themselves as the passage outside was also blocked. Only with the help of the Azure Emperor’s pure bloodline would they be able to leave this place. They needed to do their best to stop this man who was their enemy. He had already proven himself to be Long Qing’s equal.

With that in mind, they offered up all of their spiritual energy to turn this place into a blasting zone. Rubble flew everywhere and even the sturdy walls that had remained unchanged for millenia started crumbling. This was probably their only realistic chance to defeat this monster. If the Azure Emperor was unable to beat him with the help of the azure blade of dragons, then what could they do?

“Continue, give it all that you have!”

“We must eradicate this fake and secure our clan's future!”

“Hoh, you are really into it, do you want some help?”

“Huh?”

The elders looked to the voice that came from the side to witness a human shape emerging from the shadows. It quickly took on the form of the man that they were trying to kill or at least injure.

“Oh? You don’t need my help? Well, I’ll excuse myself then but could you step to the side, I need to concentrate on this last door a little bit…”

“I… it’s the usurper! How did he get here?”

The Elders panicked, the man that they were trying to stop was right there. His clothes were somewhat messed up but this was more due to his battle with the Emperor than from their attacks. It didn’t seem that he had been even grazed by one of their spiritual blasts. Was he able to predict this trap before they could spring it or was he just so strong?

“What’s with those faces? Do you still want to fight? I’m sorry to inform you but without your leader, this will not go your way.”

This answer was answered rather quickly as a massive surge of spiritual energy filled the entire area. All of them started getting pushed down to the ground. It was a strange combination of a suppressive aura attack and gravity shift in the whole area. They could not feel how powerful this person was because of the mystical chamber he was occupying with the Emperor. Now they became aware that they were nothing but flies and could not even stall him for more than a few moments.

…

“Good, just stay there while I open this thing…”

Zhang Dong called out to the scared cultivators while using his Dao of Gravity to keep them in check. Thanks to his fast reaction time he was able to evade the ambush and sink into his shadowy form. He then waited for a moment to allow these people to drain their spiritual energy. If not for this fact it would probably be impossible to suppress them this well even with his unique cultivation realm.

Killing or ripping out their dantians crossed his mind but there was no time to waste. Long Qing was not among these people which allowed him to push forth. The quasi-immortal blade that he possessed was still on his mind. Breaking it was unsuccessful so he needed to open up this gate before even thinking about lowering the number of his enemies.

Living all of these powerful people alone could potentially cost some of his people their lives but if he died, then his entire sect would be eradicated. They would be branded traitors and hunted down to the last remaining one. The people of this world were extremely brutal to their opposition and he did not want his people to be left with nothing but misery.

‘Bob, help me out here.’

‘Initiating bloodline… unlocking successful.’

At first, it looked like it would be a headache to open this new gate but after tapping into the first one, it wasn’t such a problem. His bloodline seemed to already be part of this structure so having Bob work his magic didn’t take long. With the gate spreading apart he quickly shifted into his darkness form to slip through the tiniest opening.

‘It’s a shame to leave this place when it’s fully operational. Now that I look at it, there are some other tunnels leading out from this main area… There are probably other secrets hidden here…’

Perhaps after everything was over he would return to this place to find some answers but as it stood now, it was time to return to his people. There were only five hundred meters until he arrived at a clearing. Then it would be finally possible for him to teleport out of this place. However, would his dear older brother just allow him to escape without even trying to stop him?

‘Warning.’

It didn’t take long for a red system massage to appear before his face. There was another ambush waiting ahead and this time around his dear brother was part of it. It seemed that Long Qing left his goons to stall him for a while while he waited above the city that they found themselves under. Even without getting there, he could feel a dangerous presence.
“I wanted to end this without bloodshed but you leave me with no choice, farewell my young brother, may you find peace in death!”

Long Qing's brotherly love could only go so far as he had finally decided to part ways with Zhang Dong. The Golden Dragon in question had become too strong to be left alive and showed that he would not surrender. It was clear that Long Qing would rather lob off his head than try to reason. There was time for peace to occur but the Long Clan was unwilling to give an inch.

Zhang Dong didn’t stop, he was too close to the exit for even someone like Long Qing to stop him. Even if he had the blue sword, there wouldn’t be a problem as long as he didn’t get hit. Only a few hundred meters remained before he reached the safe zone and his opponent was not aware of this.

‘I’m not sure if he is aware of the limits of my teleportation ability. Perhaps I won’t even need to lift a finger. Bob, be sure to instantly teleport me when you get the connection.’

‘Affirmative.’

While the plan wasn’t bad in itself he underestimated his opponent's resourcefulness. The sword he was holding wasn’t the only problem as the massive amount of spiritual energy that was building up was not coming from it. He was making his way straight up and had a good view of the bottom of the flying Azure city. What he had thought to just be a rock had more to it than he initially thought.

‘Is that a giant spirit cannon? Does he not care about all the elders that I left behind in that chamber? Or are they supposed to be a noble sacrifice?’

His brother was not even trying to swing his sword. Instead, he was waiting for the humongous ray of concentrated energy to do the deed. The Long Qing he was looking at was not even real, he was either a hologram or an illusory technique used to keep him focused on the wrong thing. It was too late to go back now, the energy blast was coming but so was he.

‘There is no other choice… I need to take it and survive.’

Zhang Dong decided to use up his reserves. The ray of energy was bursting forth from the top of the city above him. It was wider than the tunnel he had found himself in after leaving the previous gate. Drilling to the side was not an option as the diameter was just to large, the only way out of there was up.

His whole body turned into a blur as he surrounded himself along with Bahamut in a thick layer of energy. His lightning crackled and another sonic boom resounded through the place as his body slammed into the wave of energy. Everything turned blue and he could feel immense pressure coming from all sides. The force attempted to push him down but he could not let it win.

‘Eleven… ten… nine… eight…’
Bob counted the meters remaining before he could teleport him out of this place. The first set of defenses started to give in as his shield of gravity could not withstand the pressure. Following it were the flames he received from battling the Emerald Phoenix Emperor and other Daos quickly followed suit. Only a thin coat of golden light remained as he pushed himself forward.

His eyes went red and blood spouted from within his nose. He could feel his bones starting to shatter under the immense heat and pressure. This attack contained various energies that when mixed created an almost perfect weapon of death. Yet, with a final burst of vitality and using his forearms to shield his face, he pushed on.

A massive explosion of unprecedented proportions spread through the area as the earth under the capital city collapsed. A giant shockwave spread in all directions and bounced off the defensive barrier of the floating city. The sound was so loud that if heard by a normal person it would instantly rupture their eardrums and the heat resembled an atomic blast.

Only one man remained in this zone of death and only after the dust was starting to settle, did the person that ordered the attack appear. Long Qing had moved into the safety of his city to observe the spectacle along with a few other people. What was left over was a giant crater with a large opened gate beneath it.

“The path was open so the elders probably didn’t survive.”

The man mumbled while focusing his gaze on the few charred corpses in the chamber the elders were supposed to block Zhang Dong’s escape. All the walls there were made from an extremely sturdy material that not even the giant cannon could budge.

“He should be dead… but I won’t know for sure unless I find his body…”

Long Qing flew down with his hand resting on his hip. Even though he had won their confrontation there was something bothering him. What would happen if his brother had escaped? Could he really win another confrontation if his weapon was not there?

“Follow the Emperor! Find the remains of the usurper!”

He was not alone here as his oldest son followed after. The intrusive thoughts were pushed to the background as he focused on the search. If his brother was still alive, then he should be somewhere nearby. There was no escape and if he lived, then finishing the job would not be hard.

Chapter 691

“Honey… I don’t want to go to the elder meeting…”

“...”

“Huh?”

Zhang Dong opened up his eyes to see a cute small dragon’s head in front of him. Before he could say anything his face was assaulted by Bahamut’s tongue. His face was covered in a lot of slobber which meant that he had been out for the count for a while now.

“Aghh… stop licking me… ugh…”

While trying to push away his small dragon companion he felt pain shot through his body. Now that he was awake he noticed that his body was in a rough state. His robes were torn and he had various burn marks everywhere, even the long white hair that he was proud off was somewhat charred.

‘I pushed into the beam and was barely able to teleport away, It’s a miracle that I’m even alive.’

It took him a second to remember the previous incident with Long Qing. His brother through some strange manner was able to pull him into a secluded location. It forced his teleportation function to not function which resulted in quite the escape. Somehow he was able to activate it in time before he was disintegrated by the giant beam cannon of the capital city.

“Ugh… is everything in place? Both arms are there, my legs too and most importantly… yeah it’s still there.”

His body was darker than usual as he suffered third-degree burns. Even though the body refining technique was at the great circle level it could not resist all that damage. Luckily he was in possession of many healing techniques, already the wounds were starting to heal and even his hair was returning to its previous form.

“I must have been out for a moment as a large chunk of my Qi has already recovered but… where is everyone?”

During the stressful situation, he had instructed Bob to bring him back to the Golden Palace. It was supposed to be close by and a safe haven. He expected to be injured by the energy beam and barely make it out alive. Then his plan involved getting scooped up by the sect members that were supposed to help him stabilize. Yet, no one was here and he woke up with all the wounds intact.

Perhaps the only reason he was alive was due to Bahamut being here. His dragon was able to use healing techniques as well. Their souls were connected so his power had decreased but it was enough to keep his body stable. To get to the bottom of this mystery he quickly brought up his status screen.

‘What happened…Bob, scan the palace, search for anyone that could be alive or even dead, prioritize Zhang Liena.’

He had a bad feeling about this as he was greeted by red windows. The Golden Palace looked to be in bad shape, even the room he was in now had a lot of sizzling panels. This was supposed to be the main cockpit where all the elders gathered. His chair that he usually used to sit in was there but the whole place was devoid of life.

‘Scan finished, unable to find any life signals.’

‘No life signals? Could it be?’

When Bob was finished with the quick scan and forwarded him the information he almost fell over. Was it possible for everyone to have been dead? This golden palace had thousands of people in it before he was forcefully teleported away, his wife included.

‘Bob, what about the bodies?’

‘No bodies could be found.’

‘No bodies either? So they all could be alive then? But where did they all go then…’

It seemed that there was just no one here. It was probable that the people were also caught up in some type of trap, perhaps even teleported away. If no dead remains were present in this huge palace then his sect members were probably somewhere else. To no surprise, he could not check for them in his faction window. It showed an error when trying to seek out Liena’s location.

‘It’s working in some ways but not in others, it’s only a partial blockage…’

His system was working to some extent as he could actually use his teleportation feature. It was limited to the area he was currently in as something was blocking him from going to places like Spirit Spring City. This could only mean one thing and partially explained what transpired.

‘They must have pushed into the formation after I was pulled into it by Long Qing. My connection to the Golden Palace lets me get back here but this formation is blocking me from directly leaving, it must be something similar to the Cerulean Empress area.’

He had enough experience with taking out the other Emperors to know what was happening. His people must have fallen into a trap and were whisked away to another location. After they were gone the palace must have crashed somewhere. Considering that there was damage done to the main engine, the main protective formation must have been depowered during the descent.

‘It’s like an EMP was sent through this place… Bob, can you bring this place back online?’

‘Golden Palace is offline, do you wish to spend spirit points to reactivate it?’

‘Nothing is free but this is just highway robbery, why does it cost so much to reactivate the generator?’

‘The main power battery has been destroyed, it needs to be replaced.’

‘The main battery?’

Zhang Dong didn’t want to waste time but he decided to quickly make his way into the engine room. What was previously powering this place was a holy golden egg. It could output at least as much energy as it could and also restore it with time. Now it was just a collapsed cracked shell with powder in the middle.

‘I see… This whole place is unusable…’

After the power outage, it seemed that the whole place couldn’t really hold itself together. This golden palace defied the laws of physics and also architecture. Some spaces had spatial formations in them to compress them to fit the palace. All of them had expanded and caused massive amounts of damage to the entire fortress. How something like this could have happened was above him as he believed this place to be impenetrable by normal means.

‘It has an obvious weak point that not many should be aware of, could this be Long Qing’s doing?’

He had no idea how it was done but somehow the whole Golden Palace was shut down in one fell swoop. It was the first time that this fortress had fallen and it came rather easily. His only explanation was the location and the closeness to the Long Clan. Perhaps the ancestors of this clan had prepared for such an occasion when the golden dragon could rise again. Only legends remained but perhaps the golden and azure had a problematic relationship in the past.

‘If I spend points to reconstruct this engine will it just collapse again?’

This was a conundrum that he was not sure about. If he used up his points it was possible to repair this flying fortress. With it operational it would probably be easier to traverse the outside areas. The only problem was the reason behind the collapse, if it happened once it could happen again. His resources were limited and after upgrading this fortress, the point expenditure had increased.

‘Maybe I should postpone this for now. First I need to figure out the reason behind this, otherwise, I’ll quickly run out of spirit points.’

After making the decision he changed locations to the teleportation chamber. While he would not repair the main generator this didn’t mean that he wouldn’t do some minor repairs. It was impossible to teleport outside this area but it was within its boundaries. However, it was possible to create a safe haven for his people. This chamber still had a mostly intact gate that could be quickly repaired with spirit points.

After bringing up his system window and clicking a few times the entire room started shifting. The rubble that covered the floors started to shift around and connect back with the partially destroyed walls. The gate was doing the same as the parts that it was composed of started reforming. It was quite an interesting sight which still baffled him. How was something like this possible and how would he handle the being that was able to create this system?

‘I should probably not worry about that for now, I thought the biggest problem would be the Overseer but Long Qing already almost killed me once…’

After his victories against the other Emperors, he somewhat discounted his older brother as a potential threat. His power was around the level of the Emerald Phoenix Emperor which at this point was nothing special. The Quasi-Immortal weapon that he produced was not something that he expected to see. It was possible for more such items to exist and probably the formation that caused this golden palace to fall was of such quality.

‘I need to figure out how this happened.’

The teleportation chamber was restored to its previous glory. While the main generator was offline this didn’t mean that he couldn’t use a secondary one. There were various devices in this palace that with some fuel could at least power this one area. The smaller generator looked like a cylinder and was quickly connected with the help of cables to the gate. After jump-starting it with his lightning Qi, it was operational once more.

‘Good, the system is picking it up. I’ll be able to send people back here after I find them.’

Zhang Dong continued to wander through the golden palace to repair some of the critical structures. The costliest procedure would be to recreate the whole generator but getting some critical areas working first wasn’t that bad. First came the gate to allow his people to come back, then the medical chamber for any potentially injured, and finally he also decided to recreate the shield formation. It wouldn’t be that strong but he at least needed to have the insides of this fortress to be protected from any outside forces.

‘So this is it…’

It took him around twenty minutes to get the few places back to working order, a task only possible thanks to his system. After it was done he found himself outside together with Bahamut. Both of them were greeted by a lush jungle filled with massive trees that were thicker than a person. It looked similar to one of the pocket dimensions he visited during the raid of the Cerulean Empress's lair.

“Let’s go Bahamut, they can’t be that far off…”

“GAO!”

The tiny dragon gave out a rather cute-sounding roar before the two ascended into the air. Both kept their senses spread out for any signs of life and quickly discovered something nearby…

Chapter 692

‘Hey Bob, can you tell me why this shitty thing always stops working when I really need to? This would be a lot easier if I could see where everyone is located.’

‘Unable to answer, insufficient date.’

‘Yeah, sure at least keep the scanners running and tell me if you detect anyone from the sect, even if it’s just a regular foot soldier.’

‘Affirmative.’

‘If I haven’t found anyone by now, then maybe they are all at one main location?’

Zhang Dong flew through the barrage of trees while trying to find his sect members. For one reason or another his faction window wasn’t working correctly. Things like the location of his troops were giving him errors and he could not even pinpoint where his wife was. Usually, he would be able to instantly teleport to her side but even the rings that connected the two weren’t functioning.

“This makes no sense, is it only allowing larger-scale teleportations?”

Something wasn’t adding up, he was able to use the system to get to the golden palace but not to anywhere else. It was like a setting that was limiting his selection just to make things harder. Was the Overseer watching from the shadows and interfering with the scenario? Without all these strange traps his people should have been able to use the stronghold to invade this formation.

“Or is there some program running in the background to artificially equal everything out? Realistically speaking, Long Qing should not have been able to defeat me. That sword wasn’t there when I came to the city.”

Zhang Dong strained his brain to try and recall everything that transpired when he visited the capital city. Long Qing back there never used a sword like the one he had now. Could it be something hidden away in their treasury or was it manifested to equal things out? As it stood, he was above everyone when it came to cultivation might. The quasi-immortal weapon shifted things in the favor of his enemy.

‘Could the last boss be given a boost if things play out too easily for our hero?’

That was a possibility but this was not the time to speculate. What he needed to do was to get to his people and get them back to the golden fortress. After enough people were gathered then the renovation could progress and with his presence within the ship, he hoped to defend against whatever destroyed the main generator battery.

‘Now where could they be, considering I’m up against the bastards from the Long Clan, they will probably use things that don’t involve them directly in the conflict.’

Ever since this conflict started it became apparent that the Long Clan didn’t like to get their hands dirty. Within this space was something that they had control of and they could decide on the tactics against trespassers. Would they risk their own lives by engaging the people trapped here? This was not very likely, instead, they probably had other ways like traps and beasts to do it for them.

Just as he had assumed, soon a few life signals started popping up. They didn’t belong to his people but to spirit beasts instead. There was a herd of cat-like creatures that looked like tigers with horns on their foreheads. Their fur was mostly white with bluish spots that fell in line with the Azure esthetic.

‘Those are some powerful fire energies, those things are radiating…’

There were thousands of these monsters running around and many of them were of the nascent soul level of strength. On thing was strange, all of them were running in just one direction as if they were chasing after something. With his system being blocked and his senses not able to pinpoint the location of his people, perhaps this was a clue.

‘I should follow these beasts, they might take me to my people.’

He had sunk into the shadows of the many trees that were inside this jungle. It was impossible for these beasts to find him as he didn’t produce a smell their enhanced noses could pick up on. The whole spectacle reminded him of the pocket dimension in the ocean. There after he triggered the main trap a swarm of monsters attacked him. They were able to track his exact location and this could be similar to that time. Thus he followed after them while pushing himself to the forefront where the leader of the pack was outrunning everyone else.

‘It’s big, at least twenty-five meters in height…’

These beasts seemed to grow to large proportions the stronger they became. The leader made all the other beasts look like little kittens. Most of them were around the three-meter mark when it came to height but there were also some that were close to twenty.

‘Should I just book it?’

Zhang Dong started getting stressed. This monster was quite strong, to the point that it would even give Huo Qiang the second strongest of his sect some trouble. All these beasts were sprinting in one direction which he could just focus on. It was possible that his people were already under siege by some other creatures. His top speed was above this and in a situation where a second could save even one person from dying, it was worth risking it.

The large tiger creatures didn’t notice him as they seemed to be occupied with running in one direction. It gave him ample time to quickly use the shadows to travel to the leader and wait for a good opportunity for a strike. His shadowy form didn’t allow him to utilize his full speed and when he performed his attack his position would quickly become known. Everything needed to be done quickly and with no mistakes if he wished to defeat this monster.

His body which was covered in shades blurred forward as he left his hiding place. In his right hand, he held a new sword that quickly went into motion. A blade of golden light was created with a combination of newly gained swordsmanship enlightenment and electrical might. The huge beast glanced down quickly but it was already too late when it realized. Its head went flying through the air as a massive surge of energy appeared from under it.

‘My fight with Long Qing made me a bit stronger…’

This beast was at the level of an advanced great circle nascent soul master. If released into the Empire it would be able to probably destroy a medium-sized sect along with all its masters. Its skin, body, claws, and leather would be too thick to be pierced or slashed by conventional means. Yet, such a monster easily lost its life to his strike which was reaching the limitations of this world and his own body.

The head was flying through the air and the monster’s huge body was collapsing. Yet, the other creatures from the pack didn’t even react to losing their leader. Instead, they all focused their gazes at the human that had done the deed. All of them roared at the same time which even sent shivers to run down his spine. There was no fear, only maddened rage as they threw themselves in his direction.

Zhang Dong didn’t have time to play around with these beasts, taking out their pack leader was supposed to stop their approach. After this plan had failed he just turned around and used his superior cultivation to get out of here. His power was still limited and wasting too much of it could prove deadly.

‘They shouldn’t be able to keep up with me anyway…’

A tactical retreat was initiated as he just flew up and out of their range. Even though these beasts were strong, they were incapable of maintaining themselves in the air. Some of the larger ones could jump quite high but after a few dodges, he started gaining some distance. His trip soon continued and with time he widened the gap even further to the point of not being able to see his pursuers.

‘Those creatures, they looked familiar… where did I see them before?’

During his trip, something started bothering him. This whole place had some type of nostalgic vibe that he couldn’t really pinpoint. With doubts in his mind, he continued further where he finally discovered a large structure in the distance. The old memories rushed back into his mind the moment he saw it as it reminded him of a very early time of his life.

‘It looks like that stronghold. Wait, didn’t they fight four beasts during that trial? There was a large white tiger… a turtle, a phoenix, and a snake…’

It all started coming back to him as he noticed a group of beasts sieging the large fortress in the distance. Many serpents were attacking with a huge one trying to constrict the walls from all sides. His people were manning the walls where large spirit cannons were placed. It all looked similar to the tower defense trial in the first expedition the Zhang Clan had to participate in.

‘Why would the Long Clan have something like this…’

He asked himself the question but soon realized that there wasn’t really any time to lose. The swarm of tiger beasts would reach this place soon and they were not the only ones. In the distance, he could see a black cloud but when using his enhanced vision to look closer he noticed a giant azure bird in the front. Around it were many smaller version that looked similar all covered in blue flames.

‘That only leaves out the turtles…’

There was only one direction that they could be coming from, there he only saw a large unsuspecting mountain. However, after his new realization, he paid attention to this rocky formation that seemed to rise up and then back down. It was not a naturally formed mountain nor a hill instead, it was something that was slowly moving towards the fortified castle.

‘Did that person actually recreate this strange area inside that secret ground he made? Was it to prepare me for it?’

Zhang Dong couldn’t be sure but it somehow made sense. His predecessor won it all and could ascend into the immortal realm at any time. He took his time to analyze the world here before finally succumbing to old age and moving on. His connection to the Long Clan was probable which begged the question. Did he have to watch out for something similar to the pride demon that had almost cost him his life, or would these four beasts be the only problem?

‘Not everyone is there… could it have multiple layers of traps and this is only the first one?’

He quickly took off as spiritual energy belonging to his sect members was present. They weren’t all there but at least, this was a start.

Chapter 693

“Grand Elder, the serpent is destroying the wall, it won’t hold!”

“Leave it to me!”

A massive snake with an azure pattern continued to constrict the fortress walls. Its body had wrapped itself around it multiple times as the body was not all that thick. Yet even when the thickness wasn’t much more than that of a regular tree, the scales could not be easily cut or damaged. Even when everyone was hacking and hitting the exposed parts, not more than scratches were being produced.

“It’s Elder Qiang!”

“Leave it to me!”

A large man with an even larger horned being behind it appeared. It was Huo Qiang and it was up to him to take care of this problem. In the absence of the other two great elders, he was not in the position of the leader. Instantly the temperature around the place increased as he went for the snake monster’s head.

“Come here you oversized noodle!”

A gigantic fist rained down onto the monster's body that continued to entangle the walls in hopes of breaking the protective formation. Various other smaller snakes jumped forth with venomous fangs aimed at Qiang’s throat. Before they could sink them in an absolute inferno blazed forth to burn them all to cinders. The elongated monster could not rely on its minions and opened up its large mouth from within which an azure flame appeared.

“You want to use flames against me? You must have a death wish!”

It was fire against fire as the sparks started flying. Crimson light collided with the azure as a hole was blown in the side of the fortress. The monster snake's head flew back after the collision. The fangs that were inside its mouth flew away as it could not take the hit filled with red flames.

“G-grand elder the wall!”

“Haha, take this you damn snake!”

Huo Qiang roared out as he descended upon the long beast. Even while the sect members screamed in horror he continued blasting a larger hole into the wall. The beast finally lessened its grip on the wall but the damage had already been done. Smaller serpents poured in the moment they were able and only now did the temporary leader realise what he had done.

“C-contain the snakes, don’t let them through the wall!”

“Ahh, quickly plug up the wall, activate the defensive formation!”

“I uh… Shouldn’t the others have died with it or something?”

The man in question scratched his forehead while looking at the dead snake. The massive size and elongated body started to get shorter but it didn’t stop the attack. He had tried thinking about Zhang Dong, his senior brother, and what he would do in such a situation. When the largest serpent appeared he assumed that with its defeat all would be over, to his surprise all the smaller snakes were still there and well.

It wasn’t over by a longshot and even a strange occurrence took place. The much smaller minions started attacking the now-dead body and biting into the flesh. Their smaller bodies started packing on some size as they began to engorge themselves in their leader's flesh and Qi. Now Huo Qiang realized that unless all of the snakes were destroyed, this wave would never end.

“Elder, more beasts are coming, we can barely hold them, what should we do?”

One of the other nascent soul elders called out from a distance. He was using all of his might to keep more snakes from getting through the hole Huo Qiang created. The other sect members were beginning over various construction materials in an attempt to reform the wall before it fully collapsed.

“Don’t worry! I have a plan!”

Huo Qiang called out with a lot of confidence while raising his index finger up into the air. The large ifrit soul beast behind mimicked his gesture and a massive orb of plasma started to form. Within a few moments, it looked like a miniature sun and it was bursting forth with flame energy.

“Grand elder, please wait, an attack of this size could…”

“I wait for no one!”

This attack was quickly then thrown at the charging group of snakes and created another huge explosion. It caused the whole fort to rock back and forth due to the ensuing earthquake. The flames engulfed the entire outside and caused all of the flora to go up in flames. While Huo Qiang cheered as he was able to destroy most of the pesky snakes, the castle walls were starting to crumble.

“The walls, they are collapsing!”

“Haha, what do we need walls for, all of the snakes are dead anyway, we don’t need to hide anymore…”

As Huo Qiang was about to cheer for his might winning over he noticed something in the distance.

“More beasts approaching, these ones are capable of flight… it’s a massive azure phoenix!”

It was a giant flock of bluebirds with one massive one in the front. The largest flagship their sect was capable of creating was not comparable in size to its thing. They all were coming in fast and due to the crumbling walls, the whole place was now wide open.

“Ahaha… L-leave that oversized chicken to this Huo Qiang, just repair the formation!”

“B-but there are still some snakes left outside and the flames are spreading inside.”

“Can’t you handle it by yourselves? They are just little flames…”

“But Grand Elder, it’s burning and weakening the formation, please contain your Qi!”

The attack that was produced was a double-edged sword as the flames continued to burn any living matter they came in contact with. The long snake beasts spread through the entire battlefield and some of them had even made it inside of the walls. To make things worse the giant snake body that had previously wrapped itself around the whole fort was also starting to burn up. If Huo Qiang charged into the distance and didn’t contain his technique better, then his people could actually burn to death.

“Damn, hold on, give me some time to think…”

Huo Qiang’s head started going red and his body exuded even more flames than before. His decision was important as it would dictate the flow of battle. If he remained within the fortress the flames could be contained easier and the formation would be repaired.

However, the flock of killed birds would surely reach the walls by that point and they would be left in an even worse spot than with the snakes. If he went for the birds instead, then maybe he would be able to hold them back the leader for a while. The smaller birds would be able to attack his sect members while they were trying to reform the formation and contend with the flames as well. It didn’t look good but he needed to make a decision before it was too late.

“Wait, what’s that?”

“What now, I’m trying to think!?”

“It’s coming from the other side… could it be?”

Something started approaching from another direction that looked like a giant mountain. When looking in closer the people discovered a vast quantity of large turtles moving at a moderate pace. All of them were gigantic but could not be compared to their leader that was larger than the whole fort they were protecting. However, this was not what everyone was looking at, instead, they noticed a golden ray of light shooting from the distance.

“This spiritual essence… it can only belong to one person.”

The golden surge of light flew forths and targeted the flying monster in the distance and as it was passing the fortress everyone noticed the man inside of the light. It was their leader that had gone missing within this strange formation.

“Tend to those flames Qiang, leave the birds to me then focus on the giant turtle.”

“Haha, senior brother, I knew you’d make it back!”

“You know me, I won’t go down that easily now focus on those flames before the whole place burns down, Qiang.”

“Of course!”

Huo Qiang started laughing as he saw his senior brother passing by. All the other sect members that were gathered here started cheering as their true leader was finally here. With him on their side there was nothing to fear, they just needed to focus on the task before them and he would guide them towards victory.

…

‘I don’t see gramps nor Liena among those people, they must be somewhere else…’

As Zhang Dong flew at the phoenix made from blue flames he started pondering about this place. It looked similar to the tower defense stage from the past. All the four beasts had appeared but their sizes and power eclipsed the ones in that secret ground. The ones back there were also not of the same elemental alignment of azure flames which these were part of. Two of them were not defeated but their minions still continued to push towards the eradication of his people.

‘First I needed to get a hold of this situation, I didn’t realize how bad Qiang was at leading…’

Before arriving he could see his junior brother cause the collapse of the defensive formation by himself. His techniques were quite volatile so he wasn’t the greatest ally to be next to during a large-scale battle. It was always better to use him as an attack hound and send him into the middle of an enemy army where he could cause more damage.

Giving him the task to attack the giant turtle would allow for the least collateral damage to their forces to occur. The monster was a mountain in itself so his explosive techniques could be utilized without a problem, the more damage he caused the better. Zhang Dong on the other hand was against flying foes that would not stand a chance.

His whole body produced a purple light that expanded in a sphere in all directions. The moment the flying beasts entered this zone they were instantly pulled down to the ground. His Dao of gravity was the best counter against flying creatures the didn’t use proper flying techniques but their wings to keep themselves afloat. The increase in weight was strong enough to destabilize their flight paths and bring them down to the ground. The only one that was not faltering was the leader but his movement had become sluggish.

“You’re not much stronger than that giant blue tiger, just give up before I’ll have to kill you.”

“CAW!”

“It was worth a try…”

The monster gave out a maddened roar as it looked at the tiny human covered in purple light. Zhang Dong attempted to reason with the beast but it didn’t seem to be anything more than a mindless puppet used by the strange place they were in. The only thing he could do now was to bring this thing down and then tend to the remaining blue tigers that were still approaching from the way he came.

“Well then, I can at least give you a quick death…”

He shouted while pulling out his sword and charging forth, a part of his troops was here but the search was not over yet. Zhang Jin and his wife were the two he was concerned about the most. After clearing things up here his search for them needed to continue.

Chapter 694

A continuous amount of explosions echoed through the air as the sound barrier was broken. These continuous blasts drowned out the screams of the massive flying creature that was receiving all of them. Its large body was soon parted into many smaller fragments that lit up in an azure haze. While it looked as if the monster bird’s body was gone it quickly changed into a ball of fire that sucked in the previously destroyed body parts.

“Like I’ll let you reform!”

Zhang Dong on the other side lifted up his finger to produce a giant ball of obsidian. A tremendous suction force was exuded from inside and it was quickly thrown at the beast bird that was going through a rebirthing technique. Part of its head was back in place but it was quickly pulled into the purplish darkness of the created technique.

The azure flames were getting sucked inside and the beast could not escape. Its light that was illuminating the sky just a moment ago was being extinguished by a combination of darkness and gravity. Many smaller birds flocked towards the larger one but they could offer no aid. Instead, they were getting yanked inside the gash in space that started quickly closing itself behind them.

“I don’t have time for you to go through multiple rebirths! Now, disappear!”

The Azure tiger went down after one slice from his sword, the serpent was burned by Huo Qiang’s ferocious flames and this bird was now the third that was eradicated. Its capabilities of rebirthing were well known as it was of the phoenix category. It would continue to reform itself until the last of its spiritual energy was extinguished. To hasten the process it was better to send the monster into a miniaturized black hole. He didn’t really know where it led to but it was a better choice than spending hours fighting this thing the conventional way.

‘That only leaves…’

After the large Azure Phoenix was gone the smaller minions didn’t pose much of a threat. They could be easily dispatched by his sect members that had a whole fortress defending them. The more important enemy was in the distance and was as big as a mountain. However, now it was turning into a gushing volcano after a meteor in the form of Huo Qiang collided with it.

‘I guess I don’t really need to help him with that one…’

A massive turtle with Azure patterns on its face was rampaging around while being burned. The forest area it was going through had turned to ash along with the smaller variants of its kind. These creatures had massive shells and hard hides that should have been able to resist most kinds of trauma, yet now they were just part of a massive pool of lava that turned them into a soup.

‘I’ll clear things up here then…’

Without needing to help Qiang in his fight he decided to take care of the small fry here. The beasts were unable to contend with a master of his caliber and continued to get eradicated rather quickly. Even though they had no chance of winning they continued to push forth until the last of them was gone.

‘They were clearly controlled by something, there is no survival instinct anywhere here.’

Zhang Dong hovered around the battle area that was drenched in beast blood. His people were able to leave the walls as no opposition remained. It was around an hour since he arrived here so the battle was won rather quickly. While this feat was remarkable he was no happy, his wife and grandfather were still missing and he needed to get some answers.

“We greet the Patriarch.”

“Explain the situation to me, where are the other elders? How did you come to this place?”

“Of course, let me, Patriarch.”

“Go ahead.”

Huo Qiang was still in the distance where he left a large sea of lava behind. One of the nascent soul elders that he helped push into the realm greeted him first instead. While it would normally be best to ask the person with the most evolved spirit sense about what transpired, it was hard to trust his friend's perception. This person before him was an older gentleman that had a whole lifetime of experiences as the grand elder of fire.

“As you wish. After the Patriarch was pulled in through the gate…

Zhang Dong was given the events that played out after he was dragged into the special chamber by the Azure Emperor. His people apparently started a quick debate about what they should do. His wife of course wanted to push in immediately without looking back. Zhang Jin managed to talk her down and they decided to send in a team of elites led by Zhang Zhi in first.

This didn’t go well as after he crossed through the gate all traces of him vanished. No one could reach him or see his location on the mapping devices. Bob was connected to a lot of software in the sect through which information could be forwarded. Yet after Zhang Dong was forced into the chamber the connection was broken.

After that, everyone started worrying even more. Two powerful elders from their sect had gone missing. Other sects might have decided to backtrack to conserve their forces but everyone decided against it. It seemed that no one believed that they would have much of a future if their Patriarch actually perished. Thus as a last-ditch effort and a gamble, they directed the Golden Palace through the gate.

What happened next confirmed his theory. The holy energy engine was disabled and after their protective formation was gone everyone was caught in a teleportation trap. All of the people that were here appeared in the middle of a large fortress. With people present that participated in the expedition to the old secret ground, they were able to build up some defenses. They were not given much time as soon after they were attacked from all sides by waves of monsters. Then Zhang Dong finally appeared to drive two of the boss monsters away while Qiang took care of the other two.

“So that’s what happened… and you probably have no idea where the others ended up?”

“My apologies Patriarch. This place is strange and its blocking our senses, our devices have also stopped responding.”

“I see…”

His army was equipped with some more modern devices that allowed them to usually talk through large distances. They also had something like a GPS inside of them to track the movements of their troops. Nothing was working at the moment so finding their lost sect members was not easy.

“Senior Brother, I knew that you would return!”

“It’s glad to see you Qiang but we can’t stay here, get everyone together we will move out and search for the sect.”

“Hah, I was waiting for that, this place has already become a bore.”

Zhang Dong was able to reestablish his connection to these people. It seemed that he needed to get in close proximity to the people from his sect for them to show up in his faction system. It was very reminiscent of the time in the pocket dimensions when he was hunting the Cerulean Empress.

‘This sucks, where am I supposed to go…’

While his people were packing up and gathering the injured he started looking around. This place was huge and it would probably take weeks to search through everything. It would probably be best if he ordered the nascent soul masters to fly out into different directions to gather more information instead of traveling together. The more eyes on the place the better the chances became of them finding their sect members.

‘Hey Bob, I know that you didn’t exist back then… but is it possible for you to access all data from within the mapping system before it was altered?’

‘Is it possible, which data would you like to access?’

‘Give me the layout of the secret ground I’ve visited and compare it to the place we are at now.’

Zhang Dong had visited the secret ground where his adventure had started. His AI companion Bob wasn’t there to help him tell the way. However, both of them visited the secret area later and he had mapped out the entire place. He needed to overlay the old path that he took with the matching terrain on his map to get to his destination. It took a bit but luckily everything lined up with the old secret ground.

‘So that’s how I went through it. If I backtrack then perhaps I can make it back to that tower with the sins.’

It was surprising to see that he was able to confirm the connection to the secret ground. This area was much larger but if he zoomed out with his map everything started lining up. It was as if this was the full version while the one back then was just a trial run. Considering that he found the tower defense part here, the other places that he visited back then would be there.

‘I should expect similar monsters to appear along the way, now what to do…’

While the paths aligned it didn’t mean that everyone would be in the trial tower where he fought the sin of pride demonic being. There was also a series of tunnels his clan members needed to go through and kill a side boss where they could have been transported to. It would probably be better to send someone there that had been through that area before.

Qiang had joined him in the battle against the sins so he somewhat knew what awaited him there. After witnessing the demise of the large turtle he came to a conclusion that it was probably better for him not to lead. His power was hard to contain and only he with a few other nascent soul masters in the sect would be able to survive all of that friendly fire.

“Qiang…”

“Yes, Senior brother? Have you decided?”

“Indeed, you will come with me and part of the warriors will head in that direction.”

The elder that explained the situation to him would be the temporary ladder. He looked at the spot Zhang Dong was pointing at and nodded.

“It shall be done my lord but should we take everyone? What about the injured?”

“They will return to the Golden Palace instead, I have the updated coordinates to the gate there.”

Everyone agreed without asking for an explanation. Part of the group would descend into the tunnels while the others took a break in the Golden Palace. Huo Qiang and Zhang Dong on the other hand would pay an old location a visit. With some luck, they would find all of their sect members at those two locations and then prepare their counter attack against the Long Clan.

Chapter 695

‘Wait, isn’t that the spot…’

“Is there something wrong, Senior Brother? Should I dispose of those creatures?”

“No, just leave them be, there isn’t anyone there.”

Zhang Dong along with Huo Qiang were looking at a large village made of wood. Inside of it, they spotted a variety of green creatures that resembled goblins and orcs. They were wandering around without doing much besides scratching their posteriors. His mind was drawn more to the scenery and a certain large chasm that he remembered from days long past.

‘It’s a lot wider than that one, I was barely able to jump over it that one time…’

He was taking on a trip down his memories. A certain woman was in a similar place more than ten years ago that he saved. At that time he did not realize how important she would become to his life and how much of an effect on it she would have. It was not the same place and this place was devoid of her presence so he decided to move on.

‘Let’s go, no one from our sect members was here…’

Their trip continued to old locations that were quite familiar yet different. The cave where Zhang Dong gave Liena first aid was there and nearby it was also an area filled with orcs where Qiang and his bodyguard were almost killed. It was similar to the spot they met and where their journey had started. After that, they set out to clear the secret grounds test which brought them towards a tower structure.

‘So it does exist here too…’

“Senior Brother, this looks almost the same.”

“Indeed but I can’t see any marks of people entering…”

After using his spirit sense he started analyzing the opening gate. He hoped to see some tracks or residual Qi leading inside that belonged to his wife, yet there wasn’t anything there. This place looked fishy but there was no way around it, they needed to check out the giant structure.

“Should we head inside? Do you want me to go in first, are the other sect members inside?”

“That is possible but…”

“But?”

“I think we should take another route…”

Zhang Dong had enough experience with these sorts of things to know that all of this was just some type of elaborate setup. Probably if he went inside, something that would hold back his progress would occur. The secret ground was built with this place as a basis so it was probable that there were similar traps they faced inside.

“Remember back then and what happened?”

“Hm… wait, wasn’t there a really hot sister in there?”

“Is that the only thing that you took away from there…”

“Was there anything else… I’m not sure…”

Huo Qiang started straining his brain but the only thing that he recalled was getting charmed by a succubus demon. She appeared on the first level and gave the group a headache, after the issue was resolved the group was sent into a safe zone. This safe area was what Zhang Dong was interested in. It was a giant library that to this day had become the largest treasure that he was given. If that tower was made to mimic this one, then perhaps many scriptures like those existed here as well.

“I was talking about the library area, just come with me we aren’t going to go through the main door directly, that will only slow us down.”

“Oh, a library! Now I remember!”

“I’m sure you do…”

‘Bob, are you finished with the scan, does this place have some backdoor that we can enter through instead?’

Zhang Dong was sure that this place had a connection with whoever made the system. After visiting the Cerulean Empress area and discovering another secret room, some interesting discoveries had been made. First of all, it was now possible for him to detect similar structures and hidden entrances. This whole place was probably tailor-made for anyone with the system to go through so the probability of such a room existing was there. If not, then perhaps a door to get through this tower was made by someone instead.

‘Entrance discovered… please wait, attempting to unlock …’

“Ha, I knew it!”

“What is it, Senior Brother? Did you find something?”

“Ah yes, something like that, just give me a moment…”

He didn’t really want to have Huo Qiang see anything related to the system but this was no time to keep secrets anymore. Enough time had passed in their relationship for trust to have been gained. His friend was also probably not intelligent enough to grasp the situation even if he tried to explain it in detail. Bob did his magic and soon a door in space started opening which gave Huo Qiang quite a jolt.
“What is this…”

“It’s our way inside, now try to keep up and watch your back, we don’t really know what we will find on the inside.”

“Of course!”

The door appeared on the side of this large tower made of stone that didn’t seem to have a limit. At first, it might have appeared to have been an illusion brought on by the formation this place was empowered by. Zhang Dong wasn’t sure if this was the case as they were reaching into buildings created by immortal bearings. It wouldn’t be strange that they went above the possibilities of the inhabitants of this world.

While passing through the unsuspecting entrance they ended up in a white tunnel. Strangely enough, everything here was reminiscent of a hospital corridor. On the sides, there were other closed doors with named plates on each one. This place was something like a hub between levels of this large tower. Judging by the sheer length of this corridor this place was several times larger than the one at the secret ground.

‘So is anyone of our sect members behind this door…’

After glancing at the first door he decided not to open it yet. It would be quite a bother to have to go through each and every one of these. There were limits to what Bob was capable of and it also took a lot of spirit points to run his hacking skills. Instead of going through every one of these trial floors, it would be better to find one that connected them together.

‘I need to either find the master control room or this place’s version of the library.’

In the past, they were forced to battle monsters or go through puzzles. After completing each one they were then allowed access to a temporary safe haven, a large library filled with books. If this place worked on the same concepts then anyone in the area would wind up in the library. With some luck, they would be able to meet that group already in there or just wait a bit until they completed a challenge.

‘Even if they aren’t there, it’s still better to go there first to check.’

“Follow me and don’t open any of the doors.”

“If you wish, Senior Brother but…”

“Is there something?”

“Hmm… do you perhaps know these strange words? They don’t seem like anything I’ve ever seen… and they are also shifting around in meaning, is it under some type of illusory technique?”

“Illusory technique, what are you talking about? The words aren’t moving around.”

“They aren’t? Perhaps my mind is not as strong as Senior Brother’s to see through the technique…”

He was confused at first but then realized that there was something keeping a denizen of this world from identifying the writing. Huo Qiang was born in this world and even his soul belonged to it. It was possible that different rules applied to the people born in this world. For him that came from another world the words on the plaques were in plain and simple English.

There had to be some type of mental block not allowing Huo Qiang from perceiving even the letters as words. The only worrisome part about it was that it could be applied to his soul as well. He didn’t even want to think about the possibility of his own people being controlled by an angry god, even worse if his children were affected as well. Their mother Liena was like Qiang here, born in this world. However, perhaps his unique deposition would at least allow his own children to be immune to the effect.

While some stray thoughts entered his mind he continued to pass through many of the doors. They all had numbers assigned to them as well as some words. The first set had jungle areas written on them that started with one and ended with ten. There seemed to be variants with sub-letters like ‘A’ and ‘B’.

‘B and A? It seems that this place is a lot more complicated than the ones we were in before. It probably means that there are several ways of going through the tower floors and probably some are easier than others.’

He was not really interested in defeating the beast or monsters that were probably patrolling this tower. His system didn’t give him any spirit points for killing them, instead, it was focused on his entire faction. It was better to find his people and just get out of here before the Long Clan found them all.

‘What are those guys up to anyway? Could it be that they can’t enter this place at leisure?’

As he was trying to find the door to the library he started wondering about his true enemy, the Long Clan. If his people were trapped in this large place, wouldn’t it be easier to just swarm them with their masters? Were they just waiting for the monsters inside of this place to soften them up before making their move, or was it possible that they actually couldn’t enter this place themselves?

‘They probably have no control of this place either, so if they just come in, they will have to contend with the swarm of beasts and monsters. That would be nice if it was the case but I can’t make a decision based on a hunch, for all I know Long Qing could be watching us from outside…’

His brother was a bit too much to handle with that sword of his and was better avoided. If he was waiting to spring out while Zhang Dong was injured had to be taken into account. However, while he was in this side area only allowed to people not from this world, there was probably nothing to worry from the Azure Emperor.

‘I hope that overseer won’t find me out though, I’ve been taking a lot of chances lately… anyway, I think this should be it…’

Finally, he ended up at a white door with a resting area plaque written over it. Perhaps it was not the same library that he remembered but if things were the same, it was possible that the people from his sect were waiting for him on the inside.

Chapter 696

“This is… different.”

“Senior Brother, is this some kind of high-class resort? The water here could be considered to be a tonic and that food…”

“Qiang… don’t eat that.”

“I wasn’t about to…”

“Then why are you holding that spirit chicken drumstick?”

“I’m not…oh but what about this, the water feels warm…”

“Could you not…”

Huo Qiang dropped a roasted chicken piece that looked to be filled with spiritual energy. It had been laid out on a large dining table with various other delicacies. There were salads made from various vegetables filled with massive amounts of spiritual energy. Dishes that most people could only dream about and not even found in the Long Clan’s kitchen were all here.

This wasn’t the end as soon after dropping the food Qiang was pulled towards a bathing area. It consisted of many pools filled to the brim with regenerative liquid. The Zhang Clan was considered quite knowledgeable when it came to regeneration via liquids. By drenching one's body in any of these baths, they would regain all of their spiritual energy within minutes and all their wounds would be healed.

“Oh, what is this strange contraption, Senior Brother! It looks like there is space to put something in!”

“It looks like a vending machine, you probably need some coins or tokens to use it.”

“Coins? Darn, I don’t think I have any… but that colorful thing looks intriguing…”

Another strange thing was not far away from the bathing area. It was a large lounge with a large vending machine in the middle. There were some snacks inside as well as drinks in cans. While he had brought a lot of modern things into this world, vending machines were not one of them. After having a go around this place it was clear that someone from a place similar to his home world had created everything here.

‘This looks like some kind of spa resort… there is even a large swimming pool, it’s not what I expected to find.’

Zhang Dong expected to encounter a library area with books and maybe some clues but he was given something else. It was a giant resting area inside what looked to be a closed-off hotel. There were no windows or sky that he could see which made some sense. This area was probably just a resting area for people to temporarily inhabit. After passing a floor in the tower people probably ended up here to rest.

There was a lot of food and regenerative liquids to cure even serious injuries and the things inside the vending machine were also special. They looked like consumable items that a person could probably take away from this place. If everything here followed the usual gaming rules. Then people that went through the tower earned some currency that could be spent in the vending machine.

Then there were also closed-off areas with slots for that currency. One of them had ‘Training Area’ written above it. This place was some type of trial tower that allowed people to get stronger by going through the levels. Either it was a testing area or something to get people up in power. It wasn’t strange that a lesser copy was included in the secret ground as the basics were quite similar.

‘Maybe there is an actual library somewhere here but I’m not here to get stronger.’

While these facilities looked to be state of the art they wouldn’t allow him to get any stronger. They seemed to be able to push nascent soul masters a bit higher or help core formation practitioners get through that last hurdle. He assumed that this place had its limitations but why the Long Clan left it here for everyone to enter was somewhat strange. It was possible for their enemy to enter weak and exit stronger than before which would be counterintuitive.

‘Probably another scenario point to help any system holders to get stronger if the need arose…’

His assessment of the situation was simple. People were forced to go through the levels and after finishing up they would be taken here. However, there were no signs of life anywhere and the food had been untouched. It was possible that the people from his sect were in the tower but had perhaps not reached the required floor. Perhaps it was different than the one in the secret ground that allowed them back each time they defeated one of the bosses.

‘Maybe you need to get through multiple levels? The tower is much larger so it makes some sense…’

His senses weren’t picking up any residual Qi left over by anyone but this didn’t mean anything yet. Before he could make a decision he needed Bob to run a few tests. They had gone into this area through unorthodox means. It was not yet obvious where they needed to head out to find their sect members. There was a possibility of others arriving after they left and sometimes backtracking was impossible.

‘Bob, is there an exit or some type of hidden console that we can access? If this was made as a trial then a control room should be somewhere…’

‘Affirmative’

While he was scrolling through his faction window he tried focusing on the more prominent members of his sect like his wife and grandfather that came with him. None of them were showing up but the people that he did encounter apparently had some luck. They did come across some signs of life in the underground tunnels and were now trying to find the people that they belonged to.

“Senior Brother, what are you looking at?”

“Ah, nothing… the food is fine, you can eat it if you want but don’t overdo it, I’ll go look around this place, recover your stamina while I’m gone.”

“You don’t have to tell me twice!”

Huo Qiang lost a lot of spiritual energy when he fought the large Azure Turtle and Snake. The food and recovery bath here would allow him to restore himself back to full strength in around half an hour. This would be enough time for Zhang Dong to go through he entire large hotel and perhaps figure out what he was working with.

‘So, this is the living area, the rooms seem to be divided as well…’

The first thing he came across was a set of floors with rooms. The ones on the bottom one were open while the upper area required coins. The free ones were rather small and similar to a dorm room without much inside, just the basic necessities without anything. It became clear that this place was supposed to house a large group of individuals for a long time.

‘It doesn’t fit the aesthetic too much though, could this have been some kind of prototype that wasn’t used?’

Nothing really fit this world’s Eastern aesthetic. Everything was more western and even the hotel reminded him of luxury ones from his old home. It didn’t make sense that this was here as it would be too obvious. The secret ground that he previously visited must have been to a finished product that was altered to fit this world.

‘Why would they need a prototype, could it have been used in another era or something?’

There were a lot of things floating through his head but he couldn’t really make sense of anything. Before he received an even bigger headache, Bob finally finished scanning and pointed him at an unsuspecting wall. The location was strange as it was inside a large bathing area. Above there were many shower heads that could be activated by simply pushing a button on the side.

‘So it’s this one… could the one that designed this have been a pervert?’

The hidden wall started sliding up as a secret room was revealed. The large shower room was on the female side which made this reveal somewhat uncomfortable. When entering inside and looking behind himself he could easily see the whole large bathing area with the showerheads. Any person that was inside this space would be able to easily see anyone showering and they would have no idea.

After arriving inside he saw a similar setup with screens and computers. They were in much better shape than in the room he found at the secret ground. There was even power running through the cables and a few of the screens were flickering.

‘Bob see if you can connect to these.’

While his AI went to work he turned around and began wondering about the reason for this place's existence. He could only imagine someone immature placing such a room in an area like this but it also gave him some hope. Would some ancient godlike being create such an environment for people to go through?

‘Probably not, someone immature like Wang Long is more likely but if it was someone with the same character flaws, then this could be disastrous…’

If the godlike being that ruled over them all was someone like Wang Long, then his efforts could be in vain. However, this realization wasn’t all bad as it also brought something else to the forefront. This place looked to have been created by someone from an earth-like place. It meant that they had at least at some point probably been a regular normal human. It was one thing to go against a true god and another if he was just against another person.

‘Perhaps this was a testing ground for previous system holders like me? Or another scenario like in the world of magic but why would it still be here? Was it not supposed to be found or something?’

He was not sure why this place existed in this Long Clan formation but perhaps it had something to do with him messing with the main scenario. He had defeated the other Emperors in record speed and even forced the Long Clan to act against him. They were supposed to be his allies and perhaps this defensive formation was never to be triggered in the first place.

‘I can speculate all I want, I should focus on the monitors.’

Bob had managed to access the system and the monitors started lighting up. They were divided into smaller squares that allowed him to look through this large hotel. In one of them, he could see Huo Qiang dozing off in the warm regenerative waters, seemingly without a worry in the world.

‘Can you show me something outside of this place? It should link to the other floors.’

Bob continued to go through the consoles and finally, after around fifteen minutes something was triggered. One of the monitors presented him with a familiar face that looked to be in a bit of a bind.

‘Shit, that doesn’t look good but how do I get there? Bob, help me out here!’

His mind raced as he could see several people from his sect running away from a bunch of monstrosities. If something wasn’t done, then their lives would surely be at risk.

Chapter 697

“Elder, what should we do? There are too many beasts for everyone to handle.”

“Keep them back as long as the Matriarch can vanquish the leader this trial should end.”

“But we won’t last for much longer…”

“You must!”

“But we have so many injured we can’t… huh what’s that glow?”

Before the man could finish the sentence a strange glow appeared in the middle of the battlefield. It looked like a soap bubble that continued to increase in size before taking on the shape of a blue orb. This orb started to pulsate rapidly and the faster it got the more spiritual energy the members from the Unlimited Element Sect could sense.

Some of them recoiled in fear as it looked to be some type of trap. The amount of energy that was gathering was possibly a prelude to an explosion. One of the elders held up a talisman and started chanting as he quickly attempted to place a small defensive formation around this glowing orb. Yet, the explosion never came and instead, a golden pill popped out from within the blue orb.

“Is that… a recovery pill?”

The man that created the small formation that looked like an octagon continued to stare as more and more of those pills were created. Soon the whole bottom portion of the octagon was filled out with round pills that could be used to recover energy as well as health.

“Those pills, can’t we use them on the injured?”

“They do look safe… let me just examine them.”

It was a critical juncture in their battle as many creatures were pushing from all sides. In the distance, there was a giant beast that their strongest elder was clashing with. It was a devastating one-on-one battle. Everyone else was gathered here to keep the unending waves of smaller monstrosities from reaching their elder and attacking her back.

There was no end to them as they continued to pure in from all sides. The group found themselves in this strange place after activating the teleportation trap. Most of them were reputable elders of core formation and up but in this place, they felt like newbies. Most of the monsters were at least at their level with many being at the nascent soul realm.

Only thanks to a handful of nascent soul elders having been taken away with them were they able to survive for this long. Zhang Liena along with Zhang Zhi were both here but even they were having some trouble with the gigantic monster that looked like an ice dragon. Its element countered Zhang Zhi’s water techniques which continued to freeze over and the winds that Zhang Liena produced just made the entire area even colder.

The place they were in was a desolate world of ice and rock. What they were fighting were creatures attuned to ice spiritual energy. Ice stemmed from the water and was more specialized in its usage. It was susceptible to fire that melted it but required a difference in power to work. Perhaps if Huo Qiang was here instead of the two other elders the ice dragon they were battling would stand no chance. As it stood now though, the battle was dragging on and they were getting overrun. The longer it took to defeat the beast the more of these beasts would continue to appear.

Everyone here knew this to be true as it followed the pattern they experienced on other floors. At first, everyone appeared at an empty plain with not much around it. Later they started traveling toward an obvious monument. From nearby a massive behemoth arose that was easily dispatched by the elders and soon stairs appeared.

The process was repeated as they encountered more similar beasts and varied locations. Once they were put into a forest, other times into a swamp or even a fortress made of stone and strange metallic monsters that looked like armor. Each time they had to find the strongest beast before the stairs appeared but this was a trap that they didn’t realize until they arrived here.

Their leader, Zhang Liena was clearly in a rush as she continued to push everyone to push on. Rushing was however a big mistake as people noticed that the monsters they defeated were special. After their death, their bodies would vanish and leave behind various items. They seemed to be random in their worth and type. Sometimes it would be a pill while other times a weapon. Other times even strange maps showed hidden areas with apparently more treasures.

These were regretfully mostly ignored by the main two elders that agreed that they needed to get out of this place. They assumed that after defeating enough enemies the strange trials would end. It was similar to some other secret grounds created by immortals which some people from this group had experience in going through. They prioritized getting through the traps and areas over exploration, this was a mistake.

Remembering the previous level which was close to a volcano they now realized. Some of the monsters when killed dropped pills that aided in protection against the ice. Some of them even produced weapons that could easily dispatch the creatures they were facing. If they just stayed there for some time and defeated these beasts that continued to respawn, they would have been able to get through this ice area easily.

Instead, they triggered some type of trap which caused an endless wave of ice creatures to come after them. They were all on a large mountain range with a massive dragon above them that was comparable to Bahamut in size. It was surrounded by many ice wyverns and other monstrosities on the mountain. While Zhang Zhi was trying to contend with the flying mobs, Zhang Liena continued to battle the dragon creature. Its hide was extremely hard, it would take her some time to defeat it, time that the people down below didn’t have. Their people were suffering injuries from which they couldn’t easily recover, this was until the pills just appeared out of thin air.

“Is it safe to eat those? Could it have been some secret treasure?”
“We don’t have the leisure to ignore them…”

The elder that was producing the octagonal barrier removed his technique to look over the pills. After touching one he could not find any faults but only boons. It wasn’t a simple recovery pill, it was one that also had a lot of fire energies hidden inside of it. For a moment he hesitated in handing them over to the medical team but with their own pill reserves running short, there was nothing left for them to wait for.

“I’ll take it.”

“Are you sure? If this has some unforeseen side effects…”

“I’m practically a dead man already, if this won’t help him then I’ll just die anyway… if you manage to get through this, please tell my son that his father died with honor.”

“... I will…”

The most injured person called out to the worrying elders. A large ice spear was sticking through his abdomen and he was bleeding out. There was not much that anyone could do in this situation so he decided to risk his life to see if these pills could save his life. After coming over and placing one of them into his mouth the other sect members started praying.

Almost instantly the injured man could feel the pill dissolving in his mouth. The effect was quite visible as his entire body started glowing red and releasing steam. First, the wound that was pierced by the spear started bubbling as if the man’s blood around it was boiling. In a matter of moments, the ice around the wound melted and broke off. Everyone marveled at the display of hyper-healing as the wound was closing up. In under a minute it was over and the man opened up his eyes.

“I… I feel great!”

“Junior, are you really okay?”

“I am… all the pain is gone… and I feel rather warm…”

The elder that presented him with the miraculous pill started looking over the man that was even able to stand up. The ice spear went through his lower abdomen and came out from the other side. Where the wound would be there was nothing more than scarred flesh. The hole that should be there had been closed off and no blood was leaking. It even seemed that the man had regained all of his vitality without needing a secondary blood pill to substitute all the blood that was lost.

“It doesn’t seem to have any side effects, I can’t feel any poison or demonic energies either. Give it to the injured!”

“Yes, Elder!”

Soon the pills were getting given out to each and every injured person. It was a miracle drug that was even able to heal a nascent soul master and restore most of their used spiritual energy. With this boost in recovery, they were finally able to push the swarm of creatures back. The sect Matriarch was finally given enough time to face her opponent. Thanks to the miracle pill's appearance the tide had shifted.

“Die you overgrown lizard!”

Zhang Liena launched a massive blade of wind at the dragon’s elongated neck. Its hide was covered in hundreds of small cuts with the largest concentration of them being close to the neck. Finally, the wind technique connected with the weakened spot and caused the dragon’s head to fly up into the air. There it was shredded by the cyclone the large monster was already surrounded by and finally, the creature was dead.

“The monsters, they are fleeing!”

“The Matriarch killed their leader! Long live the Matriarch!”

The people down on the ground started cheering while looking up to their current leader. Liena was floating above without any wounds to her body. The monster was far too slow to produce any type of wound. Its defensive attribute of ice prevailed throughout the whole battle and the mass of minions was the problematic part. After the sect forces managed to get a handle on them, she could finally focus on the battle without worrying.

She landed down on the ground, right where the strange orb of light appeared. There was something about the spiritual energy that this thing gave out that reminded her of someone that she was looking for. Her spirit sense homed in on this energy signature as she continued to check. Within a moment a smile appeared on her face as she made the realization that her husband was nearby.

“Matriarch, a large staircase has appeared, what are we going to leave?”

Before she could make the decision another light appeared to the side. It had the same Qi pattern as the previous orb and without even batting an eye she decided to follow after it.

Chapter 698

“That was a close one.”

Zhang Dong leaned back in the chair that was still present in this strange room. On the screen, he could see the massive ice dragon’s head flying through the air after being severed by his wife. Thanks to Bob and his system he was able to figure out how this room worked. It was possible for him to alter the levels by sending over some gifts or giving pointers.

‘This feels like someone created a game for themselves.’

When he was getting used to the controls and possible things he could do, a strange feeling washed over him. It was as if someone was treating the struggle of people taking part in the tower like a strategy game. Whoever was in here could hand out items and even change the difficulty. Only a bit later he discovered that he could lessen the number of beasts that were appearing.

Everything was on the highest difficulty which made even the tenth level of this tower a struggle. He started thinking if this was left here like this on purpose or if the person that used it as a game just got bored and left. The whole thing was devoid of life with only monsters created from formations remaining. They were all generated by spiritual energy and would vanish into a mass of light particles after being defeated.

Even the huge dragon Liena killed was in the process of vanishing. Now that he turned down the difficulty it even dropped some better equipment. The only downside was that these items created in this space were limited to it. There was some kind of domain residing over this whole place that could alter reality to suit the game’s experience. Perhaps it was a grand formation that he couldn’t grasp yet as it was at the level of immortals. Nevertheless, it left a bad taste in his mouth when he imagined that someone had been here playing with other people's lives.

‘I guess a godlike being would see people as NPCs, I hope that I’m wrong though…’

While thinking about the worst possible future outcome he looked back to the monitor screens. For some reason, the person that created this whole setup gave multiple types of access to it. Bob was only able to log him in as a guest user that had limited functions. There was now a possibility that there had been more than one person in this room at some point. Perhaps there were other past immortals playing around with people as if it was a game. This explained why he could only fiddle around with a minimal amount of settings without being able to just open a path to this area.

‘The tower has a hundred levels but if they get to the 25th one they will be able to access this resting area.’

His previous assumption was that the participants would be able to enter the area he was occupying with Huo Qiang after completing ten floors. Perhaps it was due to the harder setting but another fifteen waited for Liena’s group before they came here. Thanks to Bob he could see every option that was allowed. Without shifting the setting the group of cultivators probably wouldn’t have stood a chance as this place seemed to be meant for stronger people.

‘If I go by the description, the more people there are the harder it gets. They would have no chance reaching the higher floors with so many core formation experts among them but perhaps this could be used to our advantage…’

Besides Liena and Zhang Zhi there were six other nascent soul masters with them. The rest was composed of around two hundred core formation experts. These he had inside of his faction system and some that were in the early stage had managed to advance into the middle ones. Defeating monsters in this tower area acted in a similar way to his old system. Some of the spiritual energy would make it into the people that took part in killing it. He was able to confirm this after Liena killed the dragon and some of its Qi made it into her dantian.

‘This place might have been used to progress people through the realms faster, like a tutorial before the real thing but why is it so hard?’

Zhang Dong could see that the beasts and trials inside were becoming hard even on the nascent soul masters. Liena was in the middle stage but with the help of her immortal grade cultivation technique she was much stronger than a regular master at this realm. Considering that the nascent soul was the limit of this world it shouldn’t have been hard for them at all.

The last boss should be a great circle nascent soul monster that should have been manageable. It made more sense if they continued to level up and actually managed to get past the limitations of this realm. If they continued like this, then soon enough not even the masters there would be able to contend with the boss monsters.

‘Could this place have been created before the limit was set in place? Am I in some type of Alpha test of this world?’

He had no idea of knowing how old this tower was. There were strange energy fluctuations involving the Dao of Time. After dipping his toes in its mysteries he was at least able to identify the pattern. It was possible for this tower to be hundreds of thousands of years old, perhaps even millions.

‘Perhaps the last boss is a creature at a higher realm than a nascent soul master? It would be best to get them out of there as fast as possible but…’

There was one good thing that emerged from this fiasco, the sect members that were trapped inside there were able to quickly progress their realms. If things continued like this then perhaps some of the core formation experts would be able to transcend to the next level. Thanks to his faction window he could see a few people that were slowly edging over that barrier.

‘Would have been nice to find this place earlier, will the Long Clan and that Overseer let us just train here in peace?’

When looking at the bigger picture it wouldn’t be outlandish to take this opportunity to level up. Both Zhang Zhi and Liena would perhaps be able to reach the late stage if they continued on their path. There were training facilities in this rest area which would also allow people to get stronger and Huo Qiang could use them before they leave.

‘I’ll think about it after they are safe, for now, let me focus on this game…’

Zhang Dong went back to looking at the screen and the prompts. He had a main resource that was oddly enough named the same, spirit points. The people inside of the testing region were gaining this resource for him and he could use it to help them out. Before he spent them on a large amount of recovery pills and to guide them towards the exit. Now he was using them to point his people in the right direction.

‘They can’t keep skipping the grind areas and secret treasures, if this continues I’ll run out of resources in just a few floors.’

Liena was now on the eleventh floor. This area was covered in small islands and a lot of water. Thankfully the group that was here were all veterans of the Cerulean Empress expedition and had also fought in the ocean. It would not be hard for them to defeat the underwater creatures that tried to halt them from reaching the other islands.

The stage started out with them being given a simple raft but each island they visited allowed them to upgrade it to something better. There were many hidden treasure chests along with monsters hidden away in the tropical forest areas inside. For some reason, the flight technique of every nascent soul master was severely limited and would not allow them to use it outside of the islands. Whenever they attempted a huge storm would befall them along with many sea creatures spawning to hinder their travels.

Zhang Dong identified this as a chance to get stronger as the monsters that were being spawned weren’t all that difficult to kill but dropped a lot of items. The slower they took to cross the sea the more rewards they were given before arriving at the next island. Thanks to his guiding orb he was able to somewhat communicate with his sect members. They learned to trust the light which led them to many previously ignored treasures.

While he was helping his sect members through the tasks there was one thing that he noticed. When looking at a side screen where Huo Qiang was resting, there was no noticeable change. He continued to sit back in one of the pools of water which made him exit this room. After arriving at the bathing area he measured the spiritual energy of his friend that had not recovered by much.

“Oh, you are back already Senior Brother? Did you find some clues?”

“Yeah, something like that, by the way, how long was I gone for?”

“Oh, I don’t know… about ten minutes?”

“Only that much?”

“Is there something wrong?”

“No, just keep recovering your energy and after you are finish you could try visiting one of those training chambers, the energies there will help you gain some insight into your powers.”

“I can gain some insights?”

Huo Qiang was surprised by the offer but didn’t argue with his senior brother as he knew that it had to be the truth. Zhang Dong on the other hand returned back to the room he left to discover that a lot more time had passed than he anticipated. It was clear that there was some type of time-dilation thing going on between the two areas.

‘There were half done with the floor but now they are already facing the boss?’

The tower floors were small pocket dimensions that required hours and even days to get through. Thanks to this time change they weren’t losing that much time and instead reaching new heights at a rapid pace. This was to the point of Zhang Dong wishing that he was there with them. If they could absorb the energy of monsters then he would probably also be able to. For someone like him that wanted to get as strong as he could before the confrontation with the Azure Emperor, it would have been a good chance.

‘I could use that tunnel to go where they are and join them… but that would just scale the difficulty even higher.’

There was a way for him to join them but it would potentially put them in some danger. They would also lose his guiding orb and the help that he could provide from this room. Perhaps if he wanted to join them on their adventure it was better to just wait for them to get here before making a decision…

Chapter 699

“Surround him, use the net, keep him from running away!”

“There is no place to run now bastard!”

A strange-looking gelatinous creature with a giant toothy skull inside its body was trying to squeeze through a constricting net made of metal. The body was attempting to squeeze through the gaps but a surprisingly sturdy thin energy filament kept it from escaping. Above in the air, a group of nascent soul masters were completing a grand technique that produced crackling lightning.

“It won’t last for much longer, give it your all, we must destroy that core!”

The monster continued to struggle but instead of trying to slip through the spaces in the net, it started to expand its gelatinous body. Inside it, there were several red orbs that were constantly moving around. To defeat this boss monster they had to identify the true core and destroy it. If not the creature would keep regenerating its body with no end.

Something like this was easier said than done. There were hundreds of fake cores swimming around the large translucent body which was quite toxic. If anyone attempted to place their limb into the gooey body, it would instantly dissolve it. Even their weapons like spears quickly corroded before being able to do much damage to the core.

The only way of destroying this monster would be by either identifying the true core and destroying it before the weapon gave out. The United Element Sect elders decided to go with a second option by bathing this monster in divine lightning. A strong enough technique that could devastate the creature’s entire body would also do the trick.

Everyone here had fought bravely and even suffered acidic wounds from luring the monster in. It was different from all the other strange things and trials that they had all faced here. Without the help of this net and other items that the glowing orb led them to, most of them would have already been dead.

The skies rumbled as all the nascent soul masters focused on the grand formation they created. Soon a massive surge of energy flew towards that silvery net that was able to contain the monster in one place. Thanks to some strange attributes on the net the electrical energy was equally distributed through the whole monster. Soon the people could see all the cores bursting like overfilled balloons and filling out the gelatinous monster’s body with a red pigment.

“The fake cores are bursting, don’t let up!”

A high-pitched screech escaped from the monster’s skull head as it continued to try to squeeze itself out of the net. It was not letting itself be killed by this wide-area attack and started focusing on one point of the electrified net. The skull shot upwards in a last-ditch effort of freeing itself and after slamming into the metallic barrier it was able to burst through it.

“It's heading for the elders, watch out!”
The people that were down on the ground called out while watching the skull heading up in the direction of the nascent soul masters. The creature had probably identified the sect matriarch that was the focal point of the formation as the main enemy. However, this was not enough to shock the experience group of cultivators anymore. Zhang Liena opened up her eyes and utilized one of her wind techniques to intercept the monster’s ascent.

“Zhang Zhi, the true core is inside of that skull, destroy it.”

“Yes, Matriarch!”

It was pushed back by a burst of green wind energy and put itself in a bad situation. Due to the wide-area electrical field, it was put in, the monster was forced to do something drastic. It abandoned most of its body and just surrounded its skull head with a more concentrated sludge. Inside it was the last core that didn’t have any space to move around.

Zhang Zhi shot out toward this monster that was momentarily halted. His blade remained in his hilt that was hovering right next to his hip. The creature opened up its mouth to reveal a plethora of shark-like teeth. The skull was a lot larger than a human and it could devour Zhang Zhi in one gulp if he failed in his attack.

Suddenly just as Zhang Zhi was about to get devoured by the massive skeletal head, his body turned to water. The monster chomped down hard but it only damaged its own jaw with that ferocity. Instead of a man, it got a mouth full of water that impeded its view for a fraction of a second. This was all the time that this swordmaster needed to deliver a thousand cuts, shredding the skeletal body into many tiny pieces.

Even if the core was still swimming around inside the monster’s cranium it was unable to contend with the mass of sword energy. The monster’s body started crumbling into many tiny even slices of bones before exploding into a red mist. With this the boss was dead and everyone could breathe out in relief.

“It’s over!”

“Elder Zhi did it!’

Everyone started cheering while the monster’s body disintegrated into a million tiny wisps of energy. This energy started making its way into the bodies of each and every cultivator here. They could feel a massive boost of energy coming over them and some were even ready to make the push towards a new realm.

The net that they used to trap the monster dropped to the ground and lost all of its luster. Within it, a bright glow appeared that everyone here already knew. Soon from within the light an item appeared, it was a long spear with a jagged tip. It was green and looked to possess some poisonous affinities.

“Get ready everyone, we have some time to rest before the exit appears, use it to recover your stamina and Qi! Gather up all the items, herbs, and anything that could be useful!”

One of the elders that took part in creating the large heavenly lightning formation floated down to give out some orders. The pattern of this secret ground was already known to them. After thirty minutes of defeating a boss, an exit would be created. They had then around ten minutes to get through it or be left behind in this place. One time they had almost lost one of their sect brothers that was slow in passing through.

“Wait… something is wrong… it's opening too soon, everyone, pick up your weapons! This might not be over yet!”

To everyone’s surprise, the path to the next level appeared a lot sooner than before. A regular-looking double door appeared in the air with a set of stairs made up of white light heading up to it. Previously what was presented to them was usually not as eventful, a simple blue portal down next to the strongest creature in a given tower level.

“What should we do? Could it have been the last beast?”

The group looked at the snow-white door that wasn’t opening but looked quite inviting. Before anyone here made a decision they looked at the orb of light that had helped them out throughout their adventures. Previously fake portals had appeared and the orb had reacted by glowing red to warn them. However, this time around the orb started floating towards the stairs and started quickly flying up.

“Does it want us to follow inside? It must be safe.”

Zhang Liena moved towards the orb while the other sect members followed after. No one really knew what would happen but the blue orb had allowed them to pass through many tiresome trials and they had learned to trust it. For some reason, there was something familiar about it but no one could really describe it with words. Only after the door started to open by itself did the people realize that this orb had been sent out by someone that they knew very well.

“I see that you all managed to get through it, welcome back.”

Without anyone's input, the path ahead started opening and a figure appeared from within. He did not cross through the threshold but his face was one that everyone knew. Those snow white hair and handsome features were plastered all over the United Element Sect, it was their patriarch, Zhang Dong.

“W-we greet the Patriarch!”

Everyone besides Zhang Liena clasped their hands together while bowling. The orb of light that was their helper flew toward their Patriarch and settled down on his shoulder before quickly vanishing afterward.

“You’re not an illusion.”

“I hope not, I wouldn’t be able to give you a hug if I was one.”

He reached out with his hand and Liena hesitated. There were traps and techniques that could impersonate loved ones. They usually lured in people like her that longed to see their family again. At their lowest, they would present them with what they were searching for and sometimes it would mean death. Her eyes quickly went over the mannerisms of this Zhang Dong and she could not see it as anyone else but her husband.

“Don’t worry I’m not an illusion but I can’t really get through this barrier either. You’ll have to step inside, there aren’t any more beasts inside.”

The man pressed his palm against the empty air in the door to show off that there was some kind of invisible barrier that he couldn’t cross. Liena slowly pushed her hand forward and was able to stick her hand through the threshold of this door. Soon her palm made its way to Zhang Dong’s cheek.

“It is really you, husband.”

“Of course, now get over here.”

He pulled her inside and their bodies touched, the fear of this all being an illusion evaporated. Liena could tell the soul of her husband from anything else thanks to their close relationship. Soon the two were leaning against each other, his arms were around her waist while hers were around his shoulders. The two embraced in silence as the other sect members watched without uttering a word.

“We should probably call over the juniors, this door won’t stay open forever.”

“Why did you have to ruin it…”

Liena puffed up her cheeks like a little pouty child after Zhang Dong whispered into her ear. The troubles all of them were facing weren’t over yet. The Long Clan was still after them and not everyone was assembled. Zhang Zhi and Liena were here but Zhang Jin was still missing. He was not in this trial tower so perhaps he remained in the other area where his sect members went to explore. Going by the number of people here, there were still a lot of missing people from his sect that needed to be rescued, time was of the essence.

Chapter 700

“What is this place?”

“Welcome Madam, why don’t you come in and have something to eat… before Huo Qiang devours it all that is…”

“Huh?”

Zhang Liena was guided inside the hotel area she was now able to access after defeating the boss on the twenty-fifth floor. The other members from the sect started pouring in behind her and quickly filling up the lounging area. There were over a hundred people in this large party and some of them were actually able to push into the nascent soul realm. The only reason that they couldn’t was due to the hectic trip through the tower floors. Now that they were in a resting area, it was possible to use one of the rooms to push into the next level that required time, silence, and concentration.

“It’s true I haven’t eaten in a while and those spirit grain pellets aren’t too tasty…”

Zhang Dong smiled at his wife whom he previously embraced before the other elders arrived. After a bit of catching up, he had brought her to the dining area where all the best food was gathered. Most of their rations consisted of ration pills that satiated hunger but didn’t taste like anything. They were just swallowed and quickly dissolved in the stomach. They lacked the enjoyment of a feast that they were all about to have.

“I’ve picked out your favorites and saved you the best seat.”

“Best seat… but why is that there?”

“That?”

He followed the finger to see her pointing at Huo Qiang that was sitting at a seat. For some reason, he had pulled a separate chair to the table that he prepared for his wife. His intent was to have a chat with her in relative peace but judging by the maddened expression, it wouldn’t be possible.

“Senior Brother, come sit! I brought over some more meat too!”

“Qiang you were always a savage, can’t you read the room? How could a person with so many wives lack so much decency…”

“If you won’t eat it, then I will… that gold rainbow carp looks tasty…”

Qiang looked at a specific dish that was sitting there. Zhang Dong picked it out because his wife had a thing for eating fish instead of other meat. Besides that, she usually went for sweet things and salads which were all placed in one place. Before the big brute could finish the sentence the matriarch moved at an astonishing pace to get to her seat. Zhang Dong chuckled while taking up his spot on the side. Soon all three main elders were eating while the other sect members waited for them to finish.

“What are you waiting for, just start eating you don’t need to show proper decorum today, see it as a reward for bringing the Matriarch and everyone back safely.”

“But Patriarch…”

“You want my husband to repeat the order? Just sit down and eat.”

One of the elders wanted to decline the invite but he was glared down by an angry-looking Liena. Soon everyone gathered in the large dining area to eat and rest. At first, they all were silent to not disturb the elders from eating but after a few nods even they started talking with each other. It was a well-deserved rest after many months of struggles.

Time inside the tower floors worked differently while this resting area was not affected by it. For Zhang Dong and Huo Qiang only a day had passed but for the people inside it was three months of battling strange monsters and survival. Now that they were here it was possible to activate his system’s gate function and let them travel back to the golden palace.

“We can return to the Golden Palace?”

“Yes, I think the juniors and you should go back. They can help the others search for Gramps and the others, most of our people should be accounted for and I bet he is together with the last group in those tunnels.”

“We should go back? What about you husband? It almost sounded like you wanted to remain here…”

Liena picked up on the scheme that would leave him in this area behind. He had already mentioned the time shift that transpired. It made this area a good place to raise their strength in a short amount of time. Even if a year passed inside of the levels only a few days would pass in the real world. It also seemed that the time dilation got greeted the higher the floor they reached. Perhaps if they continued climbing for a whole year eventually it would amount to an hour here.

“Well, that is…”

“If you are going to stay here, so will I.”

“Oh? If she is staying then so will me!”

Answered Huo Qiang without thinking while devouring a large drumstick from a strange bird creature. Zhang Zhi was standing to the side and quickly nodded as if he wanted to imply that he wanted to remain here together with everyone else.

‘The stay here would probably be better for them than me… but it also will become dangerous.’

The thing that he was concerned about was the strangeness of this tower. He had access to some of its functions to make things easier but it wouldn’t be a cakewalk. The main reason was that he anticipated creatures in a higher realm to be included. This place didn’t work on the same limits and the bountiful amount of spiritual energy that went above what should be possible confirmed it. If he took everyone in then perhaps before they reached the next safe area they would be assaulted by a boss monster they couldn’t handle.

‘But Bob is already connected to the console, he can give me all the help that I will need. If we grind enough items then perhaps even a boss at a higher realm won’t be a problem…’

What he and his group needed was more power. If they were stronger and better prepared then getting themselves trapped in this strange realm would have not occurred. They were not ready to tackle the Long Clan and Azure Emperor that was in possession of quasi-immortal weapons.

After his confrontation with Long Qing, he realized that it wouldn’t be that easy to gain victory. He wanted to reach the fiftieth level in an attempt to gain better weapons and maybe absorb enough spiritual energy to counter his elder brother. The Azure Emperor was not his only enemy and they also had their flying city that seemed more powerful than the Golden Palace he possessed.

Getting these three here to the great circle of the nascent soul before the final battle would not be a bad idea. With time aspects that existed in this place, it wouldn’t take that long and he would also be able to absorb some knowledge involving the Dao of Time that he needed for his final confrontation with the Overseer.

“I guess it wouldn’t be bad if you tagged along but only on one condition! You’ll have to listen to whatever I have to say, even if it might sound strange.”

“If it won’t have anything to do with that idiot, then everything is fine with me.”

Liena smiled at Zhang Dong while still glaring at Huo Qiang who in retaliation stole some of her food from the plate.

“You dare!?”

“I do dare!”

The two soon started chasing each other around the whole dining area which caused a lot of chaos. Luckily the food here was plentiful and self-replenished after it was gone. So even if it was being thrown around by the two it would just strangely vanish and reform itself later in another location. This place was dissolving things into spiritual particles and recycling them at an astonishing rate. If he was able to recreate such an effect then world hunger would not be a problem anymore.

“Patriarch, the two Grand Elders are… what should we do?”

“Leave them be, they'll tire out after a while… Instead, have everyone assemble in the main lounging area.”

“Of course Patriarch.”

Zhang Zhi clasped his hands while Zhang Dong stepped to the side with a smile on his face. Huo Qiang continued to munch on some meat while also grabbing other things that continued to fly around. Liena continued to chase after him while trying to not get any of the food on her clothes or hair. It took around ten minutes for them to settle down and even required him to move in for a grab.

After disarming his wife by taking away her chopsticks he pulled her into the resting area with other people. This place had a vast array of massaging chairs on which he could place her to forget about the recent incident. It was funny to watch her face that melted away almost instantly after the chair was activated. The other nascent soul masters joined them in this room which allowed them to relax.

“Now that you are all here, I shall open the portal. Everyone besides me, Elder Liena, Elder Qiang, and Zhi will go through it. Our sect members are waiting for you on the other side, you will…”

Soon all people were assembled in the large lounging area and listening to his orders. The four of them would remain in this place and attempt to clear it at least to the fiftieth level. While this was the plan, he knew that things didn’t always work out as they should. There was a possibility that they would be unable to leave or even perish during one of the boss battles. Yet, their and everyone else's lives were already at stake. All of them were ready to give it all.

“I’ll leave my grandfather to you, please rendezvous with the other elders and search for him.”

“Leave it to me, Patriarch, I won’t disappoint you!”

Zhang Dong nodded at the most prominent elder from this group who was the temporary leader. His job was to prepare everything for their return and considering the time discrepancy he probably didn’t have that much time to perform the search. If the Long Clan came along, their people would need to somehow survive before their four strongest fighters returned, time was of the essence.

“Okay, The entrance will open in about twenty minutes, I hope you are ready.”

“I was born ready.”

“I will follow the Patriarch’s orders.”

After all the other cultivators from his sect left through the gate the four of them remained here. Qiang and Zhi were quick to nod as they were ready for more action. Liena on the other hand just smiled and placed herself to his side. With his closest friends around him, there was nothing to fear. It was time to become stronger and finally pave a future for his people.

Chapter 701

“This is like in the good old days but I guess we are missing a few people…”

Huo Qiang commented while looking at Zhang Dong, Zhang Liena, and Zhang Zhi. He was the only person that came from a different clan. In the past, the three grand elders went through quite a great adventure in the secret ground and now this would be a continuation.

“Does he really need to go with us? Wouldn’t it have been better with just the three of us?”

Zhang Zhi didn’t say anything as he was still considering himself as not on equal footing with the other three people here. The Patriarch was like a godly figure to him and he could not be disrespectful to his wife. Huo Qiang’s strength spoke for itself and he put him as his goal. The man didn’t even think that he had the possibility of reaching the power that the sect leader possessed.

Everything that he was now had been granted to him by the Patriarch. In his mind, it would take a whole lifetime to pay back all the opportunities and help that was given. Even now, this whole place was one big fortuitous encounter. His power had already risen by a lot and he was a middle stage nascent soul master. It wouldn’t end there as he was convinced that the longer they stayed here the stronger everyone would become. Perhaps reaching the Late or the great circle stage of the nascent soul realm wouldn’t be a dream.

“Yes, we need all the help we can get, now that there are fewer people the tower floors will start changing. We won’t need to fight as many monsters but it won’t be a cakewalk either. So Liena and Qiang, I want you both to work together. Our lives will be constantly at risk so we can’t allow for any disturbance in our teamwork.”

“If it is a request from my husband then… But don’t get the wrong idea you blockhead, don’t try anything funny!”

“Haha, don’t worry Senior Brother we will be fine, I bet I can kill more monsters than you can!”

“What did you say…”

“Oh boy…”

Zhang Dong smacked his forehead while looking at the two grownups arguing again. Luckily there was also Zhang Zhi with him that would follow all of his orders. The only problem when it came to him was that he took everything too literally. If he told the man to live for ten years at the top of a secluded mountain and wait for the next order, then he would do it. Even if it meant abandoning his own wife and children he believed that his Patriarch would not lead him astray. His approval rating was so high that he was more like a cult member that saw him as some kind of god.

“Can I be of service Patriarch?”

“No, it’s fine. How about I show you some things before we leave, we have around an hour left before time is up.”
The group nodded and quickly followed behind their leader. The hotel had a few facilities that could still aid them in their recovery. Both Zhang Zhi and Liena were able to gather some hidden points that would allow them to enter some previously locked chambers. Even Zhang Dong, who had some access to the hidden control room, was not able to enter it previously.

“Here, these rooms work similar to a secluded cultivation cave. Inside you’ll find all that you need to consolidate your realm. I’ve noticed that both of you have pushed into the higher stages of the middle nascent soul realm but your foundations are becoming shaky.”

“That is true but will an hour of time be enough?”

“Don’t worry, these rooms have a similar time affecting property as the tower levels. An hour here amounts to a week inside of this room, you’ll have plenty time.”

“A whole week?”

“Is something wrong?”

“No, nothing…”

Zhang Dong smiled at his wife and pouted a bit.

“Don’t worry, we’ll be spending a lot more time together after we enter the next floor.”

“... You dummy, don’t just say that in front of everyone!”

She blushed a little before entering the room as her husband proposed. Zhang Zhi didn’t even ask any questions but instantly entered the room that was pointed to. This left Huo Qiang and Zhang Dong alone for another hour.

“Can’t I use one of these rooms, Senior Brother? Maybe later for now, how about we just go to the gym instead?”

“Gym huh…”

The two arrived at a room that could be accessed by anyone. It looked like a premium gym from the modern world. There were various squat racks and bench-pressing machines everywhere. They were all things that could be used to train the body. They were clearly made by the creator by the system as lifting the weights infused spiritual energy at a very rapid pace. Even though he had maxed out on his body refining technique the moment he grabbed some dumbbells and performed a few curls he could feel that he was getting stronger.

‘I wonder if my body could pass through the limits if I stayed here for a few weeks…’

While Zhang Dong had recreated something like this gym back home, it was only used by Qi condensation practitioners. Regular muscle training didn’t really give good results as thanks to body refining techniques they just grew in a passive manner. There was no need to spend hours lifting just to increase their strength.

“This is heavy… How much does it weigh?”

“If you lift it up like that you’ll snap something in your back…”

Huo Qiang decided to perform some heavy deadlifts by pushing as many plates together. They were a bit deceptive and weighed a lot more than a few dozen kilograms. The two were handling multiple tons of weight and whenever the weight dropped on the ground it would send ripples down the entire space.

“You’re overdoing it…”

“Nonsense Senior Brother, this is noth…”

He had to somewhat babysit Qiang through the entire experience. The man just wanted to go heavy and max out all of his lifts. Luckily he was there to spot him whenever the bar was close to taking out his head during a bench or during a heavy squat. There was not much time for him to get in a good sweat as he was worried about his junior brother hurting himself.

After close to an hour of lifting in this gym, both of them took a break to head to the cultivation chambers. Luckily at their level, there wasn’t much sweat and odor produced by their bodies so they didn’t need to take showers. When they arrived the room that contained Liena slowly opened and she emerged with a satisfied look on her face. Her disposition had improved and some progress in her cultivation could be seen already.

“Welcome back, I see that you have improved.”

“I’m back and of course, who do you think I am?”

Liena smirked proudly as if her progress was something obvious. Huo Qiang stopped for a moment as he also scanned her with his spiritual sense. She did not appreciate the gesture but after promising that she would behave, it was hard to act out on her emotions like before. Soon after the other door opened and Zhang Zhi walked out with about the same level of progress.

“Good, let’s go then I bet the path forward will open soon.”

The group of four left for the hotel lounge where before this moment it lacked a door. When they arrived one suddenly appeared in a place that would normally lead them outside. It was the same one that appeared when Liena defeated the boss on the twenty-fifth floor.

‘Going by the control room, we have around ten minutes to go through the door.’

Bob was connected to the control console in the hidden room. Through it, Zhang Dong could see the ticking timer that had appeared. It was possible to not go through this pathway but then their journey would be at an end. They would all be kicked out to the front of the tower where they entered and would be unable to get inside again.

Everything here was a one-time thing and entering could only be done through the secret route which he did not want to continue using. The overseer could be looking and would probably attack him if he was ever found in a place there was no access. To have a fighting chance he needed to break through his limits and perhaps this place would allow him to.

“Let’s go, I’ll take the front…”

“Patriarch, it might be dangerous, I should be the first one to go!”

“Oh? So you can actually refuse an order?”

“M-my apologies, Patriarch I spoke out of term, please punish me!”

“I was just joking Zhi, relax. I’m still the strongest here, if someone survives a surprise attack it will be me.”

The other three people in the group thought differently but didn’t want to start arguing with their leader. A normal sect leader would use their sect members as protection by sending them out to perform difficult tasks. Usually, a person in Zhang Dong’s position wouldn’t act until the very last moment. Even if elders died, as long as the strongest person in the sect remained, the situation was always salvageable.

Finally, he took a step forward and grabbed the door handle. While he and Huo Qiang were not part of the initial expedition, the moment they went through this door they would be included in it. After flinging the door open he took a step forward and finally vanished through the obvious teleportation gate.

‘What will it be this time around, a water level? A lava one?’

A lot of light was produced by the teleportation phenomenon, before his eyes could register anything hot air collided with his face. Before him, a vast empty area of nothing but sand appeared. It was a desert area with absolutely nothing around him and his companions quickly noticed as well.

“It’s hot…”

“My cultivation is being suppressed by the spiritual energy here…”

“Haha, I feel fine.”

Zhang Liena started fanning her face while Zhang Zhi complained about the lack of water energy in the air. He followed the path of water Dao so desert areas didn’t mesh well with his combat ability. The only happy person was Huo Qiang who thought that the hot blistering sun actually felt nice for a change.

Chapter 702

“Zhi are you okay? How about we take a break.”

“No it’s fine Patriarch, this weather isn’t affecting me at all.”

“Right…”

Zhang Zhi’s face was covered in sweat and his usual palace face had turned red from the prolonged sun coverage. They had been wandering through a sandy desert for about a week. There was nothing besides dunes of sand and blistering sun above them. For some reason the sun refused to go down, leaving them at its mercy.

Even when flying through the air at a reasonable pace, they weren’t really getting anywhere. Attempting to get a better view was also not possible as a strange wind kept pushing them down whenever they tried to fly up higher than a kilometer. It was at a level that Zhang Dong couldn’t handle and the higher they attempted to go, the worse it became. It reminded Zhang Dong of the wall between the Emerald Phoenix Empire and the Azure Empire. His body was the strongest here and would still be shredded to pieces if he decided to ignore the warning signs.

It was a good idea to have the core formation experts leave the current expedition team. Some of them would have probably not survived for the weak or some of the nascent soul masters would have had to drain their spirit energy reserves to keep them shielded from the elements here. Zhang Zhi, who was no slouch, was starting to feel the strain as his body was mostly filled out with water Qi which had a hard time in this type of environment.

‘He should be fine for another few days, it would be better if we found some type of shelter before we get there, luckily I have that.’

“Husband, we have been going around for so long are you sure that we aren’t going around in circles?”

Zhang Liena had mostly remained quiet for the weekly trip but now even she was not sure about their location. There weren’t any landmarks to orient themselves on and with a lack of a day and night cycle, there were no stars to orient themselves on. Zhang Dong had assured everyone that he had a way of keeping track of everything but it wasn’t something that he could explain.

“We have not been going along in circles at least, that I can guarantee you. This place is just excessively large.”

Thanks to Bob and his map he was able to keep track of their point of origin. They went in one direction and kept to it but perhaps there was nothing there to wait for them. It could be that this place was just an empty space without anything waiting for them. Perhaps finding the exit was the true test as they had also not encountered any type of living beings.

“If you say so.”

“Are you tired already? It’s just a little desert, the heat isn’t even that bad.”

Huo Qiang was the only person that was enjoying himself. His cultivation was composed of fire Qi and he could even absorb all of this heat to keep himself going. Liena wasn’t fairing badly either as her body-refining skill kept her from being affected by the heat as much. Zhang Dong on the other hand had multiple Dao knowledge and could mostly shrug everything off that was put against him. Even with the three of them passed out he could probably still pull them through this weird area.

“Wait, something is there … ”

“Where?”

“In that direction, did you see the sand move?”

“Now that you say it…”

Finally, after a few more hours of flying in the same direction, something was different. A large space in the distance was shifting around in a strange manner. All the nascent soul masters here also started noticing it after he pointed it out. At first glance, it looked just like regular desert sand but when they looked closely they could see a subtle shift in the environment, there was something below it.

“Well, just to be on the safer side…”

All of them stopped while Zhang Dong pointed out with his finger. Above the spot in the ground, a sphere of electrical energy started forming and expanding at a rapid pace. The thunderous sound was quite loud but it didn’t seem that it was bothering whatever was hiding down there.

“Fine, have it your way then…”

A giant bolt of lightning descended from the charging sphere and collided with the ground under it. Soon after a rain of lightning bolts ensued and hit with the sandy dunes below. The tremendous heat and energy that was generated quickly started turning everything into crystals. The longer the technique lasted the more of the ground became affected by this crystallization and finally, the creature that was lurking below had enough.

“So it is one of those… Look out for the mouth, it will devour you whole if it has a chance.”

The sand that was turning to glass shifted as a massive worm erupted from under it. The size was tremendous with the thing being at least five hundred meters long and many meters wide. Without a problem, it would be capable of gulping all of them at once. Its whole body was covered by strange slabs of rocks that imitated dragon scales and even while under the effect of his lightning shower, it was able to just take minor damage.

“Finally some action, let me have this one Senior Brother.”

“Be my guest…”
Liena scoffed while flying up as she ignored the massive beast for now. She appeared next to Zhang Dong and Zhang Zhi. The group of three continued to look around the area while Huo Qiang faced the beast alone. The monster was strong but only at the level of an early-stage nascent soul master.

“It might not be alone, stay focused on the sand.”

Just like he expected soon another similarly large creature burst through the ground. It wasn’t the only one as two others were right behind it. Everyone here had one sandworm for themselves and Zhang Dong decided to go for the one that was the largest. Their techniques roared as they could finally unleash all the build-up stress from wandering the empty sand prison for over a week.

First was Huo Qiang who just created a miniaturized version of the sun that ended up down the monster's toothy gullet. While some people might have thought that these creatures were heat resistant, there was a reason why they usually stayed below the sands. The temperature was reasonably low down there so blasting them with fire Qi did the job quite nicely.

Second up was the one that chased after Zhang Dong. With a few well-placed sword slices the monster turned into sashimi. The work couldn’t even roar as it got cut into pieces in a matter of seconds. Zhang Zhi copied his role model by performing his own sword dance in the air, even in his slightly diminished state a worm like this was nothing. Zhang Liena was dead last as she just kept her distance and continued to shred the monster with concentrated wind blades. This didn’t go unnoticed as Huo Qiang used this chance to gloat for being the first.

“Haha, I win, maybe you should spend more time in that cultivation room when we come back?”

“Shut it, damn brute with no brain!”

“Bwahaha.”

Just as per usual, the two started fighting but these four worms were just the tip of the iceberg as the ground burst open. It was clear that the group finally triggered some kind of event and perhaps soon this floor could be cleared.

“There are more of them coming out, get ready!”

“Husband, that’s not all, look!”

Zhang Dong looked at the spot that Liena was pointing at with her fan and noticed that one of the worms that had been cut up, started to reform itself. The one that exploded from being melted by Huo Qiang’s technique was quickly regenerating itself while squiggling around and so were all of them.

“These beasts have powerful regenerative capabilities… there might be a core inside of their bodies!”

They started by fighting four sandworms but they quickly turned to twenty. Luckily the monsters couldn’t fly and only extended their bodies to a certain degree. By dodging all the pounces the group continued blasting and slicing away. However, soon they realized that something was wrong as no beast cores were present inside the destroyed bodies. Even fully burning them didn’t resolve the issue as the monsters continued to come back.

‘Something isn’t right, I should check in with Bob.’

By activating his system window he was given a view over the battlefield from a different point. There he could see some oddities about the monsters they were fighting. One of them was that these worms didn’t seem to have an end. Their bodies never fully left the sandy desert below as if they were connected to something below.

“I see…”

“Did you find something?”

“Yes, give me a moment, I’ll force it out. Just keep them from attacking me.”

“No problem!”

Huo Qiang smacked his fists together while increasing the heat. Zhang Dong floated closer to the central point where the monsters were coming out. A purple haze surrounded his body and was then transferred down to the ground. Soon the sand particles started rising up as he reversed gravity and made everything lighter.

The monstrous worms didn’t like that they were being dragged out of their sandy environment and tossed themselves at the man responsible. Before they could reach him they were blasted away by the three other people that were with him. Even as they continued they were unable to do anything about being pulled into the air.

“That is…”

Zhang Liena covered her mouth while looking at what Zhang Dong pulled out from the earth. Their true enemy wasn’t the worms but the thing that they were all connected to. It was a giant-looking leech monster with around a hundred sandworms sticking out of its upper side and connected to its obsidian-looking body. It was truly tremendous and not something that he could keep in the air for too long.

“I’ll keep it in place, you have to destroy the real body before it goes underground!”

“Hah, so it was this ugly thing!”

“I will fulfill my duty, Patriarch.”

“Such a disgusting thing…”

The three nascent soul masters didn’t need to be asked twice before they utilized their most powerful techniques. Red, Blue, and green energy flew through the air and ground the monster into a paste. The monster’s whales shook the space around this desert area but it was still unable to free itself. The gigantic body was nothing but a training dummy for these three nascent soul masters and soon the sand below was drenched in the creature's black blood…

Chapter 703

“Argh…”

“What is it, an enemy?”

“No… I just stepped into something… it smells…”

“...”

“What’s with this place!”

“Just stay quiet Qiang, we have to use our other senses to get through this. Try to concentrate and you’ll be able to avoid such things…”

“Serves that idiot right, that’s what he gets for never learning proper cultivation.”

Zhang Liena snorted while covering her face with a fan. No one could really see the gesture she made but needed to sense it instead. The group of four had moved on from the desert region that took them over a week to get through. Afterward, they arrived in another jungle area that was filled with giant mosquitos. They spend many weeks wandering through the area while having to protect themselves from the bloodsuckers. The floor finally ended with a boss battle against their queen who succumbed quite easily to Huo Qiangs flames.

Their journey continued through other floors that were usually wide open areas with a lot of free movement. It felt like they were on a survival trip through all the possible variations of the world outside. There was even a water area through which they needed to push through. Various small caverns with air were spread out which they needed to detect before they suffocated. However, after arriving at floor number forty things started changing.

They were now in a strange cavern with little space around it. The darkness was so profound that even their hands when placed in front of their faces were invisible. Then there was also the strange unsettling silence, they could actually not communicate with each other as no sound waves could travel through. The lack of sound created a sense of disorientation, making it challenging to navigate.

Not even the faintest glimmer or flicker dared to disturb the pitch-black void. The walls, jagged and rough, seem to close in on themselves, creating a claustrophobic atmosphere that amplified the sense of unease the group of four masters faced. Only thanks to their heightened spiritual sense and touch were they able to feel the presence of others.

It was a different type of test that would normally force the group to experience some existential dread. When venturing into the abyss their senses of foreboding intensified. They could not see or hear the potential shadowy beasts that lurked in the shadows. Even if they produced their techniques no light was produced and they only caused damage to themselves. Luckily, one person from the group had a little helper on his side that could connect them through.

“Patriarch, this technique is quite peculiar, I can hear your thoughts… how is it called?”

“I guess you can call it a group chat if you want, we’ll be able to stay connected with each other as long as I’m nearby.”

“Groupchat? Fascinating! I knew that the Patriarch was an astonishing person but how could this be possible, maybe…”

“Zhi, you must stop thinking out loud like that, everything that you say will be forwarded here by the technique…”

“Oh, really? My apologies.”

“I really wish that there was some meat here… can you eat a creature made of shadows? Maybe I should ask Senior Brother about it!... Hey Senior Brother, is it possible to eat…”

“You’re doing it again Qiang and I don’t know…”

“Can you shut up for a second you muscle-brained buffoon, how can someone with such an empty head think so much about idiotic things!”

Zhang Liena was the only one that had figured out how the chat feature worked and was quite maddened by how idiotic Huo Qiang’s thoughts were. The only things that he was thinking about were eating, battling monsters, and fondling women. He would parrot the thoughts that everyone could then later hear through the system which felt like they were listening to an empty record.

“Try to silence your thoughts Qiang, we can’t get distracted in a situation like this, otherwise…”

Before he could continue with his sentence something appeared before him. His senses were superior to everyone here and the creature seemed to have been waiting. It was as if it was observing them from afar to pounce at the moment the group was arguing with each other.

His hand moved to grasp something sharp going for his throat and successfully stopped it from reaching it. With the help of his superhuman strength the owner of this sharp object was held in place and instantly destroyed by his other palm. The attack that he used would normally produce a lot of light but in this case, it just caused the place to flicker for just a minuscule moment. However, this was enough for him to get a look at the enemy that they were fighting.

“These things… they are humanoid in shape but their hands are replaced by scythes, be careful everyone!”

Amidst the darkness and silence a battle was now taking place. The four martial masters formed a circle and started to predict the blades coming from the various attackers. From time to time a flash of light was produced that was strong enough to light the way. It revealed the inhumanly looking shadowy beasts that were pitch black and lacked faces.

‘I’m slowly getting used to this…’

Zhang Dong felt that he should have normally been able to traverse this darkness with the help of his Dao of Darkness. For some strange reason, it wasn’t much help in this situation that made him believe that this was either something else entirely or a higher form of the path he had learned. This darkness felt much deeper, like the void and it wouldn’t let him perceive it too well. However, with some time he was starting to see the path ahead even without having to spend all of his spiritual energy for a tiny light to light the place up.

There wasn’t much at first but he was able to perceive a small region around them. When a shadowy specter got within the ten meters that he could see, the fight became a lot easier. Each of his strikes landed with a hard impact, the force behind them enough to turn the monsters into nothingness. But the shadows seemed to have no end, as more and more of the creatures materialized, their featureless heads fixated on the group of four. If he didn’t do something about it then all of them would eventually give in.

“There is something there, everyone lock your hands together and follow me!”

“You want me to do what?”

“We need to stay together, there is no other way.”

He couldn’t see Liena’s expression but by her tone, he knew that she wasn’t happy to hold hands with other men. Even less when the man that grabbed her hand was Huo Qiang whom she despised. Normally she would deliver a kick to his nether regions instantly but it was clear that the situation was no laughing matter and they needed to get through this first.

Soon the group took off running but in reality, they were just dangling around. Their leader was running at such speed that they were just dragged along behind him. They had no idea what was happening but soon something appeared within their vision. It was an entrance opening before them into which they all quickly ducked into. Behind them was a mass of shadowy beings which when faced with the light started to burst into flames.

“The creatures, they are vanishing. They can’t survive in the light?”

Zhang Dong nodded at the question as he observed the chamber that he entered. Thanks to Bob and his mapping device he was able to discover something like a safe room for them to hide in. In the middle was a large brazier filled with strange-looking coal. It was not black but white instead and illuminated this place in bright white light.

“I’ve heard of creatures born of the void, could they be those legendary beings?”

Asked Zhang Zhi while investigating the small room. There was not much here besides the lit fire in the middle and three arches. Only darkness was coming from them and it seemed to be somehow alive but when coming into contact with the light, it continued to evaporate into nothingness.

“That could be possible, this darkness is different and those monsters aren’t like anything I have ever seen, they don’t even have souls but perhaps…”

“Senior Brother, have you found something?”

“Maybe, I think we can use these. The wood is similar to those white coals, I think whoever created this place wanted people to use them.”

The path leading to this safe room wasn’t long and if they weren’t so cautious they would have probably arrived here sooner without even getting attacked. The flames in the brazier could destroy the strange shadow creatures and two stick with the same coloring were placed in one corner.

“Are those supposed to be torches?”

“I think so, who wants to be on torch duty?”

Zhang Dong looked in the direction of his three companions as he intended to have his arms free. It was probable that whoever was carrying the light wouldn’t be able to utilize their fighting skills.

“Let Liena do it, Senior Brother!”

Before he could make a decision the two started fighting again. Perhaps taking both of them on the trip was not the smartest idea. It was however hard to deny the progress that the entire group was making. Their power was increasing at a rapid pace and Qiang was about to properly enter the late stage of the nascent soul. Probably after finishing the next boss, he would gain enough energy to push through the threshold.

“Why I know that you don’t want to but it would be best if you and Zhang Zhi carried them.”

“I knew that you’d see it my way, Senior Brother.”

Huo Qiang smirked while looking at Leina who started fuming out of anger. She gave Zhang Dong the death glare but he was quick to send her a secret message to diffuse the situation.

“Please understand, I don’t want to put you in danger. The closer you are to this flame the safer you will be, I’m just worried about my cute wife. Also, we will use one at first and have Zhi carry it around, you might not even need to use it yourself.”

Liena’s face started changing instantly as he gave her the explanation. She covered her face with one of her battle fans to not show her rosy cheeks. Soon the group picked up the two sticks and brought them over to the fire. It was clear that they would not last forever so they needed to make it count…

Chapter 704

In a dimly lit cavern, four individuals found themselves frantically running away from shadowy monsters that lurked in the darkness. They clutched onto a single torch, its flickering flame providing the only source of light in the eerie underground space. The torch illuminated the rugged walls of the cavern, casting long shadows that danced and twisted with their every movement.

Their footsteps echoed throughout the cavern, creating an unnerving cacophony that mixed with the distant growls and hisses of the pursuing monsters. The sound that was previously muffled by the void-like darkness now produced a resounding echo. The torchbearer remained in the back of the group with a solemn expression on his face. This protective light was quickly dying out and the monsters just continued their pursuit with no end in sight.

“There has to be a safe room somewhere, spread your senses!”

“That’s easier said than done, Senior Brother!”

Huo Qiang called out while trying to incinerate one of the shadowy claws coming their way. While his flame was able to push the attacker away soon its form was replaced by another.
Their movements were swift and agile as they skillfully evaded obstacles that threatened to trip them up. The torchlight illuminated stalagmites and stalactites, which quickly started falling down in an attempt to bar them from going forward.

“Husband, the darkness is too thick, it’s impossible to tell where we should go…”

“If it comes to this, then I guess we’ll have to do something a bit drastic, Zhi give me the torch, and all of you, get ready to run.”

Zhang Zhi didn’t hesitate in giving the white torch to Zhang Dong who was determined to find a path in this treacherous depth. The area they found themselves in was a lot more spacious with nothing visible outside the ten-meter radius this torch was providing them. If they continued with this tactic in a few minutes the flame would be gone. Thereafter the shadowy fiends would have free reign to assault them from all directions.

“Get ready, it's going to get bright, there has to be a tunnel leading out.”

With a swift motion, he launched the torch up into the air, its flames dancing wildly as it soared higher and higher. As the torch reached its peak, a moment of anticipation filled the cavern. Zhang Dong infused a hefty amount of his own spiritual energy into the white stick of wood to overcharge it. Suddenly, with a resounding explosion, the torch burst into a brilliant display of light and illuminated the cavern they found themselves in.

To everyone's surprise, the place they found themselves in was a lot larger than they anticipated. It became clear that they would have never been able to discover the way out if they kept to the old strategy. Even as the light filtered through the darkness and pushed away the monsters inside no hidden passage was revealed. However, right at the end of the explosion of light, a tiny gleam of hope caught their eyes.

“There, I can see something!”
Liena called out while sprinting forth. A lone passage became visible in the vast distance to all of them. Without any discussion, the four marital masters activated their movement skills and tossed themselves toward their new destination. Time was of the essence as the light source they relied on was quickly fading. The previously dancing light that easily revealed the judged edges and crevices of the cavern walls was going out.

“This might feel strange but bare with it…”

Zhang Dong was still a lot stronger than the other three nascent soul masters here. By his calculations, the group would not make it into the passage before the light fully went out. Thus to not get attacked by an angry army of shadows he surrounded everyone in a bubble of golden light. With the help of this bubble, he could carry all of them towards their destination at an increased speed.

“Woah!”

“N-not so suddenly!”

Huo Qiang shouted out in surprise at the increase of velocity and Liena wasn’t far behind. The only one that remained silent was Zhang Zhi that just concentrated on not sustaining any damage.

The bright orb of golden light flew in the direction of the only exit from this place. The white blaze that illuminated the way forward began to quickly die out and soon the monstrosities that were hidden within the darkness started to approach. Yet, Zhang Dong’s speed could not be stopped even when the path darkened yet again he still continued to push through. On the way, he felt the clawing of the shadowy beasts but there was no stopping this golden train anymore.

With a resounding sound, the group squeezed through the darkened corridor and arrived in another safe room with more white light illuminating the area. The technique was canceled but the momentum wasn’t. He reached out his hand to catch Liena before she flew away into the wall. The other two gentlemen that he was carrying were out of luck as they were tossed into the distance and collided with some rock formations.

“Are you okay?”

“I’m fine but…”

“But?”

“Doesn’t this chamber look different than the others?”

After putting Liena down Zhang Dong’s attention returned to the problem at hand. They were still on the fortieth floor where they had spent a whole week at. They had followed a similar pattern of finding safe rooms with white torches for a while now. Each and every room looked the same with one large brazier of flames in the middle. Here on the other hand they could see a lot more of them.

“You are right, this might be it. There are also four torches this time around and they look a lot thinner than the other ones and then there is that…”

He along with Liena looked at a large stone gate that could be reached by going up a flight of stone stairs. On the side of these stairs, there were similar braziers that they encountered in other safe rooms that were unlit. It didn’t take a genius to realize that probably after lighting all of them the way forward would be open. Before they attempted clearing this floor they needed to strategize as the boss inside would probably be different than the ones they previously met.

“Qiang, Zhi we will take a small break, eat the ration pills, and recover as much of your energy as you can, this will probably be it.”

They had been inside this tower for around three months now. This was the amount of time it took them to get from the twenty-sixth level to this one. Time outside had not advanced that much and Bob continued to inform him about the changes. His grandfather had not been discovered but traces of their sect were found in the underground tunnels. Perhaps after they were able to clear up to the fiftieth floor, it would be time to continue their true mission and take care of the Long Clan once and for all.

“Are you ready?”

“Yes, Patriarch. Would you allow me to?”

“Sure, go ahead, just be careful we’ll be right behind you.”

Zhang Zhi urged the leader to let him enter the chamber first. His fear of potential traps murdering him was there. On some previous occasions, Zhang Dong had walked into some hidden encounters that would have potentially cost him his head if he was not quick on his feet. Now when the stakes were a lot higher, Zhi felt like it was time to step up. If he was injured it was fine as long as their number one fighter remained in full health to clear the level. If they reached the safe zone at the end of the fiftieth floor then it wouldn’t matter if he lost a limb or two.

After lighting the path forward the four torches remain lit. The massive doors started to creek and swung open to reveal a darkened chamber with no lights just like everyone expected. The only light there was coming from the room the three were in and they knew that the moment they went inside, these large doors would close behind them. Zhang Zhi moved forward at the point of the formation, his eyes darting around as he tried to feel out any potential traps.

“Is this place empty? I don’t see any paths heading out…”

Huo Qiang called out while looking around. The chamber itself was mysterious, with ancient symbols etched into the walls, and the only source of light emanating from flickering torches. Soon just as they predicted the way behind them began to close and soon they were surrounded by a pitch-black void.
Suddenly, a low growl resonated from above, causing the martial masters to instinctively look up. From the ceiling, a shadowy figure began to materialize, its presence both daunting and ethereal. The beast emerged with a sense of grace, its form shifting and contorting as if made of smoke and darkness.

“Spread out, it's coming!”

This being had no true shape, it looked like an ooze made from obsidian water. It descended from above in a torrent of darkness that wanted to swallow up the light that they were producing. Even though this being was illuminated by their torches it didn’t seem to waver as the lesser shades that they encountered during their travels.

All of them jumped to a corner of the circular platform they were battling. The moment the creature's body slammed into the middle it erupted in a hail of some sort. Instantly Zhang Dong realized that the light they were holding on to was in danger. His instincts told him to protect the torches at all cost as they were the only thing that would allow them to fully perceive this monster.

“It’s trying to douse out the torches, don’t let its body touch the torches!”

His allies nodded as they performed techniques to protect themselves from the water-like discharge. When the darkness connected with their elemental techniques it quickly attempted to engulf them. The fact that it was in close proximity to the light source would not turn this darkness away, yet the room continued to shift. Losing this source would force them into an unfavorable position so they needed to finish it fast.

Huo Qiang let his fists roar and Zhang Zhi performed a thousand cuts with his blade. The chamber was quickly filled out with particles of water and fire that attempted to destroy the beast made of shadowy energy. Their combined efforts and teamwork at first seemed to push back the strange creature but the darkness persisted. The more they moved the quicker the flames died out and soon Qiang’s torch was gone leaving only three to illuminate the area.

‘This form is probably not its true body, this monster must have some type of core that is hidden where the light from the torches can not reach…’

Zhang Dong was sure that if they continued with a conventional approach then the battle would be lost. Before the torches went out they needed to locate this beast's true body and slay it…

Chapter 705

“I understand now, quickly bring the beast over here, it is the final piece of the puzzle!”

“Thank the heavens…”

“Lure it over to the formation, we don’t have much time left!”

Zhang Dong shouted out, his focus unwavering, amidst the dimly lit chamber. In front of him, a solitary white torch hovered, teetering on the edge of extinguishing. The fight with the shadow being had turned extremely tedious as it continued to dodge most of their attacks without sustaining much damage. The group was now down to a lone torch that was being sustained by his own cultivation.

Despite his deep understanding of the Dao of Holy energies and fire manipulation, Zhang Dong found himself unable to rely on these insights for the task at hand. The flame they were dealing with possessed a distinct essence, one that was primordial and ancient. It seemed to draw power from the Dao of Light, making it an entirely different challenge. Engrossed in deciphering the nature of this radiant light, Zhang Dong's companions valiantly engaged the monster, recognizing that gaining more insight could potentially be the true test of this floor, he continued.

They commenced the battle with four torches, but soon only one remained. Zhang Dong encapsulated it within a protective bubble of his holy light, enabling him to study and absorb the energies contained within. This light was of the purest form, unlike anything he had encountered before. Despite having spent years contemplating the complexities of a more challenging Dao, such as time manipulation, this particular essence felt comparatively simpler.

However, there was one crucial element he lacked which was the darkness of the void. The creature they faced stood as the antithesis to this radiant light, a void of absolute darkness. To gain insight into this void, Zhang Dong needed to merge his Dao of Darkness with its essence. This fusion would provide him with enough understanding of the light energies to overcome this peculiar trial. Consequently, his allies baited the monster, which had grown increasingly aggressive upon witnessing the dwindling torchlight.

In a mere blink of an eye, everything unfolded. Qiang, utilizing his flames, successfully lured the monster's attention towards himself. The area where Zhang Dong had been meditating had previously evaded the creature's notice, but now, in the absence of illumination, it seized the opportunity to strike. However, the creature was in for a rude awakening. Just as the white light on the verge of extinction, it erupted into an immense radiant explosion, engulfing the entire chamber in blinding whiteness.

Desperate to absorb this intense source of radiance, the monster attempted to assimilate it through its own body. It resembled a black hole, existing to devour not only light but space itself. This was the precise moment Zhang Dong had been patiently awaiting. While the creature was preoccupied with the excruciating pain induced by the radiant light, Zhang Dong swiftly unsheathed his blade and struck.

With a simple, unremarkable movement of his sword, Zhang Dong executed a basic vertical slice. Only he was able to perceive the slight use of the light dao that he just barely comprehended. Fortunately, the beast they faced was only at the nascent soul level, despite possessing a higher path. It still had its inherent limitations. As the monster was defeated, it dissipated into a cloud of dark smoke, reminiscent of polluted air. The victory was theirs, and swiftly, a luminous passage materialized, offering a way out of the gloomy dungeon.

“One down nine to go…”

He glanced at the three people that he was with. His eyes could finally relax and so could his senses. After the monster was defeated its essence was spread equally between all of the participants. This phenomenon showed just how much better it was to limit the size of the group. There was no limitation for delivering the last hit, all of the spiritual energy was equally distributed to all the participants. Only when battling lesser demonic beings besides the boss would it become more individualistic.

“How is everyone doing?”

“I don’t want to lie Senior Brother, I am slightly tired… this beast was an annoying and cowardly opponent.”

Even though nascent soul masters were at the limit of what was humanly possible they still had their limits. Huo Qiang, Zhang Zhi, and his wife Liena were all covered with sweat. They had all used up a lot of spiritual energy on an opponent that they could not even injure. The dread that they must have been feeling was probably immense.

“We have fifteen minutes until the door closes, I propose we take some recovery pills and have a short meditation break before going through.”

“That would be wonderful.”

Liena responded as she swiftly sank to her knees, seeking to regain her stamina that had been depleted during the battle. Zhang Dong followed suit, his energy levels significantly diminished after his attempt at utilizing a technique he was not entirely familiar with. Although he had caught a fleeting understanding of the Dao of Light, there remained much that eluded him. It was an enigmatic energy, simultaneously potent and delicate. A mere glimmer of light had the ability to dispel darkness, yet it was equally susceptible to being consumed entirely.

Usually, Zhang Dong would take several days to contemplate this newfound revelation and potentially incorporate it into a new technique. However, there was no luxury of time at this moment. They had to pass through the door swiftly, or else the path would seal shut, leaving them trapped in this realm of darkness.

Upon examining the rules of the trial tower, he unearthed some unsettling truths. Failing to defeat the boss or complete the level would condemn them to an eternal existence within this pocket dimension. While Bob and his system might eventually find a way to create a new exit, it was best not to rely too heavily on luck.

“Okay, it has been ten minutes, we should go.”

The timer on Zhang Dong's system window alerted him that it was time to proceed. Though his companions hadn't fully regained their strength, they appeared slightly more refreshed than before. Perhaps in the upcoming area, they would find a moment of respite. However, for now, they needed to stay alert. Without hesitation, the group leaped through the closing door and emerged in the new area.

“Where are we now? This one looks a lot different than the previous ones.”

“There are so many books… it's much larger than even our sect library or the one we experienced in that old sacred ground.”

Liena remarked, her gaze sweeping across the vast expanse of the library. Zhang Dong nodded in agreement, their anticipation for another wave of monsters dissipated as they took in the scene before them. Instead of facing another onslaught, the air was filled with the scent of aged books and parchment. They found themselves standing in a colossal library, with bookshelves soaring over a hundred meters in height and spanning an impressive width.

“Why does it have to be books… I think this task will be up to you…”

Huo Qiang's eyes widened in awe as he beheld the sheer volume of books in the library. As a formidable cultivator, he had achieved his power through rigorous sparring and intensive training, rather than through extensive knowledge. Without the guidance and teachings of Zhang Dong, who mastered the knowledge-parting technique, Huo Qiang would likely never have attained the level of mastery he had reached.

“How did an idiot like you even survive this long, your ancestors are crying in their graves that someone like you represents their name.”

“My ancestors are doing just fine!”

“Stop arguing you two, this place doesn’t seem like it is focused on combat. Qiang, you have probably noticed that you are close to the threshold. Go find yourself a secluded space and meditate.”

“Senior Brother!”

Qiang clasped his hands while grinning widely. He was sure to show that grin to Liena that started to tremble with anger. Yet after a few pats on her back from her husband she managed to calm down. He was sure to remind her that they needed to work together for their safety and having Qiang ascend to a small realm would be quite helpful.

“Zhi, keep an eye on him, we don’t really know if this place is fully safe. I and Liena will examine this ‘library’ and call you when we find something.”

“Of course Patriarch, I will see to it that Elder Qiang isn’t disturbed while he cultivates.”

“Good, just be careful, and don’t be afraid to call me when you discover something important.”

The group soon dispersed, going their separate ways. The married couple, now alone, relished in the rare opportunity for some privacy. However, they quickly realized that their surroundings didn't allow for any extravagant activities. As they explored the area, they stumbled upon bookcases brimming with ancient scriptures. While many of the texts were beyond their comprehension, they did come across a few practical manuals of varying quality.

“I have never seen this language before, have you?”

“No, it doesn’t look like it belongs to this world… what could it mean.”

“Doesn’t belong to this world?”

Zhang Dong pondered this response and instantly thought about the other worlds that this universe they resided in was composed. There was a possibility that the scriptures here were taken from other realities where different cultures arose. Humans weren’t the only intelligent creatures out there so there was a chance that it was true.

‘If I had access to hundreds of worlds, creating such a library to hide the important stuff wouldn’t be hard…’

His theory revolved around the architect of this level. Perhaps the abundance of books in this library was nothing more than a diversion, a clever ploy to waste their time. If they persisted in meticulously examining each book, they would be doomed to spend an unreasonable amount of time here.

Despite the time distortion in this place, they continued to age, and the immensity of the library seemed to stretch endlessly into the distance. Reading every single book would likely take an eternity. He knew he had to find a more efficient way to navigate through this area, but first, he needed to uncover a clue that would lead him in the right direction…

Chapter 706

“Hm… so this was the answer? How did you figure it out?”

“Well, Let’s say that I had a little helper…”

Zhang Dong responded, grabbing a book from a seemingly random section of the massive bookcase. The helper he referred to was Bob and his system. With his keen analytical skills, Zhang Dong swiftly identified the pattern necessary to solve this minor puzzle. This location lacked any obvious clues or shortcuts, instead demanding mental exertion.

Once the initial discovery was made, the puzzle didn't appear as daunting as first assumed. Zhang Dong's keen perception led him to notice a distinct spiritual energy pattern emanating from certain books. It became apparent that by following this pattern, they could locate the specific books that, when viewed from a distance, formed a unique character. This character held the key to unlocking the central mechanism in the library—a combination lock with an overwhelming number of possible combinations, making it impractical to try each one individually.

The most difficult task was finding the correct books as the energy pattern they had was miniscule. The only way to sense these patterns was through direct skin contact with the hidden book. With millions of books tightly packed together, this task seemed impossible. Fortunately, Zhang Dong had Bob's assistance, allowing him to expedite the search by scanning for the elusive pattern. Without Bob's help, the four masters would likely have been compelled to further evolve their spiritual senses, which this test undoubtedly aimed to assess.

‘Just like the previous one, this test was not about strength but about resourcefulness. There might have been another way to go around it if I didn’t have Bob around but it kind of seems like it was meant for system holders and not people from this world.’

Ordinary System holders had the option of purchasing diverse skills that could potentially aid in solving this puzzle, akin to the scanning ability provided by Bob. Otherwise, a heightened sensory skill, surpassing the nascent soul level, would be necessary. As they ascended to higher floors, Zhang Dong couldn't shake the growing fear that they would soon face challenges beyond their normal capabilities.

Perhaps these tests served the purpose of preparing them for the ultimate showdown on the fiftieth floor. He could only hope that his companions would strive to reach new heights before getting to that point, for he knew he would require every ounce of assistance. Luckily, his junior brother was already on the pacifist of reaching the late stage of the nascent soul.

“With this, we have the combination to the lock but I propose that we stay here for a while. I can feel that you have progressed immensely as well, you should be able to do the same soon and it’s the same for Zhi.”

“Hmph, I’ll catch up to that fool in no time!”

Zhang Liena wore a complex expression as she glanced at Huo Qiang. The man who had been a source of countless headaches now hovered in mid-air, enveloped by a colossal orb of swirling flames. It was as if he were summoning a miniature sun, his spiritual energy pulsating and expanding with immense power. Within a matter of moments, the condensed fiery sphere was drawn back into his body, momentarily tinting him with a reddish hue.

“Hah, I did it! I entered the late stage!”

“Congratulations Elder Qiang.”

Zhang Zhi nodded, in comparison to Zhang Liena he seemed impressed by the feat of reaching the late stage of the nascent soul. There was probably no one in the whole empire at the age of Huo Qiang that achieved this feat. The man was not even a hundred years old and was almost at the end of his cultivation journey. Only the Great Circle of the current realm remained before all progress would be locked away by the laws of this world.

“Relax Qiang or you might burn everything in this library… Good work in containing those flames Zhi.”

“I just did as you asked of me, Patriarch.”

Thanks to Zhang Zhi’s watery art the flames that were produced could be doused. The man was sweating profusely though as the difference in might had become even more apparent now. If Qiang were to focus a bit harder, the water elements in the vicinity would undoubtedly evaporate in an instant.

“How can I relax? Isn’t there something that I can hit?”

“There are no beasts on this floor, just consolidate your realm by meditating for now. You seem to be bursting with energy, you can probably push yourself even further.”

“You are right, Senior Brother! This isn’t over yet!’

While the nascent soul level was divided into four smaller realms, those were also divided even more. What Qiang had entered was just the elementary period of the late stage but he could push himself into the medial period of it. If he continued to cultivate with all the spiritual energy that he had gathered, it was possible.

“Zhi you did well, I’ll watch over him now. You should meditate as well and ready yourself for your own ascension later.”

“You believe that I could?”

“I’m sure that you’ve noticed the potent Qi that resides in this tower. Our bodies are like sponges absorbing it, the further we go the more powerful we will become.”

“If the Patriarch says it… then it must be true!”

Zhang Zhi clasped his hands and excused himself into a more secluded area of the library. With the trial puzzle being solved rather early all of them had time to prepare for the next level. Perhaps after they completed this trial the spiritual energy from this area would also enhance their bodies.

‘Bob, keep scanning those books, there could be something worthwhile in there.’

‘Affirmative.’

This sprawling library remained a treasure trove of ancient knowledge, holding secrets that Bob could unravel as he was capable of deciphering the strange language. However, the books contained within were of limited value, originating from diverse worlds with unique constraints. He couldn't harness external forces to augment his abilities obtained in this realm.

Thankfully, he stumbled upon a handful of precious cultivation manuals that had the potential to yield something worthwhile. Like everyone else in this place, he yearned to push himself to the next level, seeking to ascend further. With a significant power boost, he would stand a far better chance against the forthcoming adversaries. But first, he had to find a way out of this tower.

The trial they were enduring had been deliberately designed to stretch over an extended period. Upon consulting Bob, he discovered that the time dilation had intensified since their last assessment. A month spent within these confines would merely translate to thirty minutes passing in the outside world.

With each minute equivalent to a full day, they could leisurely absorb spiritual energy and contemplate their cultivation, free from concerns about the passing of time. Even he, who had glimpsed the elusive Dao of Light, had free time to reflect upon his experiences and delve deeper into its mysteries.

Thus with his guidance, his companions continued to push themselves on. Both Zhang Zhi and Liena reached the peak of the middle stage while Huo Qiang pushed himself into the middle of the late stage. While watching his friends make progress he began to ponder. The item he received after defeating the Cerulean Empress was still unused and with him. Using it would allow him to gain the Dao of Water and one related to plant life.

‘I need to save this for the right occasion…’

He made the decision to keep that option open for the future, recognizing the high risk of attracting the attention of the Overseer when his power surpassed the limitations of this realm. It was wiser to conclude his mission against the Long Clan without external assistance, granting him more time to prepare.

Based on his understanding of the enigmatic Overseer, they would remain passive as long as he successfully defeated the Azure Emperor. Their intervention would only occur if he disrupted the delicate balance of this world, potentially leading to its complete destruction.

As he pondered this dilemma, memories of his former companions and the young girl he once embarked on adventures with flooded his mind. Back then, they had successfully vanquished a lesser Overseer, whose strength had been curtailed by the limitations of their shared world. However, once he left that realm, all contact was severed, leaving the fate of that place shrouded in uncertainty. It was conceivable that another entity had taken the fallen demon's place, subjecting the inhabitants to a grim fate. Despite the potential horrors that awaited, he knew he had to press onward, striving for victory and seeking answers to the enigma of the plethora of worlds.

“Is everyone ready, I’ll activate the lock. There might be a beast guarding the entrance so be ready for it.”

“Good, let it come!”

As Huo Qiang braced himself to unleash his newly acquired power upon the world, Zhang Dong began the daunting task of unlocking the intricate mechanism. The design of this place, with its enormous padlock that required him to navigate a labyrinth of symbols, baffled Zhang Dong. Whoever had conceived this challenge had certainly intended to make it disorienting. It took him a painstaking thirty minutes to locate the ten correct symbols, and the satisfying click that followed confirmed it.

The lock slammed onto the ground with a resounding boom as it was thick as a pillar. The gate that it was protecting was on the larger side and the moment it was off a new path started to open before the group of four. At first, they were prepared to face some type of library demon but soon they realized that it was only another exit from this forty-second level.

“I guess I was right, let us step through.”

“I’ll go through first this time, watch my back Senior brother!”

“No wait, hold on…”

Huo Qiang took off while laughing, the man was around fifty years of age but still acted like a rowdy teen. Zhang Dong could only shrug and move through the door that was another teleportation gate. The moment he stepped through it he was on the forty-third floor which was indicated on his system screen that Bob was watching over.

The group found themselves standing upon an empty hill that seemingly extended infinitely, gradually transforming into a colossal mountain. At first glance, it appeared unremarkable, but soon a peculiar scent permeated the air, filling the surroundings. The initial hill they had arrived on was encircled by a dense forest, which quickly became overwhelmed by a corrosive green liquid. With each passing moment, the acidic substance continued to spread, leaving them with no choice but to ascend the towering mountain looming before them.

Chapter 707

Zhang Dong let out a weary sigh as he caught sight of the exit from this bizarre place. He had just scaled a colossal mountain, its surroundings nothing but a sea of corrosive acid. It felt as though they were trapped inside an enormous flask. In the center of it, all stood a towering mountain that they had to conquer before their flesh would be devoured by the acidic liquid. And as if that wasn't enough, they had to battle against hurricane-force winds and airborne creatures resembling harpies.

These monstrous beings, with razor-sharp talons and piercing eyes, circled overhead with an air of predatory grace, ready to strike at any moment. Zhang Dong and his companions had to remain ever vigilant, their senses heightened as they fought off the harpies' relentless attacks while continuing their ascent. All of these challenges combined, created an overwhelming test of both physical and mental fortitude as their flight abilities had been locked away. Impossible to activate as they risked being shredded by the winds around them.

‘What will await us next…’

The group couldn't afford to waste time contemplating their next move. Despite reaching the peak and defeating the mother harpy, the acid bath had already engulfed the area. Their feet were immersed in the green liquid, only saved by their body refining skills and layers of spiritual energy shielding their skin. If they had been even a minute late in defeating the final boss, victory would have been unattainable. Without delay, they leaped through the door in the sky that transported them to their next challenge on the path to the fiftieth floor.

Descending from the acidic mountaintop, they found themselves in a dimly lit dungeon. Unlike the previous one, this dungeon lacked the eerie shadows that obscured their vision. Instead, they were faced with numerous entranceways, each marked with a number. It was evident that a choice had to be made, but without any reference point, it proved to be a daunting task.

Finally settling on a path, they ventured into the first entrance, and so their expedition continued. Within a day, they maneuvered through treacherous corridors teeming with traps and malevolent creatures. Their long journey persisted until they eventually arrived back in the same expansive chamber they had departed from.

“Senior Brother, isn’t that the tunnel we used?”

“It seems to be so, I did mark it before we left…”

Zhang Dong nodded in satisfaction as the pathway they had chosen led them back to the chamber they had started from. Before proceeding, he cleverly left a trace of his spiritual energy behind to aid in tracking their progress. With the assistance of his system window, he could easily monitor their current path. It was evident that this trial was designed for individuals who possessed exceptional orientation skills or were aided by a system tracker. However, he couldn't help but wonder if there was more to this labyrinth than met the eye. Would it truly be as straightforward as he initially believed, or were there hidden challenges lying in wait?

“Let’s try another path and see where it leads us this time.”

With unanimous agreement, the group proceeded into the second tunnel. Again, a full day passed as they navigated through its twists and turns, until an unexpected occurrence disrupted their journey. The number of tunnels began to multiply, and the chamber itself expanded to accommodate this change. Initially, there were precisely one thousand pathways, but now another ten had materialized. It became apparent that there was a hidden complexity to this trial, surpassing their initial expectations.

Without any verbal guidance to rely on, the group forged ahead, venturing into the next tunnel in order to test their theories. Their journey persisted, and Zhang Dong diligently monitored his system window where the map was displayed. Through this technological aid, he confirmed a crucial fact: the maze they found themselves in was far from simple; it was constantly shifting as they progressed.

This was illustrated by retracing their steps through the initial tunnel they had traversed. Upon examining the map, he discovered that the path had transformed into something entirely different, solidifying the notion that the maze was in a perpetual state of change.

“If this blasted thing is shifting around, how are we supposed to get through the correct path?”

Huo Qiang complained while delivering a punch to the walls. Even though he was a nascent soul master that could soon reach the great circle realm, he was unable to leave a dent in the dark rocky walls. Destroying the walls with their cultivation might have already crossed everyone's mind but even with their current might, there was no going through. While it was possible to leave a few cracks in with their strongest attacks, getting through would be only possible if the walls were relatively thin.

“Perhaps we should part ways and spread through the tunnels individually?”

“Zhi is right, why don’t we split up?”

“I’m not sure if that’s the best idea…”

Zhang Liena furrowed her brows as she voiced her concerns to Zhang Zhi and Huo Qiang. Though they exuded confidence in their abilities, their tendency to act hastily was evident. Zhang Dong nodded in agreement with his wife, acknowledging her valid point. If splitting up was indeed the most effective tactic, he would have already considered it. However, he couldn't ignore the small issue that posed a challenge to this strategy.

“Liena is right, it could be possible that one of us finds the right path and ends up alone in a new section of this dungeon. There are some creatures roaming around, they might even reach the boss's chamber and be alone…”

“I see, the Patriarch is ever wise!”

“I’m fine in facing the boss alone!”

“Think for once you idiot, how will you be able to tell us that you found the right tunnel if you end up somewhere else? Would you even be able to come back to tell us? This place constantly changes shape, the tunnel you took would not be usable again!”

Liena's anger escalated as she shouted at the indifferent Qiang, who appeared unfazed by the confrontation. As their argument unfolded, Zhang Dong focused on finding a solution to their current predicament. Despite the ever-changing nature of the tunnels, he deduced that they were still confined within a single space. To confirm this, he consulted the three-dimensional map displayed on his system, which reassured him that there were no spatial techniques or formations at play in this maze.

“Please you two, just try to get along… we will probably have to spend a few weeks with this one but I think I have a solution for this dilemma.”

“You should be glad that my husband is here.”

“Why wouldn’t I be glad? Senior Brother is always good at getting out of such predicaments!”

He was glad that they believed in him this much but it was not easy to take all of this responsibility onto his shoulders. The group depended on his puzzle-solving abilities, which were augmented by the assistance of a cheat system. If he made a mistake in his assessment of this place, they could potentially be trapped indefinitely. The growing number of tunnels only served to amplify the confusion they would encounter the longer they searched this place.

Zhang Dong observed a subtle pattern that would likely bewilder ordinary cultivators. While most people would assume that the tunnels were shifting or adding themselves to the main chamber, this was not the case. As he ventured further into one of the passages, he discerned a faint clicking sound. Although it was barely audible amidst the perils of the caverns, he managed to uncover the secret of this place. Contrary to popular belief, it was not the tunnels that were moving, but rather the main cavern they had initially entered.

Within this chamber, numerous deceptive elements were at play to confound those undertaking the test. One of the primary tricks involved the manipulation of numbers. Initially, the first tunnel they entered was labeled as number one, but subsequently, the numbers were altered. As the chamber expanded, it was only the entrances to the tunnels that shifted, creating an illusion that deceived Zhang Dong's perception.

Leaving a spiritual indicator at the entrance further reinforced the false impression that the entrances remained in their original positions. If he and the other continued with this assumption then they would be unable to ever get through this place. Thus the tactic was easy, find the first tunnel they ventured through and orient themselves on it. Probably one of the thousand original entrances led to a proper exit.

“Well then everyone, I hope that you are well rested as we will be ignoring our safety for a while and aim for speed!”

The only solution Zhang Dong could conceive was to navigate through these areas with utmost speed. Although splitting up would expedite their progress, it also carried the risk of isolating them from one another. There was a chance that whoever reached the next area first would be separated from the rest of the group. However, there was another possibility to consider in case this scenario unfolded. It was plausible that multiple exits existed among the first thousand tunnels, which they could systematically explore one by one.

The nature of the test shifted from exploration to a race against time. With Zhang Dong leading the way, they disregarded the monsters and evaded traps that detonated in their wake. Although it appeared as if there were a thousand tunnels, his map enabled him to halve that number. After approximately a week of delving into the depths, they eventually reached a new area, distinct from the previous ones.

The area they arrived at revealed a temple adorned with numerous stone giants lining its sides. A flight of stairs led up to a statue seated on a majestic throne. This marked their final encounter on the floor, and without warning, the eyes of the rock behemoth began to glow a menacing red. The stone monsters then shed their petrified exteriors, unveiling a formidable layer of cold steel beneath.

The final battle approached, but by this point, it didn't faze them as much. For cultivators, navigating treacherous caves proved to be more troublesome than combating golemic contraptions. They embraced this challenge, relieved to be spared from the mental strain of puzzles and hidden pathways. Within moments, Qiang's newfound techniques unleashed intense heat, swiftly melting the army of metallic monsters before them.

Zhang Dong easily dispatched the main metal monster, resembling a gorilla made of gold and diamonds. The creature proved no match for his superior power and fell just like the others. The group breathed a collective sigh of relief as the door to the next area swung open, allowing them to leave this place behind.

With only a few floors remaining, they pressed forward undeterred. Every time they cleared a floor, a more formidable one emerged in its place. Their strength continued to grow, and soon both Zhang Zhi and Liena advanced to the Late stage, while Huo Qiang reached the pinnacle of the great circle of nascent soul. Now, only one floor remained, and once they conquered it, their true mission could finally resume.

Chapter 708

As they ascended to the final floor, a sense of anticipation and nervousness filled the air. They had come so far, faced countless challenges, and grown stronger with each trial. But what awaited them on the fiftieth floor? What final test would they have to overcome before they could continue their mission?

‘So this should be it? Just like the previous ten floors, this one is different…’

After crossing through floor forty-nine they arrived in a closed corridor. There was nothing there but stairs leading up. The group had made all the preparations that they could so without any words uttered, they continued to ascend. As they arrived at the end, they were greeted by a vast, empty space. No monsters, no traps, just an eerily quiet room. It was a stark contrast to the previous floors they had encountered, and it made them even more wary of what was to come.

Zhang Dong cautiously took a step forward, his senses heightened, ready for anything. But as he moved further into the room, he realized that there was something different about this floor. The air felt heavy with energy, a powerful aura that seemed to emanate from the very walls.

Suddenly, the ground beneath them began to shake, and a blinding light filled the room. When the light faded, they found themselves standing in a different place altogether. It was a vast, celestial realm, with floating islands and shimmering waterfalls. The sky above was a tapestry of stars, and a gentle breeze carried the scent of blooming flowers.

In the center of this ethereal realm stood a figure, cloaked in white robes and radiating a powerful aura. It was the Guardian of the Fiftieth Floor, the final obstacle they had to face. Compared to the monstrosities they encountered on the lower floors he seemed rather normal. It was an old master, a cultivator just like they were and their last opponent before they would be given respite.

"Welcome, brave warriors. You have proven yourselves worthy to reach this final floor. But before you can continue on your mission, you must prove yourselves worthy.”

On a small floating rock formation, the old man stood tall, his eyes crackling with an energy that the four cultivators present didn't recognize. There was an unmistakable air of difference about him, an ancient and formidable power. Zhang Dong cautiously advanced, scanning his surroundings. The vast area was devoid of any other living beings. There were no signs of hidden enemies or traps; there was only this old master, their sole opponent.

“Be careful, this person is not a nascent soul master, he is something more…”

“Something more? Is he an Immortal?”

Zhang Liena gasped, swiftly preparing her battle fans. Huo Qiang's wide grin revealed his excitement, having reached the great circle of the nascent soul realm, he was eager to unleash his power. Zhi, on the other hand, remained silent, his hand poised near his blade. Despite facing an unknown and potentially powerful immortal, their confidence in their leader's judgment remained unwavering. If he believed they could emerge victorious, then they would.

“An Immortal? No, not quite…”

Zhang Dong stared at his system status window, which attempted to display the man's characteristics. However, where the cultivation realm should have been indicated, there was only corrupted text. It seemed as though the system either didn't possess knowledge of this person's realm or wasn't programmed to recognize it. Recalling his visit to the ancient secret grounds in the past, Zhang Dong could only draw one conclusion. This individual had transcended the nascent soul realm and attained one of the long-lost cultivation realms that had been banished from this world.

Given the circumstances, their chances of victory appeared bleak. Zhang Dong couldn't shake the feeling of familiarity that this individual evoked, reminiscent of a past encounter. It reminded him of the first time he had faced a nascent soul expert when he was merely at the core formation stage.

Back then, the power gap had been insurmountable, even for someone like him who was blessed with a system. If the difference in strength was as immense as it had been before, winning seemed impossible. However, there was a glimmer of hope, two possibilities that he clung to, which could potentially help him advance through this challenge.

The first possibility lay in Zhang Dong's own peculiar cultivation realm, which defied the limitations of this world. He had already surpassed even the mighty Azure Emperor, the greatest nascent soul master. Progressing through the twenty-four floors had infused him with a surge of spiritual energy, causing the pure white seed he held to blossom slightly more than before. If he could glean some insights from this man who had attained a higher realm, there was a chance for him to further advance his own cultivation.

Then there was the second option which was given to him by the man himself. Those words he spoke might have been a hint on how to get through this part without necessarily beating him in a bout of pure strength. However, the first option would still be better as some hidden rewards could be given to them for finishing it with a bang.

“What are you waiting for? Come at me young ones! Show me that you are worthy or embrace the void of death!”

The group of four found themselves with little room to maneuver as the man unleashed a surge of formidable spiritual energy. In an instant, the small rock formation beneath him was obliterated, sending debris flying in all directions. The ground beneath their feet trembled and began to crumble, threatening to swallow them whole.

Reacting swiftly, the group leaped back, assuming their battle stances. Zhang Liena twirled her battle fans with grace and precision, ready to strike. Huo Qiang channeled his nascent soul power, his body radiating a fiery aura. Zhi tightened his grip on his blade, his eyes focused and determined. Zhang Dong channeled his unique cultivation realm, feeling the surge of energy coursing through his veins.
As they glanced down, they witnessed the destruction unfolding beneath them. The ground cracked and collapsed, disappearing into a swirling abyss. The battle had commenced, and they were determined to prove their worthiness in this ultimate challenge.

“Let’s do it together everyone, aim at the spot where I’m aiming and give it all that you have! Now is not the time to show reserve, we might not have a second chance!”

All four of them unleashed their pinnacle skills, tapping into the full extent of their abilities. Zhang Dong, encased in a magnificent white and gold armor that enhanced his skills, led the charge. His companions, adorned with the artifacts he had crafted for them, followed suit.

Their techniques reverberated through the air, each attack executed with precision and power. Zhang Dong summoned a massive golden lightning dragon, infused with the essence of his Dao. As the dragon materialized, his companions joined in, channeling their own spiritual energy to amplify its size and strength.

The colossal creature, a fusion of various elemental energies and cultivation paths, lunged towards the old master. But instead of evading the attack, the man stood his ground, extending his hand to intercept the incoming assault. His face displayed unwavering confidence in his abilities, a sight that Zhang Dong had been waiting for.

As the lightning dragon collided with the man's outstretched hand, a shockwave rippled through this pocket realm. The clash of powers created a dazzling display of energy, illuminating the surroundings. The impact was tremendous, but the old master remained unfazed, his aura unyielding.

Anticipating the old master's unwavering confidence, Zhang Dong had predicted that he would not attempt to evade their attacks. Masters of such power often considered dodging beneath them when facing juniors. With this knowledge, Zhang Dong had intentionally held back when creating the gigantic dragon, concealing his true intentions.

As the colossal dragon descended upon the old master, Zhang Dong seized the opportunity to execute a hidden strike. With a swift motion, he unsheathed his sword, channeling all of his hidden power into a single thrust. A thin beam of blinding light shot forth, piercing through the heart of the gigantic dragon.

The master, preoccupied with contending against the immense energy of the dragon, would be caught off guard by Zhang Dong's unexpected strike. The speed and precision of the attack left little time for the master to react, catching him in a vulnerable position. Zhang Dong's calculated move aimed to exploit the master's inability to defend against simultaneous attacks. Deflecting such a strike required perfect prediction and split-second reactions, a challenging feat even for a cultivator of such caliber.

As the culmination of their combined strikes reached its peak, an explosion of immense proportions erupted, engulfing the battlefield. The force of the blast sent shockwaves rippling through the celestial realm, pushing Zhang Dong and his companions back. Floating islands shattered and crumbled under the tremendous impact, adding to the chaos and destruction.

When the smoke finally cleared, the group looked on in bewilderment. To their astonishment, the old man still stood in the center, seemingly unscathed. His robes billowed in the aftermath of the explosion, revealing a few cuts and scratches on his skin.

"Hoho... That wasn't quite bad,"

The old man chuckled, his voice filled with a mix of amusement and respect.

"I think you even managed to cut some skin with that one..."

Zhang Dong and his companions exchanged glances, a mixture of surprise and determination reflected in their eyes. They had thrown everything they had at the old man, unleashing their most powerful attacks, yet he remained standing. It was clear that defeating him would not be an easy task.

However, instead of feeling discouraged, the group's resolve only grew stronger. They had come so far, faced countless challenges, and grown immensely in strength. They were not about to give up now. The old man's words served as a confirmation that they had indeed made an impact, even if it was just a small one.

However, just as they were about to continue struggling, a peculiar phenomenon unfolded. The man's image began to flicker, resembling a hologram. Disappointment washed over them, but soon their disappointment turned to intrigue as they observed the man with a sly smirk on his face.

"Impressive. By damaging this illusionary body of mine, you have proven your worth. I look forward to our conversation when you reach the top."

He said. Gradually, his body started to fade away, as if he were some kind of ethereal being. It became clear that a full-blown battle was not the true test, but rather landing a solid hit. This revelation highlighted the vast disparity in their powers. If a mere illusion, created from spiritual energy, possessed such strength, what hope did they have in defeating the true master behind it?

Chapter 709

"Well, that was rather underwhelming,"

Zhang Dong remarked.

"I agree. I'm sure that master could have provided valuable insights for our cultivation, Senior Brother."

"I'm just relieved it's finally over. And I can't help but feel that I've made more progress than I ever anticipated."

Liena added.

Zhang Dong nodded in agreement, acknowledging Liena and Qiang, who had joined him in stepping through the dimensional door. They had now reached the secure area of the grand hotel. As they entered, they found themselves in an empty lounge and decided to take a seat. Although they didn't bear any visible injuries, their spiritual energy had been completely depleted in order to overcome the final test.

The environment here was rich in energy and there were even refreshments that allowed them to quickly push through the moment of weakness. The group of four wasn’t here for a picnic as they already knew what to do. Zhang Dong had already explained what they had to do after getting to this safe zone as their time was limited. First, the group needed to get into the premium cultivation chambers that became accessible and he would be entering one as well.

"We should enter now. Time is of the essence, and we still need to find Gramps," Zhang Dong suggested.

"Is there no way for us to stay in the same room?"

Liena asked, a hint of disappointment in her voice.

"I don't think so,"

Zhang Dong replied. While he would have loved to be in the same room as his wife, they knew it was better to cultivate separately. The rooms they were entering would slow down time, allowing them to achieve a year's worth of cultivation in just one hour. The idea of being locked in a room alone for that long wasn't exactly pleasant, but they needed to become stronger.

Each cultivation room was unique, allowing them to customize it according to their needs. Liena needed a high concentration of wind elements to enhance her cultivation, while Zhang Dong required a more balanced setup with a combination of multiple elements. His mastery of various elemental Daos made him adaptable to different energies and would slow his progress if he was together with his wife.

"I'll catch up with you later, Senior Brother! Maybe we can have a friendly sparring session once we're done... I can't wait!" Qiang said eagerly.

"Save that energy for our enemies, Qiang. We still have to deal with the Long Clan after we finish here and we need to find Gramps."

"Think before you speak!"

Liena scolded, frowning once again. She then gave her husband a tight hug, silently expressing her affection. Zhang Zhi, who had been quiet in the background, observed the scene. Both Liena and his own realm had reached the peak of the Nascent Soul Late stage. With a little push, they could probably reach the Great Circle. Having three masters at this level would greatly increase their chances of victory, but he also needed to make some progress. His realm had remained stagnant for many years, not advancing much even after absorbing the Dao from other Emperors.

"Take care, everyone. I'll see you later,"

Zhang Dong said his goodbyes, and everyone made their way to their individual cultivation chambers. They were fully committed this time, utilizing all the points they had earned from clearing the tower floors. Although they had the option to continue further, Zhang Dong had concerns about their ability to progress all the way to the seventy-fifth floor, where the next safe spot awaited.

As he had anticipated, this tower turned out to be a relic from the past, like an alpha test that had been abandoned by the creator of the world. The phantom master they had encountered was inexplicably powerful, serving as just a small glimpse of what lay ahead. It wouldn't be surprising if the boss enemy on the fifty-first level was on par with that formidable old man. And beyond that, his true form might appear, a foe they would likely be unable to defeat.

Zhang Dong contemplated the possibility of breaking through the limitations imposed by this world, but he knew his companions would face more challenges. Unlike him, they were born in this world and likely had inherent limitations ingrained in their very souls. Even if the tower produced higher-level spiritual energy, they wouldn't be able to fully harness its power. Their understanding of the Dao was also somewhat incomplete due to their rapid progression through their realms. Even if they attempted to advance into the next realm, they would likely be unable to do so.

He could not do anything but worry as he stepped into the premium cultivation chamber he spent all of the points he received from within the tower. While on the outside the room was situated in a hotel corridor things looked different on the inside. It was a large cave with ample room to train and in one particular spot, it was swirling with elemental dao. It was the central area of this cave and probably where he would spend the most time in.

“There is even a refrigerator with food, Liena did say that it kept refilling the food and even provided her with some pills…”

During the first few minutes in the spacious cultivation chamber, Zhang Dong took the time to familiarize himself with his surroundings. The chamber was well-equipped with everything a cultivator would need, including a large side area with training dummies and puppets. These could be activated for sparring and used to test his techniques as he progressed. Knowing that his companions were also in solitary cultivation, he couldn't help but feel a sense of loneliness.

"Well, at least I have Bob to keep me company, right?" Zhang Dong said with a hint of amusement.

"Affirmative," Bob, his AI assistant, replied.

Zhang Dong smiled, appreciating the small comfort of having Bob's presence. Though the AI wasn't particularly talkative, it could follow his orders and provide some entertainment. However, he quickly reminded himself that his primary purpose here was to train and not to indulge in leisure activities.

Assuming the lotus position, Zhang Dong focused his attention on the spiritual lights within the chamber. The lights danced before his eyes, radiating with immense energy. With each breath, he absorbed the lights into his cultivation seed, a powerful vortex akin to a black hole devoured all the spiritual energy it encountered. The seed eagerly swallowed the lights, fueling his cultivation and pushing him closer to his goals.

Time seemed to blur as Zhang Dong delved deeper into his cultivation. Days turned into weeks, and weeks turned into months. Within the solitude of the chamber, he honed his skills, refining his techniques, and expanding his understanding of the Dao. The spiritual energy within the chamber became a part of him, merging with his essence and empowering him with each passing moment.

As the final hour approached, Zhang Dong felt a surge of power coursing through his veins. The cultivation seed within him had grown stronger, its hunger for spiritual energy insatiable. With a final burst of energy, he opened his eyes, feeling a renewed sense of purpose and determination.

“I certainly have gotten stronger but this blasted thing… it still won’t budge?”

The white seed truly didn’t want to budge at all, while he did absorb a huge amount of energy through this whole year it still didn’t want to blossom into anything. A small change was noticed by him though as it was enriched. Perhaps with a little budge from the shell he received after defeating the sea Empress, he would be able to progress.

“I guess, I’ll use it if there is no other option then… It’s time to reunite with the others, they have probably gotten a lot stronger than before.”

Zhang Dong knew that his companions had also undergone intense training and growth during their time in seclusion. With their combined strength and unwavering resolve, they were ready to face the challenges that awaited them in their quest to protect their sect. Before leaving the cultivation chamber, Zhang Dong took a moment to appreciate the journey they had undertaken. The trials they had faced, the sacrifices they had made, and the bonds they had forged had brought them to this pivotal moment.

He had no doubt in his mind that they would be able to defeat the Long Clan and bring an end to this war. If everything went according to plan, it might also provide him with an opportunity to confront the true enemy who lurked in the shadows. However, he was uncertain about what to do with the wife of the Azure Emperor and whether killing her was even a viable option. It seemed that as long as he didn't make it too obvious, she would remain docile and not activate her formidable Overseer powers.

With his cultivation complete, Zhang Dong left the premium cultivation chamber and made his way back to the lounge where they had initially gathered. As he entered, he found Liena and Qiang already there, their expressions filled with anger. Between them stood Zhang Zhi who was panicking and trying to calm them down. It seemed that the two were back to their old antics which brought a smile onto his face.

“What should I do with you two?”

“Husband!”

Liena exclaimed while pouncing onto him the moment that she saw him. Her movements were fast and sharp like the wind Dao that she had mastered.

“Haha, I see that you also made it into the Great Circle realm, congratulations.”

Zhang Dong smiled and returned her embrace. The power that his wife and his other two companions were bursting with was tremendous. They were all given all superior cultivation methods and would be around his level if he ever continued on with regular cultivation. With all four of them gathered together he was sure that he had made the right decision.

“What will we do now, Senior brother? Continue to the next floor?”

“No, we will end now… if we ever hope to go further, we’d have to reach the next stage…”

“The next stage? You mean the legendary immortal realm?”

“Not quite but it’s not something we can get to yet, this will have to suffice.”

While he was hugging Zhang Liena, Huo Qiang came up to them. He was willing to continue as it was clear that remaining in this tower was producing results. They had made progress that normally should have taken them at least a hundred years.

“The time has come, we will defeat the Long Clan along with the Azure Emperor.”

“Finally!”

Huo Qiang smacked his fists together, his face full of smiles as he couldn’t wait. Zhang Zhi nodded in silence, his body becoming even more one with his sword. Liena on the other hand kept close, just taking in the moment of solace that she was given. Soon the group would depart on what could be their last adventure. Thus it was better to cherish this moment before it escaped into the void of time.

Chapter 710

"Spread out, leave no stone unturned. The emperor's watchful eyes are upon us, and it is imperative that we complete this mission."

"But what if we stumble upon the Golden Dragon? Can we truly emerge victorious?"

"What did you say?"

An enraged elder swiftly delivered a resounding smack to the back of his comrade's head upon hearing his response. A vast multitude of cultivators floated in the air, surrounded by an armada of ships and beasts. They hailed from the Long Clan and had been tasked with setting the stage for their leader, the revered Azure Emperor Long Qing.

Their adversaries, the United Element Sect, were concealed somewhere within this intricate trapping formation. The enemy forces were scattered, providing an opportunity for the Long Clan to locate and neutralize them. However, traversing this ancient formation, despite being in their own territory, was no simple feat. It had been crafted by their ancestors and was not easily controlled or traversed by anyone other than those of royal blood. For now, the royal family resided in their main floating city, leaving the task at hand to their loyal disciples and elders.

"I-I apologize, Elder."

"Follow your orders precisely. Once we discover their whereabouts, the Emperor will personally deal with his treacherous brother. Though he managed to escape, he was injured in the confrontation. Do not consider him an equal to our esteemed leader!"

"Of course!"

Nods of agreement rippled through the crowd, as the weakened state of their adversary filled them with confidence. While Zhang Dong had managed to evade their previous trap, the might of their Emperor was unparalleled. It was rumored that Zhang Dong had been struck by the main cannon of their city, leaving him gravely wounded. Perhaps, he was now weakened enough for them to emerge victorious. If they were to slay or capture the Golden Dragon, their clan would undoubtedly reward and immortalize them as heroes in their long and illustrious history.

"Remember to keep your bracelets on at all times. These bracelets are our only defense against the spirit beasts. Without them, we'll be vulnerable to their attacks. Also remember that they will stop working if you bare your swords at the beasts yourself."

The cultivators nodded in agreement. Although they didn't have complete control over the area, it still belonged to their clan. Thanks to the special equipment they possessed, the beasts in the vicinity perceived them as nothing more than air. As long as they refrained from initiating any aggression, the beasts would leave them alone. This allowed them to safely navigate the treacherous trapping formation, which served as their main defense against intruders.

Curiosity sparked within Zhang Dong as he glanced at his AI, Bob.
‘Can you examine the bracelets without risking discovery?’

Zhang Dong posed the question to his Ai Bob who quickly calculated the odds.

"There's a 75.34% chance of being detected if I perform a scan from this distance. To minimize the risk, you need to get closer.’

Zhang Dong sighed, realizing it would be too risky to investigate further. He engaged in a conversation with Bob while his three companions concealed their presence. The quartet of powerful elders had recently escaped from their tower prison and were now en route to their sect. However, their plans were abruptly interrupted when they encountered an imposing army of thousands of cultivators. It was evident that this was the main force of the Long Clan.

The Long Clan's army was formidable, boasting at least a hundred nascent soul masters among their ranks. It was clear that their opponents meant business and were determined to swiftly resolve the conflict. The fact that they were also immune to the ferocious beasts in the region added to the complexity of the situation. Despite the immense power increase experienced by Zhang Dong and his companions, engaging in battle against such overwhelming numbers with only four individuals would be unwise.

Zhang Dong's thoughts turned to the safety of his companions, particularly Liena and the others who would be left to face the remaining forces if he were captured by the Azure Emperor. Though the trio were now considered among the strongest masters in the world, they had not yet undergone extensive training in their newfound realms.

It wouldn't be surprising if they failed to pace themselves correctly and suffered defeat against such a large enemy force. Moreover, the true extent of the Long Clan's capabilities remained unknown. There was a possibility that their entire city would emerge, posing an insurmountable threat. Even Zhang Dong knew he wouldn't survive a prolonged assault from that city, let alone his companions. With their lives hanging in the balance, Zhang Dong understood that a cautious and strategic approach was essential if they were to survive this perilous encounter.

‘Okay, we should be able to talk now.’

To avoid getting noticed he activated a group chat with the others. The people from the Long Clan probably had a varied array of detection devices but they would be able to detect anything that went through his system. With its help he could relay his findings and also decide on the next scheme, infiltrating the enemy army.

‘Oh, senior brother’s voice is inside of my head!’

‘This always feels strange…’

‘...’

Qiang as always was the loudest while Zhang Zhi remained silent. Zhang Dong knew that the three would do whatever he decided on which made it easy to create this tactic.

‘You all know the disguising technique that I taught you, right?’

‘Sure, it was a great help on the forty-sixth level.’

During their ascent through the tower, they stumbled upon an unexpected challenge. It required them to assume the roles of covert assassins in a meticulously crafted replica city. With his disguising technique, they seamlessly blended into the bustling crowd, effortlessly accomplishing the given task. Fortunately, there was ample time for him to impart his knowledge and teach his companions the art of deception. Equipped with this newfound technique, their next objective was to patiently await the opportune moment to infiltrate the Long Clan's ship.

"Yes, we shall bide our time and seize any opportunity that comes our way. Considering they are actively searching for our sect, it's highly likely that they will dispatch scouting parties. We will target one of them,"

He proposed.

"Sounds like a solid plan,"

Liena responded, nodding in agreement.

"Ah... why don't we just launch a direct attack instead? What's the point of possessing this newfound power if we don't utilize it, Senior Brother?"

Qiang chimed in, voicing his impatience.

"Once again, this fool speaks without thinking!"

The two bickered, their argument echoing within the confines of their minds. Meanwhile, he scanned the surroundings for potential targets. Their concealment technique provided them with a secure hiding spot, ensuring their safety as long as they maintained a safe distance. The enemy armada soon began to move, and as long as they trailed behind discreetly, they would remain out of harm's way.

"Enough squabbling, you two. We must follow their lead. Stick to the ground and refrain from using any techniques, including flying,"

He commanded, suppressing any further disputes. Liena frowned, feeling somewhat disgruntled as she was now compelled to run on the ground like a junior sect member. However, there was no alternative, as utilizing flight would inevitably emit spiritual energy that could easily be detected by their adversaries.

Therefore, they persistently pressed forward, maintaining a cautious distance. While Zhang Dong possessed the ability to create a teleportation gate, which could have swiftly transported them back to the Golden Palace, he harbored a different objective. The bracelets, serving as a protective shield against the menacing creatures here, held a mysterious link to this very place. If he could secure one for himself, it dawned upon him that there might be a means to employ its power for the benefit of his people.

Just as he had anticipated, a golden opportunity presented itself to them. The armada, consisting of numerous ships, finally arrived over a massive and enchanting lake that emanated an overwhelming amount of spiritual energy. To their surprise, there was a mysterious creature lurking within the depths of the lake, but it did not pose any immediate threat to their ships. The long clan members quickly established a temporary base, encircling the lake and dispatching smaller vessels to explore further.

These smaller vessels primarily carried a group of two to three hundred core formation experts, each accompanied by five nascent soul masters. It was an invaluable chance for them to strike back at their adversaries. Determined, they unanimously agreed to seize one of these ships and turn the tide of the battle in their favor. Despite being limited to relying solely on their physical prowess, their bodies had been honed to the peak of their current realm. Even after running tirelessly for days on end, they remained untiring and managed to keep pace with the flying vessels.

The trapping formation spanned across a vast section of the empire, making it exceedingly difficult for their opponents to locate them. Even with numerous search parties dispatched, it would likely take weeks for their adversaries to make any significant progress in finding their hidden stronghold. Which they clearly didn’t know the location of yet.

'Husband, do you think we've traveled far enough? And how can we ensure that our attack remains undetected?'

Liena inquired, her eyes fixed on their unsuspecting prey in the distance.

'Don't worry, my love. I will disable their defenses and disrupt any means of communication they possess. Can you handle their masters and the core formation juniors?'

He replied, exuding confidence.

'I don't see why not. They appear rather weak.'

Liena responded, a hint of excitement in her voice.

'Finally, some action!'

Qiang commented, a surge of adrenaline coursing through his veins.

'Just wait for my signal, Qiang and Zhi. I'll leave the nascent divinities to you. Don't let a single one escape,'

'Of course, Patriarch. We won't disappoint you'

Zhi quickly replied while Qiang just started to rub his fist together as he would finally be able to use them against a proper foe again.

'Good. Let us proceed, then!'

He declared with a sense of purpose driving him forward. The moment they had all been waiting for had arrived. The trio, whom he had personally trained, were eager to showcase their skills, the five nascent soul masters and core formation soldiers stood no chance against their enhanced capabilities. They would serve as mere training dummies, their defeat inevitable. With the bracelets securely in their possession, the plan could finally progress, making it crucial for them to execute their mission swiftly.

Chapter 711

“What’s happening, why did we stop?”

An old man asked, his voice filled with concern while one of the younger men replied, fear evident in his voice.

“Elders, we are being attacked!”

“Attacked? Preposterous, who would be stupid enough to…”

The old man started to say, but his words were cut off by a massive burst of spiritual energy that filled the entire area. The five nascent soul elders were inside a large cabin within their ship, a vessel built to hold a large number of people. They were accompanied by over a hundred core formation experts, forming the crew. And now, they were under attack.

“It must be those United Element Sect bastards! Quick, call the general, we must inform the Azure Emperor!”

The old man exclaimed, his voice filled with urgency. Yet, the younger core formation expert that he was shouting at hesitated, his voice trembling.

“About that…”

“What is it? Speak up, junior…”

The old man demanded, his tone impatient.

“Elder… we can’t reach the main fleet or any of the other clan ships. Somehow, they have cut us off!”

The core formation expert's voice trembled as he spoke. The spiritual energy being exuded by the attackers was tremendous, to the point where he could barely stay conscious. Even the five nascent soul masters present could only partially block this surge of energy, causing panic to spread among the group.

“They cut us off? How is that possible? Quickly, use your treasures. They should work!”

The old man instructed, his voice filled with desperation. There were various ways to forward information in times of crisis. Many items existed that, when broken, would signal that something had gone wrong. However, as the men activated their talismans and trinkets, they realized that something was amiss. Nothing was working; some greater power had rendered their tools useless.

“This is not good. Prepare for battle!”

With no other options, they rang the alarm and armed themselves. Four of the masters were at the late stage of their nascent soul realm, while the strongest was at the great circle realm. They were individuals who could dominate the empire if they so wished, and they were convinced that victory was still possible.

“Only this much? Hey, can I have them all? I don’t think they will last much longer…”

A voice from above appeared and sneered. The masters glanced up to see a man covered in flames with two other individuals not far behind.

“No, just take care of it. We can’t risk it. There isn’t much time, and eventually someone will discover that something went wrong if it continues for too long,”

Another voice replied this one filled with caution but also strength.

“Ahh, that’s a shame… but if Senior Brother thinks so, then…”

The flaming man’s voice trailed off, his disappointment evident. As they stepped outside, they were met with a grim sight. Most of their core formation experts lay on the ground, defeated. Despite their ability to combine into formations that could affect nascent soul masters, they hadn't been able to even access this power before succumbing to the spiritual aura attack.

“Isn’t that the Golden Dragon himself? He doesn’t look injured at all,”

The strongest of the masters called out, his gaze fixed on the white-haired man. Their entire ship was surrounded by a barrier of spiritual energy, trapping them within. This shield was likely the cause of their current predicament. Even the strongest master's spiritual sense couldn't pierce through it. They were completely trapped.

"Show no fear, for it is unbecoming of the esteemed Long Clan! They have been trapped in the formation for long enough, surely they must be weary. That feeble excuse for a leader is likely wounded from his battle with the glorious Emperor. Our victory is assured, just follow my lead!"

The strongest of the Long Clan elders shouted out while producing a giant blue steed made of fire. It was his soul beast which he used as a means of transportation. The horse made from fire energies stood proudly as it charged with its master who was holding a large glave in his right hand. Soon the other four masters plunged themselves forward but they would be in for a rude awakening.

Their leader shot out like an arrow in the direction of the large red-haired man who was also covered in flames. He was floating right before the man called the Golden Dragon who was also the source of this blocking barrier. The elder’s goal was to use up all of his spiritual energy in one go. Something like this would drain him but give him a tremendous boost to his power.

If he was able to take care of these two that were the strongest in the group, then his side could stand a chance. If not, then it was enough to at least wound the one producing the barrier so that they could call for reinforcement. However, he made a grave error in expecting that his opponents were just regular nascent soul masters at the great circle level. As he slashed with his glave forward and expected to cut some flesh, he found himself stopping instead.

"What is this? Is this some kind of joke? Is this truly the best you can do?"

The flaming man didn’t actually react to the glave hit. Instead, he stood there with his chest out proudly and took the hit instead. The elder from the Long Clan thought that the younger man was just being foolhardy, clearly someone that wasn’t too bright,. Yet, his heavenly weapon could not pierce his body. It only went in a few centimeters while producing cracks at the edge due to the sheer speed his steed could produce.

"How... How can this be? How are you still standing?"

Terror etched itself onto the elder's face. His plan to incapacitate or bypass this man and reach the true enemy behind him had been swiftly foiled. The vast power disparity became glaringly apparent. In his seven-hundred-year existence, he had never suffered such a defeat. He was utterly helpless, and his enemy wasted no time in demonstrating that.

"Well, my Senior Brother wanted me to be quick, so I apologize, but you won't be leaving here in one piece..."

A colossal fist hurtled towards the elder's face. Had he not depleted most of his spiritual energy in his previous attack, perhaps he might have had a chance to evade. But it was too late. His face shattered instantly, showering the battlefield in a crimson rain as his body recoiled from the devastating blow. The four elders that were behind him were shocked by this turn of events. Yet, they weren’t given a chance to think about their tactic as another enemy appeared, this one in the form of a beautiful woman.

With a swift motion of her battle fan, she unleashed a tempest of green wind energy, manifesting thousands of razor-sharp blades. These ethereal blades effortlessly sliced through their opponents' spiritual shields and refined bodies. Despite their adversary being only a small realm above them, the disparity felt much greater. They found themselves utterly defenseless, unable to conceive of any countermeasure as their bodies succumbed to the relentless assault.

The five masters crashed onto the deck of the flying ship that had transported them to this battlefield. Their physical forms lay broken, but their spirits remained unbroken. Even in the face of certain defeat, the possibility of escape lingered. They swiftly made the decision to abandon their mortal shells and ascend into nascent divinity, each dispersing in a different direction, hoping to elude their pursuers.

“Quickly we must escape, this shield can’t hold our nascent divinities, inform the clan, we must inform the Emper… Aghh…”

A piercing scream erupted from the nascent soul master as a blade of water cleaved through his ethereal form, splitting it in two. It defied all logic, for such an attack should have been impossible. Within moments, the air was filled with four more agonized cries as his companions met a swift and merciless demise. In the blink of an eye, the five masters had fallen, their lives extinguished by the silent presence of the enigmatic third man. His unassuming demeanor had fooled them all, concealing the true extent of his power until the opportune moment presented itself.

…

“Good job Zhi.”

"Secure the bracelets from all of them."

Zhang Dong commanded as he continued to focus on the barrier. In less than two minutes, they had successfully seized control of the ship and dispatched the five nascent soul masters who occupied it. While Zhang Dong would have preferred to spare their nascent divinities, it was a luxury he could no longer afford. Too many lives were at stake, and he knew his enemies would show no mercy if the tables were turned. The hundred or so nascent soul masters on the other hand didn’t pose much of a threat. They could be handled with more care.

Huo Qiang, lacking the same moral compass as Zhang Dong, produced a question while grinning.

"What should we do with these warriors? Shall I eliminate them?"

Huo Qiang and their two other companions had no qualms about obliterating their adversaries, reducing them to mere dust. However, Zhang Dong had a different perspective. Instead, he chose to render their dantians useless, leaving them as ordinary commoners for the remainder of their lives. While some might view this as a fate worse than death, Zhang Dong, coming from a more modern world with different values, saw it as a comparatively preferable option.

"No, let them be. Just strip away their cultivation. They will remain unconscious for a considerable time, they don’t pose a threat to us or the plan."

Zhang Dong asserted.

"We will transport them to a secluded location where they will be impossible to find."

"If that is your decision..."

Huo Qiang reluctantly complied, though he and the others believed this punishment to be worse than death. They meticulously collected the bracelets from each incapacitated warrior before severing their dantians. Soon, the entire group of a hundred men was assembled in the center of the ship. The first phase of their plan was complete; now they needed to assume the identities of the nascent soul masters and participate in the search. With a stroke of luck, they hoped to uncover vital secrets that would ensure an effortless victory in this confrontation.

Chapter 712

"Hm... This is not good."

"What's the matter? Is there something wrong with the bracelets?"

Zhang Liena inquired, her confusion evident.

"It's something like that. These bracelets function in a peculiar manner, rendering them somewhat useless in their current form."

"Useless? Please elaborate."

Liena pressed for more information while Zhang Dong let out a sigh as he carefully examined one of the bracelets. After a moment, he began to explain the issue to Liena.

"These bracelets are merely receptors. They receive a signal from an external source to activate their functionality. Unfortunately, without access to whatever is producing this signal, I won't be able to replicate their effects."

Liena frowned, her gaze shifting to the unimpressive treasure they had spent valuable time acquiring.

"That doesn't bode well. Where is this signal coming from?"

Zhang Dong hesitated for a moment before answering,

"It's coming from that direction."

"That... isn't that...?"

Liena's voice trailed off, realization dawning upon her.

"Yes, it's where they have established their temporary base. I suspect that one of their ships is equipped with a device that emits this signal. This leaves us with a few choices."

Zhang Dong explained, rubbing his chin in contemplation. He refused to let this troublesome encounter go to waste. Although they had pursued one of the enemy ships on foot, all hope was not lost.

"What are our options, Senior Brother?"

Huo Qiang chimed in, his expression noticeably more cheerful than Zhang Zhi's grave countenance. The two had just finished disposing of the hundred or so core formation experts, leaving them secluded in a cave where they would awaken long after Zhang Dong's group had departed.

"Our first option is infiltration. We assume the appearance of the elders we defeated and infiltrate their main ship. If I can get close enough to the signal source, I may be able to replicate or, if necessary, destroy it."

"Destroy it?"

Liena interjected, her eyes meeting Zhang Dong's. While their initial plan was to rely on the protection offered by the bracelets against the trap formations, disabling the device that rendered the Long Clan army invisible to the beasts and traps in the area seemed like a potentially better option.

"Our second option is to return to our people and utilize these hundred bracelets in battle. It might be possible for me to create a jamming device once our enemies discover us, but..."

"And that sounds dangerous."

"Yes, I'm uncertain if I'll have enough time to counteract the effect."

Zhang Dong admitted. Both he and Liena exchanged knowing nods, aware of the better choice.

"So, what will it be?" Liena asked, awaiting Zhang Dong's decision.

"I hate to disappoint you, Qiang, but I have a different mission in mind for you," Zhang Dong began, anticipating Huo Qiang's displeasure.

"A different mission?"

Huo Qiang raised an eyebrow, sensing that he might not like what Zhang Dong was about to say.

"Yes, I need you to return to our sect. Retrieve our sect members and the elders from that underground maze."

"What? You want me to go back there while you face those Long bastards? Can't Zhi go instead?" Huo Qiang protested, suggesting that Zhang Zhi, known for his unwavering loyalty and obedience, be the one to undertake the mission.

Zhang Dong glanced at Zhang Zhi, knowing he would comply without question. However, there was a reason he didn't want Huo Qiang to be part of the infiltration mission. His old friend simply wasn't suited for such covert tasks. While an exceptional fighter, he lacked the necessary subtlety and could easily give away their true identities with a slip of the tongue.

"To be honest... I'm not sure I can trust you to remain quiet during the infiltration."

Zhang Dong admitted while scratching his nose.

"You don't trust me to be quiet? But Senior Brother!" Huo Qiang protested, his pride wounded.

"Hah, my husband is right. You would reveal our true identities the moment you open your big mouth. It's better if you return."

Liena chimed in, her nose held high.

"Why, you... I can be quiet and deceptive when I want to!"

Huo Qiang retorted, attempting to make himself small and unassuming.

"Hmph."

Liena huffed, unconvinced. Huo Qiang's lack of skill for disguising and his tendency to become overly emotional or enraged made him ill-suited for the task. Now that he had also become a lot stronger he would probably have a hard time lowering his head to Long Clan members of higher authority.

“Our sect needs a capable protector Qiang, this is a mission that only you can perform.”

“Only I can perform?”

Qiang, who just a moment ago was feeling down, quickly straightened his back as he was praised.

"Haha, so it seems I am the only one capable of undertaking this crucial mission. I understand, Senior Brother, you can count on me. I will ensure the safety of our fellow sect juniors."

"I appreciate your understanding."

"He is so gullible... How did such an imbecile surpass me in strength..."

Zhang Dong nodded in agreement, while Liena muttered quietly to herself. Even now, she harbored anger towards someone she had once dismissed as a simple-minded fool, who had managed to surpass her in power. Luckily now that she had reached the great circle of nascent soul as well, there was nothing more that she needed to feel inferior for.

“Good, I’ll bring up the gate. You will appear in the Golden Palace. Remember to not use too much of your cultivation base as the Long Clan members will be searching for you. When you discover gramps just use the item that I previously gave you.”

“You mean this ring, Senior Brother?”

“Yes.”

Zhang Dong nodded as previously he had created various items for his people. This ring had a connection to his Ai Bob and would allow him to know when he reached his destination. He still couldn’t fully use his system to just teleport Zhang Jin out of wherever he ended up. Only through someone like Huo Qiang who made direct contact with his system would it work again.

“Well then, I hope you do well.”

“I won’t disappoint you, Senior Brother!”

A blue gate that looked like a water circle appeared before them. Huo Qiang quickly stepped through it while grinning widely. With him helping to find his grandfather the search would probably not take too long. The man had become similarly strong as an emperor-level threat and would probably not be stopped by anything that this trapping formation threw at him.

“Finally the oaf is gone.”

“At least try to get along with him…”

“Never!”

After giving out a sigh he just smiled as this was just part of his wife's character which he came to love.

“Let us change the subject then. I’ll take on the form of their leader and you change into one of them.”

“Maybe I should use one of the core formation experts instead…”

“It would be better if you retain the appearance of an elder, even if you make a mistake in your act not many will be able to confirm their claims.”

“But…”

There was a small problem. All of the five masters that they defeated were males. The technique that they used was strong enough to alter their bone structure and assume the appearance even of a different sex. He had actually changed into a more womanly appearance back in the past, so he understood why his wife was apprehensive about this issue.

“Maybe I should just go back to the palace along with Qiang, I bet that idiot won’t be able to find Elder Jin…”

“He’ll do fine… I think you should pick this one as he didn’t have a beard. It’s probably better than the baldy at least…”

Liena started going pale while looking at a projection of how she needed to look. Zhang Dong could use Bob to create an image that his two companions could use for their technique. The bodies of the elders had exploded during the fight already. The person that he picked out seemed like the best pick. Two others had large bushy beards and the last one was fully bald. While the technique was able to shift around and create hair it wouldn’t feel too nice.

“Ugh… I’ll be right back, just don’t peek.”

Liena didn’t want her husband to see her changing into an ugly old man. Zhi on the other hand was already changing his appearance. Thanks to the spatial rings these elders dropped they were also able to get replacement robes. Soon they were fully disguised and ready to put on a show.

“Are you ready?”

“... No …”

It was strange to see an old man pout while holding his hands on his hips in a rather flamboyant fashion. His mouth started quivering as he had to use all of his willpower to not laugh at his angry wife.

“You look great, don’t worry we won’t be there for long, and if something happens just run. I’ll contact the Long Clan now, and remember to play along.”

Soon the group was ready to put on a show. The plan wasn’t difficult; they would pretend that they went through a massive battle with the United Element Sect. The ship the other group occupied was already destroyed and the core formation experts were far away.

“There has been a problem, we have been attacked!”

Through the use of the Long Clan’s communication jades, he was quickly able to reach the main armada. These devices could transfer spiritual energy that was then turned into something similar to sounds that only cultivators could perceive with their senses.

“Is it the Golden Dragon?”

“Yes, he has appeared, he destroyed our ship and killed all the juniors me and two other elders were able to escape.”

“You let him escape? Never mind, return to the temporary base, now!”

“Of course…”

Zhang Dong impersonated the elder who created the flaming horse as best as he could. He did not know the relationship these people had with each other but at least for now, it didn’t seem like their identities were revealed.

“That should do it, he didn’t ask many questions so I think it should be fine. Let us depart.”

The trio of leaders nodded at each other while departing from the flaming wreck that they created. The bracelets that they grabbed from the core formation experts had been given to Qiang. At least some of their people could still use their effects in the coming battle. They on the other hand would infiltrate the enemy forces and perhaps give them the edge over them that they needed.

Chapter 713

"Elder Jing! Please explain what happened."

"We were attacked... and unfortunately, we lost all of the juniors. Only the three of us managed to survive."

"So, you lost both the ship and the juniors?"

"We were helpless. The traitor we encountered was even more ruthless than the rumors suggested. He lured us into a trap, some type of demonic formation that rendered our ship useless…”

The three elders from the long clan found themselves being interrogated by a larger group that had arrived on their own ship. This group consisted of a hundred experts in core formation and five masters in nascent soul cultivation. Four of them were in the late stage of nascent soul, while one had reached the great circle. In order to hide their true identities, the three individuals, including Zhang Dong, disguised themselves. Meanwhile, Liena and Zhi, who were with Zhang Dong, remained silent and pretended to be injured.

As Zhang Dong recounted the fabricated story of their defeat and the loss of their juniors, the Long Clan members listened with a mixture of concern and frustration. The loss of their ship and the young talents was a significant blow to their forces. The three disguised intruders, however, kept their expressions carefully controlled, maintaining a facade of defeat and exhaustion.

"I can't believe the Golden Dragon managed to catch us off guard like this,"

One of the nascent soul masters remarked with a scowl.

"Elder Jing, do you have any information on his whereabouts? We need to regroup and plan our counterattack," another elder inquired.

Zhang Dong, in his Elder Jing disguise, shook his head, feigning disappointment.

"I'm afraid not. He was like a phantom, attacking us swiftly and disappearing just as quickly. He seemed to know our tactics and formations well."

The elder's face grew darker.

"This is a grave situation. We must report back to the main base immediately. If what you say is true, then it would be unwise to pursue that traitorous scum. It bet he is just waiting for us to make another mistake, just using cheap tactics to prolong this farce!”

As the discussion continued, Zhang Dong took the opportunity to scan the faces of the Long Clan members around him. He was searching for any signs of recognition or suspicion. So far, it seemed that his disguise was holding up. The leader of this ship was quite mad at the thought of his people being defeated so easily but also frightened.

It was evident that the old man's primary concern lay with his own safety and the well-being of those aboard the ship. With the knowledge that two nascent soul elders had already perished, he couldn't help but consider the possibility of facing a similar fate. It seemed wise to relay this critical information to the main base and request reinforcements before proceeding any further.

After all, there was strength in numbers, and these individuals were not accustomed to such intense confrontations. The Long Clan had enjoyed a reign of power for over a hundred thousand years, largely unscathed by adversity. Perhaps they were complacent in their approach, believing that victory would inevitably be theirs if they proceeded cautiously.

Liena and Zhi continued to play their parts as injured elders, skillfully portraying the pain through occasional soft groans and the careful clutching of their wounds. Their acting abilities were truly remarkable, further enhancing the authenticity of the situation. Liena, in particular, had only to take on the role of an old man, but with a specific stipulation, she did not want to be required to speak.

As a result, they had instructed her to feign a throat injury, allowing her to avoid any verbal communication and instead rely on groaning to convey her distress. Fortunately, the arrangement worked well for them, as the elders were not positioned too closely to each other, ensuring they could maintain their facade without suspicion - at least for the time being.

“If this ferocious scoundrel Golden Dragon is this misbegotten then perhaps it will be best to call for help. Elder Jing, how about you return and make the report before the general, I’m sure you’ll be able to explain it better than I ever could.”

"You're right, Elder Yuan. I shall return to the main base immediately and inform the general of our situation. With his guidance, we can strategize a proper response to this threat."

Elder Yuan expressed his satisfaction with the decision, and the other members of the Long Clan agreed. It was evident that they had been greatly affected by the recent events and were eager to regroup and seek guidance from their superiors. With reinforcements on their way, they would soon confront their adversaries who were trapped within the expansive formation.

‘Once we arrive, we must locate the source of the bracelet signal and make a decision.’

Their objective was to infiltrate the main base and reach the origin of the signal. Upon arrival, Zhang Dong would have to determine whether it was more beneficial to reverse engineer the technology or destroy it altogether. If their enemies possessed a protective advantage from these bracelets that his side couldn't utilize, it would be wise to eliminate this advantage. Time was of the essence, as the discovery of the remains of the golden palace was inevitable. Before that occurred, Zhang Dong knew he had to successfully complete this mission.

Despite Elder Yuan's desire to return to the main base, it was not feasible. Doing so would be perceived as an act of evading the confrontation with their weakened enemy. They needed to stay within range and continue their investigation. Fortunately, the personas that Zhang Dong and the others were impersonating had the valid excuse of surviving a near-death experience, granting them temporary reprieve. While a future demotion might be in store, it was unlikely to be overly severe. As a result, instead of returning together, they were provided with a smaller escape boat, piloted by a relatively weaker core formation member.

With Elder Yuan's permission, the three disguised intruders boarded the escape boat. Zhang Dong, as Elder Jing, maintained his appearance of exhaustion and injury, making sure his movements were slow and cautious. Liena and Zhi, in their elderly disguises, followed suit, clutching their fabricated wounds and eating recovery pills. The escape boat slowly departed from the main ship, heading towards what seemed like a safe distance away.

As they continued on their journey, Zhang Dong remained watchful, scanning the surroundings for any signs of danger or potential threats. He understood the formidable strength and resources of the Long Clan and knew better than to underestimate them. It was crucial to stay alert, as they could have devised countermeasures for their disguised forms. If they were to be discovered, escape would be their only option.

After some time, they reached a distance where the main ship was barely visible on the horizon. Zhang Dong activated his system communication feature, using it to speak with both Liena and Zhi who were remaining silent.

‘Listen closely, there is a possibility that once we are there, we will be discovered. When that happens, use the items that I gave you, they will create a teleportation gate to the Golden Palace.”

The Azure Emperor had already demonstrated the ability to block out the system and its escape feature, making it imperative to be cautious. Although it was concentrated in an underground location, there was still a risk of getting captured. However, Zhang Dong took solace in the fact that even if he were to be locked up again, his two companions would still have a chance to escape without him needing to create the teleportation gate.

‘We will all return together, I’m not leaving you behind.’

Replied Liena while producing a scowl on her now elderly visage. When looking black the core formation driver could only sweat as the three scary nascent soul masters started what seemed to be glaring.

‘Not like I’m planning to be left behind, let us focus on the mission for now. We must discover the source of that signal and will decide on what to do then.’

‘Fine…’

‘Of course, Patriarch.’

For a brief moment, Zhang Dong considered opening a private line with Zhi to instruct him to grab his wife when the time came. However, he quickly dismissed the idea. Lying didn't bring him any pleasure, and he genuinely believed that besides the Azure Emperor, no one else posed a real risk. They continued their pretense of meditation for a few hours until they finally reached the main base.

As they approached, Zhang Dong noticed multiple flying vessels resembling the one they had destroyed, scattered around a lake. Among them stood a massive ship, made of a shiny silvery metal, adorned with peculiar pylons protruding from a large mast. It was evident that this ship didn't rely on wind for travel and served a different purpose. In this case, it was the source of the signal they had been searching for.

"As I anticipated..."

Zhang Dong muttered, his brow furrowing as he observed the colossal ship and its imposing spire. The flagship teemed with a multitude of people, making it a challenging target for infiltration or disabling. The protective shield surrounding it was immense, radiating energy in all directions. Even with his considerable power, forcing his way inside would not be an easy feat. Furthermore, if they did manage to breach it, the ship would likely hinder their escape when the time came.

“Elders, we will be arriving at the clan flying fortress in a moment. I have received word that the young lord wishes to see you.”

“The young lord? Do you mean, the Emperor's Son?”

“The same”

Their driver didn’t explain much further as he just didn’t really know. He was given an order that he was going to fulfill. Zhang Dong already met the Emperor’s children and if one of them was here then it could complicate things. Just like he could teleport to his loved ones, there was a possibility that Long Qing could do the same.

‘Prepare everyone, I will go meet with the Emperor’s son, if everyone goes well, I will meet up with you later but if not, I will leave blowing up that massive mast to you…’

Zhang Dong forwarded his message Liena and Zhi, his eyes focused on the looming silhouette of the flying fortress. He could feel the tension building, knowing that their next actions would be critical. They needed to proceed with the utmost caution as getting discovered when inside the main base of their enemy, could lead to their deaths.

Chapter 714

The escape boat softly glided to rest on a platform that extended from the side of the fortress. As they disembarked, a welcoming party of Long Clan members awaited them, led by a youth who seemed to be in his twenties. This young man emitted an aura of authority and self-assuredness, clearly indicating his esteemed position within the clan.

"Ah, the venerable elders have returned,"

The young man greeted him with a smile that didn't fully reach his eyes.

"It is indeed a relief to witness your triumphant survival from that perilous encounter."

'Although not one of the Emperor’s direct offspring, there's an undeniable resemblance...'

Standing before Zhang Dong was a youthful member of the Long Clan. If he had to take a guess, then this person was probably someone related to one of the Emperor’s sons or another close relative. The resemblance in demeanor, despite his young age, was strikingly similar to that of a member of the imperial family.

"Elders, your return is most welcomed,"

The young man said with practiced cordiality, his eyes briefly flickering over their wounded disguises.

"Please, follow me. My father wishes to personally hear your account of the events."

The disguised trio exchanged subtle glances, concealing their apprehension beneath their aged facades. It was clear that the clan had been waiting for their arrival, and the young lord's presence only solidified their suspicion that the situation might escalate quickly. Still, they couldn't afford to show any reluctance or fear. Their cover couldn’t be blown yet perhaps they could minimize the damage if it happened.

“Young master, I will gladly join you at the general’s side but allow my two companions to have rest, their nascent souls have suffered a lot of damage during the fight with that lout Zhang Dong. They need immediate rest, I alone should be enough for this task.”

Zhang Dong laid out his case before the young master, questioning the necessity for all of them to be present. He was assuming the role of the leader, the one likely to do the talking. As the young man's eyes shifted towards Liena and Zhi, who were still struggling with coughs and wheezes, he promptly gave an affirming nod. It was evident that he had little interest in lingering around the elderly and injured individuals, readily embracing the proposal.

Under the watchful eye of the young lord, Zhang Dong accompanied him through the expansive halls of the flying fortress. The interior was opulent and grand, adorned with intricate decorations and impressive displays of wealth and power. As they walked, Zhang Dong maintained his disguise as Elder Jing, portraying an air of weariness and pain that resonated with his fabricated injuries.

The young lord led him to a lavish chamber at the heart of the fortress, where a man who looked around thirty with a commanding presence awaited. This man exuded an aura of authority that marked him as a high-ranking figure within the Long Clan. His expression was stern, his eyes sharp, and he radiated the aura of someone who was used to commanding respect.

‘It’s Long Shen huh? He really is playing up that general role…’

At first glance, the general appeared to be a stern and commanding figure, yet Zhang Dong had crossed paths with him previously. In Zhang Dong’s mind, the general was merely an immature individual trapped in an adult's body. His behavior distinctly conveyed a sense of superiority, requiring significant self-control from Zhang to resist the urge to confront him, holding back from giving him a punch proved quite straining.

"Ah, Elder Jing was it, welcome back."

‘Good, at least he doesn’t really know who I am. Leave it to the Emperor’s kid to not know who he is even directing.’

"I have been eagerly awaiting your return and your firsthand account of the recent events. Now tell me, where did you last see that no good bastard?"

Zhang Dong bowed respectfully, his movements deliberate and calculated to match his guise. Yet, the moment the conversations started Long Shen did not hold back from insulting his good name.

"I deeply regret that we were unable to apprehend the traitor, General,"

Zhang Dong replied, his voice trembling with a mix of feigned exhaustion and respect.

"He was swift and elusive, and his knowledge of our formations caught us off guard. Our juniors fought valiantly, but his cunning tactics allowed him to escape without a trace."

General Long Shen's face twisted into a scowl, his disappointment palpable.

"Useless! All of you! How could you let this scum slip through your fingers? You've brought shame upon the Long Clan!"

Zhang Dong bowed his head, assuming a submissive stance. At this moment, he found it necessary to feign subservience as one of the man's subordinates. The offspring of the Azure Emperor held a disdainful attitude towards him, leading them to naturally criticize the members of their own clan for any shortcomings. While they likely comprehended their own limitations, they felt compelled to maintain an illusion of superiority. Shen, positioned as the next successor to the throne, attracted a significant amount of scrutiny. However, he struggled to handle this pressure, revealing signs of immaturity in the way he now acted.

"I beg your forgiveness, General. We did all we could, but he proved to be a formidable opponent."
"And what of the ship? How could you allow that to fall into his hands as well?"

"The elders and I did our best to defend it, General, but his power and tactics were beyond our expectations. He had knowledge of the ship's mechanisms and rendered it powerless before we could react. We fear that he might have used some demonic techniques, perhaps he had stolen it from that Wang Long."

“Wang Long, that demonic cultivator? Yes, some of our people have talked about that connection, it’s probably true…”

Long Shen's frustration was evident as he started tapping the large king-like throne he was sitting in. He was probably aware of Zhang Dong’s might already and also probably unwilling to seek him out himself. Calling his father over was probably the best way of handling this issue but it would also make him look incompetent. If he was able to take out someone that his father couldn’t handle by himself, then he would have proven himself worthy.

"Send out scouts to track him down immediately, have Elder Jing use this chance to remedy his previous failure."

Long Shen commanded, his tone commanding.

“O-of course, General. I will do everything in my power to track him down and bring him to justice."

Zhang Dong replied, bowing deeply. The way Shen handled the issue didn’t go well with him. He was ordering an injured soldier to go right back to the place of his previous trauma. He knew well that the opponent that they were facing was far too strong for any one Elder to handle.

The only way he could see himself succumbing to this clan would be through them luring him into a smaller trapping formation that sapped his spiritual energy away. Then perhaps he would get surrounded by a bunch of nascent soul elders with heavenly weapons. Just like the one that was standing next to the walls and staring at him.

‘I guess they aren’t as stupid as I thought they were…’

At the outset, he held uncertainty, but the longer he lingered within this chamber, the stronger his sense of alarm became. There were only nascent soul masters in this place and while he was not inside of a formation, the ground could quickly shift into one. His understanding now surpassed that of all others present, rendering the creation of a dynamic formation feasible. Directly below him, a component fitting the criteria lay, and had it not been for Bob's presence, unearthing this reality might have eluded him.

‘Zhi, Liena we have a problem. I think they already knew that it was us from the start. Be calm, I’m fine they have not attempted anything yet but we don’t have much time, on my mark go towards the mast area and destroy it…’

‘They have discovered us? Are you sure?’
‘Yes, I’m just sitting under a formation in the general's chamber and surrounded by at least twenty nascent soul masters. I wouldn’t be surprised if the Azure Emperor wasn’t on his way here already…’

Uncertain of the impending situation, Zhang Dong found himself questioning the unknown. If the Emperor was truly present, it seemed unlikely that he would have entangled his son in this dangerous situation. It could be that Long Shen had only recently realized the pretense of Elder Jing's identity. Maybe the two knew each other and he gave it away by acting strangely. Regardless, Zhang Dong now stood in the heart of the danger, but he too possessed his own set of tools to wield.

‘Now go, destroy it and meet me outside of the ship. I’ll be fine so don’t worry.’

He gave them the order to commence with plan B of just destroying the device that was producing the signal. There was not enough time to reverse-engineer it and he needed Bob to help him with this formation here. It was in the process of changing, probably ready to activate at a moment's notice. Yet now that he had been made aware of it, there were things he could do to turn things around.

“You’re not very good at acting, Mr. General… Is that a little bit of sweat on your forehead?”

“Huh? What do you mean…”

“Did you really think that I wouldn’t notice? You have a lot of gall to put yourself in the same room as me without your daddy there to save you…”

“...”

Long Shen was clearly acting strange and it confirmed his assumptions. If he really didn’t know who he was, then as an elder from the Long Clan he would be considered as crazy. The other nascent soul masters that were against the walls weren’t moving either to correct him. They were clearly afraid to move without being ordered to, a testament to his fame of even being able to contend with their leader the Azure Emperor.

Before they could act and attempt to engage the trapping formation he was standing under, the whole chamber turned red. A loud alarm started going off as the whole ship violently shook around. This was his own cue to move. Zhang Zhi along with his wife had begun their attack and unleashed their spiritual energy. Now while his enemies were confused it was time to make a move.

Chapter 715

Seizing the moment, Zhang Dong unleashed his concealed power. The façade of Elder Jing slipped away, baring his genuine identity. The chamber erupted into a mesmerizing display that would remain etched in the memories of these nascent soul masters. A fusion of diverse hues illuminated the space, with golden lightning reigning supreme while other shades intertwined. An unparalleled tempest of lightning, woven from myriad elemental Daos, was now upon them.

“What is this power? How can he generate this much spiritual energy?”

One of the nascent soul masters, struggling to contain the tumultuous energy, turned to his fellow cultivators. The chamber housed dozens of them, and even the least experienced among them was a late-stage realm master. Theoretically, no single individual should possess the capability to subdue such a large group of cultivators at this level. The sheer numbers present seemed insurmountable; not even their leader, the Azure Emperor, should have been able to handle the situation so adeptly.

"Keep the pressure on! We must detain that traitor at all costs! Initiate the formation quickly."

"General... the formation has already been activated, but something seems amiss..."

"What's the issue?"

"The energy isn't being suppressed. The formation was designed to confine his spiritual energy and draw it away, but instead, it's gathering it throughout the entire chamber and spreading it out... General, we must evacuate immediately!"

An elder who stood near Long Shen shouted urgently. The situation was rapidly spiraling out of control. They had discerned the imposter's identity the moment he had set foot on the ship. Forced to act with minimal preparation, they had summoned the Azure Emperor and isolated him from his companions in an attempt to concentrate on the leader. However, it had become apparent that something was awry. The containment formation in place couldn't control the imposter and was on the brink of detonation.

Zhang Dong continued to pour his power into the chamber, his lightning-infused energy was wreaking havoc on the formation and the nascent soul masters. The room trembled as cracks spread across the walls, and the energy pulsated in chaotic waves. His strategy was clear: create enough chaos to provide a distraction for Zhi and Liena, giving them the opportunity to destroy the signal device and escape the fortress.

Amidst the turmoil, Long Shen's authority wavered. His attempts to command his subordinates to take action were met with confusion and panic. The nascent soul masters struggled to maintain their composure as the oppressive energy within the chamber mounted, rendering them incapable of forming a coherent response.

"Cease this at once!"

Long Shen's commanding voice echoed through the chamber, but his orders were disregarded. The figure within the formation stood unwavering, his stature exuding confidence, just as the fragile barrier burst open. In an instant, the room was engulfed in a cascade of his unbridled energy, leaving the nascent soul masters helpless in its wake. Reacting swiftly, they instinctively leaped backward to shield themselves. Long Shen found shelter amidst the protection of at least five elders. His expression bore a blend of animosity and wounded pride, fueled by his incapacity to bring the situation under control until his father's arrival.

The guards surrounding their general swiftly began to withdraw. Long Shen's status as the clan's future weighed heavily on their minds, urging them to shield him from harm. More than twenty nascent soul masters dispersed throughout the chamber, grappling with the surging chaotic energy as the room trembled with impending explosion. They intended to confront the rogue infiltrator while simultaneously escorting their leader to a safer zone.

"How could this have occurred? Father entrusted me with this mission. We must return and vanquish that demon!"

Long Shen's voice held a mixture of frustration and determination. But before he could push himself into the deathly zone filled with chaotic energies, one of the bodyguards quickly interjected.

"Please reconsider, Young Lord. The Emperor will soon arrive to deal with the traitor. Our best course is to retreat and rendezvous with him."

Though a scowl formed on Long Shen's face, he recognized the wisdom in his bodyguard’s counsel. Even if he and his six companions charged back in, their potential impact seemed limited. The ongoing battle within their own vessel amplified the risk of collateral damage. Explosions echoed in the distance, shedding light on Zhang Dong's ulterior motive for infiltrating their ranks.

"They aim to destroy the main mast! This diversion is intentional. We must redirect our efforts there!"

While Long Shen couldn't match the sheer power of his uncle, Zhang Dong, he understood that not all was lost. Other infiltrators lurked aboard, intent on igniting their signal tower. This tower served as the linchpin of their control over the region, and its deactivation would expose them to swift and relentless assault from the local beasts. The flagship, as imposing as it was, would act as a beacon, attracting an overwhelming horde. This was clearly their plan that could not bear fruit.

With his decision made, Long Shen signaled to his bodyguards, instructing them to guide him towards the main mast. They moved with urgency, their steps punctuated by the constant jarring of the fortress as it was battered by the ongoing clashes of power. The situation was escalating rapidly, and Long Shen's emotions swirled between fury at the attack and anxiety for the potential fallout of their mission's failure.

As they approached the area housing the main mast, chaos reigned. Zhang Zhi and Liena, having taken advantage of the diversion, had managed to reach their destination and were engaging in a fierce battle with the guards stationed there. Their surroundings were a battleground of spiritual energies clashing and explosive discharges. Zhang Dong's diversion had drawn the attention of several guards away from the mast, allowing the couple to engage the remaining defenders in a desperate attempt to halt the mast's destruction.

Long Shen and his bodyguards waded into the fray, unleashing their own formidable powers upon the attackers. The bodyguards moved with precision, their teamwork reflecting years of coordination and training. Long Shen himself unleashed bursts of energy, his nascent soul cultivation evident in the intensity of his attacks. However, the confusion and discord that had spread throughout the fortress had taken its toll on the guards, and their combined efforts were proving to be less effective than they had hoped.

Zhang Dong continued to manipulate the energy within the main chamber, his control over the chaotic currents growing stronger. The very walls seemed to pulse with his power, cracking under the pressure. He knew that he couldn't maintain this level of intensity for long, but his goal was not to defeat all the guards; it was to buy enough time for Zhi and Liena to complete their task.

‘The prince went for Zhi and Liena, I need to trust that they will complete the mission…’

While his power had grown it wasn’t that easy to compete with these many nascent soul masters working with each other. Another issue was that he wanted to conserve his power, his true enemy was on his way here. If he arrived before this was over then it would be up to him to stop him.

“Shit, his here…”

Before him appeared a colossal warning screen, broadcasting the imminent threat. Just as he had foreseen, Long Qing had arrived. His distinctive spiritual energy signature materialized seemingly from thin air, implying his reliance on a form of teleportation technique. This development confirmed the notion that their adversary was restricted from unhindered teleportation within this domain. Had that not been the case, Long Qing would have teleported directly aboard the vessel, not outside of it.

It seemed plausible that breaching the confines of the containment formation was a prerequisite for enabling teleportation. This mirrored Zhang Dong's predicament; while he could create portals to the Golden Palace, he remained unable to traverse back to locations outside the trapping formation. Time was quickly running out but not all was lost.

Tapping into his reserves, he channeled his energy to explosively break free from the confines of the containment chamber. His radiant figure, aglow with a symphony of crackling lightning energies, erupted from the metallic shell that had encased him. The efforts of half the masters striving to subdue him proved futile; drained and overpowered, they succumbed to exhaustion against an adversary of his caliber.

"Long Qing, your presence doesn't go unnoticed! However, this isn't the arena for our showdown. Here, have a little taste of what is to come instead!"

His resounding proclamation resonated throughout the vessel, audible to all on board. His outstretched palm surged forth toward an imposing azure dragon hurtling their way. This technique harnessed a mixture of his diverse Daos, an onslaught that even the Emperor's soul beast struggled to counteract. Faced with the brunt of this assault, the quasi-immortal weapon was called into action once more. Long Qing responded with a forceful thrust, creating a gaping aperture through which his formidable soul beast could traverse.

Aided by the Emperor's swordsmanship, the struggling soul beast managed to force its way through the colossal palm strike, although not unscathed. Nevertheless, the impact had taken its toll. The mast, the pivotal source of the unceasing signal, lay in ruins. The once-sturdy pylons started to collapse, further ravaging the flagship's exterior. In a climactic detonation, the two culprits emerged from the aftermath. One astride a gargantuan watery dragon, the other perched atop an emerald-hued bird that conjured tempestuous storms.

"What held you up?"

Zhang Dong's voice rang out as he fell back, regrouping in the vicinity of Liena and Zhi.

"We had a pesky insect hovering around, trying to be a nuisance."

Liena replied in a slightly annoyed tone.

"I see... Great job. Now, let's make our exit!"

Amidst the debris, Zhang Dong's gaze settled on the bedraggled and wounded figure of Long Shen. The young master was far from deceased, yet the outcome of this clash was evident, he had been soundly defeated. His face was filled with spite and anger but he could do nothing to stop the portal from appearing and the three cultivators from stepping through it.

"You won't escape!"

The Azure Emperor's cry resounded as he hurtled from the horizon like a colossal arrow. Employing his quasi-immortal weapon, he executed another thrust aimed at the teleportation gate. Yet, in a perplexing twist, instead of impaling the white-haired man who had disappeared within it, the weapon shot forth into the expanse, failing to intercept anything. Soon the three were gone and nothing remained but the sounds of strange screams in the distance, with the tower being destroyed the grip on the formation had finally been lost….

Chapter 716

As Zhang Dong, Liena, and Zhi vanished through the portal, they were bathed in a blinding light, leaving behind the chaos and destruction of the fortress. They reappeared in a silent location that they had all seen before. They were now in the portal chamber of the Golden Palace where their people were already waiting for them.

“It’s the Patriarch and the great Elders, they have returned!”

Upon their arrival, they were met with the boisterous cheers of sect members who bowed in respect. It was a refreshing sight to be greeted with such warmth and friendliness. When counting the time dilation inside of the trial tower they had spent more than two years inside of it, one of them just inside of a cultivation chamber without any other souls close to them. But now, with everyone finally gathered, it was time to set their old plan into action and breathe life back into the golden palace.

“At ease brothers and sisters. How are things faring here, can someone give me a detailed report?”

“Yes, Patriarch if you would allow me.”

“Speak.”

The man who stepped forward was the elder whom Zhang Dong had entrusted with the responsibility of overseeing the place after his encounter with Huo Qiang. He quickly briefed Zhang Dong on all the developments that had taken place during his absence. Firstly, the Golden Palace had undergone repairs in several areas, which meant that the expenditure of spirit points would be significantly reduced. Secondly, they had managed to locate and ensure the safety of most of their sect members, although unfortunate casualties had occurred due to the treacherous trapping formation and the ferocious beasts in the vicinity. Lastly, Zhang Dong's grandfather and Huo Qiang were still yet to arrive, their whereabouts unknown.

“He hasn’t been found?”

“Regretfully no Patriarch but several of our masters have returned safely from those underground tunnels, it is composed of a treacherous maze filled with monsters and beasts alike.”

“Hm…”

Zhang Dong glanced at his system, relieved to see it finally functioning properly. Ever since his encounter with Huo Qiang, he could once again track his location. As instructed, Huo Qiang had set off to search for Zhang Dong's grandfather. Given that his junior brother was still healthy and alive, there was no need to panic just yet.

After all, the second strongest man in the sect had become even more formidable after their intense training session within the trial tower. With this newfound power, Zhang Dong had full confidence in his ability to handle any beasts that lurked below. However, the pressing question remained: could Huo Qiang reach Zhang Jin before any harm befell him?

This was not the moment to fixate on the fate of just one individual. Despite successfully evading the relentless pursuit of the Long Clan, they were not yet at their peak strength. The presence of the Azure Emperor within the trapping formation raised concerns that he might have traced their location through the spiritual energy pattern of the teleportation gate. They had to take into account the fact that their hideout was compromised, and time was running short.

‘At least those bracelets are no longer functional. That should buy us some time... but should I proceed with restoring the palace immediately, or should I wait?’

Deep in thought, Zhang Dong contemplated by weighing the urgency of their situation against the potential risks of acting too hastily. If he initiated the restoration process and the golden palace ascended into the skies, they would undoubtedly be exposed. The sheer magnitude of spiritual energy it emitted made hiding within the confines of the trapping formation impossible. However, if he allowed too much time to pass, the enemy armada might arrive, presenting an obstacle to the palace's restoration.

After careful consideration, Zhang Dong concluded that waiting any longer would only increase the risks. His sect desperately needed their colossal flying fortress, the only force capable of standing against the enemy ships. With a resolute determination, he made up his mind: it was time to set the wheels in motion and restore the golden palace, regardless of the dangers it might bring.

“Have you made up your mind?”

“That I did, we will prepare for the final battle and the Golden Palace will rise once more.”

Zhang Liena's smile widened as she nodded, and the cheers of the other sect members erupted around her. They had arrived here with the sole purpose of establishing their dominance within the empire, and their unwavering faith in their leaders remained unshaken. It wouldn't be long before the flying bastion was restored; a mere few clicks on the system screen were all it took to accomplish the task.

As the moments passed, a sense of wonder enveloped the entire place, casting a radiant, golden glow that left everyone in awe. It was nothing short of a miraculous transformation unfolding right before their eyes. The once lifeless engine at the heart of the bastion began to stir, the destroyed egg had reformed itself into a new one. Simultaneously, the once-broken walls seamlessly knitted themselves back together at a pace that defied belief.

The onlookers from the sect stood frozen in place, unable to comprehend the grand spectacle unfolding before them. They had never fathomed that such a breathtaking display of restoration could occur in their midst. The collective gasp of amazement hung in the air, and no one dared to make a move, for they were captivated by this unexplained phenomenon that defied the boundaries of their understanding.

At the same time, Zhang Dong found himself dismayed as he witnessed a steady decrease in his spirit points. He had to go and click through all the areas that this golden palace was composed of. His immediate priority was to repair the engine, for it served as the very heart of their flying fortress. Following this crucial task, he would turn his attention to fortifying the walls and defensive formations, essential for shielding them from the devastating attacks of the spirit cannons.

Fortunately, Zhang Dong had managed to accumulate a substantial number of points during his journey through the trial tower. These newfound resources proved just sufficient to fully restore their central hub of operations. Before long, the Golden Bastion burst into action, its massive form rumbling as it gracefully ascended into the skies.

An ethereal, golden aura emanated from it, coalescing into a protective, spherical barrier enveloping the palace. Swiftly, the walls and towers began to materialize, their impressive structures rising in tandem. The numerous spirit cannons, positioned strategically, awaited the skilled hands of their sect members to operate them. The radiant brilliance of this breathtaking transformation dispelled the concealing fog, pushing it back and allowing them to emerge from obscurity, their presence now revealed to the world.

“Everyone, get back to your posts. We have probably roused all the spirit beasts and demonic beings in the vicinity. They will certainly try to attack us.”

“Yes, Patriarch!”

Every member chosen for this campaign possessed the competence to execute their assigned roles with precision. In just a matter of minutes, they seamlessly returned to their respective battle stations, now focused and determined on their tasks. They stood prepared for the impending arrival of the formidable beasts, ready to face the imminent challenge head-on.

Swiftly, the trapping formation responded to the sudden surge of spiritual energy. It unfolded precisely as Zhang Dong had foreseen; this place displayed a hostile reaction to anything excessively conspicuous, and his palace was comparable to a treasure of near-immortal quality. With a sufficient reserve of spirit points at his disposal, there was potential for further evolution and growth, it could transcend its current size. While it had not reached its full capacity yet, it would have to suffice for the impending battle against the beasts and the eventual clash with the Azure Emperor.

As the Golden Palace settled into its newly restored form, the first wave of spirit beasts and demonic creatures arrived. They were drawn to the immense spiritual energy emanating from the fortress, their instincts urging them to attack. But they were met with a barrage of powerful spirit cannon fire, expertly aimed by the sect members manning the weapons. Explosions rippled through the air as the attackers were repelled, their numbers dwindling rapidly.

Zhang Dong, Liena, and Zhi stood at the forefront, directing the defenses and coordinating the efforts of their fellow sect members. Their teamwork and combat experience were evident as they seamlessly responded to each new wave of attackers. Despite the chaos and ferocity of the battles, their spirits remained unwavering.

With time, the Azure Emperor, having recovered from his earlier encounter with Zhang Dong, appeared on the horizon with a fleet of ships. He gazed up at the Golden Palace, his eyes filled with determination. He knew that the key to his victory lay in seizing control of this formidable fortress. Yet they were not alone, a vast swarm of other spiritual beast soon followed after them and started attacking. They were now incapable of controlling the trap formation and were suffering the same attack as the Golden Palace was.

Thanks to their prior actions, their enemies found themselves caught in a two-front conflict. While the golden palace served as a tempting target for these monstrous adversaries, the arrival of numerous flying vessels gave them another target. In contrast to the formidable defensive capabilities of the United Element Sect's flying fortresses, these vessels lacked similar protection. Consequently, they fared poorly, with some succumbing to merciless beastly assaults, resulting in tragic crashes and casualties among their occupants.

This was the opportunity his people had been waiting for, a glimmer of hope for victory. With their side faring better in defense, they finally had a chance to turn the tide. The tactic was straightforward: they needed to bide their time, maintaining their defensive stance while the relentless horde of beasts continued to hurl themselves at the flying ships of the Long Clan.
Their tactic was seen through rather quickly but this revelation provided no advantage to their enemies. Whenever they approached the Golden Palace, they were met by a group of monsters that simply saw them as better prey than the golden fortress encased in a golden bubble.

The advantageous terrain had unmistakably transformed into a deadly snare for his pursuers. Both he and his counterpart, the Azure Emperor, maintained their cautious approach. A premature dive into the fray would subject them to a dual onslaught of spirit cannons and beast attacks. The decision rested with his opponent, would he plunge headlong into the heart of the battle, wielding the quasi-immortal weapon, or would he opt to watch his forces gradually wither under the relentless assault of the beasts trapped within his own formation?

Chapter 717

The Azure Emperor, a man of pride and ambition, could not afford to watch his forces diminish without retaliation. He understood that time was not on his side; the longer he waited, the weaker his position became. With a steely resolve, he made his choice. He raised his hand, and his fleet of ships surged forward, their cannons blazing as they aimed at the Golden Palace.

The battle escalated into a chaotic maelstrom of energy and violence. Explosions rocked the skies as the spirit cannons of the Long Clan ships fired upon the golden fortress. The protective barrier surrounding the palace shimmered under the relentless assault, but it held. Zhang Dong and his sect members, well-practiced in their roles, continued to operate the spirit cannons with precision, striking back at the enemy vessels.

Meanwhile, the Azure Emperor unleashed his formidable power, sending torrents of azure energy that took on the shapes of dragons toward the Golden Palace. The sky crackled with energy as the two forces clashed in a dazzling display of power and skill. Zhang Dong, Liena, and Zhi stood at the forefront of the defense and aided in keeping the barrier shut. They knew that this battle would determine the fate of their sect and that defending was the best option.

While their enemies did close in and started to surround them, they in turn were being swarmed by packs of flying beasts. The longer the battle raged on, the more their armada suffered damage. Each time a ship crashed, a horde of creatures eagerly awaited anyone who dared touch the ground. Fortunately, their flying fortress possessed strong defensive capabilities, giving them the advantage of time.

As the battle raged on, Zhang Dong couldn't help but think about his grandfather and Huo Qiang. He hoped that they were safe and on their way back to the Golden Palace. Their reinforcements could make a significant difference in this desperate struggle.

This confrontation would not have a quick resolution as the two sides continued to struggle. Hours turned into days as the battle continued unabated. The sky was filled with explosions, and the ground trembled from the roars of the spiritual beasts. Both sides were exhausted, but neither was willing to give in. The fate of the Golden Palace and the future of the United Element Sect hung in the balance.

Yet, one side was at a significantly bigger disadvantage than the other as the Long Clan Armada had dwindled by at least a half. They were performing the usual tactics of trying to slowly whittle down a defensive formation with continuous assaults. However, with Zhang Dong’s system and some spiritual energy reserves he could give back some of that lost energy to prolong this fight that should have ended already. Only now did the Azure Emperor start realizing that he had walked into a battle that he couldn’t win.

Having made his decision, he resolved to unleash his most formidable weapon: the quasi-immortal blade. This ancient relic, dating back to a forgotten era, possessed the ability to penetrate the impenetrable defenses of the golden fortress. Furthermore, it had the extraordinary power to amplify its wielder's abilities to an astonishing degree. In the hands of the Azure Emperor, renowned as the empire's finest swordmaster, it became an unparalleled instrument of destruction.

“So he finally decided to use it…”

Zhang Dong didn’t frown as he was expecting the sword to eventually come into play. It was the only weapon that could turn the tide and if the Azure Emperor continued with this prolonged battle, his people would eventually be wiped out. Before more of their ships were destroyed the man needed to slice through the shield. Hovering at a distance, his sword drawn and surrounded by a whirlwind of spirit energy, the vibrations of his sword intent echoed through the air.

The Azure Emperor's aura intensified as he prepared to strike. His eyes locked onto the golden barrier protecting the palace, determination etched on his face. He raised the quasi-immortal blade high above his head, and it shimmered with an eerie azure glow. With a swift and powerful downward motion, he brought the blade crashing down towards the shield. As the blade made contact with the golden barrier, an explosion of energy rippled through the air. The shield quivered under the force of the blow, but for now it held strong.

“Concentrate everyone, do not let him destroy the defensive formation!”

Utilizing every last of his available spirit points, Zhang Dong fervently shouted commands to his fellow sect members. This critical moment held the potential to determine the outcome of the entire battle. If their shield could be dismantled, their armada of ships would gain the opportunity to advance and neutralize the spirit cannons. The imminent threat of the swarming beasts and the inevitable one-on-one confrontation with the Azure Emperor loomed, but first and foremost, the quasi-immortal blade had to be dealt with.

The initial assault tore through the heavens and anything obstructing its path, yet the protective barrier remained steadfast. Nevertheless, a minuscule fissure materialized at the precise point where the sword had made contact. The potency of this weapon was awe-inspiring, and despite expending the majority of their spiritual energy, they struggled to thwart its advance. Shortly thereafter, the leader of the Long Clan raised his sword once more, intent on targeting the same vulnerable spot, determined to bring the battle to their terms.

‘This doesn’t look good…’

Zhang Dong shifted his gaze toward the condition of his fellow sect members. Nearly everyone, except for Zhang Zhi and Zhang Liena, teetered on the brink of exhaustion. They had exerted themselves to the fullest extent, depleting the majority of their spirit energy reserves. It was evident that, with the impending strike, the barrier would be breached.

‘Huh? Did he do it?’

Before he could make a decision of what to do, his eyes were drawn to a red system window. Without thinking much he started clicking with his finger to produce a teleportation gate. Through it a large group started arriving with his grandfather and Huo Qiang at the forefront. His junior brother had finally been able to safely bring them back to the surface and close enough for a teleportation to be a valid option.
“Qiang? What took you so long?”

“I just got lost for a moment, those caverns were confusing!”

“Well, I’m glad that you are back, hope that you are feeling rested as I need your help.”

“You know that you can rely on me, Senior Brother!”

Huo Qiang smacked his chest with a lot of vigor while spotting the Azure Emperor in the distance. The man was in the process of charging up the next attack and now with some reinforcements, they had some more energy to spare.

‘Bob, are you sure that your calculations are correct?’

‘The possibility of the previous query is at 86,32%’

‘That should be enough…’

Zhang Dong nodded and focused intently on the dilemma at hand. The Azure Emperor wielded a formidable weapon capable of piercing through their shield. Nevertheless, they had managed to intercept it by anticipating the precise point of impact. With the emergence of that minor breach, it was all but certain that the enemy would target the same vulnerable spot once more. If they could successfully defend against it for just a few more rounds, his true plan would finally come to fruition.

The tension in the air grew as the Azure Emperor raised his quasi-immortal blade for another strike, his eyes fixated on the weakening point in the golden barrier. Zhang Dong, his grandfather, and Huo Qiang readied themselves, knowing that this would be the moment that decided the fate of the Golden Palace and the United Element Sect.

As the Azure Emperor's blade descended with incredible speed, the defenders focused their collective energy on reinforcing the vulnerable spot. Their spiritual energy flowed like a river, fortifying the golden barrier just in time to withstand the sword's impact once more. The explosion of energy and shockwaves that followed shook the heavens, but the barrier held.

"Good job, everyone!"

Zhang Dong exclaimed, relief washing over him as he saw the barrier endure the assault.

"Keep it up. We can't let him break through."

The Azure Emperor, frustrated by his inability to breach the barrier, raised his sword for another attempt. But he hesitated for a moment, sensing that something was amiss. The weapon in his hand felt strangely heavy and unresponsive. Yet, the gash had increased in size so he could yield. The victory was before him, with one more strike from his weapon the path would be open and his clan members would swarm the defenseless golden palace.

“It’s now or never, give me all of your strength!”
Zhang Dong issued a commanding call and, for this occasion, positioned himself directly behind the newly formed gap in the barrier. Zhang Zhi, Liena, and Huo Qiang swiftly rallied behind him, combining their strengths to bolster his own. Their collaborative synergy had significantly improved during their time spent in the trial tower. A surge of power coursed through his being as he conjured a luminous sword, ready to intercept the approaching azure light.

The azure blade descended once more, but this time, as it made contact with the golden barrier, something extraordinary happened. A burst of white energy escaped from Zhang Dong’s own sword and collided with the opposing force. For a moment the two sources of energy struggled with each other but in a sudden burst, they both canceled each other out.

"What? How is this possible? What have you done?"

The Azure Emperor roared in disbelief at his strike not being able to penetrate through the golden wall again. Instantly as if out of anger he raised his sword once more. Zhang Dong looked to be out of breath and so were the three elders that provided him with the energy to make this miracle happen. However, before the man could perform another attack something unexpected happened, the quasi-immortal weapons started cracking and suddenly exploded into thousands of pieces.

The explosion of the quasi-immortal blade sent shockwaves through the battlefield. Fragments of azure energy rained down like deadly shards, scattering in all directions. The Azure Emperor staggered backward, his expression a mixture of shock and disbelief as his most potent weapon disintegrated before his eyes.

“How could the Emperor’s blade be destroyed, it existed since before the Empire was established…”

As the remnants of the azure blade faded away, the Azure Emperor's forces were left in disarray. Without their leader's formidable weapon, their morale wavered. The tide of the battle had shifted, and it was now the United Element Sect's turn to go on the offensive…

Chapter 718

With the destruction of the Azure Emperor's most powerful weapon, the balance of power on the battlefield shifted dramatically. The United Element Sect seized the opportunity to press their advantage. Zhang Dong, his grandfather, Zhang Zhi, Liena, and Huo Qiang led the charge, their spirits renewed with hope.

While they were in high spirits, not everything was going their way. After the last collision of spiritual energy, the massive golden shield surrounding their fortress had been mostly destroyed. They were now vulnerable to an attack, and their spirit cannons started receiving hits from the enemy ships. However, their adversaries were in a much more dire state, as their treasured weapon had turned to nothing but dust in the wind.

The defenders unleashed a relentless barrage of spiritual energy and spirit cannon fire upon the remaining Long Clan ships. Their precision and coordination started to overwhelmed the enemy, causing chaos and panic among their ranks. The skies once filled with azure ships now turned into a chaotic battleground where the Long Clan was desperately trying to regroup.

Zhang Dong and his allies made their way towards the Azure Emperor, who was reeling from the loss of his weapon and the sudden shift in the battle's momentum. The sect members of the United Element Sect followed their leaders, emboldened by the turn of events and eager to claim victory.

“Leave him to me, take care of those pesky flies buzzing around him.”

“Of course!”

Huo Qiang responded to the order that had been issued by their patriarch. Everyone present desired to witness the confrontation between the two most formidable fighters, yet many also wished to avoid being caught in the middle of this clash. It was a battle between the two mightiest individuals, one that might determine the fate of both sects. While the United Element Sect cheered for their leader, the Long Clan was determined not to let their Emperor face the challenge alone. They encircled him with numerous nascent soul masters at the great circle.

The battlefield transformed into a chaotic arena, with the Azure Emperor standing at the center, encircled by his loyal followers, while Zhang Dong faced him with his own sect members by his side. The clash between the two forces was imminent, and the tension in the air was palpable.

Zhang Dong's eyes locked onto the Azure Emperor, his determination unwavering. He had come a long way on his journey of cultivation, and this moment was a culmination of all his efforts and sacrifices. His grandfather, Zhang Zhi, Liena, and Huo Qiang stood by his side, ready to support him in any way they could.

The Azure Emperor, on the other hand, wore a grim expression. He had never faced an opponent like Zhang Dong before, and the destruction of his quasi-immortal blade had shaken his confidence. But he was not one to back down from a challenge. With a deep breath, he stepped forward, his aura radiating power and authority.
"Zhang Dong my younger brother, you have proven to be a formidable adversary,"

The Azure Emperor declared, his voice resonating with a mix of respect and determination.

"But don’t think that destroying my blade changes anything, this battle is far from over and as always, I will be victorious."

Zhang Dong nodded in acknowledgment.

"I understand, brother. Let us settle this once and for all."

With that, the two titans of their respective sects clashed in a flurry of strikes and energy. The battleground became a whirlwind of power, with each move they made sending shockwaves rippling through the air. Their attacks were precise and deadly, and the onlookers could barely keep up with the speed of their exchanges.

The battle was fierce and relentless. Zhang Dong's martial arts prowess and mastery of elemental techniques were matched by the Azure Emperor's swordsmanship and profound spiritual energy manipulation. It seemed that the combatants were evenly matched, but soon enough people recognized that one of them had an obvious advantage.

Zhang Dong wasted no time as he forcefully propelled his older brother backward. Deprived of the quasi-immortal blade, the Azure Emperor found himself on a level playing field with other Emperor-level opponents he had previously encountered and conquered. His journey to the trial tower had transformed him, propelling him far beyond what should be possible. He now approached a realm never seen before, transcending the boundaries of the nascent soul realm.

This profound advancement became evident through Long Qing's futile struggle to land a single blow, a struggle that ultimately proved in vain. In a swift and electrifying moment, Zhang Dong executed a lightning-infused kick, impacting Long Qing's solar plexus with devastating force. The powerful blow sent his brother hurtling backward, crashing into one of the nearby ships.

‘This battle is not something he can win without that weapon, does he have something else up his sleeve or can I end it now?’

While Long Qing was down for the count, he continued to survey the battlefield. The remaining elders were engaged in fierce combat against The United Element Sect's forces. The Long Clan maintained an advantage in terms of the number of nascent soul masters. Huo Qiang valiantly took on ten adversaries single-handedly, while Zhang Zhi and Liena faced off against five opponents each.

Despite their collective efforts, the opposing side showed no signs of relenting, and victory remained elusive. The most pressing concern was the ever-present and ominous threat of the Empress, who concealed her identity as an Overseer. Would she intervene if he attempted to end Long Qing's life, or would she allow him to complete the gaming scenario?

“Protect the Emperor!”

As he hesitated, his chance at victory dwindled. The Azure Emperor swiftly retreated, materializing beside his formidable flying ship, a vessel that, while not quite as massive as the Golden Palace, still stood as a magnificent creation crafted from spirit metals. His hand clung to the point of impact, which continued to pulsate with crackling golden lightning energy. Even someone of his extraordinary skill and power struggled to expel the elemental energy coursing through his body. It became evident that without the aid of his weapon, this battle would prove far from simple, and his chances of prevailing were diminishing rapidly.

“I probably won’t be able to convince you but let me try. Long Qing, surrender. Let us end this useless conflict, you won’t be the Emperor anymore but you may keep your life and your children will too.”

Zhang Dong's voice echoed across the battlefield, ensuring that every combatant could hear his call. While this granted his foes a momentary respite, the ongoing clash favored the United Element Sect unmistakably. Had they faced off in an open field, the outcome might have skewed differently. However, trapped within this confining formation, their forces had been significantly reduced due to relentless beast attacks, leaving them unable to sustain the fight any longer.

“You want me to surrender?”

“Yes, don’t be a fool, you must have realized that you are not my match. Without that weapon of yours, you have no chance at victory!”

Long Qing could not deny this fact anymore. Zhang Dong has already proven to be above him when it came to cultivation power. Even though he was a more experienced fighter, it didn’t do him any good when he just couldn’t react to his enemy’s speed and power. Without using some other means, he could not win an outright clash.

“Do you really think I will believe that you will let us live? Do you really take me for such a fool?”

“Please reconsider, you have my word, and your family will be spared. I’ll give you some land where you may live with them in peace…”

“Live in peace? I think not.”

Zhang Dong frowned as his brother didn’t seem to see reason. This was not surprising as normally only death awaited the one that had lost. The other option was getting robbed of their cultivation base which Long Qing assumed would happen. His children were all over a hundred years old. If all of them were stripped of their spiritual energy, they would not live for much longer. It was still a death sentence to a cultivator and no one would take that deal.

“You underestimate my and the Long Clan’s power! This has gone on for long enough!”

As those words left the Azure Emperor’s mouth something started shifting in the air. The entire trapping formation started rumbling and even the beasts that were throwing themselves at everyone halted. Everything rippled for a moment and then started to slowly unravel. The potent spiritual energy that was around this place started vanishing and with it the whole environment changed.

‘Did they disable the trapping formation?’

Zhang Dong had underestimated his opponent. He had wrongly assumed that this entrapment formation was an ancient relic of the past, meant to be dormant and inaccessible for use, as evidenced by the uncontrollable spirit beasts. However, it became apparent that they held control over the central spirit vein, likely the key to the formation's operation. It was conceivable that they had disrupted its flow, effectively deactivating the entire formation.

“Turning off the formation doesn’t change anything!”

He shouted at his brother who just smiled. There was something wrong with this picture and he couldn’t let his opponent get ahead. Zhang Dong quickly rushed at the juggernaut of a ship and collided with its energy shield. Even as he was concentrating all of his energy, the shield was not budging fast enough. His enemy the Azure Emperor made a motion with his hand to produce a portal through which he started slipping through.

“Come find me in my city and see if the Long Clan is still weak!”

“Are you running away?”

“Running? No, this was just a small taste of what is to come.”

Soon the other nascent soul elders started vanishing from the battlefield. The ships that were still operational became abandoned and devoid of any living beings. Then suddenly they all started exploding while producing some type of strange green fog. Without thinking he quickly produced a massive shield to block this out and ordered everyone to retreat.

“I didn’t expect the Emperor to be such a coward!”

Called out Huo Qiang who mimicked Zhang Dong’s actions. The green miasma that was produced was clearly a cloud of poisonous fumes. Anyone who dared to touch it would quickly succumb to an illness of unknown proportions. Luckily this was just a badly planned solution to mask the Long Clan’s escape. The ones that suffered were their own forces that didn’t all have teleportation talismans on them.

The air was filled with the groans of many people who descended to the ground like rocks. Their bodies were turning green and their eyes along with their veins were popping out. It was clear that their enemies cared more about winning than their own people and to end this fight they would need to gather at their main lair, the capital of the Empire.

Chapter 719

‘So, there they go, but now what?’

Zhang Dong observed the changing scenery as the trapping formation had its energy source severed. The beasts that had once populated the area began dissolving into white smoke, and the skies gradually cleared. Before long, all that remained was empty grasslands, as if the previous place had never existed.

‘The phantom of the formation still feels tangible... It's as though it's merely shifted into another dimension.’

With his extensive knowledge of formations, Zhang Dong couldn't help but draw parallels to the immortal-grade medallion he had discovered many years ago. The moment his people crossed through the gate, they were thrust into something akin to that experience. However, this formation didn't create a new world; rather, it transported everyone into an already existing one.

"We can't let them get away with this,"

Zhang Jin’s voice sounded from afar as he said with determination.

"We need to pursue them to their capital and put an end to this once and for all."

They were victorious in defeating the Azure Emperor and forcing the Long Clan to retreat, but it was clear that the conflict was far from over. The Long Clan had not been defeated; they had simply regrouped and escaped. This left them with a decision to make, would they pursue their last enemy or regroup with their forces and create a new plan of action?

"It won't be easy. The Long Clan is resourceful and powerful. We should also be prepared for any traps or ambushes they might have waiting for us."

Zhang Liena responded to his grandfather as the elders gathered, and soon, everyone voiced their opinions. Some suggested taking a break to further fortify the Golden Palace. They were concerned that if they continued on their current warpath, they might incur major losses. However, others believed that their enemies were teetering on the brink of defeat. With their entire armada lost and huddled in their flying city, this might be a unique opportunity that would be lost if they decided to retreat.

"We need to be cautious, but we can't let fear paralyze us. Our sect's future is at stake here. If we leave now, there might never come a chance to regain our freedom. Remember what the Long Clan is capable of, if they retain access to the central spirit vein, the whole Empire will dry up."

The elders nodded in agreement with Zhang Jin's wise words. Previously, the Long Clan had somehow managed to reduce the concentration of spirit energy by tampering with the central spirit vein. If they persisted in this course of action, most regions within this vast empire would soon lack the Qi required for cultivation.

While the United Element Sect possessed its own concealed vein, it did not necessarily mean that it wasn't connected to the central one. However, that wasn't the main issue at hand. The concern was that other sects and clans would start blaming them for this crisis. The Azure Emperor was still widely regarded as the most powerful individual alive. If they chose to retreat, it would essentially confirm his dominance, potentially swaying others to join his side in the conflict.

As cultivators with lifespans of up to a thousand years, waiting for the Azure Emperor's demise didn't present a significant obstacle. In fact, it could be a viable strategy. They could patiently bide their time while the Long Clan waited, gradually expanding their influence into the upper regions. They could potentially conquer everything, including the eastern region, if they so desired. With time on their side, they could amass formidable armies, to the extent that none of their initial sect members would even need to engage in direct combat themselves.

Even if the spirit energy continued to diminish, they could potentially find solutions with the assistance of Zhang Dong's system. It was conceivable that another spirit vein was awaiting their discovery, or they might even be able to create an underground tunnel to connect to a different vein. There were numerous ways to address this issue, potentially in a safer manner. However, there was a lingering uncertainty. Their enemies might return with greater power and ferocity than before, rendering all their efforts futile.

“That would be concerning but do you think we stand a chance against that flying city of theirs? I’ve heard that it stood for more than a hundred thousand years, it is probably another immortal relic…”

Feng Maling who was trapped along with Zhang Jin appeared from behind one of the other elders. Ever since reaching the nascent soul level, she regained some of her youthfulness but her face was still full of wrinkles.

“Don’t we also have an immortal relic?”

Replied Zhang Jin while looking at the huge floating Golden Palace. It had managed to survive the quasi-immortal blade that the Azure Emperor wielded. The defensive formation suffered an overload but it was still intact, within a day or two their fortress would be fully operational. They would still need around that time to even get to the Empire's Capital and with the help of portal technology they could call in reinforcements as well.

“That’s true, we might stand a chance…”

The discussion continued among the elders and leaders of the United Element Sect. Zhang Dong, his grandfather, Zhang Zhi, Liena, and Huo Qiang listened carefully, knowing that the decision they were about to make would shape the fate of their sect and the entire Empire.

“Patriarch, what do you think?”

As always, the people looked to him as their leader and the linchpin of their entire strategy. If he believed there was no possibility of victory, they would immediately retreat and seek a peaceful resolution. Zhang Dong understood that his brother and the Long Clan were unlikely to favor a peaceful resolution. They were accustomed to being the dominant force in the region, and there was no room for two such formidable entities.

“I feel that if we retreat now, we will probably regret it. Our enemy has suffered nothing but losses and our troops are mostly intact. The Azure Emperor has fled instead of confronting me, he is not my equal.”

“Senior Brother is right, if that bastard didn’t fear us, he would have remained here!”

"That's true, but it would be foolish to assume we won't encounter any resistance. We must exercise caution, Patriarch!"

Feng Maling chimed in once more, her worries apparent. It was evident that the Long Clan was a cunning adversary, and there was a possibility that the Emperor was luring them into a trap.

"Granny Maling speaks the truth. They will likely be prepared with all they have. They have a whole city backing them, but... I still believe it's a chance we can't afford to pass up."

Zhang Dong continued, his fingers absently scratching his chin. A determined gleam sparkled in his eyes, a resolve he hadn't felt in a long while. He had once been inside that city's walls, and aside from the defensive formation, the interior didn't seem all that formidable. The inhabitants within were relatively weak, as the Long Clan preferred a smaller group of elites that had probably mostly perished in the recent battles.

Most of them had never experienced the extended battles and wars that his people were already accustomed to. All they needed to do was breach their primary defenses for it to be a victory. Once Long Qing was defeated, his people would quickly surrender. They were the type to unwaveringly follow the absolute authority of the Azure Emperor. If he managed to defeat his older brother, they wouldn't oppose him, and his bearing of the Long Clan's name would only facilitate matters. They would likely accept this defeat under the presumption that their dynasty still stood strong, viewing it as an internal conflict between two brothers.

"We pursue them to their capital, but we must be cautious and strategic. The Long Clan is wounded, but they are not defeated. We'll need to gather our forces, prepare for any traps or ambushes, and approach this with a plan."

Zhang Dong stepped forward, his voice filled with unwavering determination. The other elders and sect members began nodding in agreement, their cheers echoing in the air. To them, this was an opportunity to leave their mark on the world. They all aspired to become the world's strongest sect, and to achieve that goal, they needed to topple the ancient giant that was the Long Clan. After a string of victories, they were now firmly convinced that their patriarch could lead them to this promised land. There was no hesitation, only anticipation for the day they would become legends.

"Good, I see that most, if not all of you, agree with me. Then, we shall return to the Golden Palace. We must restore it to working order. Send out scouts in the direction of the city to ascertain the Long Clan's plans…"

He started barking out orders as the decision was made, and the United Element Sect began preparations for their journey to the Long Clan's capital. They sent out scouts to gather information about the enemy's movements and fortifications, and they fortified the Golden Palace to ensure it was ready for battle.

As they set out on their journey, they knew that the road ahead would be treacherous. The Azure Emperor and the Long Clan were not to be underestimated. However, the United Element Sect was fueled by their determination to protect their sect, their region, and their way of life. They would face whatever challenges came their way with courage and unity, just like their Patriarch had taught them.

First, they dispatched messengers to their main sect in the depths of the lower region. While they had brought a substantial army, some individuals had stayed behind to safeguard Spirit Spring City. With the decisive battle approaching, they now decided to summon their reserve masters and troops. Additional flying vessels would soon be arriving, but the ones they had arrived in were also present. Similar to the Golden Palace, they had been rendered useless upon entering the trapping formation. Nevertheless, some of them could still be salvaged and put to use in the impending battle.

Within a few hours, an abundance of new cultivators arrived on the scene, ready to tend to any potential injuries and strengthen their forces. Their presence invigorated everyone on the battlefield. A sense of unity and determination washed over the sect members. They knew that this battle would not only decide the fate of their sect but also the fate of the entire empire. The stakes were high, and the challenges ahead were formidable, but they were ready to face them head-on.

This could very well be the culmination of all of Zhang Dong's adventures. His way of life was distinct from that of the people native to this world, but he had managed to find a place among them. With his lovely wife at one side and his friends on the other, he would finally put a stop to this war, once and for all.

Chapter 720

As the United Element Sect prepared for their journey to confront the Long Clan in their capital, a flurry of activity filled the Golden Palace. The atmosphere was charged with anticipation and determination. Zhang Dong and his core group of supporters, including Zhang Jin, Zhang Liena, and Huo Qiang, gathered in a large meeting chamber to discuss their strategy in detail. They were the three prime elders and were the deciding factors for the upcoming battle.

"It's essential that we gather as much intelligence as possible about the Long Clan's defenses and Long Qing. We need to know what we're up against and plan our approach accordingly."

Zhang Dong commented while Liena nodded in agreement.

“We dispatched our most skilled scouts to discreetly infiltrate the area surrounding the Long Clan's capital. They should be returning shortly with more information, it seems that they have at least retreated for the time being and aren’t planning any counter-offensives.”

He nodded at her response as they continued with the conversation, Huo Qiang just acting like a fly on the wall as he didn’t really care for the strategy. Instead he just wanted to finally contend with more of the Long Clan masters.

“It does look like they are ready for a more defensive battle but let us wait for the information to arrive before making a decision. We shall focus on gathering every abled body sect member to aid us, we will also include every other sect and clan that we have access to. We must remind them that if we fall, then their current wealth of resources will fall with us.”

While the scouts embarked on their covert mission, the rest of the sect members worked tirelessly to repair and fortify the Golden Palace. The defensive formation was reinforced, and its various offensive capabilities were tested and improved. It was clear that the Golden Palace would play a pivotal role in their upcoming battle.

Days passed as they gathered intelligence and made the necessary preparations. The scouts returned with valuable information about the Long Clan's capital, which allowed Zhang Dong and his team to formulate a detailed plan of attack. They discovered that Long Qing had indeed taken refuge in the city, which was heavily fortified with powerful defensive formations.

“It looks unassuming at first…”

“You speak the truth, Patriarch. It’s probably a trap.”

Feng Maling commented, and Zhang Jin, who stood beside her, nodded in agreement. After days of meticulous preparation, they had at last arrived at the doorstep of the Long Clan. Their location was a mere fifty kilometers from the capital city, and they had exhausted every resource within their sect to reach this point. Numerous flying ships hovered around the colossal golden palace, resembling a swarm of flies. Their armada was nearly as impressive as the one once belonging to the Long Clan.

Only half of those ships were actually owned by their sect; the rest had been acquired from various vassal sects and clans residing in both the lower and upper regions. Following the United Element Sect's numerous triumphs, some inhabitants of the empire were eager to collaborate, desiring to play a role in toppling the Long Clan's long-standing rule.

Many harbored dreams of acquiring treasures during the city's raid, but there were other motivations at play too. The Long Clan's behavior during previous attacks from other empires had revealed their unwillingness to treat fellow inhabitants as equals. They readily abandoned territories and offered no assistance to those in need. In contrast, Zhang Dong's sect had stepped in to fill the void, demonstrating their competence as emerging leaders who were genuinely willing to aid the less powerful.

There were even individuals from the eastern side. Despite the Heavenly Crane Sect's proclamation of neutrality, they discreetly provided a few of their own ships that couldn't be traced back to their faction. Some hidden masters from their ranks also joined the impending battle, contrary to their council's decision. These renegades believed that the forthcoming future would certainly be golden and not azure anymore.

Furthermore, support extended from outside the Empire as well. A contingent of golden knights, accompanied by a formidable wizard, formed a formidable fighting unit. Zhang Dong had sought their assistance, initially met with reluctance, as they had no interest in clashing with the Azure Emperor. However, their inability to locate all the necessary artifacts eventually led to their agreement. Once the Long Clan was defeated, they could resume their search in the central region without hindrance.

It seemed that having some mercy when traveling on the path of the cultivator had it’s merits. People that would usually not trust others to hold up their part of the deal, could look at the history and make an informed decision. Everyone involved with this fight knew that the United Element Sect was just and that the rewards would be given to everyone. If not from the Long Clan then from the United Element Sect directly.

It appeared that practicing some degree of compassion along the cultivator's path had its advantages. Those who might typically harbor doubts about others upholding their end of the deal could examine the sect's history and make informed choices. All those engaged in this battle understood that the United Element Sect operated with fairness, and rewards would be distributed to all. If not provided from the Long Clan loot, then instead directly from the United Element Sect’s safe.

Thanks to the scouts who could relay real-time information, they possessed a detailed image of the enormous capital city. Zhang Dong had visited this metropolis before, familiar with both its interior and exterior, which added to the perplexity of the situation. Firstly, there appeared to be nothing in its vicinity. In the past, numerous flying ships had patrolled the area, but now it lay barren, devoid of any activity. It was challenging to discern from this vantage point, but it also seemed as though the area lacked signs of life, as if the entire place had gone into seclusion.

The city's image hung in the air, a sight witnessed by every elder in this chamber. Both of his disciples had earnestly implored him to join the battle, but he had no choice but to decline their plea. The warpath was fraught with danger, with too many of their fellow sect members at risk, and he needed to ensure the safety of these two young disciples in case of a loss. Zhang Xue and Liu represented the potential future of their sect, and if something were to happen to him, they were the only ones he could truly entrust with his legacy and children. It might have been a selfish reason, but as the Patriarch, he had earned the privilege to prioritize his own needs to some extent.

"Their city is impressive, but it's not impervious… Yet, it looks like a trap…"

“A trap you say? What do you think it could be, Elder Jin? Perhaps they have abandoned their city?”

One of the other elders inquired, his gaze fixed on what appeared to be nothing more than an empty city. For some among them, the possibility that the Long Clan was not even present crossed their minds. After all, their leader, the Azure Emperor, had not only lost his weapon but had also been forced back by their Patriarch. To many, these were clear indicators that they were on the path to victory. In the world of cultivation, the outcome of a battle was often determined by the strength of the most powerful cultivator, and this fact had played a significant role in garnering support from other clans and sects.

"It's a possibility. The Patriarch mentioned the existence of underground tunnels beneath the city that could serve as an escape route. However, I share your concern that they might simply be biding their time, waiting for us to draw closer."

"Could it be yet another illusionary formation?"

Another elder asked.

"We must exercise caution, the possibility of it being another illusion is valid. We cannot let our guard down."

Everyone among them desired a swift resolution to this conflict, yet none harbored the illusion that the Azure Emperor would capitulate without a struggle. The capital city, it seemed, had remained untouched and impervious to external forces for as long as history recalled. Any attacker had probably been dealt with inside the trapping formation that their troops had miraculously been able to pass. While this marked a monumental achievement, it did not discount the possibility that their adversary possessed other concealed weapons, apart from the one they had managed to breach, they needed to remain vigilant.

"They are undoubtedly biding their time. The ancient legends speak of dire times, a hundred thousand years past when the city ascended into the sky, seeking refuge in a safer location. If their intention was to flee, they wouldn't have stayed here..."

Zhang Dong chimed in, drawing from his knowledge of the ancient records and the history of past conflicts between the empires. He had long assumed that the city had some type of safety measure, perhaps used by the Overseer that used it as the main base. Whenever a scenario fell through they moved the city out of the way and waited until the bridges between empires closed themselves once more.
“If the Patriarch says so, then it must be true.”

The group of seasoned elders continued their strategic discussions, but eventually, the moment arrived for them to take action. They remained vigilant, fully aware of the potential for encountering more enigmatic formations. However, with their collective strength growing stronger by the moment, doubt about their ability to overcome such obstacles had dwindled. At last, the counter armada of ships set into motion, their destination set firmly on the capital city, where they believed the Azure Emperor would be found.

As they neared the capital, the sheer scale of the Long Clan's flying city came into view. It was a colossal structure, a floating metropolis that had endured for over a hundred thousand years. The city's walls were made of gleaming azure stones that shone in the sunlight, and it was adorned with intricate carvings and decorative spires. The city seemed impervious, like a fortress suspended in the heavens.

Zhang Dong, standing at the helm of the Golden Palace, observed the city with a mixture of awe and determination. He knew that this would be their greatest challenge yet, but he also believed that victory was within their grasp.

"So, there it is.”

Zhang Dong said quietly, his gaze fixed on the city.

"The heart of the Long Clan's power and perhaps the end of this strange journey…”

Beside him stood numerous friends and cherished family members, their gazes fixed upon the imposing defensive fortress. A multitude of emotions coursed through their minds, but a shared understanding prevailed, in one way or another, the conclusion to this epic tale was finally drawing near…

Chapter 721

As the United Element Sect's armada closed in on the colossal floating city, a tense silence enveloped the Golden Palace. The massive azure walls of the Long Clan's capital loomed ever larger, casting a shadow over the hearts of those aboard the ships. It was a daunting sight, a testament to the Long Clan's centuries-old dominance.

The city's intricate carvings and ornate spires glinted in the sunlight, a stark contrast to the battle-ready ships approaching it. Zhang Dong knew that breaching these formidable defenses would be no easy task, even with their newfound allies and the information they had gathered. He could feel the weight of responsibility on his shoulders, knowing that the fate of not only his sect but also the entire empire rested on their success. Zhang Jin, his grandfather and trusted aid, approached him and spoke with a firm resolve.

"Dong’er, we have come a long way, and we have overcome many challenges together. This might be our final test, and we will face it head-on. The fate of the sect depends on our victory and for all it’s worth it has been an honor to fight alongside you. The heavens have truly blessed me by giving me such a splendid grandson!”

He turned towards Zhang Jin, a man he had encountered at the beginning of it all. The old man had been a source of both trouble and invaluable advice. Without his presence, he wouldn't have been able to navigate the sect's politics effectively. While family matters posed challenges for him, in the realm of battle tactics and advice, Zhang Jin was undoubtedly one of the best.

“It seems you doubt whether we'll all return unscathed. Have more faith in your grandson.”

As the two reminisced about the old days, the armada of ships began to assume formation, meticulously aligning themselves in preparation for the impending assault. Each ship was armed with powerful offensive and defensive arrays. Their crews were primed for battle, ready to confront the inevitable chaos that awaited them.

A palpable mixture of anticipation and anxiety hung in the air aboard each ship, yet there was an unspoken, collective conviction that they could accomplish the seemingly impossible victory. The Long Clan had cast a shadow over the Empire for generations, and their current actions left many in a state of disbelief. They were determined to either carve their place in history by establishing a new dynasty or meet their end in the attempt . This was a harsh reality they had come to accept.

“I have faith! I don’t think any of us would be here if we didn’t have faith in our grand victory… Just imagine, our small Zhang Clan will go down in history as the ones that defeated the Azure Dragon!”

“Don’t forget about the Feng Clan you old bastard, if it wasn’t for us then you wouldn’t be here!”

Feng Maling along with some other elders appeared to chime in. She didn’t seem too happy at Zhang Jin’s words that implied that he was able to achieve all of this with only the Zhang Clan’s help.

“I know you old bat, but it is my grandson that made it all possible and he is of the Zhang Clan!”

“Is he now? Last time I heard, they were calling him Long Dong and not Zhang Dong. I feel bad for that Long Clan woman that you tricked. However, at least your fickle loins managed to be of help for a change…”

“You’re just jealous that it wasn’t one of yours!’

Zhang Jin couldn't help but chuckle as he exchanged a scornful glance with the old raisin. However, they quickly set aside their differences, recognizing that this was not the moment for petty bickering. They were not alone in their presence; all the other elders were there as well. Even Huo Qiao had made a reappearance, accompanied by Huo Qiang's father. Both of them appeared fixated on the massive floating city, which seemed eerily empty and lacked any visible defenses.

“I don’t like this…”

Their entire approach encountered minimal resistance, leading Zhang Dong to raise his hand in caution. Although the entire armada had successfully encircled the city, they remained several kilometers away from where the defensive formation should have been positioned. As the scouts had described, there was a conspicuous absence of any visible inhabitants. The once-thriving city appeared eerily deserted.

‘This should be the right spot, the ground under it is proof…’

Initially, Zhang Dong pondered whether they had stumbled upon a decoy city designed to deceive them. However, as he gazed downward, the unmistakable scar from the massive laser blast met his eyes. The chasm extended for countless kilometers, and he vividly remembered his narrow escape by teleporting to safety. It was the very location where the Azure Emperor had once held him captive, providing irrefutable confirmation of his suspicions. This had to be the exact region where the city resided but everything pointed to some type of trap or event that he was not yet aware of.

‘I really hope that the Overseer isn’t involved yet. Could they have just erased the citizens in the city or did they just evacuate into a safer location?’

Zhang Dong's mind raced as he considered the possibilities. The mysterious absence of the city's population could indeed be a sign of something more sinister. Perhaps the Long Clan had evacuated its citizens to protect them, but it was equally likely that they were preparing for an ambush or used those citizens for something nefarious.

"This is not right. It's too quiet, too empty.”

Zhang Jin nodded as he voiced his opinion.

“We should send out some people to investigate the issue before we proceed…”

“You’re right then I will…”

Before he could finish the sentence he noticed that the group of people were looking at him with concern. His wife seemed somewhat made while Zhang Jin was just shaking his head.

“What are you talking about? Have you not learned anything from the last time you went out alone?”

“I… I see, you’re right… We should probably let someone other handle this issue.”

Zhang Dong had always borne the weight of burdens on his own shoulders, and for the most part, it had yielded favorable outcomes. However, his last attempt had proven disastrous. Nearly meeting his demise at the hands of the Azure Emperor and inadvertently leading some of his comrades into a deadly trapping formation, he had learned a harsh lesson.

While he was forcefully taken inside, it was always possible to keep a distance and arrive at the battlefield a little later, just like his brother did. However, Zhang Dong's approach was different; he refused to use his armies as mere pawns. While his forces struggled under immense pressure, Long Qing would eventually make his entrance. His opponent had no qualms about treating his armies as expendable resources, but Zhang Dong's conscience wouldn't allow such ruthlessness.

He was willing to place himself in perilous situations if it meant saving lives, a trait perceived as a significant character flaw by other cultivators who believed that the strongest among them should be the last line of defense. If he were to perish in a large-scale conflict, it would have profound repercussions. Only as long as he remained alive could the sect continue to operate as the well-oiled machine it had become.

“Very well, send in the special unit first. Let them investigate the issue first…”

Zhang Dong's orders were swiftly carried out. A specially trained reconnaissance unit, composed of skilled cultivators, embarked on small airships and descended towards the city. Their mission was to assess the situation, gather intelligence, and ensure that there were no hidden dangers lurking within the seemingly abandoned metropolis.

It didn’t really sit well with him but too many lives were at risk here. At this stage of his life, he already knew that sometimes sacrifices had to be made and that it was better for these less important people to endanger themselves instead of him who was the sect’s Patriarch and leader.

The small reconnaissance vessel, under the guidance of the cautious elder, advanced with utmost vigilance. They stood prepared for an immediate retreat, equipped with teleportation devices on board. Zhang Dong, too, kept his system window open, ready to expend his spirit points either to hasten to their aid in case of an emergency or to forcefully return them if necessary.

Nevertheless, as they inched closer to the tranquil city, an eerie stillness prevailed. Even when they were a mere hundred meters from where the defensive formation should have activated, there was no sign of any activity. They had anticipated a barrage of spirit bullets or, at the very least, a barrage of verbal reprimands from the Long Clan elders, but there was nothing.

“Did they actually decide to abandon their city and run? But where would they hide? At the Heavenly Crane Sect?”

Zhang Jin stood stupefied, his gaze fixed on the holographic image displaying what their scouts were witnessing. Their people had drawn close enough to discern the eerily vacant streets and buildings. In a place that had once been home to hundreds of millions, there was no trace of life, not even a solitary animal roaming the streets. However, when Zhang Dong examined the scene, he couldn't help but notice something suspicious.

“That looks strange…”

“Did you spot something? Are they hiding in that vast emptiness?”

“No, I don’t think they are there, at least not in the outer city. Take a look at that, doesn’t that seem strange to you?”

Zhang Dong enhanced the image, zooming in on the nearest residential area. As they focused on that area, they finally spotted some discarded items. Initially, Zhang Jin couldn't grasp what his grandson was getting at, but it soon dawned on him.

"Are those... robes and clothes?"

"Yes. It appears the citizens were teleported away, leaving even their clothing behind. By all the scattered items on the ground, it doesn’t look like they were expecting this to happen either…"

As the image grew sharper and clearer, some of the mystery began to unravel. It was evident that some form of teleportation had indeed occurred. However, the crucial question of where the citizens from this city had been transported to remained a puzzling enigma that they needed to solve. However, before they got to this mystery Zhang Dong felt something, without thinking much about it he quickly shouted.

“Order the scouting unit to return, something is coming!”

Chapter 722

The reconnaissance unit, upon receiving Zhang Dong's urgent command, swiftly began their ascent back to the safety of their airships. The tension aboard the vessels increased as they watched the small vessels maneuvering away from the stillness of the abandoned city.

The azure sky above the city began to churn with unnatural energy. A swirling vortex of dark clouds formed, crackling with ominous lightning. It expanded rapidly, casting an eerie shadow over the seemingly abandoned city. The entire armada of ships observed the phenomenon with a mix of awe and fear.

“What is it, were there hiding within it?”

Zhang Jin called out to Zhang Dong who had ordered the scouting ship to quickly return. All of the elders jumped forward as they were ready to fight. However, they still couldn’t see or feel anyone within that large structure. Instead, they saw a strange phenomenon that appeared above the city, which then started to spread through its entirety.

The vortex continued to expand, its ominous energy pulsating and swirling, when suddenly it unleashed a powerful shockwave that rippled outward. This shockwave slammed into the reconnaissance vessel, making it shudder and divert from its intended course. The cultivators aboard fought to regain control as the strange force disabled their airship's spiritual engine.

The vortex began to gather around the entire city, enveloping it in a shroud of spiritual energy. As the darkness deepened, it became increasingly apparent that this technique was rather unsettling. Nevertheless, just before the energy wave emanating from the epicenter could reach the scouting ship, Zhang Dong swiftly activated his system screen. Through the interface, he promptly teleported the people from the ship to a secure location near the Golden Palace, ensuring their safety.

“What is this strange technique… It doesn’t feel natural and can you hear those sounds? It’s like voices…”

“It does sound odd… It's as if they are screaming for help?”

Zhang Dong responded to Zhang Jin, both of them struggling to comprehend the bizarre phenomenon unfolding before their eyes. The entire city was ensnared in an inexplicable storm of unknown energy, its swirling vortex extending farther and farther from its center. This unnatural force even began to influence the ground, sending sizable boulders hurtling into the air. Over time, it became apparent that there was a discernible pattern emerging from the chaos, resembling the outline of a figure.

"Is it taking shape? Are those perhaps intended to be legs and arms?"

Zhang Dong asked while his voice tinged with curiosity and concern. As the city continued its transformation, it became evident that the swirling energy was indeed taking shape, forming massive legs and arms. The ground trembled as if the earth itself was struggling to give birth to this colossal entity. The silhouette of a gigantic golem began to emerge from the heart of the city, and the eerie voices grew louder, resembling a choir of anguished souls.

The central city stood firm at the heart, enclosed within a protective bubble of spiritual energy. This barrier drew in everything from its surroundings, gradually fashioning rocky legs and towering, mountain-like arms that began to take form. It appeared to be utilizing the city as both its core and power source. However, for its head, a different element emerged. An azure palace slowly materialized from within the city, ascending into the sky to complete the construction of this colossal, golem-like entity.

As the city golem rose to its full height, it let out a deafening, otherworldly roar that shook the very foundations of the world. The ground quaked beneath its colossal feet, and the sky darkened further as it extended its enormous arms toward the heavens. It was as if the golem sought to challenge the gods themselves.

“Is this the Goliath that Long Qing mentioned before?”

In the past, Zhang Dong's brother, the Azure Emperor, had mentioned a secret weapon known as the Goliath. Its exact form had always been unknown, but with Zhang Dong's arrival, it was supposed to become operational. As he observed the entity taking shape before them, it finally made sense. However, it became evident that this colossal creation could function autonomously, seemingly independent of Zhang Dong's direct involvement.

“Those voices… did he really do it?”

“Do what? Dong’er do you know something about this strange creature?”

“Not much, think it’s called the Goliath and was supposed to be the Long Clan’s trump card in the battle against the other Empires. However, I thought they wouldn’t be able to activate it without me getting involved and after examining this strange energy, I think that I know how they did it…”

Zhang Dong employed his spirit sense and relied on Bob to delve deeper into this perplexing mystery. The unsettling question concerning the fate of the city's inhabitants was swiftly unraveled. It appeared that they had been transformed into a peculiar form of power source, akin to batteries. The eerie cries emanating from the energy field were, in reality, the anguished screams of these people, expressing their indignation. To Zhang Dong's astonishment, they were all alive and had been harnessed to activate this clandestine trump card of the Long Clan.

“They used the people to power this gigantic monster? Are they all just souls now?”

“I’m not sure, they could be trapped inside of the city and still be alive…”

Zhang Dong's heart sank as he realized the horrifying truth. The Long Clan had sacrificed countless innocent lives to power the Goliath, a colossal monstrosity that now stood before them, a symbol of both awe-inspiring power and unfathomable cruelty. It was unknown if any of the citizens were still alive but that would not stop him from trying to help.

"We have to stop this."

Zhang Jin declared, his voice filled with determination.

"We can't let this abomination continue to exist, and we must find a way to free those trapped souls."

The other elders nodded in agreement, their faces etched with a mix of anger and sadness. They couldn't stand by and allow such an atrocity to persist. But the task ahead was daunting. The Goliath was a formidable opponent, and they had no idea how to disrupt the energy field that bound it together.

Zhang Dong found himself taken aback by the reaction of his fellow cultivators. Typically, individuals like them were not known for their concern for the weakest members of their circles. Yet, he couldn't fathom the idea of them willingly sacrificing their own city or sect merely to secure victory in a single battle. The actions of the Azure Emperor indicated a willingness to employ his citizens as fuel for this victory, raising questions about his true priorities. It seemed apparent that he held a deep attachment to the core of his clan, securely concealed within the Azure Palace residing in the head of the Goliath.

“The Azure Emperor has revealed his true colors, he is not any better than the demonic cultivators we defeated in the north! When faced with opposition, this is what he chooses!”

Zhang Dong listened to his wife's words while his mind was racing. This gigantic enemy was quite strong, probably stronger than the quasi-immortal blade that he had to face before. However, there was an obvious weakness that this thing possessed and thus he turned to Bob for some advice.

‘Bob, can you analyze the energy field surrounding the Goliath? Is there any way we can weaken it or find a vulnerability?’

Bob's monotone voice sounded in his mind as the monstrous form of the Goliath continued to take shape.

‘Analyzing... It appears that the energy field is being sustained by the combined spiritual essence and soul essence of the trapped city citizens. If we can find a way to disrupt that connection or release them, it might weaken the Goliath or disable it.’

Zhang Dong relayed Bob's analysis to the group. They now had a potential strategy to weaken the Goliath and put an end to this nightmarish creation. However, it would be a dangerous and challenging task. Even now their ships had already begun shooting their spirit cannons at the monstrosity but could not even pierce the shroud of energy.

“First of all… Make the order to shoot before that thing fully forms itself!”

“As the Patriarch commands!”

The colossal monstrosity, though still in the process of taking shape, presented a brief window of opportunity for Zhang Dong and his allies. Recognizing this chance to weaken their formidable new adversary, they wasted no time. Their flying ships and the Golden Palace swiftly opened fire, launching a barrage of powerful spiritual attacks toward the emerging creature. A massive, arching display of colorful energy clashed with the forming monster. The collision of these opposing forces sent shockwaves in all directions, intensifying the already trembling ground.

The Goliath roared in something akin to agony as the powerful spiritual attacks from Zhang Dong's forces struck its massive form. Cracks and fissures appeared in its energy field, and parts of its rocky limbs began to fracture and crumble. The anguished cries of the trapped
grew louder as their connection to the Goliath weakened, or at least it looked that at first.

As the fallen rocks began to self-assemble and the energy field surrounding the monstrosity's body grew more potent, it became clear that their efforts were having limited impact. Despite the continuous influx of energy from the ships, the creature persisted in reshaping itself. The escalating screams of the city's inhabitants only served to underscore the futility of their attacks; it appeared that they were causing more harm to the trapped citizens than to the monstrous entity taking form from their collective energy.

The monstrous entity gradually neared completion in its formation. At its core, the Azure Dragon capital city was situated, enclosed by a thick layer of rocks, with only a small section of the defensive formation protruding around the heart area. Above this, the colossal golem's head had been constructed, enveloping the old Azure Palace, a structure even larger than the Golden Palace that Zhang Dong had come to possess. The magnitude of this entity was becoming increasingly daunting.

‘Bob, can you find a way to release the trapped people without harming them?’

Zhang Dong asked urgently while Bob's monotone voice responded.

‘Analyzing... It is possible to create a localized disruption in the energy field to release the trapped citizens. However, it must be done with precision to avoid harm.’

‘I guess you’d have to get someone inside of the city first to carry out that plan…’

The situation looked bleak, they were now up against a monstrous enemy that dwarfed their entire armada. Even though they were constantly pelting it with spirit bullets and other attacks, they could not get through the layer of spiritual energy protecting its main body. They needed to come up with a strategy and they needed to do it fast as the Goliath was probably not going to wait much longer…

Chapter 723

Zhang Dong's mind raced as he contemplated their options. The Goliath was nearly complete, and they were running out of time. It was clear that they needed someone inside the city to create the localized disruption in the energy field and release the trapped citizens. But who would undertake such a perilous mission?

There was a part of the protective formation still sticking out of the massive golem’s chest. When examining it, there was a possibility of forcing a small opening through which a few individuals would be able to slip through. However, the city's situation was not the only concern, as the Azure Palace had shifted position and now occupied the head. There had to be a reason for this, and it was possible that they needed to control both areas simultaneously to achieve any meaningful results.

“We need to act quickly.”

“Have you decided on a strategy, Dong’er?”

Zhang Jin, engrossed in conversation, turned to him with a question. The other elders sought his guidance and were likely to follow any order he issued. The dilemma lay in his desire to use himself as bait. While there was some room to force people into the main city partition, gaining access to the head portion would prove far more challenging. He could only see himself being capable of getting in. Inside, his brother along with many other challenges probably waited.

Zhang Dong continued to view this situation as an impromptu scenario imposed upon them by external forces. Perhaps the Overseer had manipulated the Azure Emperor's mind, driving him to this irrational state. The laid-back nature of the Azure Emperor made it improbable for him to typically engage in such actions. After all, he was not a tyrant who would willingly sacrifice an entire city's population for victory; there had to be more to this puzzle.

Considering his role as the hero in this unfolding narrative, the Azure Palace appeared to be the final stage meant to bring everything to a culmination. It wouldn't be unusual for the difficulty level to increase if he chose to bring more individuals along with him. It resembled the trial tower experience he had shared with Liena, Qiang, and Zhi. In that setting, the difficulty escalated with more participants, and this setting seemed to persist throughout the entire world they now inhabited.

“First, we need a small group of our elite elders to go into the main city. Search for whatever strange device is siphoning the power from the citizens and destroy it.”

That's when Zhang Liena, Huo Qiang, and Zhang Zhi stepped forward. They had been listening intently to the discussions and realized that they were the best candidates for this dangerous task. Zhang Liena, the stealthiest among them, believed she could infiltrate the city and create the disruption without harming the trapped citizens. Huo Qiang and Zhang Zhi, skilled in combat and protection, vowed to accompany her to ensure her safety.

“I am the most elite of the elders, leave it to me, Senior Brother.”

“Don’t worry, I’ll keep him in check.”

Zhang Liena commented on Huo Qiang’s words. The master of immolation was ready to give it all but he needed help from both Zhi and Liena to be his guides. Even though he did not want to endanger this trio, they were the best choices for the mission. After spending years in the trial tower, they were ready to complete this mission without a problem.

“Good, Gramps you will command the ships and the palace then…”

“You are leaving the Golden Palace to me? Do you intend to head into the city with the others?”

“No, I must confront my brother in the Azure Palace, I know that he is waiting there for me.”

“You want to go in there alone? I’m not sure if that’s a wise idea.”

Zhang Jin made his comment, and the other elders regarded him with concern in their eyes. They didn't want him to put himself in unnecessary danger, but they also understood that he wouldn't issue such an order without valid reasons.

Zhang Dong turned to face his fellow elders, his gaze unwavering.

"I have to go in alone. I believe that whatever is happening here is connected to my brother, and I need to confront him personally. It's possible that he's being manipulated or deceived by external forces, and I have to find out the truth."

They didn’t need to know the whole truth but he wasn’t lying. There was a chance that what he encountered inside the Azure Palace, would not be the Azure Emperor anymore. The other elders exchanged glances, recognizing the determination in Zhang Dong's eyes. They knew that trying to dissuade him would be futile. Instead, they just nodded in agreement while also focusing on their own tasks.

“I know that look, just promise me that you will return to me, even if you have to run.”

“Hah, my Senior Brother would never be a coward and run from a battle!”

“Will you shut up you bird for brains, we were having a moment here!”

Liena and Huo Qiang began bickering, and their playful banter brought a smile to his face. Occasionally, he wished they could get along better, but at times, their bickering served as a source of relaxation. He hoped that these small, cherished moments could persist indefinitely. However, for that to become a reality, they needed to overcome the obstacle looming before them.

“There is no time for fooling around, we have a battle to win!”

With their roles assigned and their resolve firm, the group split into two teams. The city infiltration team consisted of Zhang Liena, Huo Qiang, and Zhang Zhi. Zhang Dong was the only member of the Azure Palace infiltration team as he needed to confront his brother alone. The rest and the largest was the Goliath stalling group. They were their whole army and their job was to contend with the massive spiritual construct.

“Gramps, don’t overdo it, keep your distance this thing doesn’t look too nimble.”

“Don’t worry about me Dong’er, I’ll keep everyone safe while you’re gone but are you sure you can get in there?”

“Just live it to me, use our ships to distract it, now let’s go before it’s too late.”

They were still looking at a barely formed monstrosity that wasn’t fully operational. It was a massive automaton made up of spiritual energy, rocks, and city parts. It would take a few more moments for it to be fully operational. They needed to use that time to get close and start their mission as the more time they took, the worse it would get.

The city infiltration team, composed of a select group of nascent soul elders, began to depart. Before leaving, Zhang Dong made sure to embrace his wife tightly, and they separated after a moment of silence. Both of them were aware of the dangers of the mission, understanding that this might be their last interaction. However, they refrained from exchanging words, choosing instead to hold onto the belief that their lives wouldn't end so soon. They had their entire future ahead of them, with their children eagerly awaiting their return. Nothing would deter the two of them from fulfilling their duty in this war and returning home to share their harrowing tale.

Two orbs of light shot out from the Golden Palace, one being entirely golden, aimed at the Goliath's head, and the other a mix of spiritual energies emanating from all the elders within. The latter was significantly larger and steadily gained momentum as it needed to breach the defensive barrier in one decisive move. To assist the elders, the ships and Golden Palace aimed their massive cannons at a specific point on the barrier.

Simultaneously, the cannons fired, concentrating their firepower on that precise location, preparing it for the upcoming infiltration attempt. The sphere of spiritual energy enveloping all the elders continued to gather speed and mass. Upon the impact of the barrage, it struck the weakened point and began to penetrate. There was some resistance, and the Goliath emitted a peculiar roar, almost as if it were experiencing discomfort. However, before long, the orb carrying the nascent soul elders began to tunnel through, and with one final push, it disappeared into the enclosed capital city, where the trapped citizens were presumed to be.

"Good, they made it through. Now it's my turn."

Zhang Dong remarked, his gaze fixed on his people and friends successfully completing their part of the mission. Time was of the essence, as the colossal construct, reaching up to the clouds, began to rumble. The massive legs, once immobile, now quivered, and the arms composed of rocks and spiritual energy trembled. This creature, formed from energy and debris, was beginning to stir, and the clock was ticking.

Unlike his friends who had launched themselves through a breach in the barrier, Zhang Dong had a different target in mind. The Azure Palace had been largely ensnared by rocks and a dark energy vortex, leaving little of it visible. Yet, as he concentrated, one part stood out, an entrance of sorts, likely discernible only to him.

‘That must be it…’

With a deep breath, Zhang Dong made a daring decision. He closed his eyes, allowing his spiritual sense to expand and connect with the mysterious entrance he had identified. The energy around him surged as he channeled his power into a concentrated form. In a burst of golden light, he propelled himself toward the concealed entrance with incredible speed, like a shooting star slicing through the night sky.

The world around him blurred as he entered the darkness of the energy vortex surrounding the Azure Palace. It was a turbulent and chaotic journey, with unseen forces pulling and pushing him in all directions. Yet, Zhang Dong remained focused, using his formidable cultivation skills to navigate through the treacherous currents.

Moments later, he burst through the barrier and found himself within the Azure Palace. The sight before him was both astonishing and disheartening. The once-majestic palace had been twisted and corrupted by dark energy. The walls were covered in strange occult symbols, and the air was thick with a malevolent presence.

‘This looks strangely familiar…’

Zhang Dong brushed off his white robe, which crackled with lightning energy. The atmosphere in this location held a resemblance to the trial tower, and some of the symbols adorning the walls carried a familiar vibe. It was evident that this place shared similarities with the simulated worlds he had traversed alongside his companions.

“It was the right choice to go through that place…”

‘Warning, incoming danger!’

Before he could think of a strategy, Bob started raising the alarm. He was not alone in this place as some enemies were fast approaching. It seemed that he would need to find the Azure Emperor in this altered palace and put an end to this once and for all…

Chapter 724

“General, we await your orders!”

“What’s there to say? Show this abomination why we are called the strongest sect in the Empire!”

Zhang Jin shouted from the command center of the Golden Palace, his voice resolute. The Goliath, now fully awakened and fueled by dark energies, had started to advance toward the defensive line the elders had formed. It moved with a lumbering yet menacing grace, causing the ground to tremble with each step.

The Golden Palace, flanked by a fleet of airships, hovered in the sky above, its cannons pointed on the behemoth. Zhang Jin, in his role as the commander of the defense, relayed orders to the ships and coordinated their firepower. The massive cannons on the airships unleashed a relentless barrage of energy projectiles upon the lumbering monstrosity, creating spectacular explosions on its rocky surface. However, the construct seemed undeterred, and its dark energy shield held firm against the assault.

“I guess it’s time to use that thing. Ready and Fire the spiritual energy destabilizer!”

Zhang Jin ordered, his gaze never leaving the approaching threat. One of the airships, the largest among them, carried a powerful spiritual energy destabilizer device. Its purpose was to disrupt and weaken the spiritual energy field surrounding the Goliath, making it vulnerable to further attacks. The crew of the airship worked with precision, aligning the device's emitters with the target.

With a brilliant burst of energy, the spiritual energy destabilizer fired a focused beam at the Goliath. The beam struck its mark, causing the construct to convulse and emit ear-piercing shrieks. Dark energy rippled across its body as the destabilizer began to erode the protective field, exposing cracks in its defenses.

“We've got an opening! Focus all firepower on those cracks!”

Zhang Jin shouted while all the airships adjusted their positions to target the weakened areas that now appeared on the Goliath’s body. Their cannons fired relentlessly, blasting away chunks of rock and dark energy. Slowly but surely, the construct's defenses crumbled under the relentless assault.

“It’s working! Keep at it!”

“General! We are picking up a large burst of power coming from the epicenter of the construct!’

One of the people in the command center shouted as the bombardment continued. Initially, it appeared as though they were successfully penetrating the massive entity's body, but soon their collective gasps filled the room. An eerie energy signature emanated from within the chest area, precisely where the city was positioned.

"It's... It's regenerating that ominous spiritual energy?"

Zhang Jin exclaimed as the phenomenon unfolded. While the spiritual energy destabilizer had shown promise initially, the shield surrounding the colossal rocky entity was rapidly restoring itself to full strength. The fragmented rocky pieces that had fallen to the ground began to shift back into place, and before long, the monstrosity had fully regained its previous form.

"I see this won't be an easy task. Prepare the destabilizer once more; we must keep it occupied while the grand elders handle that power source!"

Zhang Jin ordered with determination.It became increasingly evident that the monstrous entity they faced would not be defeated without a fierce struggle. It had nearly a billion people at its disposal to be used as batteries, some of whom were likely potent cultivators. As long as the Goliath could harness them to regenerate its spiritual energy shield, it would continue to pose a significant threat. The responsibility now rested on the others to sever this power source, but that was far easier said than done.

Amidst the raging battle in the skies, Zhang Liena, Huo Qiang, and Zhang Zhi cautiously maneuvered through the treacherous streets of the city. Just as their initial observation from a distance had indicated, there was an eerie absence of any living beings. The streets that had once been teeming with life and echoing with laughter were now desolate and hauntingly empty. Their urgent mission was clear as they had to swiftly locate the whereabouts of the missing populace and liberate them.

"This place is strangely silent...too silent,"

Zhang Liena cautioned in a hushed tone.

"Stay vigilant."

Liena whispered to her companions as they advanced cautiously. The three elders who had experienced the challenges of the trial tower were well aware of circumstances like this. They understood that in such silence lay the greatest danger. It was highly unlikely that a city like this would be completely devoid of defenses, and there was a strong possibility of a concealed enemy lurking in the shadows, biding its time.

Huo Qiang and Zhang Zhi, armed and ready, remained vigilant as they followed her lead. Their mission was to locate and destroy the device responsible for siphoning the citizens' energy and disrupting it. Their objective was to accomplish this mission without causing harm to the afflicted citizens. However, they understood that if it became impossible to avoid collateral damage, they were prepared to employ more drastic measures.

As the infiltration team cautiously proceeded deeper into the city, they couldn't help but notice the eerie transformation that had befallen it. Buildings had twisted into grotesque shapes, and the once-vibrant streets were now an ominous labyrinth. It was as if the very essence of the city had been corrupted by the dark energy that fueled the Goliath.

“There is something there… let us continue with caution.”
Liena detected something and soon the other elders confirmed it. The group started jumping through the streets and empty buildings devoid of life and headed for something that looke like a central plaza. The plaza's centerpiece was a majestic fountain, its waters frozen in time, mid-spray, as if an invisible hand had pressed pause on the city's existence. The fountain's intricate stone sculptures depicted mythical creatures and legendary Long Clan heroes, their features beautifully chiseled and now cloaked in eerie tranquility.

The group came to an abrupt halt, their steps faltering, as a peculiar energy seemed to emanate from the entire area. They fell into an uneasy silence, their senses on high alert as they attempted to pinpoint the source of the strange, unsettling aura they felt. Amid the empty plaza, their collective gaze focused on the centerpiece, the frozen fountain which appeared to be ensnared in some kind of time-stopping enchantment. Its waters suspended mid-spray, as if trapped in a moment that defied the natural flow of time.

The group cautiously approached the fountain, each step echoing in the stillness of the plaza. This enigmatic source of energy was not something they could understand but it was clear that they found a clue as to where the people had disappeared to. Upon drawing nearer, they discerned a presence, something concealed within the frozen waters. Huo Qiang took the initiative, his strong hands gripping the polished stone of the fountain's edge. With some effort, he began to lift the stone, revealing what lay beneath.

“There is a passage here?”

“I wonder where it leads…”

“There is only one way to find out…”

Huo Qiang glanced at both Zhang Liena and Zhang Zhi, and the other elders accompanying them inched forward as their destination became apparent. After setting the fountain aside, they commenced their descent into the opening they had discovered. The place they were entering was shrouded in darkness, filled by hushed screams from the very citizens they had set out to assist. It was evident to them that in order to uncover the truth, they would have to descend further into this ominous abyss.

Without hesitation, they all descended into the darkened abyss. While some of the other elders displayed signs of fear, the trio, who had previously conquered the treacherous trial tower, were brimming with anticipation. They eagerly anticipated uncovering the city's secrets and harnessing their newly acquired cultivation levels to demonstrate their true value. Their deepest desire was to finally repay the one who had protected them for so long. They were determined to prove that Zhang Dong was not alone and that he could depend on their newfound strength.

…

“I hope the others are having more luck than me…”

Meanwhile, inside the corrupted Azure Palace, Zhang Dong pressed on, guided by his intuition and Bob's alerts. The moment he arrived here, some type of defensive reaction was triggered. Strange phantoms similar to the ones he encountered in the trial tower appeared to attack him. Thankfully there was no need to produce specialized light techniques as they could be defeated by regular ones.

These monsters weren’t the only ones here as autonomous puppets of various sizes swiftly emerged. These constructs bore some resemblance to the angelic army he had once created, but they also concealed a sinister secret within. He could sense an eerie, decrepit essence residing within each autonomous piece of armor, all driven by a malevolent intent to end his life. What was once a paradise had transformed into a nightmarish palace, more reminiscent of a lair belonging to a vampire lord than the sanctuary of a martial master.

‘Is this because of me?’

He couldn't stop pondering this question. His brother, Long Qing, didn't seem like such a heartless person, certainly not someone who would imprison the souls of the deceased within living armors. At that moment, he found himself locked in combat with an army of vengeful spirits, fortunately they were susceptible to the soul arts he had honed through his travels.

With a powerful sweep of his hand, he conjured a translucent gust of wind. As it passed through the various phantoms, their connection to the treasures they were haunting was severed, causing them to tumble to the ground. Gradually, he pressed onward through this place saturated with the stench of death. However, after passing through a few corridors he realized that he returned to the same place as before.

“Why do they always have to make it harder… Just let me into the boss chamber!”

Zhang Dong shouted while shaking his fist angrily at whoever thought it was a great idea to create another spatial maze within this place. He now had to go through vast quantities of rooms that led to more places that all looked the same. Luckily Bob and his system’s mapping feature was there to help him out.

‘That trial tower was really the alpha for this entire world. The monsters and traps are all the same…’

His journey through that darkened place had prepared him well, allowing him to make swift progress. Time was of the essence, but he continued to advance steadily. Before long, he stood before a colossal gate that promised to be his first genuine trial. As he stepped through it, his thoughts remained fixed on his comrades waiting outside and the urgency of completing this crucial phase of the mission before it became too late…

Chapter 725

Beyond the colossal gate lay a vast chamber, and at its center, a towering figure awaited. It was Long Qing, clad in dark robes, his face obscured by shadows. The chamber was bathed in a surreal, bluish glow, emanating from the massive crystalline structure that loomed behind Long Qing. This structure appeared to be the source of the sinister energy that had corrupted the Azure Palace.

"Long Dong."

Long Qing's voice echoed through the chamber, a sinister edge to his tone.

"I must admit, I didn't expect you to make it this far. But your journey ends here."

Zhang Dong's eyes narrowed as he assessed the situation. He had expected a confrontation with his brother, but he couldn't help but feel a sense of unease in the air. The crystalline structure behind Long Qing pulsed with malevolent energy, and it was evident that this place held dark secrets.

“You are not actually Long Qing, are you?”

“Oh? I am not?”

“No, it’s too soon for the main boss to appear… and it’s obvious that you are just a crude imitation.”

As Zhang Dong questioned the figure before him, it chuckled ominously. Shadows danced around its form, and its voice took on a distorted, eerie quality.

"You are perceptive, Long Dong. I am indeed a mere projection of your brother, created by the malevolent energy that now permeates this palace. You could say I am an embodiment of his darkest desires and intentions."

“Darkest desires? I haven’t known him for a long time, but I don’t think his desire would result in such a drastic change?”

Zhang Dong replied cautiously as he attempted to discern the mysterious azure crystal hidden behind the shadowy replication of the Azure Emperor. It emitted an eerie energy akin to that of the demonic cultivation energies. Bob was quickly trying to analyze the spirit energy pattern while he continued to ask questions and prolong the conversation. There was no way of knowing what he had walked on into so taking everything with caution was best.

‘Warning, detecting unknown corrupted energies, trying to analyze pattern… energy identified to be not of this world’s origin…’

Just like he had predicted, there was more to this place that met the eye. The presence of these crystals, clearly foreign to the world's natural structure, indicated they had been imported from elsewhere. Only one person came to his mind that could produce such a result, the overseer that he was wary of. While she was not here, the phantom he was interacting with could be of her making.

‘I can’t call her out directly, she will know that I’ve figured out the truth of this world…’

His deepest desire was to engage in a peaceful dialogue. He remained uncertain about the nature of these overseers and whether they were open to negotiation. However, considering that they didn’t see anyone in this world as anyone important, there was a problem. If he failed to thwart the ambitions of the Long Clan and their Emperor, a looming darkness threatened to envelop everything he held dear. His entire sect faced annihilation, and his offspring would be relentlessly pursued, a fate he could not permit to come to pass.

‘Warning, prolonged exposure to the unknown energy could affect the user’s mind, activating defensive protocols to keep the mind from being affected.’

‘I see, so this is probably what made them do this…’

It appeared that the enigmatic dark azure crystals were at the root of this intricate situation. Their capacity to influence people's minds likely played a pivotal role in Long Qing's transformation. Whether his brother had intentionally triggered them or if the overseer had intervened remained uncertain. Nevertheless, a potential solution existed that didn't involve violence. If these crystals were indeed responsible for affecting the Azure Emperor, there might be a chance to resolve the matter peacefully. By either destroying or neutralizing their influence on others, he could potentially address the issue without resorting to combat.

‘Bob can you figure out a way of cleansing those crystals?’

‘Affirmative… Calculating…’

‘I guess I’ll have to keep this guy busy for now…’

While he was having the conversation with his AI partner, the shadowy Azure Emperor started changing. His body started floating upwards and his face was contorting. His skin grew pallid and translucent, veins visible beneath the surface like faint webs. His facial features elongated and contorted into grotesque tentacle-like appendages, protruding from where his nose and mouth once were. His eyes clouded over, losing all color and vitality.

In place of Long Qing, he encountered something that bore a striking resemblance to a familiar adversary from his previous encounters. Yet, this entity appeared notably leaner and more compact compared to the Cthulhu-like monstrosities he had confronted before. When he attempted to analyze it using his system, all he received was a cryptic designation that could only be translated as 'Psychic Abomination.'

“You shall not leave this place alive!”

“Sure I will!”

The creature's voice resounded within his mind, its lack of a conventional mouth or lips making communication an eerie experience. It appeared to wield psionic abilities, reminiscent of telekinesis, and had every intention of employing them against him, evident in its attempt to hurl the dark azure crystals in his direction. The colossal crystal lurking behind the creature ruptured into countless shards, and was propelled toward him by its peculiar telekinetic powers.

Zhang Dong's reflexes kicked into high gear as the crystalline shards shot toward him. He leaped to the side, narrowly avoiding the deadly projectiles. With each shard that struck the chamber's walls, a surge of malevolent energy rippled through the room, intensifying the ominous aura.

Bob's warning echoed in his mind, urging caution. He knew he had to act quickly to cleanse the corrupted crystals and put an end to the entity's influence on Long Qing and the Azure Palace. But facing this Psychic Abomination was no small task, and he couldn't underestimate its powers.

The creature displayed an uncanny ability to teleport at will, effortlessly anticipating his every move. Given its evident mental powers, it seemed plausible that it could delve into his thoughts. To win this fight he couldn’t let himself think and instead, he would need to react before the monster read through his actions. Acting on a martial artist's instinct seemed like the way for it and luckily, he was one.

Zhang Dong focused on his martial arts training, relying on muscle memory and instinct to guide his movements. The Psychic Abomination continued to manipulate the shards of the corrupted crystal, sending them hurtling towards him with incredible force. Each dodged attack was followed by another, as the creature's relentless assault tested Zhang Dong's agility and stamina.

Despite channeling a substantial amount of spiritual energy, a vexing issue emerged. The corrupted crystals scattered throughout the vicinity exhibited an unsettling ability to siphon away a significant portion of his spiritual energy. Even his most potent palm strikes and long-range finger attacks fizzled out before reaching the elusive monster, which persisted in its teleportation. It became evident that he couldn't hope to overpower this creature through sheer spiritual energy alone, not as long as those malevolent crystal shards swirled about, sapping his strength.

As the Psychic Abomination continued to harass him with telekinetically propelled crystal shards, Zhang Dong began to observe the patterns of its attacks. He noticed that the creature had a slight delay in its teleportation after each attack, as if it needed a moment to recharge its psychic abilities. This observation gave him an idea.

Timing his movements precisely, Zhang Dong waited for the creature to unleash another barrage of crystal shards which he quickly evaded as many times before. After a quick counter-attack, the monster quickly teleported away. However, the previous palm strike was just a faint, it contained a marginal amount of spiritual energy. His intent was to go for the area where the Abomination repositioned itself.

Seizing the opportunity, Zhang Dong leaped forward, his movements fluid and precise. Just as the monstrosity materialized from a swirling cloud of smoke, he wielded his sword with precision, thrusting it straight through the creature's head. He left nothing to chance, recognizing the creature's brain as the wellspring of its psionic abilities. In the wake of this decisive strike, the monster disintegrated into an unusual sludge-like substance.

"It reeks!"

Zhang Dong exclaimed, leaping back in abhorrence, his spiritual energy forming a protective shield. This barrier offered some resistance against the corrosive nature of the monster's bile, though it was not impervious to its malevolent touch. It attempted to go through his radiant shielding and forced him to push it away instead.

As Zhang Dong stood there, defending against the remnants of the Psychic Abomination, he realized that the chamber around him was beginning to tremble. The crystalline structure behind him, which had been the source of the malevolent energy, started to fracture and crack. A bluish light erupted from within, and it became apparent that the dark aura that had tainted the Azure Palace was dissipating.

Then from the collapsed azure crystal, a tiny wisp of blue light appeared. Zhang Dong didn’t need Bob to identify this occurrence as he could feel that it was a fragment of someone’s soul, Long Qing’s to be precise. After wiggling with his finger the fragment floated towards him and it unraveled the mystery of this place.

“Hm… Do I have to collect these fragments to get through this place?”

For a moment he contemplated if he should just absorb this fragment to add to his own power. If it was part of the soul that belonged to the Azure Emperor, then it could act as a powerful elixir or even be made into a soul-nourishing pill that would enhance his cultivation base.

Zhang Dong carefully considered his options. The fragment of Long Qing's soul held immense power, but he couldn't ignore the ethical implications of absorbing it. He had come here with the intention of helping his brother, not further harming him. Besides, the corrupted crystals were the true source of the problem, and he needed to find a way to cleanse them.

He used his spiritual energy to carefully encapsulate the wisp of blue light, creating a protective barrier around it. With the fragment securely contained, he turned his attention to the shattered crystalline structure.

"Bob, let's try to cleanse these corrupted crystals. We need to undo the damage that has been done to the Azure Palace and find more of these fragments. Find me where other corrupted crystals like this are.”

With Bob as his guide, Zhang Dong embarked on a new mission within the labyrinthine depths of the Azure Palace. His goal was to find more shards and bring them all together before confronting what was left of his brother…

Chapter 726

“Ugh… this is disgusting… and that smell, what is this place? Are we in the belly of some sort of demonic beast?”

Zhang Liena exclaimed as she gazed at the pale gray walls and the muck on the ground. The group of nascent soul masters had successfully infiltrated the Azure Capital. They had discovered an entrance to an eerie underground cavern that initially appeared quite ordinary. However, as they pressed on in their quest to locate the city's inhabitants, the landscape began to undergo a dramatic transformation.

The walls gradually became adorned with what appeared to be flesh and arteries, and this grotesque pattern continued to extend across both the walls and the surroundings as they ventured deeper. Zhang Zhi, with a look of concern, extended his hand towards the fleshy wall and gently brushed his fingertips against it.

"This is not natural, nor is it the result of any typical demonic cultivation. It's as if this entire underground realm is a living entity."

As the group continued to navigate through this bizarre underground landscape, the air grew thicker with an unsettling atmosphere. Whispers echoed through the cavern, barely audible but filled with an undeniable sense of despair and anguish. The walls seemed to pulse and quiver with a disturbing rhythm, and an unpleasant odor lingered in the air, a nauseating mix of decay and something far more sinister.

“This is indeed strange, the walls are reacting to my flames…”

Huo Qiang couldn't resist poking the pulsating walls with his finger, and he promptly activated his flames in an attempt to incinerate this peculiar obstacle. To everyone's astonishment, the entire place began to rumble, as if it were a living entity. It was increasingly likely that they were inside some form of living creature, or that these tunnels were interconnected in a mysterious way. It appeared that the tunnels could possibly sense pain, as attacking or burning them triggered a visible reaction.

“Elder Qiang, I think we should refrain from doing such things. It might be possible that these tunnels could constrict or…”

“Or?”

Before Zhang Zhi could respond to that question, all the nascent soul masters turned their attention to a dark section of the tunnel. From within, they could hear a strange noise resembling a high-pitched scream. Even after the rumbling ceased, it continued to persist and draw nearer to their location.

"This could jeopardize our position..."

"You see what you've done? You dense fool! If we make it out of here alive, I'll kill you myself!"

Liena shouted, realizing what Zhang Zhi had been implying. If this tunnel was part of a living creature, disturbing its walls would reveal their presence. Now, they had been exposed, and some unidentified creatures were approaching them. All of them got ready with Huo Qiang heading to the forefront, his fists clad in plasma energy that illuminated this corridor.

As the eerie noises drew closer, the group tensed, their senses on high alert. The dimly lit tunnel seemed to close in around them, and the grotesque, fleshy walls pulsated with a malevolent energy. Whatever was approaching was not friendly, and the group prepared for a confrontation.

Moments later, a horde of grotesque, malformed creatures emerged from the shadows. They resembled twisted amalgamations of various beings, with mismatched limbs and horrifying features. These abominations shuffled toward the intruders, their movements unnatural and jerky.

"Stay together, we can’t let them surround us!"

Zhang Liena commanded, her voice steady despite the disturbing sight before them. She unleashed her spiritual energy, creating a burst of wind energy with her fans. The razor-sharp blades flew towards the malformed monsters, cutting them into smaller parts.

Huo Qiang followed suit, releasing torrents of plasma energy that enveloped his fists. With powerful punches, he sent bursts of searing heat through the oncoming horde, reducing some of the abominations to ashes. Zhang Zhi, on the other hand, employed his refined control over water-based spiritual energy to create dense barriers, shielding the group from the relentless onslaught of the creatures.

Despite their formidable skills, the grotesque entities were relentless in their advance. They seemed to be drawn to the intruders like moths to a flame, driven by a dark and insatiable hunger. The group quickly realized that these creatures were not ordinary foes; their resilience and regenerative abilities made them a formidable challenge.

"We need to find a way out of here, fast!"

Zhang Liena urged as she dispatched more of the creatures with a flurry of wind-based attacks. But escape was easier said than done. The labyrinthine tunnels continued to twist and morph, leading the group deeper into the nightmarish landscape. It was as though the very walls of this living entity conspired against them, guiding them further into its dark and grotesque heart.

As they pressed on, the group encountered more of these malformed creatures, each wave more relentless and grotesque than the last. They fought valiantly, but exhaustion began to set in, and it became clear that they couldn't keep up this pace forever. The grotesque creatures seemed to be an endless horde, and the group's situation grew increasingly dire.

"We need to find the source of these abominations and put an end to this. If this continues we will just exhaust all of our spiritual energy before we get to the end.”

“That’s all fine, but what do you propose we do? There aren’t that many places we can go, should we split up?”

Huo Qiang directed his question to Liena, who had been leading them through one of the tunnels. These passages branched out like arteries, offering multiple pathways. With Zhang Dong absent and being unable to rely on his system's mapping function, they were now navigating in the dark.

“If only Senior Brother was here…”

“Stop relying on my husband, I know he is great but we must get through this without him!”

“I think, I know what we can do Elders…”

Zhang Zhi was the one who finally spoke up, even as the others continued to race through the tunnels. He had made a realization as they progressed, and he believed that this revelation could potentially lead them out of this labyrinth.

"What is it, Zhi? What did you observe?"

"It's the walls, they pulsate at a specific rhythm, and it quickens in certain areas. I believe that if we follow these vibrations, we'll find our way to an exit!"

“Yes… there is something to this pulsating phenomenon, that must be it!”

The others quickly focused on the fleshy walls that acted like veins. The path they were on continued to pulsate at an increased pace as they followed it and after arriving at another fork they quickly identified a path that would follow the same pattern.

“But wait, what of the monsters? They will just keep chasing us, even if we find the right path, what if there is a stronger beast just waiting for us at the end?”

“Oh? You can actually think things through?”

“Hey! What’s that supposed to mean?”

Huo Qiang furrowed his brow, feeling the weight of the truth in Zhang Zhi's words. It was highly probable that at the conclusion of this labyrinth, a more formidable monster awaited them. They had already triggered the trap that had set these monsters against them, and if they allowed all of them to converge in the final chamber, the odds would certainly not be in their favor.

“Grand Elders, allow us to help! We will distract these abominationis while you infiltrate this place further!”

“Are you sure?”

“Yes!”

Qiang, Liena and Zhi weren’t the only ones here. They were accompanied by seven other nascent soul elders. They were a lot weaker and felt that they couldn’t really contribute to a fight too much. Nevertheless, they realized that they could redirect these monsters away from the main group. As they lured the creatures away, the other three could continue with the mission on their own.

With the plan now in action, the group of nascent soul elders divided into three teams. The seven elders formed two smaller teams, one with three members and the other with four, and each group took separate paths. They skillfully divided the wave of monsters among themselves, using their spiritual attacks on the walls to entice the creatures and guide them in their respective directions.

Zhang Liena, Huo Qiang, and Zhang Zhi pressed onward along the pulsating path, following the eerie rhythm of the fleshy walls. They moved swiftly and efficiently, each step propelling them deeper into the heart of this living labyrinth. As they ventured deeper, the unsettling ambiance of the place intensified. The walls seemed to close in around them, pulsing with a sinister life of their own. The whispers grew louder, as if the very walls of the labyrinth were trying to communicate some malevolent intent. The grotesque creatures that pursued them before weren’t there anymore so the strange sounds were pointing to a confrontation soon.

After what felt like an eternity of winding through the nightmarish tunnels, they finally reached a massive chamber. The walls of the chamber were adorned with grotesque patterns that seemed to writhe and squirm, and at the center of the chamber lay a massive, pulsating heart-like organ.

"That must be the source!"

Zhang Zhi said, his voice filled with a mixture of awe and disgust. This red organ was not the only thing that was here as when they glanced around it, the true face of this place became apparent.

“What are those strange things… Are there people inside of them? Is this what became of the citizens of the capital?”

The heart-like organ in the center pulsed with an eerie glow, connected to numerous pulsating veins that stretched out like roots throughout the chamber. But what truly chilled them to the bone were the strange, pod-like structures that hung from the walls. Each pod contained a humanoid figure, encased in a gel-like substance. It was as though the citizens of Azure Capital had been captured and assimilated into this grotesque, living entity.

The chamber was surprisingly vast, and a multitude of pods clung to the walls, mirroring the pulsations of the central heart in this expanse. With just one look, it was evident that there were tens of thousands of these peculiar pods scattered all around. However, despite the chamber's considerable size, it couldn't possibly accommodate the millions of citizens who once inhabited the city. It became apparent that they had only arrived in one of the locations where the people were being held captive, and there were still more places to discover.

“Should we destroy the heart? It must be the cause for all of this!”

“Wait Qiang, stop!”

Before Liena could restrain her overconfident friend, the heart began to pulse rapidly in response to the approaching brute, emitting an unusual spiritual energy signature. Without delay, the organ began to ascend from the ground, shrouded in a peculiar green translucent substance. Swiftly, the heart disappeared into this mass, undergoing a transformation into a bizarre and fleshy golem-like creature.

“Great going you idiot, now we have to fight with it!”

Liena frowned and readied her battle fans, if they managed to slay this monster then perhaps part of the city would be liberated and their mission would be on it’s way…

Chapter 727

“General Jin!”

“You don’t need to shout, I can see it…”

Zhang Jin's expression darkened as he witnessed the Goliath's colossal hand gripping one of their ships. Fortunately, it wasn't the one containing the spiritual energy destabilizer, but their armada was still sustaining damage. Thankfully, the people on board the affected ships managed to evacuate, thanks to teleportation technology on the other vessels and the arrival of an army of angelic puppets that reinforced their ranks.

Since the group of elders, along with Zhang Dong, had entered the Goliath, only about fifteen minutes had passed. In this brief span, they had already suffered losses amounting to nearly ten percent of their forces. It was evident that they couldn't hold out for much longer, and the relentless behemoth showed no signs of stopping. Its colossal form unleashed peculiar rocky projectiles that transformed into flying scarabs, voraciously seeking to destroy and consume anything in their path.

Zhang Jin was acutely aware of their dire circumstances. The Goliath proved to be not only formidable but also relentless, adapting and growing in power with each passing moment. When its massive limbs couldn't land a hit, it began to innovate. Initially, it created missiles from its own body, but these were thwarted by their ship's defensive formation. However, the Goliath quickly evolved its tactics, transforming those missiles into strange bugs that could shred their shields and inflict direct damage. It was akin to witnessing a newborn child rapidly maturing in the midst of this intense battle.

“Firing on its chest and head has proven ineffective… I think the only thing we can do is prolong this battle…”

He pondered the idea of launching a combined attack on the Goliath's head but quickly dismissed it. The monster's shields were at their strongest around the head and chest, where the main city was located. Breaking through these formidable defenses seemed beyond their current capabilities, especially given the heightened level of spiritual energy radiating from the creature. Instead, it made more sense to concentrate on stalling and prolonging the battle. With their group of elders and Zhang Dong inside the Goliath, they needed to have faith in their abilities to weaken the creature before launching a full-fledged counteroffensive.

"Notify the ships and our allies to fall back. Our primary focus will be containment rather than suppression. Target its lower limbs to limit its mobility!"

Zhang Jin commanded, emphasizing their new strategy. As Zhang Jin's orders echoed through the command center, the airships repositioned themselves, targeting the Goliath's massive, rocky legs with relentless firepower. Energy beams and projectiles rained down upon the behemoth's lower limbs, causing violent eruptions of dark energy and debris.

The Goliath, now under concentrated assault on its legs, roared in frustration. It attempted to retaliate, but the constant barrage of attacks made it difficult for the construct to focus on offense. Its movements became less coordinated, and its steps grew increasingly frantic. With every ship dispersing to the sides it found it hard to do anything with the ever-growing space between its enemies.

“General, it’s working, the beast is slowing down and confused!”

“Good… Wait, did you feel that?”

“General, our scanners are picking up a massive surge of energy from within the beast’s body!”

“It’s trying to do something, warn the other ships to make space!”

They were not alone in this battle. Numerous ships from other clans and sects had joined forces to assist in defeating this final enemy of the Empire. Fortunately, their communication network allowed them to issue warnings to everyone to retreat. Despite appearances, the Goliath wasn't faltering, something was amiss.

The colossal creature, a fusion of stone and spiritual energy, began to lean forward. Its massive arms collided with the ground as it supported its body with all four limbs. Initially, this might have appeared to be a reaction to the bombardment of its hind legs. However, in reality, it was executing a peculiar technique. With its back now facing the sky, it released a powerful burst of energy upward.

It was a torrent of azure energy, intermingled with hints of black. Ascending like a watery geyser, at its zenith, it fragmented into millions of tiny threads of the same color. The entire sequence of events unfolded with such rapidity that no one had a chance to react. This wasn't a technique intended to harm or attack; rather, it was designed to ensnare and imprison them within this place.

"What is this? A colossal net? Or perhaps a spider's web?"

Zhang Jin exclaimed, his astonishment evident. The burst of energy into the heavens spread out from the top like an immense azure net, ensnaring the entire armada of ships. They now found themselves enclosed within a colossal cage crafted from spiritual energy. This energy was intricately linked to the Goliath's back and its massive form. It was apparent that the creature had realized it couldn't catch up to the evading ships, so instead of pursuing them, it had devised a strategy to trap them within its own confines.

As the azure net closed around the fleet of airships, panic and confusion spread among the crews. The spiritual energy cage was unlike anything they had encountered before, and their attempts to break free were futile. Energy beams fired at the net were absorbed and dissipated harmlessly, leaving them trapped in an area of around ten kilometers from the giant monster that was as tall as a mountain. Inside the Golden Palace's command center, Zhang Jin assessed the situation with a grim expression.

"This is bad… Someone analyze that net, we need to break it!”

His subordinates scrambled to find a solution, but the combination of the Goliath's dark energy and the cage's mysterious properties made it nearly impenetrable. Outside, the Goliath itself seemed to gloat, its rocky form pulsating with dark energy as it held the airships captive. It seemed that their plan of prolonging the battle by avoiding it would be now impossible. Instead, they would need to prepare themselves for the worst as the number of flying bugs increased.

“I guess it’s all up to you Dong’er…”

Zhang Jin clenched his fist as he studied the holographic projection before him. Escaping from this net appeared to be an insurmountable challenge, or at the very least, an extremely difficult one. They couldn't afford to turn their backs on the monster while attempting an escape. Their best course of action was to maintain their focus on weakening the Goliath's body. This colossal creature required a significant amount of energy to function, and that energy source was not limitless. If they could diminish it to the point where their team inside the Goliath could proceed with their intended mission, it would suffice.

Amid the chaos and uncertainty within the spiritual energy net, Zhang Dong continued his journey within the labyrinthine depths of the Azure Palace. The wisp of Long Qing's soul that he had encapsulated remained safely protected within his spiritual energy. While his primary mission was to cleanse the corrupted crystals, he couldn't help but wonder about his brother's fate.

Was he merely a victim of the system, or had he genuinely made these choices of his own accord? It would certainly make the decision to confront and battle him easier if he were simply an evil monster hell-bent on world domination. Although Zhang Dong and Long Qing hadn't known each other for an extended period, Zhang Dong still harbored doubts about whether killing was the only option available. The soul wisp he carried served as a constant reminder that perhaps there was a path to saving Long Qing and concluding this ordeal with a happier outcome than the impending bloodshed.

As he ventured deeper into the palace, the corrupted crystals grew more numerous and sinister in appearance. They pulsated with an eerie azure light, and the malevolent energy they emitted sent shivers down his spine. Bob's analytical abilities worked tirelessly, trying to identify a method to cleanse these crystals at a higher rate. While he was attempting to do that, he was stuck being chased by lanky tentacle monsters.

Reminiscent of eldritch horrors, slithered through the darkened corridors of the Azure Palace. Despite their grotesque appearance, Zhang Dong couldn't help but be reminded of the trials he had faced in the trial tower. These monsters seemed to be a manifestation of the same malevolent energy that had corrupted the palace. Perhaps somewhere in the background the Overseer was sitting somewhere in a hidden control chamber and monitoring the situation.

If it weren't for this enigmatic adversary, Zhang Dong might have assigned Bob to investigate whether such an area already existed within the Azure Palace. There was often some sort of fail-safe or hidden entrance to places like this. However, taking such an action would risk exposing his knowledge to his primary adversary. Therefore, it was undoubtedly a wiser choice to proceed with a more conventional approach and defeat these monsters through force.

‘I need to hurry up, it doesn’t look good for my people…’

As he continued to evade danger, the entire surroundings began to tremble. With the aid of his system and sect interface, Zhang Dong could monitor the events transpiring outside. The Goliath was in the midst of enveloping his entire fleet within some form of energy cage. While the power source resided somewhere inside the chest area, it was likely that the construct could be controlled through the Azure Palace. All he needed to do was handle these corrupt crystals and then confront the ultimate adversary, presumably his brother, Long Qing.

‘I need to get rid of these guys first though…’

Zhang Dong nodded, his eyes scanning the area for nearby corrupted crystals. He spotted one embedded in the wall nearby, its pulsating energy source evident. With a swift and precise strike, he unleashed a burst of spiritual energy, shattering the crystal into fragments. As the crystal shattered, the tentacle monsters let out an agonized shriek and tossed themselves at him as if possessed by something.

It became evident that the corrupted crystals were the key to confronting these abominations, and by destroying them, he could gain the upper hand. Not all but some contained soul fragments belonging to the Azure Emperor and the more of them he gathered the better his chances at a softer resolution. However, it was also clear that the more he gathered the more ferocious his enemies would become.

Soon he was speeding around this labyrinth, destroying the corrupted sources of energy and slaughtering the tentacle friends everywhere. However, before he would have his victory a new foe needed to be defeated. In the last chamber that probably led to a safe haven, a massive mass of tentacles was already waiting for him and it took on the form of something that he recognized.

“So, they were some type of lesser spawns…”

Chapter 728

The massive mass of tentacles coalesced into a grotesque form that resembled his old enemy, another version of a Cthulhu. He knew that this was just another manifestation of the corrupted energy within the Azure Palace. More than likely this was a monster that was created within the scenario to combat people with the system. It was unlikely that he would normally meet so many variations of these beings without it being manufactured by someone else.

‘The Overseer is probably watching me right now. If I say too much or do something that shouldn’t be in the script, then they might intervene…’

He didn’t have much time to think but could afford to be distracted either. The monster he was facing was comparable to his level of power and would not be an easy opponent. As the creature lunged at him with its writhing tentacles, Zhang Dong summoned his spiritual energy, forming a defensive barrier around himself.

The tentacles struck the barrier with tremendous force, causing it to ripple and crack, but it held. Zhang Dong then retaliated, extending his own spiritual energy into the tentacles, attempting to disrupt the creature's body and perhaps cut off the source of its power.

The battle with the grotesque Cthulhu-like entity raged on, each of Zhang Dong's strikes met with equal resistance from the corrupted monster. The walls of the chamber trembled as the two combatants clashed, their spiritual energies colliding with explosive force. Tentacles lashed out like whips, seeking to ensnare Zhang Dong and crush him within their slimy grasp.

Zhang Dong's determination was unwavering. He knew that this battle was a crucial step in his mission to cleanse the Azure Palace and save his people from the clutches of the Goliath. With every strike, he channeled his resolve and the memories of his previous fights. He had come a long way since his days as a core formation expert, and he was determined to prove his strength.

But the corrupted entity was not so easily defeated. It regrew its severed tentacles with astonishing speed, and the battle continued to escalate. Zhang Dong's energy was being depleted rapidly, and he knew he needed to find a way to overcome this formidable foe.

‘The regenerative ability is even greater than before and it can even sap away at my spiritual energy…’

The last encounter he had with a being of this nature was when he was forcibly thrust into another dimension. That being wasn’t a simple opponent and this guy here was even stronger. However, upon his return, he had surpassed his previous limitations. The current monster, though stronger than its predecessor, still obeyed the laws of this realm.

Due to the unusual frequency of these encounters, he had developed a strategic approach for any future confrontations. The primary challenge always revolved around the extent of the creature's regenerative abilities. Typically, he had to obliterate the entire body, leaving no remnants capable of regeneration. This task was far from simple, for as the monster grew stronger, it became increasingly difficult to completely purge it from this realm. A different approach needed to be devised, and he had prepared a technique specifically for this circumstance.

He had devised this technique and, with the assistance of Bob, had completed it. It wasn't a method he typically favored, but in this particular situation, it proved to be the quickest solution. Though he was not a practitioner of demonic cultivation, there were certain poison techniques that could be adapted. The only way he could think of to prevent the monster from regenerating was to accelerate the deterioration of its cells, essentially consuming it before it could reassemble itself. To achieve this, he had crafted a unique poison technique.

"I've only crafted one of these, so I must make it count..."

From within his spatial ring, he retrieved a seemingly unassuming pill. The medicinal sphere emitted an eerie aura of decay, and it needed to be ingested or somehow introduced into the monster's body. Zhang Dong's eyes narrowed as he assessed the situation. The grotesque Cthulhu-like entity lunged at him once again, its tentacles reaching out to ensnare him.

With impeccable timing, he launched a punch, driving his fist directly into the monster's gaping maw. He could feel the impact of his hand shattering through the creature's sharp teeth. Despite the injury he might sustain, his priority was to ensure that the pill reached the creature's body. With his hand deep inside the monster's throat, he proceeded with his plan. Concealed within his fist was the special pill he had crafted, and with an infusion of his holy Qi, the process began to take effect.

The grotesque entity convulsed violently as the poison began to spread through its corrupted form. Its tentacles thrashed wildly, but it was too late. The decay seeped into every nook and cranny of the monster's body, preventing it from regenerating. Zhang Dong quickly withdrew his hand, his fingers coated in the creature's foul insides.

‘I don’t like these methods, but it’s better than having to blow this whole place up…’

With a final, desperate screech, the corrupted entity dissolved into a noxious mist, leaving behind only a lingering stench of decay. Zhang Dong sighed in relief, his body trembling from the intense battle. He knew that this victory was just a small step in his larger mission, but it was a significant one. With the monster defeated, he could continue his quest to cleanse the Azure Palace.

As he caught his breath, he noticed that the corrupted crystals in the chamber had lost their malevolent aura. They no longer pulsated with dark energy, indicating that his victory over the grotesque entity had purged this part of the palace. Soon some more soul fragments appeared that he could add to his collection.

His old foe was down but this was not over. This monstrosity was only a guardian and a distraction for the coming task of getting the Goliath under control. With it gone the path forward was finally over and he could continue with his mission. What he needed to do now was to confront the Azure Emperor and finish it all.

Meanwhile, outside the Azure Palace, Zhang Jin and the remaining members of the fleet were locked in a desperate battle against the Goliath's energy cage. Despite their best efforts, they couldn't find a way to break free. The situation grew increasingly dire as the Goliath's relentless assault continued. Back in the command center of the Golden Palace, Zhang Jin was growing impatient. He knew that time was running out, and they needed a solution fast.

"We can't stay trapped in here forever. There has to be a way out. Keep searching for weak points in the energy cage. We can't let this thing destroy us."

His subordinates worked tirelessly, scanning the energy cage for any vulnerabilities. Unfortunately, it appeared that there were no discernible weak points they could exploit, at least not without dangerously approaching the colossal Goliath itself. The epicenter of the trap lay at the monster's back, but gaining access to it posed a formidable challenge.

"Wait... what's that?"

"Have you found something?"

Zhang Jin noticed one of the sect members gazing at the screens in astonishment. The man nodded quickly and raised the issue.

"We've detected a peculiar disturbance near the head area!"

"Near the head area? Did Dong'er make a move?"

Just as he posed the question, a tremor reverberated through the Goliath, accompanied by a low-pitched rumbling. Suddenly, several of the spiritual energy strands attached to the beast's back began snapping, as if it could no longer sustain them. The effect subsided soon after but it showed that the being was sustaining internal damage.

The realization hit Zhang Jin like a bolt of lightning. It was clear that Zhang Dong and the group of elders inside the Goliath were making progress in their mission. They were weakening the creature from within, causing it to lose control over some of its defensive mechanisms. This was their opportunity to break free from this energy cage that it created.

“It’s faltering but… this is not enough…”

There was an opportunity but not quite yet. The Goliath continued to exhibit signs of resistance, its imposing energy cage still looming over the entire area. Nevertheless, this development brought a smile to Zhang Jin's face. If their team was making progress from within, it meant they were buying precious time. It was a glimmer of hope in the midst of this challenging battle, and they needed to persist and maintain their belief that victory would ultimately be theirs.

With newfound determination, Zhang Jin and his subordinates redoubled their efforts. They continued to fire upon the Goliath's whole body as now it was crawling around on all fours. To their surprise, more and more chunks of rocks continued to peel away and fall onto the ground.

“It’s not regenerating as fast anymore?”

Another member of the crew spotted a secondary effect. The monstrous entity began to move in an erratic fashion, and the spiritual energy field it was generating started to waver. It became evident that something was affecting its energy reserves, which were supposed to be drawn from the people within the city.

"Could it be the Matriarch and the others? They must have located the source of the Goliath's energy and started to disrupt it!"

Zhang Jin's hope swelled as he considered the possibility that Liena and Huo Qiang were indeed making headway in their mission within the Goliath. If they were disrupting the source of the creature's energy, it explained the diminishing regenerative abilities and the erratic movements of the colossal construct. They were chipping away at the beast's strength from both inside and outside, and this coordinated effort might be the key to their victory.

"Continue the assault! We're making progress!"

Zhang Jin shouted to his crew, his voice filled with renewed determination.

"Coordinate with our allies and focus your fire on the weakened areas. We need to bring this monstrosity down!"

The fleet outside the energy cage adjusted its positions, concentrating their firepower on the sections of the Goliath that had shown signs of vulnerability. The behemoth roared in agony as it continued to lose chunks of its rocky exterior. Its movements became even more uncoordinated, and its attempts to attack the trapped ships grew more feeble. The momentum was back on their side and perhaps soon they could see this creature falter beneath their spirit cannon blasts!

Chapter 729

‘The whole place is shaking, they must be lighting the Goliath up…’

Zhang Dong contemplated as he navigated through the Azure Palace. After defeating the main tentacle monster, he found it relatively straightforward to cleanse the corrupted azure crystals that had overrun the area. With each crystal he restored, the palace began to resemble the one where his brother once lived.

As he moved through these corrupted corridors, he couldn't help but notice the positive impact of his actions. For every crystal he purified and every soul fragment he collected, the Goliath outside showed signs of weakening. It appeared that the construct couldn't operate properly without the corruption in the area diminishing.

That wasn't the only development; in addition to its loss of control, the Goliath was also depleting its power rapidly. The other individuals who had entered the capital city must have successfully rescued a significant number of trapped citizens. Without these individuals unwittingly serving as its power source, the monstrosity began to weaken.

They were steadily and surely forcing the Goliath to its knees. However, despite all their efforts, the monster was closing in on the fleet. If things continued at this rate, many of his people would be at risk during the impending confrontation outside. Perhaps the smarter thing would be to take things slowly but he couldn’t let his army outside stall for any longer than they already did. Before most of them were eradicated, he needed to get inside of that throne room that probably contained his last foe.

Having previously explored the palace and meticulously mapped it out, Zhang Dong was intimately familiar with its layout. While numerous entrances had been obstructed by corrupted crystals or bizarre fleshy walls, the fundamental structure remained unchanged. As he moved through the palace, the path to the throne room gradually cleared, revealing itself to him once more. The time to confront the Azure Emperor and put an end to this madness was upon him.

As he finally reached the grand entrance to the throne room, Zhang Dong took a moment to steady himself. He knew that whatever awaited him inside would be a formidable challenge. The Azure Emperor was no ordinary foe, and he had likely been waiting for this confrontation. There was also the possibility that the person inside might not be the Long Quing he had encountered before. Instead, it could be some type of twisted monster that was affected by the Overseer.

‘There is one way to find out…’

Pushing open the massive doors, Zhang Dong entered the throne room, his senses on high alert. The room was vast, with towering pillars and a magnificent azure throne at the far end. Seated upon the throne was the Azure Emperor, a figure shrouded in an aura of overwhelming power.

The Azure Emperor, or what appeared to be Long Quing, slowly rose from the imposing throne. His eyes, once filled with warmth and camaraderie, were now cold and emotionless. It was evident that the corruption had taken hold of him, twisting his noble features into something sinister.

"Zhang Dong…"

The corrupted Long Quing hissed, his voice a venomous whisper.

"You've come a long way to face me. But you cannot stop what has already begun. The Goliath's awakening is irreversible, and the world will soon bow before its might."

“I see…”

Zhang Dong could discern that this wasn't the Long Quing he had once known. By employing his system in conjunction with his spiritual sense, he obtained his answer. The man standing before him had been corrupted by an unfamiliar spell or technique. His skin had paled significantly, even taking on a purplish hue, as though all the air had been drained from him. It was evident that something had gone awry since their last encounter, and it was likely that the Overseer or the Goliath were the primary culprits behind this transformation.

With a heavy heart, Zhang Dong knew that he had to confront this corrupted version of his so-called brother and put an end to the madness that had taken hold of him. He couldn't allow the Goliath's awakening to continue unchecked, for it posed a grave threat to his people and the entire world.

Zhang Dong couldn't be certain about the exact cause of the profound change in the once happy-go-lucky Emperor, but it was most likely linked to his handling of the war between the Empires. The Long Clan was originally supposed to be a safe haven, a group of people who were on his side. However, he had managed to eliminate almost all of them without their assistance, which had thrown them into a state of panic.

In the original scenario, perhaps he was supposed to fight alongside them and gradually build a bond. As it currently stood, the Long Clan regarded him as an adversary, someone who had accumulated enough power to challenge their reign of over a hundred thousand years. There was no trust between their factions, and they saw him as nothing more than a threat to their entire empire, an usurper.

‘His giving me a similar vibe to the demon lord that I faced, like he isn’t quite in there…’

Long Qing appeared disoriented, as though he had been transformed into something he shouldn't have become. He sat on his throne with a bored expression, his face cradled in his hand, observing Zhang Dong's entrance with indifference. The throne was strategically placed to oversee the subjects below, ensuring that no one could stand or sit above the emperor.

“I like what you did with the place, it feels like you’re going through something… let me guess, it’s not a phase though?”

“You dare mock me? The Azure Emperor? Bow down before me and I might offer you a swift death!”

With every step he took closer to the throne, Zhang Dong knew that he was stepping into the unknown. The corrupted Emperor's words echoed through this large chamber. Behind him the huge gates started to close and it was clear that this would be the next ground for their battle. There was time to avoid this battle, maybe even wait for his fleet to obliterate the Goliath from outside. Time was on his side if he considered his people to be expendable but that was just not his style.

‘I got all those soul fragments but how do I go about this… He probably won’t just stand still and let me reassemble his soul…’

There was something unsettling about this version of Long Qing. He seemed devoid of any emotion and didn’t even seem perturbed by his appearance in this throne room.
Zhang Dong observed the corrupted Emperor closely, searching for any signs of his brother's true self beneath the malevolent exterior. As he approached the throne, he considered his options. Either he needed to kill him or attempt a probably harder mission by somehow redlining his destroyed persona.

“A swift death you say? I think I’ll have to pass on that one. How about instead, you surrender and we will disable this Goliath? I promise to spare your children along with…”

“You dare bargain with me? The Azure Emperor?”

“I see that you’re too far gone. It’s a shot in the dark… but where are your children and wife?”

The Emperor paused for a moment when Zhang Dong mentioned the children and the Empress. It seemed as if he was attempting to retrieve a distant memory, but it slipped through his fingers before he could fully grasp it. Soon, his face became devoid of any emotion as he responded.

“Hmph, they are of no concern to me or you now. All that matters is the awakening of the Goliath and how I will restore order to the Empire. After you are gone, I will make it my sole purpose to eradicate all opposition. The Long Clan will remain forever and no one will remember the name of the usurper Long Dong.

Zhang Dong couldn't help but feel a surge of sadness as he realized that Long Qing, was now lost to corruption. There was no reasoning with this twisted version of his sibling, and it became clear that their confrontation was inevitable. Even his love for the Empress that was probably behind it all seemed to have gone away and he didn’t even want to think about what had happened to his children.

As their conversation continued the massive doors to the throne room finally sealed shut behind him, Zhang Dong knew there was no turning back. He had come here with a mission, and he couldn't afford to let the Goliath continue to unleash its destructive power upon the world. The fate of his people and the safety of countless lives rested on his shoulders.
“I'm sorry it has come to this, Long Qing.”

Zhang Dong said with a hint of sadness in his voice.

“But I won't allow you to destroy everything I hold dear. Even if it means facing you in battle.”

With that declaration, the two clashed in a flurry of spiritual energy aura. Without leaving his throne Long Qing exuded a surge of dark azure energy that made the whole huge throne room tremble. The wave of force was intercepted by an aura of golden lightning. The two energy sources seemed to match each other without either budging even a millimeter.

Their battle had begun, a clash of power that resonated throughout the grand throne room. Zhang Dong's golden lightning aura met the corrupted Long Qing's dark azure energy, creating a palpable tension in the air. It was a battle not just of strength, but of wills, as Zhang Dong sought to break through the darkness that had consumed Long Qing’s soul.

The two combatants moved with blinding speed, exchanging blows and strikes that shook the very foundations of the room. The throne room, once a symbol of power and authority, was now the arena for a desperate struggle to save not only the Azure Empire but also perhaps the whole cultivation world.

With every clash, the room seemed to warp and distort, as if reality itself was being affected by their battle. Long Qing's attacks were relentless, fueled by the dark energy that coursed through him. Each strike was accompanied by a malevolent laughter that sent shivers down Zhang Dong's spine. It was clear that he was not clashing with the same person as his might had gone up a notch once more.

Even without the quasi-immortal blade, he was proving to be on equal grounds, something that shouldn’t have been possible. It was clear that the man was being empowered by the Goliath and the trapped residents inside the Azure Capital city. However, even though he was mighty a way of separating the connection existed…

Chapter 730

As the battle raged on, Zhang Dong desperately searched for a way to sever the connection between the corrupted Long Qing and the strange entity that was the Goliath. This thing was sapping away the energy from all the citizens in the city and also probably all of the Long Clan members. There was a reason why his opponent had gotten a large power boost as he was getting it from the monstrous construct.

Zhang Dong's opponent proved nearly unbeatable. Even when he landed some powerful blows, the damage he inflicted was swiftly regenerated. Long Qing was evidently harnessing the energy and possibly even the lives of the city's residents to sustain himself. Each strike he delivered to his brother's face and body could potentially result in the deaths of a few people still trapped within the palace or the main city. The longer this conflict persisted, the more lives would be lost due to his actions, and this was something Zhang Dong could not bear.

Both combatants possessed a similar level of skill and techniques. Zhang Dong, thanks to his Divine Dao, had the ability to heal himself continuously after sustaining injuries. However, he had one glaring weakness compared to the Azure Emperor: he didn't possess an almost limitless supply of spiritual energy to draw from others. It was impossible to outlast his opponent; he needed to defeat him outright or find another way to make him cease his actions.

This was the point where the soul fragments he had harvested from the corrupted crystals came into play. There had to be a way to use them to bring Long Qing back to his senses. However, infusing these fragments into an opponent who was moving at supersonic speeds presented a considerable challenge. First, Zhang Dong needed to immobilize him for at least a moment and conduct a few tests to determine if the infusion was even possible.

Drawing upon his extensive knowledge of cultivation techniques, Zhang Dong began to weave a complex array of energy manipulation. His golden lightning aura crackled and surged as he channeled it in a specific pattern, creating a barrier of spiritual energy that surrounded Long Qing. This barrier acted like a mirror, reflecting the dark azure energy back towards its source.

The corrupted Emperor's attacks grew increasingly frenzied as his power was turned against him. He roared in frustration as his own energy battered against the barrier, causing cracks to appear in the once-magnificent throne room.

But Zhang Dong knew that this was only a temporary solution. To truly free Long Qing's mind he needed to wrestle him from the grasp of the Goliath's influence, he needed to find a way to disrupt the connection at its source. As he continued to deflect Long Qing's attacks, he concentrated on probing the Emperor's spiritual aura for any signs of vulnerability through which he could make his move.

It was during one intense clash that Zhang Dong sensed a faint thread of energy connecting Long Qing to the Goliath. It was like a thin, pulsating thread of light that seemed to be feeding energy from the Goliath into the Azure Emperor. Through this connection, he could sense millions of tormented souls, likely the people from whom Long Qing was siphoning energy and those who were trapped within the city.
Zhang Dong's heart sank as he realized the extent of the Goliath's malevolence. It was not only a destructive force but also a twisted machine that fed off the suffering of countless souls. The torment of the trapped citizens fueled Long Qing's newfound power but also caused him to become a monster with no remorse. Zhang Dong could clearly see that Long Qing was beyond reason. Millions of tormented souls screaming directly into his own soul was an overwhelming force, something that one couldn't simply overcome on their own.

The thread connecting Long Qing to the Goliath remained stubbornly immovable. Even when Zhang Dong attempted to force his spiritual energy into the cage he had created, the thread showed no sign of yielding. Nevertheless, a glimmer of possibility emerged when he approached the problem from a different angle. By infusing his energies with the soul fragments and applying pressure against the connection, he could feel a reaction taking place.

As Zhang Dong continued to apply pressure to the connection, he noticed a subtle shift in Long Qing's demeanor. The once-raging Emperor began to twitch, his movements becoming erratic and uncoordinated. The dark azure energy that had surrounded him started to waver, and for a moment, a flicker of recognition passed through his eyes.

"Long... Dong?"

Long Qing muttered, his voice strained as if he were battling against an invisible force. The treatment administered by Zhang Dong had provided a brief opportunity, during which the man had regained a semblance of sanity. However, this moment was short-lived as the Azure Emperor's eyes clouded with corrupted energy once more, plunging him into a state of intense rage.

‘Shit, he is breaking free… I can’t hold him!’

Zhang Dong seized the opportunity and intensified his efforts, attempting to infuse more soul fragments into the thread. He channeled his energy into the barrier, determined to disrupt the connection between Long Qing and the Goliath. The souls trapped within the Goliath cried out, sensing the intrusion into their tormentor's control, which made the process significantly more challenging.

The battle between Zhang Dong and the corrupted Long Qing continued to rage on as the struggle for control of the connection intensified. The throne room trembled with the force of their clashes, and the very air seemed to crackle with the energy of their confrontation. With each passing moment, the barrier Zhang Dong had created strained against Long Qing's relentless assault.

But Zhang Dong couldn't afford to relent. He had a glimmer of hope that he could sever the connection and free Long Qing from the Goliath's influence. The souls within the Goliath cried out in agony as their tormentor's control was challenged, and their collective suffering fueled Long Qing's rage.

‘I… I can’t do this alone, he is breaking through…’

Zhang Dong realized that his power had its limitations, unlike Long Qing, who didn't suffer from this constraint. The barrier he had created began to crack, and the corrupted azure energy was now seeping through. It was evident that the man trapped within would soon break free. Once that happened, it would likely be impossible to contain him within the same barrier. Techniques once seen were unlikely to be effective against someone of Long Qing's caliber twice. It seemed that the only way to end this battle would be through his defeat.

As the barrier cracked and Long Qing's corrupted energy surged forward, Zhang Dong unleashed a torrent of golden lightning. The lightning arced and crackled, merging with the soul fragments he had infused into the connection thread. It created a blinding, pulsating light that surged towards Long Qing like a celestial wave.

“Not…enough…”

Despite utilizing all the resources his new, peculiar cultivation method offered, it still proved insufficient. The corrupted energy began to resist his golden wave of energy, and Long Qing was breaking free. It became apparent that it would be impossible to restrain him long enough to inject more soul fragments, assuming he was truly alone in this battle. As the corrupted energy seeped out, its intensity began to fluctuate, and the Goliath was suddenly losing power.

It seemed that his friends and companions wouldn’t let him face this problem alone. Just as the Azure Emperor was about to go free the Goliath stopped moving, the whole center portion of him began shaking and chunks of rocks started falling. On the outside the ships moved in to seize the moment and started blasting as if there was no tomorrow. The corrupted energy that made up the beast’s shield started flickering as it had trouble in mustering up its own defenses.

‘I see, Liena and the others must have found a way to cut off the energy source…’

The Goliath was having trouble supporting its own weight and the capital city that was surrounded by thick rock started to become revealed. Zhang Dong could sense that something was happening outside but at the moment he needed to focus on the Azure Emperor. He once again mustered up his power to guide more soul fragments and attacked that connection that had now weakened.

Pouring all his spiritual energy into the assault, Zhang Dong unleashed a final, desperate surge of golden lightning toward the connection thread. The blinding light enveloped Long Qing, causing him to convulse in agony. The Azure Emperor's roars of torment filled the throne room as the connection between him and the Goliath strained and faltered. For a brief moment, Long Qing's corrupted form seemed to flicker, and his eyes regained a glimmer of clarity.

"Brother...help...me...I…"

Long Qing's voice, laced with despair, reached out to Zhang Dong. He now knew that Long Qing was still in there, buried beneath the layers of corruption and torment. With renewed vigor, he channeled every ounce of his spiritual energy into the attack, pushing it to its limit.

The connection thread between Long Qing and the Goliath began to fray, like a thin rope on the verge of snapping. The Goliath's power waned further, and the energy cage surrounding the city grew even more unstable. It was a race against time, with the fate of the Azure Emperor and all the citizens trapped inside the city hanging in the balance.

Long Qing's body convulsed violently as the corruption within him fought to maintain its hold. But the combined efforts of Zhang Dong and his allies on the outside were taking their toll on the Goliath. Chunks of rocks continued to break away from the colossal construct, and its once-impenetrable energy shield flickered and waned.

“Hold on Long Qing, just open yourself up to the soul fragments!”

Long Qing's body convulsed violently as the corruption within him fought to maintain its hold. But the combined efforts of Zhang Dong and his allies on the outside were taking their toll on the Goliath. Chunks of rocks continued to break away from the colossal construct, and its once-impenetrable energy shield flickered and waned.

Outside the energy cage, Zhang Jin and the fleet continued their relentless assault on the weakened Goliath. The creature's struggles had intensified, and it was clear that it was on the brink of collapse. The energy cage that had trapped them for so long was beginning to disintegrate, giving them a glimmer of hope…

Chapter 731

“Long Qing are you still in there? Try to remember your family and the members of your clan, do you really want to devour their lives just to defeat me? Is that what the Azure Emperor would do? Sacrifice his whole clan so that he can survive?”

Zhang Dong called out to Long Qing who was clutching his head. His mind was a battleground between the corruption that had consumed him and the remnants of his true self. The cries of the trapped souls echoed in his consciousness, a constant reminder of the horrors he had unwittingly wrought upon his own people.

"Long Dong... you... I can't... control... the power."

Long Qing's voice quivered as he spoke, his words barely audible amidst his torment. Zhang Dong knew that Long Qing was fighting against overwhelming odds, trapped between the insidious influence of the Goliath and the guilt of his actions. The thread continued to weaken, and there was a glimmer of hope that Long Qing could be saved from his own descent into darkness.

"Long Qing, I know it's difficult, but you have to resist. Remember who you are, the Azure Emperor, the protector of your clan and your people. You don't have to sacrifice them to this abomination. Embrace the fragments of your soul and break free from this darkness."

The inner turmoil within Long Qing intensified as he clutched his head, the struggle manifesting physically. His body trembled, and for a moment, his eyes regained clarity, filled with a mixture of agony and longing. It was a small victory, a sign that the true Long Qing was still buried beneath the corruption.

The Goliath, on the other hand, was in its death throes. Chunks of its colossal form crumbled away, and its energy shield finally shattered, leaving it vulnerable. The combined efforts of Zhang Jin and the fleet outside were paying off, and the once-unstoppable monstrosity was now teetering on the brink of destruction.

Zhang Dong looked at his faction interface and noticed that his allies were closing in from all sides. The Goliath had been depleted of approximately half of its energy resources and teetered on the brink of collapse. Long Qing was the brains behind this operation, and as long as he remained incapacitated, the monstrous machine would remain immobilized. Perhaps, by exerting more pressure, victory could be secured. With this in mind, Zhang Dong focused on what mattered most to the man and exploited that vulnerability.

“Yes, that’s it, you are almost there, remember your family! Do it for them!’

“M-my family… I… no what did I do…”

However, this was when things started going wrong. Instead of drawing strength from the memories of his loved ones, Long Qing went berserk. It was at this moment that Zhang Dong realized that the Azure Emperor may have inflicted irreparable harm upon his children. As this realization gnawed at Long Qing's already fragile psyche, his mind began to shatter, and the Goliath reactivated with a vengeance.

The Goliath's resurgence was swift and brutal. It roared to life, its remaining energy surging through its colossal frame. The energy cage surrounding the city began to reform, trapping Zhang Dong and everyone once again. The momentum had shifted, and the battle seemed to have restarted.

Zhang Dong's heart sank as he watched Long Qing's transformation back into a puppet of the Goliath's malevolence. The Azure Emperor, consumed by his guilt and despair, had lost all control. The dark azure energy that had once been contained within the barrier now raged unchecked. The Goliath's influence over Long Qing was stronger than ever, and it seemed that any hope of saving him had vanished.

‘His changing? The soul fragments, what’s happening to them?’

The fragments were an integral part of Long Qing's very being, and they should have been the key to restoring his sanity. However, at this very moment, they were undergoing a strange and twisted transformation. This change was beyond his control, as even the core of his soul was being altered, rendering him powerless. It exceeded the capabilities of his Dao of Souls; at most, he could only deliver a blow to provide himself with a fighting chance.

As the Goliath regained its strength and the energy cage solidified once more, Zhang Dong felt a sinking feeling of despair. His efforts to save Long Qing had seemingly backfired, and the Azure Emperor was now more under the Goliath's control than ever before. The soul fragments that were meant to be a lifeline for Long Qing had transformed into a strange and twisted energy, leaving Zhang Dong at a loss for what to do next.

His plan was to pacify his estranged brother and to set the citizens free of Goliath's control. The plan had almost worked until he started mentioning Long Qing’s family members. It was clear that he had done something to them, something that had made his mind break and to transform even more. His body was transforming into something twisted and not human anymore.

“Shit, he is breaking out…”

Zhang Dong shifted into an attacking stance, extending his palm forward. The barrier containing his brother was on the verge of shattering, so he aimed to strike before Long Qing could break free. His palm emitted a radiant glow, causing the entire throne room to tremble. The radiant technique collided with a swirling vortex of dark azure energy, resulting in a powerful explosion.

"Did I get him?"

The two energies repelled each other, pushing Zhang Dong back a few steps. As he gazed at the swirling dust that had formed, he received his answer: the Azure Emperor was undergoing a transformation, morphing into a monstrous dragon-like creature. His limbs elongated, his hands turned into obsidian claws, and his once-pale skin became dark and corrupted, resembling more a zombie dragon than a true dragon.

“Is that supposed to be his final phase or something?”

He didn't like it, but it had become abundantly clear that there was no way to make any further progress. Long Qing's corruption had taken a deep hold, and even his soul had lost all of its previous brilliance. Zhang Dong had no knowledge of what had befallen this man's children, but if they had perished during the creation of the Goliath, it seemed unlikely there was any way to bring Long Qing back from the abyss. To rekindle his humanity at this stage would necessitate presenting him with someone he held dear. It could only be either his children, who were most likely deceased, or his wife, who, in reality, was the Overseer.

‘Are we really just puppets that are dancing in their hands? Is there no other way?’

Zhang Dong's thoughts raced as he considered his options. He couldn't bear to see his someone become a puppet of the Goliath, but it seemed that all his efforts had failed. He glanced at the remnants of the soul fragments, now twisted and corrupted, and realized that they held the key to Long Qing's transformation.

The situation was undeniably dire. Even if his comrades managed to bring down the Goliath, Long Qing was beyond salvation. The transformation had fundamentally altered his soul, and this draconic form had become his true self. Despite the system's assistance, there was no way to reverse what had happened to his brother. The only way to escape this predicament was to eliminate him and put an end to his suffering.

The transformation into the monstrous dragon-like creature was complete, and there was no way to reach the true Long Qing buried beneath the corruption. As he looked at the twisted soul fragments, he knew that they had become a part of this dark, new entity. Now only fighting remained and he would be the one to end it all.

His power surged as Zhang Dong finally abandoned the idea of saving the Azure Emperor. While he wasn't entirely convinced that Long Qing was solely responsible for all of this chaos, it was clear that he had played a significant role in it. When they had first encountered each other after Zhang Dong was forcibly teleported underground, his brother had still been able to communicate normally.

The corruption had not taken hold at that point, and even then, Long Qing had shown hostility towards him. It appeared that there was truly no other option, and he had to prioritize the safety of his own people over Long Qing's well-being. Allowing this monster to leave the throne room would put not only his sect but also everyone in the Empire at risk. This was not something that he could allow to happen.

With a heavy heart and a sense of grim determination, Zhang Dong prepared to face the transformed Long Qing. The monstrous dragon-like creature let out a deafening roar that shook the very foundations of the throne room, and its eyes glowed with a malevolent, otherworldly light.

As they clashed once again, the battle raged on with even greater intensity. The transformed Long Qing possessed immense power and ferocity, and Zhang Dong found himself pushed to his limits. Each blow he landed was met with a devastating counterattack, and the throne room continued to crumble around them.

Outside, Zhang Jin and the fleet were locked in a desperate battle with the resurgent Goliath. The energy cage had reformed, trapping them once more, and the Goliath's power seemed to have increased. It was clear that the fate of the entire city hung in the balance, and Zhang Dong knew that he had to end this battle as quickly as possible.

Zhang Dong tapped into the full extent of his Dao of Heavenly Lightning and all the rest, channeling his energy into his attacks with precision and determination. He dodged, weaved, and countered with all his might, refusing to let the transformed Long Qing gain the upper hand. The battle was fierce, and both combatants were pushed to their limits.

Long Qing's bizarre draconic form was unrelenting, resembling a crazed beast hell-bent on swallowing him whole. His limbs moved with such speed that Zhang Dong struggled to keep up. It was only his martial expertise that allowed him to anticipate the demonic creature's attack patterns. Long Qing was in a frenzied state, and this heightened state had amplified his latent abilities several times over.

Fortunately, Zhang Dong's mastery of the Dao of Souls, which he had previously employed against Long Qing's soul fragments, allowed him to read his opponent like an open book. He anticipated the claw's swipe before it even came and swiftly moved to another position, delivering a powerful punch to the monster's face. The battle raged on, and he was determined not to let it continue for much longer.

‘I guess there is no way around it, I must go all out … It’s now or never!’

Chapter 732

With a deep breath and a surge of determination, Zhang Dong unleashed the full extent of his power. His attacks became more relentless, his movements more precise, and his resolve unbreakable. The throne room became a battleground of epic proportions, with energy blasts and shockwaves shaking the very foundations of the city. The transformed Long Qing, now a monstrous force of destruction, roared in defiance as it fought back with all its might.

Their energies collided with such force that it created a shockwave that rippled through the entire throne room, shattering everything and causing the very Goliath to quake. The fate of the city, the empire, and countless lives hung in the balance.

As the battle between Zhang Dong and the transformed Long Qing reached its climax, the throne room became a chaotic maelstrom of energy and destruction. The very air crackled with power as the two adversaries unleashed their most devastating attacks against each other. The throne itself crumbled into dust, and the grandeur of the room was reduced to rubble.

The entire Azure Palace quaked as the formidable figure of the Azure Emperor grew increasingly powerful. He stood on the precipice of breaking free from this chamber, putting Zhang Dong’s people outside in grave danger. The monstrosity born within these walls had no semblance of reason; it attacked him solely because he was the sole living person nearby. If he were to retreat, his people would be at risk of being devoured by this entity, which was evidently more formidable than a typical Great Circle Nascent Soul Master.

Zhang Dong knew that he couldn't afford to hold back any longer. He had to end this once and for all, even if it meant risking everything. The transformed Long Qing, now a nightmarish amalgamation of his former self and the corrupting power of the Goliath, lunged at him with a ferocity that was beyond human comprehension.

In that critical moment, Zhang Dong channeled all of his energy into a final, devastating attack. His body glowed with an intense, blinding light as he summoned the full power of his Dao of Heavenly Lightning, his martial prowess, and his mastery of all other paths that he had taken. With a thunderous roar, he unleashed a devastating strike and directed it at the creature’s chest area where the soul also resided. This being of malice and corruption could not be harmed in any normal way, its soul needed to be eradicated.

The transformed Long Qing let out a deafening, agonized scream as the light engulfed his chest. The energy that had corrupted his being began to dissipate, and for a brief moment, the true Long Qing shone through. Zhang Dong could see the pain and regret in his brother's eyes as the corruption was instantly purged along with his very soul.

“I’m sorry it had to come to this…”

Zhang Dong was discontented with the way things had unfolded. He had exerted every effort to avoid the scenario that the Overseer had orchestrated for them. It was evident that the Empress had likely been influencing Long Qing from the very beginning. She was the true instigator and might have been observing the battle from a distance. His initial hope had been to resolve this without resorting to violence, but it had become clear that this was the only means to rescue the citizens trapped in the capital city.

The Azure Emperor's expression appeared serene as he attempted to whisper something in Zhang Dong's direction. However, before long, the light in his eyes faded, and his body started to disintegrate before Zhang Dong's eyes. A colossal hole had emerged in the Emperor's chest as Zhang Dong poured his entire being into the final strike. Beyond the gaping chest wound, a clear path had been created, blasting through the entire throne room and revealing a breathtaking view of the azure sky.

As the transformed Long Qing disintegrated, the oppressive presence of the Goliath began to wane. The energy cage surrounding the city gradually dissipated, and the citizens who had been trapped and controlled by the malevolent machine began to regain their freedom. Outside, Zhang Jin and the fleet watched as chunks of rocks started falling down to the ground. A cascade had begun as the monstrosity was no longer being controlled by anything and could no longer sustain its massive body.

The city, once concealed beneath a heavy shroud of rocks, began to reemerge. Within its confines, the trapped citizens gradually awakened, with some already assembled in the square, having been rescued by Zhang Liena and the other elders. With the absence of the Azure Emperor, all the constructs and bizarre entities within the city started to fade into nothingness.

Inside the crumbling throne room, Zhang Dong stood amid the ruins, his chest heaving with exhaustion. He had given his all in that final, decisive strike, and it had cost him dearly. But it was a sacrifice he was willing to make to save his people and put an end to the chaos that had gripped the Azure Empire.

As the dust settled, Zhang Dong noticed a faint, ethereal glow in the center of the destroyed chamber. It was the remnants of Long Qing's soul, a small, shimmering light that had somehow survived the destruction of his physical form. With a sense of sadness and regret, Zhang Dong reached out in an attempt to gently cradle the fading soul fragment.

“I wished there was another way…”

He apologized again as the soul fragment pulsated weakly. For a moment their souls connected and Zhang Dong could see some of the memories of the man that he had defeated.He saw the young Long Qing, full of hope and ambition, the protector of his clan and his people. He saw the love and warmth that Long Qing had felt for his family, and the burden of responsibility that had weighed on his shoulders. But he also saw the darkness that had consumed Long Qing, the corruption that had twisted his soul and led him down a path of destruction.

With a heavy heart, Zhang Dong released the soul fragment, watching as it faded into nothingness. He didn’t know if Long Qing's soul was at peace or if it could even be saved. The damage that he delivered to it was significant but he hoped that it was so. The victory felt hollow but his people had come out on top. With this feat, all was now over and the United Element Sect reigned supreme, or at least that would be how it looked on the outside.

‘It’s her… she really appeared…’

Before he could rejoin his people to revel in their victories, the entire area underwent a dramatic transformation. The clouds ceased to move, and all sound gradually faded away. It wasn't the first time Zhang Dong had experienced this phenomenon; it had been the same when he confronted Wang Long. Time was being suspended. The true adversary who had orchestrated events behind the scenes was about to reveal themselves, and he harbored doubts about whether he could confront them in his current weakened state.

‘I need to remain calm and pretend that I’m under their technique…’

As time came to a standstill, Zhang Dong's senses remained sharp. He knew that the Overseer, the mastermind behind the chaos in the Azure Empire, was about to reveal herself. He had to stay calm and play along with her illusion, pretending to be ensnared by her technique.

Before his eyes, a door materialized in the midst of the crumbling room. Stepping through it was the person he had feared to confront - the Azure Empress. She appeared much as she had during their last encounter, with one striking difference. Her neck bore a gaping wound, and blood had seeped into her robe.

‘Did she make him kill her?’

He recalled how the Azure Emperor's demeanor had shifted upon mentioning his family. As he gazed at the wound on the Azure Empress's neck, it occurred to him that Long Qing might be the one responsible. However, it was evident that she was not dead, as her form started to undergo a transformation right after walking through that spatial door.

‘What is that… A puppet?’

With Long Qing's demise and the annihilation of the Long Clan, there seemed to be no purpose in maintaining the facade of the Azure Empress any longer. The Overseer had reverted to its original form, resembling a humanoid puppet devoid of facial features or fingers. Its body was immaculate white, bearing joints akin to those found on typical dolls and puppets used by cultivators.

The puppet-like Overseer moved gracefully, floating towards Zhang Dong. Despite its lack of features, he could feel the intensity of its gaze, as though it were scrutinizing him. Zhang Dong maintained his pretense of being ensnared by the time-stopping technique, hoping to gather as much information as possible while staying hidden.

While he had contemplated the Dao of time, he did not master it. If he intended to confront this being then he needed to wait for an opportunity. Thanks to his system and Bob he would not be discovered and that was his plan. When the Overseer approached him, he would deliver the strongest blow that he could muster while its defenses were down. Even an expert of formidable might was susceptible to hidden attacks, as long as he could perform it while its defenses were down, it would be possible.

The puppet appeared to be more fixated on the dissipating soul that had once belonged to Long Qing. It drifted in their direction before eventually zeroing in on the man who had vanquished the Azure Emperor. It moved slowly toward him without saying a word, almost as if it were analyzing the aftermath of the battle.

There it was, a peculiar automaton that appeared devoid of a soul. Zhang Dong was uncertain; he couldn't utilize his system or spiritual sense without risking discovery. The enigmatic entity hovered above him, seemingly conducting its own examination. If it happened to discern that he was manipulating the rules of the world, he might be regarded as an adversary. Nevertheless, if the Overseer remained oblivious to his tampered system, perhaps there was no immediate need for a confrontation…

Chapter 733

Zhang Dong continued to play the role of someone ensnared by the time-stopping technique, maintaining an appearance of vulnerability while his mind raced with thoughts and plans. The puppet-like Overseer circled around the remnants of the throne room, occasionally glancing back at the fading soul fragment of Long Qing that had been locked in time. Its movements were deliberate and methodical, as if it were conducting a thorough inspection.

As the Overseer approached Zhang Dong, the tension in the room grew palpable. He could feel the intensity of its scrutiny, and it seemed to linger on him longer than anywhere else. The puppet floated closer, its blank visage devoid of any emotion or expression. This was the moment that he needed to make a decision. Would he use this chance to attack the strange being, or avoid conflict?

He had encountered only one other creature from another hidden world, and that one had been significantly weaker, easily vanquished. However, this one appeared to be a more formidable adversary, and he questioned whether it was truly necessary to engage in a battle. It seemed that these puppets existed to maintain a particular balance in the world, perhaps as a means to keep those with the system in check. If he remained passive and refrained from taking any action, he would gain valuable time.

As he contemplated the situation, he couldn't help but think about what had befallen his predecessor. If he considered his predecessor's fate, this might be the end of the scenario. The previous system holder had been able to live out his life before ascending further. Zhang Dong hoped that the same would happen to him and in that time he might gain the answer for this conundrum.

Yet, Zhang Dong couldn't dismiss the possibility that this might be his sole opportunity to confront this formidable being while it was off guard. If he let this opportunity slip through his fingers, another might never present itself. So, he continued to wait, carefully weighing his options. The peculiar puppet steadily approached him until it stood before him at roughly the same height. At this close range, he could discern that the material from which it was constructed was something entirely unfamiliar to him.

The time to strike was there but he hesitated. His entire army remained outside, and his wife was in close proximity. His thoughts were muddled by the prospect of potential chaos if he failed to eliminate this creature with a single decisive blow, a feat he wasn't confident he could accomplish in his weakened state. Battling through the Azure Palace and defeating the tentacle fiends, along with the corrupted Azure Emperor, had drained him significantly, to the extent that he couldn't make the decision easily.

‘Unauthorized access detected…’

‘Shit, what now?’

‘Warning, the being known as the Overseer is performing a scan of the user’s body, caution is advised…’

As Zhang Dong deliberated on his course of action, his adversary persisted in its analysis. Given that the Overseer resembled an automaton tasked with maintaining order, it appeared to be following a set of procedures. One of those procedures likely involved scanning for any anomalies in the system holder. Zhang Dong's system had indeed been tampered with, but with Bob's presence and assistance, even this entity might not be able to detect the alterations.

‘Bob, are you sure he can’t get through your fire wall?’

‘Affirmative.’

‘... What about him, could you get through his defenses without being found out?’

An intriguing idea began to take shape in Zhang Dong's mind. His system was undeniably unique, and Bob was an anomaly that likely confounded the Overseers. If these beings were, in essence, machines, they had their inherent limitations and perhaps couldn't evolve beyond certain parameters. It seemed plausible that no one anticipated a system holder being aware of the existence of such entities, and thus, their defenses against hacking might be nonexistent.

This theory held water when he considered his predecessor, who had somehow created the hacking procedure without being eradicated by any Overseers. The fact that Bob remained undetected further supported his hypothesis. Beings of unfathomable power were usually very arrogant and did not even think that a lower being could pose as a threat.

‘Calculating… It is possible to leave a part of my program in the Overseer to create a backdoor, without alerting it, should I proceed?’

‘... Do it … ‘

As Zhang Dong and Bob communicated through the help of the system, the Overseer continued its meticulous examination. It floated just millimeters away from him, seemingly unaware of the hidden plans being formulated in his mind.

Bob, with his hacking capabilities, began the delicate process of implanting a small portion of his program into the Overseer's system. It was a task that required precision and subtlety, and Bob executed it flawlessly. The program fragment subtly merged with the Overseer's code, leaving no trace of its presence.

‘Bob, is it done?’

‘Affirmative, the backdoor is in place. We can access its systems whenever we need to, as long as we remain in close proximity.’

‘I see, good job.’

With the backdoor established, Zhang Dong had a newfound sense of control over the situation. He still didn't want to initiate a confrontation with the Overseer just yet, but he now had a valuable ace up his sleeve. The opportunity to strike back would come at the most opportune moment.

As the Overseer continued its scrutiny, it gradually moved away from Zhang Dong and the fading soul fragment of Long Qing. It appeared satisfied with its inspection and began to drift toward the exit of the throne room. Zhang Dong continued to feign vulnerability, hoping that the Overseer would depart without any suspicion.

It seemed that he would be lucky today. The puppet-like being exited the room through the same spatial door it had arrived from, leaving Zhang Dong in a state of cautious relief. The tension in the room lessened as time began to flow once more. The sounds of destruction and chaos outside gradually returned, and the reality of the situation reasserted itself. Zhang Dong remained still, pondering the enigma of the Overseer and the implications of his newly established backdoor. He knew that he had to be patient and await the right moment to use this advantage and also prepare the right measures to use it.

Meanwhile, outside the Azure Palace, Zhang Jin and the others observed the gradual collapse of the Goliath and the return of the city to its normal state. The citizens who had been trapped in the chaos began to regain their senses and gather in the square. The relief and gratitude in their eyes were palpable.

The Azure Palace that had risen to become the Goliath’s head started falling down as it was cut off from its main source of power. The descent was gradual but Zhang Dong knew that he only had a minute before it crashed into the ground below. Now that the Overseer had departed he glanced at the throne and the door that opened up behind it.

He took up into the air and floated there to peek inside. The layout of the Azure Palace was strangely similar to the Golden Palace and just like in his, there was another room behind it. When stepping inside a foreboding feeling washed over him but he continued forward. There he could see some items that resembled toys that young children would fancy and also some paintings.

“Is that Long Qing and his family?”

One large painting portrayed a man and a woman standing side by side, accompanied by two boys and a daughter. It was Long Qing's entire family, and their faces bore genuine smiles tinged with a hint of awkwardness. Even the woman in the picture, who was meant to represent the Overseer, appeared to exude the warmth of a loving parent. He did not know if at this point in time, she had been replaced or if the Overseer started the act from a younger age.

As Zhang Dong gazed at the painting, a sense of melancholy washed over him. It was a stark reminder of the tragedy that had unfolded in this palace, the corruption that had taken hold, and the family that had been torn apart. Long Qing's transformation into a pawn of the Overseer had not only cost him his own life but had also led to the downfall of his entire clan.

The room held more than just paintings; there were also diaries and personal belongings scattered about. Zhang Dong picked up one of the diaries and began to leaf through its pages. It chronicled Long Qing's life, from his early childhood to his rise as a prominent figure within the Azure Empire. It was filled with memories of happier times, of a family that had once been united and full of hope.

As he read, Zhang Dong couldn't help but feel a deep sense of sorrow for Long Qing and the path he had been forced down. It was clear that the Overseer had manipulated and controlled him from a young age, gradually corrupting his soul and turning him into a tool of destruction. Long Qing's love for his family had been genuine, and the burden of responsibility had weighed heavily on his shoulders.

"Long Qing, you deserved a better fate than this…"

Zhang Dong whispered to himself, closing the diary with a heavy heart. But there was no time for dwelling on the past. The Azure Palace was rapidly descending, and he needed to return to his people and ensure their safety. With a final glance at the room, he made his way back to the throne room, where the collapse of the palace was imminent.

As he re-entered the throne room, he could see that the palace was falling at an alarming rate. Chunks of stone and debris rained down from above, and he knew that he needed to act quickly. He activated a protective barrier around himself and then used his profound energy to fly out of the crumbling palace just in the nick of time.

Outside, the Azure Palace crashed to the ground with a thunderous roar, sending shockwaves through the surrounding area. The impact created a massive cloud of dust and debris, obscuring the once-grand structure from view. The other cultivators who participated in the battle watched in awe and relief as the threat of the Goliath was finally eradicated.

With the fall of the Azure Palace, the empire teetered on the brink of transformation. Though it had fallen, the Golden Palace remained aloft in the sky, symbolizing a new world order that the survivors within the Azure Capital could no longer ignore. The United Element Sect had emerged victorious, solidifying their status as the supreme power now ruling these lands!

Chapter 734

As the dust settled and the realization of their victory dawned on the survivors, Zhang Dong descended from the sky, landing amidst a cheering crowd of his fellow cultivators. Zhang Jin, his wife, rushed towards him, her eyes filled with a mixture of relief and concern.

"Are you alright, my love?"

She asked, her voice trembling. Zhang Dong smiled at her reassuringly.

"I'm fine, Liena. The threat is over, we did it…"

He responded in a monotone voice, his demeanor reflecting his dissatisfaction with how the situation had unfolded. While the immediate threat from the Long Clan appeared to have diminished, another problem loomed over him. He was the sole individual privy to the complete truth about this place, and at this juncture, he wasn't certain how to address it all.

The overseer could have infiltrated anywhere and assumed anyone's appearance. When he gazed at Zhang Liena before him, he knew he had to be vigilant. It was possible that the puppet had targeted the wives of the Empire's leaders, and he might soon become the new Emperor. With the Azure Dragon now gone, the Golden Dragon would reign supreme and probably not face much pushback from the survivors.

“Is something wrong? Are you sure you’re not hurt?”

“No, I’m just a bit tired but what about you? What’s with those tattered robes?”

“It’s nothing, I’m sure we had a far easier time than you, my husband.”

Liena appeared fatigued and drained of spiritual energy. Along with Huo Qiang and Zhang Zhi, she had managed to siphon a substantial amount of energy away from the Goliath. Among them, Qiang appeared to be in the worst condition, his body covered in claw marks and bleeding profusely. It was evident that he had borne the brunt of the attacks while traversing the underground tunnels of the Azure Capital.

Zhang Dong couldn't help but feel an overwhelming sense of gratitude for his wife and the others who had bravely fought by his side. They had put their lives on the line to weaken the Goliath and had played an essential role in securing victory. The same sentiment extended to his entire sect and Zhang Jin, who had led them. His angelic puppets had fortunately absorbed the worst of the attack, ensuring that most of his sect's forces remained unscathed. This intact army would be instrumental in securing a seamless transfer of power.

"Thank you, all of you, for your bravery and sacrifice."

He said, his voice filled with genuine appreciation. As they gathered amidst the remnants of the fallen Azure Palace, the survivors of the battle began to take stock of their situation. The Azure Capital had been saved, but it was not without its costs. Many lives had been lost, and the city itself had suffered significant damage. Rebuilding and healing would take time, but there was a newfound sense of unity among the survivors.

At that moment, the massive city still hovered high in the sky, its levitation system remaining intact. Only the Azure Palace had collapsed under its own weight. The Golden Palace began to ascend into the sky and positioned itself above the city. The once-active shield that had previously kept them at bay was no longer operational, granting them a clear view of the conquered citizens below.

The city was predominantly populated by Long Clan members and their closest branch families. However, there was also a segment of the population composed of servants and lower-ranking workers who were employed for cheap labor. Some of them had managed to awaken from their dreamlike state after being trapped in those strange pods, but not everyone was as fortunate. As anticipated, a significant portion of them would never return, as their fate had been sealed when they were used as energy sources to power the Goliath.

Zhang Dong and his allies faced a dilemma. With the Azure Palace's fall and the Golden Palace's ascent, they now had the power to dictate the fate of the Azure Capital. The question that loomed over them was how to handle the population below. Zhang Dong couldn't ignore the fact that many of them had been unwitting pawns in the Long Clan's schemes, trapped in a nightmare while their energy was drained to fuel the Goliath.

While Zhang Dong didn't actively participate in the process of freeing these people, he had a system through which he could witness some of the actions taking place. The scenes it displayed were grim, with some individuals sobbing uncontrollably. The pods that had contained their loved ones didn't always yield survivors. Their life forces had been consumed by the Goliath, which utilized them to power various systems, including the energy net. It became evident that a substantial portion of the population had been reduced to dust during the confrontation, leaving them with the daunting task of determining how to proceed in the aftermath.

In many cases, the victorious sect would traditionally eradicate the old superpower. Some of Zhang Dong's followers were eager to exact revenge on the defeated Long Clan members. If the situation were reversed, everyone anticipated the Long Clan descending upon the lower regions and not stopping until every United Element Sect member was killed. It now rested on Zhang Dong's shoulders to make a decision, whether to adhere to the old rules that had governed this world or to usher in change.

“Has anyone found the Emperor’s children or the grand elders?”

“We are quickly searching through the survivors, what shall we do with them, Patriarch?”

The looming threat of the Overseer weighed on him heavily, but Zhang Dong had to remain focused on guiding his people. He could see that they were still intoxicated by the taste of victory and thirsted for revenge. If he left it to the others, he feared that the entire city would be decimated in an instant. The city lacked any form of defense, and the survivors were depleted of spiritual energy, rendering them incapable of defending themselves to any significant degree.

“We will provide them aid, send down our healers and call for more support from the main sect.”

“You wish to provide support? Zhang Jin asked but his tone didn’t carry any surprise.”

“Yes, those people suffered enough for one day. We shall allow them to live under us if they so wish, they pose no threat to us anymore.”

“I see…”

Zhang Jin nodded in agreement, recognizing the wisdom in Zhang Dong's decision. It was a chance to break the cycle of violence that had plagued this world for generations. By extending a hand of mercy to the defeated Long Clan members and their families, they could potentially foster a new era of cooperation and unity. However, as an old man, he wasn’t quite sure if this move was right. All depended on their might which could dwindle with time.

As healers and relief teams from the United Element Sect descended to provide aid to the survivors below, Zhang Dong and his allies initiated a dialogue with the remaining Long Clan elders and high-ranking officials. It was a delicate negotiation, with both sides cautious and wary. Zhang Dong made it clear that they had the upper hand but offered a choice: they could either join the new order under the United Element Sect's leadership or choose to leave the Azure Capital forever and abandon their Clan name with it.

“You want us to leave and abandon our name?”

“How can we trust in your words? What guarantee do we have?”

“Guarantee? I don’t think you have realized the position you are in now.”

Zhang Jin stepped forward to speak in place of Zhang Dong, who remained at a distance. He recognized that certain matters were better handled by individuals other than Zhang Dong himself.

"The guarantee you have, dear elders, is that the world has changed."

Zhang Jin said with a calm but firm tone.

"The Azure Capital is no longer under the control of the Long Clan, and we have no interest in perpetuating the cycle of violence that has plagued this land for generations. We offer you a choice to start anew, to leave behind the old ways and the old grievances."

The Long Clan elders exchanged glances, clearly torn between the options presented to them. They were well aware of the overwhelming strength of the United Element Sect and the futility of resisting. Still, pride and a deep sense of loyalty to their clan weighed heavily on their decision-making. One of the elders, an aged man with a long, white beard, stepped forward and spoke.

"Great Elder Zhang Jin, while we acknowledge the changed circumstances, we must consider the wellbeing of our people and the preservation of our heritage. We would be willing to leave the Azure Capital and abandon our name, but only if you provide safe passage and guarantees of our safety."

Zhang Jin nodded in agreement.

"We are prepared to offer you safe passage out of the Azure Capital and our assurance that you will not be harmed by us. In fact, we would welcome the opportunity for cooperation and peaceful coexistence, should you choose to do so. We believe that together, we can rebuild this city into a place of harmony and progress."

The negotiations continued for some time, as both sides painstakingly worked through the specifics of the Long Clan's departure. It was evident on some participants' faces that leaving this place wouldn't be a straightforward matter. The initial step would involve taking control of the entire location, including the spirit vein. The depletion of spiritual energy had already begun in the lower regions, and everyone present hoped to unleash the floodgates once more.

For some, this would be the end but for others, it was only the beginning. With the negotiations underway, Zhang Dong and his allies began the process of stabilizing the situation in the Azure Capital. The city had suffered significant damage during the battle, and their first priority was to ensure the safety and well-being of the survivors.

While the healers tended to the still-trapped citizens, Zhang Jin began to scan the area. Bob utilized his own scanners to uncover the potential extent of hidden rooms within the city. The Overseer they had previously encountered had resided in this city for hundreds of years. They understood the importance of discovering all of its secrets, as these could be crucial in the final confrontation that lay ahead.

‘I guess we still have some work to do, Let’s get to it BoB!’

‘Affirmative.’

Chapter 735

‘That’s isn’t surprising when I think about it… But they made it quite blatant…’

“How should we proceed Patriarch? Do you wish for the Golden Palace to dock?”

“Hmm…”

Zhang Dong hovered in the air, engaged in conversation with one of his loyal retainers, Zhang Kuo. The war with the Long Clan had finally come to an end, and approximately eighty percent of the city's population had managed to survive the Goliath's onslaught. Unfortunately, the unlucky ones had been turned to dust during its berserk rampage, while another fifteen percent were left crippled to varying degrees.

The draining of their spiritual energy had left some of the survivors unable to function as they once had. While their strength would gradually return with time, their cultivation would remain compromised if left unchecked. To cultivate good relations with the newly occupied city, it was decided that they would offer assistance. However, convincing the Long Clan to accept this aid proved to be a more challenging endeavor.

Merely a day had transpired since the confrontation had concluded. The Long Clan had reigned as the supreme force within the empire for as long as the empire itself had stood. Accepting a reality where they were no longer the dominant power was inconceivable for many. Taking assistance from those who had conquered them felt like a profound blow to their pride, and a significant portion of them were unwilling to accept any help.

“It needs to be done, we probably won’t be able to control the spirit vein without it, very well have gramps land it.”

With Zhang Dong's decision made, the Golden Palace slowly descended, its imposing presence casting a shadow over the city. As it touched down on the ground, the earth trembled under its weight, and the survivors of the Azure Capital watched in awe but also disdain. For many, it was their first close encounter with the powerful sect that had brought down the Long Clan and they just replaced their old Azure Palace with the Golden one.

The new Golden Palace, while not as expansive as the old Azure Palace, appeared to fit seamlessly into the space from which it had risen. It was evident that this structure was intended to serve as the new command center for the city and perhaps, in a hundred thousand years or more, as the focal point for the next conflict between empires. How history would ultimately remember this day could be shaped by the Overseer's intentions, and Zhang Dong might never be acknowledged as the one who had defeated the old Emperor.

‘The more I think about it, the more it seems that this is the end of my adventure… at least when it comes to this world…’

While the Golden Knights still remained here, they didn’t pose a threat to him who had now unified the entire empire under his rule. Even if their true leader were to arrive, they wouldn't pose a significant threat since the main spirit vein was under his control. As the Golden Palace descended, Zhang Dong's attention turned to the system window. It quickly became apparent that he was gaining an enormous amount of spirit points and energy. His passive income had surged by thousands of times, as the entire empire now appeared as his territory.

It seemed to connect with the system, granting him a measure of control. Through the Golden Palace, he realized he could now fully command this spirit vein, which was evidently situated directly beneath the city. Upon consulting his mapping device, he observed that it stretched throughout the entire region, encircled by immense mountains.

‘There is so much energy down there… It’s no wonder that they could survive for this long but… Most of its heading somewhere else… ‘

After a few moments of revelation, the truth about the Long Clan and the Azure Capital began to emerge. While the spirit vein was indeed substantial, most of its energy had been channeled into the grand formation that had previously entrapped him and his army. The remaining energy had been gradually distributed throughout the rest of the empire, with the highest concentration residing in the central region. Now, all of it was under his control, and Zhang Dong faced several choices.

‘Bob, I want you to integrate with the city. Find any hidden routes that the Overseer could have used, I want to know all of the secrets that they are hiding from me…’

‘Affirmative.’

As one battle concluded, the next one commenced - a silent and subtle one. Zhang Dong needed to determine the extent to which he could influence the empire. With his recent victory, he was on the cusp of ascension. When examining the history of other system holders who had come before him, he recognized that this was the endgame.

With the significant spiritual point income at his disposal, he could begin investing in his own cultivation. The transaction rate was abysmal, but without any more immediate concerns, he could afford to pour his resources into strengthening himself. Even if it took years, eventually he would probably arrive at the level of an immortal and be cast out of this world.

However, if he just did that, then he would be doing what the Overseer and the thing that was above him wanted. His predecessor wasn’t able to figure out the reason for the system and the scenarios before ascending. Zhang Dong worried that there could be a potential trap waiting for him when he finally moved on. He needed time to prepare as even if he didn’t want to, eventually, it would run out.

‘Sooner or later I will become old, just like that guy I could try suppressing my cultivation level but … I’ll have to make a decision eventually.’

The future appeared promising for Zhang Dong's entire sect. They had emerged victorious and could anticipate thousands of years of prosperity. Although some harbored reservations about the fact that a significant portion of the old Long Clan still remained, they understood that if push came to shove, the United Element Sect would prevail.

As Zhang Dong contemplated the future and the complexities of his newfound power, he couldn't help but feel a sense of responsibility weighing heavily on his shoulders. The decisions he made would shape the destiny of not only his sect but also the entire empire.

The negotiations with the Long Clan continued, and gradually, a consensus began to emerge. Many of the Long Clan members, especially the younger generation and the ones coming from branching families who had not been as deeply entrenched in the old ways, saw the opportunity for a fresh start. They recognized the strength of the United Element Sect and the potential benefits of cooperation. Some even embraced the chance to abandon the Long Clan name, which had been tarnished by the recent events.

However, there were still hardliners among the Long Clan elders who clung to their pride and refused to accept the terms offered by Zhang Dong's side. Zhang Jin, with his years of experience and wisdom, took it upon himself to engage with these stubborn elders individually. He appealed to their sense of responsibility for their people and urged them to consider the greater good of the empire.

In the end, a majority of the core Long Clan members chose to leave the Azure Capital, abandoning their name and accepting safe passage to an undisclosed location. It was a bittersweet moment as they departed, leaving behind a legacy that had spanned generations. The remaining survivors, both Long Clan and others, were gradually integrated into the new order established by the United Element Sect.

The Golden Palace became the center of governance for the city, and the survivors were provided with resources and assistance to help them rebuild their lives. Healers from the sect worked tirelessly to mend the physical and spiritual wounds of the survivors, and Zhang Dong made it clear that vengeance was not the path they would follow. Instead, he emphasized unity and cooperation, hoping to break the cycle of conflict that had plagued the empire for so long.

As days turned into weeks, the Azure Capital began to transform. The once-divided population slowly started to coexist, and new alliances and friendships formed. Zhang Dong and his allies worked tirelessly to ensure that the transition was as smooth as possible, and gradually, a sense of stability descended upon the city. Nevertheless, the atmosphere still remained solemn as accepting such a large shift and fall from power was not easy.

The surviving core elders of the Long Clan were confined to an area that was closely monitored, with their every movement reported to the higher-ups. Although it might have appeared on the surface that they had acquiesced, the peace was fragile. It would likely take years, perhaps even generations, for this complex situation to truly reach its conclusion. Everyone knew that hidden forces would eventually form and they needed to make sure that they didn’t gain enough power to pose a threat.

Meanwhile, Bob's integration with the city's systems yielded significant results. Hidden tunnels and chambers that had been used by the Overseer to manipulate events were uncovered. Zhang Dong was determined to understand every secret that the city held, for he knew that the ultimate confrontation with the Overseer and the entity above it was inevitable.

In one of those concealed rooms, the bodies of Long Qing's family were discovered. Even the Empress, whom Zhang Dong had witnessed transform before him, lay there with the same fatal wound that had marked the puppet. All of them had been killed, and the murder weapon appeared to belong to the Azure Emperor, bearing his spiritual signature and fingerprints. To the uninitiated, it might have seemed like the work of a mad tyrant, but only Zhang Dong understood the true motives behind these actions.

Zhang Dong's heart sank as he examined the grim scene. The bodies of Long Qing's family lay cold and lifeless, a testament to the brutal actions of the Overseer. It was clear that the puppet had framed the old Emperor for this treachery. It was something that would actually be beneficial to his own rise as he could present himself as a benevolent revolutionary who defeated the corrupt demonic leader. It was as if in this case the Overseer was helping him out from behind the scenes, something that he disliked tremendously.

He knew that the Overseer's intentions extended far beyond the boundaries of the Azure Capital and into the whole Empire. It wanted to manipulate everything to suit the scenario it was programmed for and perhaps even allow its sect to flourish in the coming years.

Chapter 736

“Are you sure about this Dong’er? I’m not sure if the people will accept this…”

“Yes, I have made my decision, the sect will allow the remnants of the Long Clan to reside in the city and we will assign one of our elders to govern the old capital city.”

“I guess if that is what you want, no one will stop you. I bet some of those old farts will actually love the idea of governing this old city…”

Zhang Jin commented as both him and Zhang Dong were looking at the Azure City which was slowly transforming into the Golden City. Zhang Dong gazed at the Golden Palace now firmly established as the center of governance. The once-divided Azure Capital had started to regain its vibrancy, and with the integration of the Long Clan remnants, it was slowly becoming the Golden City, a symbol of a new beginning that brought its own problems with it.

Even though everything appeared peaceful on the surface, Zhang Dong knew that old grudges would resurface over time. His sect had managed to climb from the bottom to the top in under twenty years. They had started as a lone lesser clan with only one surviving core formation elder, Zhang Jin. With his arrival, they had swiftly risen to prominence. Such an achievement was considered nearly impossible without outside assistance, so most people assumed that the sect had been fortunate in discovering some immortal-grade treasures.

As a result, the remnants of the Long Clan and other external factions would likely make efforts to uncover the truth behind their power. Most of the evidence pointed to Zhang Dong, who had seemingly emerged out of nowhere, initiated the conquest of the lower regions, and was subsequently revealed to be the younger brother of the former Emperor. Many believed that he had schemed for hundreds of years and instigated the rebellion when threats from other empires began to mount.

The collection of information on how he had accomplished this remarkable ascent would likely begin soon, and some of his followers might find themselves in peril. Zhang Dong understood the ambitions of these individuals when it came to acquiring power, and if they believed that a single item could make them the most powerful in the empire, they wouldn't hesitate to resort to extreme measures, even including harming their own family members.

To counter these potential threats, Zhang Dong recognized that he needed to consolidate his power, not just for himself but for the future of his sect and the city as a whole. He needed to create a foundation that would withstand scrutiny and ensure long-term stability. With the looming threat of the Overseer out there, it was possible for him to not always be here. If he vanished before his armies became truly self-sufficient the remnants of the old Long Clan could rise up again.

Zhang Dong was well aware of how these dynamics played out. There was often a hidden sect, clan, or cult working in the shadows, waiting for the right moment to emerge. It was even possible that this Overseer had created such forces to provide system holders with challenges in the later stages of the scenario. This concept was akin to repeatable quests in massively multiplayer online games, a thing Zhang Dong was familiar with from his past experiences.

His thoughts shifted to the enigmatic spirit vein beneath the city. It represented a formidable source of energy and influence but also posed a potential risk. If left unattended, it could lead to a disaster. While controlling it required the Golden Palace, making it inaccessible to ordinary individuals, it did not preclude the possibility of people attempting to access the vein directly. The potential for corrupting or harnessing the power of such spirit veins for personal gain existed. Protecting it from both external threats and those within, who might have a change of heart, was imperative.

“That’s why we will be establishing a council of elders and Qiang will be one of their main members.”

“The Matriarch won’t like the idea…”

Zhang Jin chuckled at the idea of entrusting someone like Qiang with leadership over a crucial sect asset like the Golden City. The primary reason was the trustworthiness of Qiang. Despite his lack of managerial skills, he would not intentionally act against the sect or Zhang Dong. Furthermore, he was the second most powerful elder within the entire sect, and power was always held in high regard by the cultivators in this world.

Zhang Dong decided to establish a council of elders and experts, including representatives from the Long Clan remnants, to oversee the management and distribution of the spirit vein's energy. By involving various factions in this critical decision-making process, he aimed to reduce suspicion and gain their trust. The council would ensure fairness and transparency in the allocation of resources, preventing any one group from monopolizing the spirit vein's power which he planned to share with the whole Empire.

The old Long Clan, along with the other two most prominent sects, had monopolized this resource for hundreds of years. From Zhang Dong's perspective, coming from another world, these people were not necessarily enemies, and they could potentially assist him in future conflicts. The future remained uncertain, and having a more potent empire with him at the helm represented a superior outcome.

“I know but I’m sure she will be happy that he won’t be around Spirit Spring City anymore.”

“Ah that’s right, you won’t be staying here.”

Zhang Dong nodded as he had decided to not reside in the old Azure City that was the symbol of the old Long Clan. One of the reasons was that he didn’t want to be seen as a replacement for his older brother and continue with the same tired traditions. He preferred a more democratic approach to most of the decisions with him only being called forth when no decisions could be met.

Yet, the primary reason he wished not to linger here was because the entire area seemed custom-made for the Overseer. The region contained numerous concealed areas that Bob had uncovered. Zhang Dong didn't want to remain too close to this enigmatic being, and this sentiment applied to his family as well. The peculiar puppet had a fondness for replacing significant members within clans and sects. To safeguard his family from being substituted, he needed to maintain constant surveillance. The old city served as his main base, where his faction system operated most effectively.

“Keep Qiang in check, golden council elder Jin.”

“Ah… You have to let this old man retire one of these days.”

“Hah, tough luck, you’ll be using that longevity for the sake of the sect, don’t even try to run away or I’ll have Granny Maling assigned with you.”

“You know how to give an old man nightmares!”

Zhang Jin frowned at the notion of having Feng Mailing living in this city.

“Just try to keep your hands to yourself for once, I don’t want any timebombs within our clan…”

“I know, I know, who do you think I am!”

“A pervert? Some would call you the scum of the earth I guess? I would be surprised if you could be the most hated elder among the men and women in the sect.”

Zhang Jin averted his gaze, while Zhang Dong stared at him with a squint. He comprehended his grandfather's intentions regarding the newfound power and extended lifespan. Zhang Dong feared that many Long Clan members would offer their daughters in the future, and he worried that his grandfather, with his questionable inclinations, might accept a few into his fold. He also had concerns that these children could be nurtured into potential assassins by their disgruntled mothers, patiently awaiting the opportune moment to exact revenge.

“Hey, cut it out, I’m a respected elder! Why would anyone hate me?”

“I don’t know, stealing young maidens away will garner some animosity?”

“I won’t do it!”

“We shall see…”

Zhang Dong couldn't help but smile at the playful banter with his grandfather. Despite the weight of responsibility and the challenges they faced, moments like this reminded him of the bonds that held their family together. They had come a long way from their humble beginnings, and now they were responsible for the fate of an entire city and the future of the empire.

As they continued to discuss the future of the Golden City, Zhang Jin couldn't help but feel a sense of pride for how far their sect had come. He had witnessed the rise of the United Element Sect from obscurity to becoming a dominant force in the empire. It was a testament to Zhang Dong's leadership and their collective efforts.

As the Golden City gradually took shape and the council of elders assumed the responsibility of overseeing the spirit vein, it was time for Zhang Dong to return home. Liena had left the city some time ago, and the children had stayed behind in Spirit Spring City. To some, the United Elements Sect's headquarters held the status of the true capital, while the rebuilt Golden City served primarily as a facade.

Typically, the location with the most power also housed the most powerful individual. Zhang Dong chose to stay in the old city, which had never been under the Overseer's influence and lacked any hidden chambers. This decision would enable him to keep a watchful eye on the area to see if his adversary decided to establish any hidden chambers. While one battle may have concluded, this war was far from over.

“I guess this is it, gramps, I’ll leave the rest to you and the other elders. If there is something that you can’t deal with, you know where to reach me.”

“Don’t worry, I’ll take good care of this place, you have my word!”

Finally, the two parted ways, and Zhang Dong headed towards a more secluded location. With an abundant supply of spirit points, teleportation throughout the entire empire became effortless. The expenses were further reduced, as most of the lands were considered part of his faction or under his control.

Zhang Dong's journey continued, but it had now shifted from one of conquest to one of consolidation and preparation. As he teleported to Spirit Spring City, he was met with the familiar sights of the city where he had spent many years cultivating and building his sect. The United Element Sect had come a long way from its humble beginnings, and it had Zhang Dong to thank for its meteoric rise. The city had expanded significantly, and the sect had become a formidable force in the empire.

However, his mind was in an entirely different place. He wanted nothing more than to forget about his future plans and focus on the present. Before him stood a beauty with a bright smile on her face to welcome him.

“Welcome home.”

“I’m back…”

Chapter 737

“We couldn’t have done it without you. I Lucius, will forever be grateful for the aid that you have provided for me and my people.”

“It’s fine, you don’t need to kneel, I actually prefer the more snarky Lucius.”

“I had been a fool…”

“Argus, could you do something about this…”

“I don’t think I can, Patriarch Dong. The help that you have given us, this debt is not something that we can take lightly.”

“Hah…”

Zhang Dong gazed at the golden knight kneeling before him, surrounded by a diverse assembly of other armored men. Several years had passed since their arrival in the empire, and after their triumph over the Azure Emperor, they had finally managed to collect all the pieces of their holy relic. Fortunately, upon assembly, it didn't transform into another world-ending threat. It appeared that this war had indeed come to an end.

Although a century had not yet passed, everything could now draw to a close. There was no longer any reason for Argus and the group of golden knights to remain here. They could all return home and present their relics to their king. Zhang Dong didn't know the true purpose of the holy equipment - perhaps another system holder would be summoned to that empire in the future and use it to achieve victory in their adventure. Or perhaps it was merely an empty quest with no genuine purpose, meant to create tension between his faction and others. Regardless, it was now concluded, and these individuals could leave these lands behind.

To them, Zhang Dong was a great benefactor who had allowed them to preserve their forces and accomplish the quest entrusted to them by their holy king. Argus and Lucius, as the two main leaders, would be richly rewarded and perhaps even granted higher positions. Their lives would be secured, and their families would be well taken care of by their kingdom. From what he had heard, Lucius might even request the hand in marriage of one of the princesses, which would elevate him to the title of Arch-Duke. In the future, one of his descendants might even ascend to the throne, something for which they were now profoundly grateful.

“Just get up, we had a deal and I just followed through it. Without your help I wouldn’t have been able to complete my task either.”

Argus and the golden knights rose to their feet, a sense of gratitude and respect in their eyes as they looked at Zhang Dong. Their armor gleamed in the sunlight, and the presence of these noble and chivalrous warriors added a unique aura to Spirit Spring City. It was a testament to the diverse and extraordinary individuals who had gathered under the banner of the United Element Sect. Lucius stepped forward, his voice filled with sincerity.
"Patriarch Dong, if you ever find yourself in need, know that the knights of our order will be at your service. We owe you a debt that can never truly be repaid, but we will do our best to honor it."

Zhang Dong nodded, but he knew that Luciu’s words didn’t carry that much weight. The Duke of the Golden Knights might not have realized yet but the bridges that had opened up were only a temporary measure. Even if he wanted to call for their aid, there would be no way of reaching them.

"Thank you, Lucius. I'll keep that in mind. But for now, go back to your kingdom, and may your people find peace and prosperity."

With their farewells exchanged, the golden knights mounted their horses and rode out of Spirit Spring City, disappearing into the horizon. Zhang Dong watched them go, a mixture of emotions swirling within him. It was the end of an era, and he couldn't help but feel a sense of closure but also one of dread. The people around were all cheering but he could not get over the bad feeling.

In reality, the true mastermind that created this whole debacle was out there and he could not reveal the truth. It had been a few months since the defeat of the Azure Emperor and his sect was still in the process of taking over the Empire. He couldn't help but think about the looming presence of the Overseer but truly the person hiding behind what looked to be a puppet.

The enigmatic figure had orchestrated the entire scenario, manipulating system holders and setting up challenges in this world. It was clear that the one above the Overseer was playing a deeper game, one that transcended individual scenarios and involved something much bigger. What was his purpose and why did they want people to go through trials before ascending?

At first glance, it might have seemed that the system holders like him were giving everything to thrive. However, upon closer examination of the role he played and the events that unfolded throughout the entire scenario, it was far from an easy journey, at least not for a conventional system holder. As he observed Wang Long, he couldn't be certain if the man would have been strong enough to overcome the other emperors. Similarly, Zhang Dong had perished during the clash with the Pride Demon in the secret domain.

Survival was no simple feat, and even with the system, people would still perish. It wasn't unreasonable to consider that the creators of this system didn't intend for everyone to survive, but rather to persevere the ones that could push through. This was one possibility, while another could be that the scenario would offer a challenge that each system holder could theoretically overcome without becoming overwhelmingly difficult. It would allow more people with some aptitude to get through without losing too many of them.

Zhang Dong contemplated these questions as he gazed at the sky above. The Golden Knights had departed, leaving him alone in his residence. In the distance, he could hear the laughter of others. The once-small city he had established had grown into a bustling metropolis, and they were now even constructing a secondary grand palace to rival the Azure one that he had destroyed. At least for his people, this was an age of prosperity, the time for the United Element Sect had arrived.

He had ascended to the status of a true emperor, the uncontested number one cultivator in the entire world and empire. There was nothing that could oppose him or would dare to challenge his authority. His forces had established themselves as the new dynasty, poised to dominate for as long as he guided them. With nearly a thousand years of life left, he could prepare them for the future, just as the emperors who came before him had done.

Even though everything had gone his way, he couldn't escape the feeling that there were still challenges ahead. The enigmatic puppeteer who had orchestrated the scenario remained a looming threat, and the true purpose behind the system's existence eluded him. If he continued to look at the life of his predecessor, things had gone in a similar fashion. The man had conquered the whole empire and plotted for a thousand years before ascending into supposedly a higher realm.

Nonetheless, what lay beyond that point remained uncertain, but it was a matter he would eventually need to explore. Time may seem like a non-issue when you lived for a thousand years, but inevitably, he would reach that limit. Nascent Soul Cultivators could maintain their peak strength for roughly six to seven hundred years before age began to take its toll. He wasn't even a hundred years old yet, so he still had time to make preparations.

One thing was certain - he couldn't afford to relax just yet. Everything he had built and everything he knew could be swept away in an instant at the whim of an unknown force. If it wasn't the Overseer, then perhaps someone else had an interest in his fate. It was evident that he was only temporarily allowed to exist in this realm, without truly comprehending the full scope of what was transpiring.

Perhaps, if he unleashed his full power, he could potentially defeat that puppet, but there were likely more like it out there. He had no chance of emerging victorious without ascending first. He could only hope that the mutated cultivation realm he had within him would ultimately lead to success.

With a sigh, he returned to the present moment. The celebrations in Spirit Spring City were in full swing, and he couldn't allow his worries to dampen the joy of his people. They had come a long way, and they deserved this moment of happiness.

Zhang Dong decided to join the festivities, at least for a while. He mingled with his sect members, citizens, and guests from the remnants of the Long Clan. The transformation of the city into a vibrant and prosperous place was a testament to their hard work and resilience.

He witnessed numerous faces and old sects from years gone by. Everyone bowed in his radiant presence, for to them, he was the most potent cultivator to ever exist—an individual who had ended a dynasty that had endured for a hundred thousand years, a living legend. They all sought a place by his side, imploring him to accept them into his sect, even if only as servants.

The same scenario unfolded with his disciples and even his own children. Everyone wanted them to betroth their daughters or sons. One of the grand chambers had to be transformed into a treasury to house all the gifts that his children were receiving.

Despite just entering their teenage years, their value was intrinsically linked to their father, who held dominion over it all. If he desired it, they would be granted anything they wanted, and he was somewhat concerned that this might corrupt their character. Receiving things without having to truly earn them could potentially lead to unethical behavior, something he hoped to prevent at all costs.

‘The few years that I wasn’t here might have done them good, but Jun has been getting a bit arrogant lately and I don’t want him to turn into another young master, I might have to give him some proper fatherly love then…’

As the night sky adorned with stars took over, Zhang Dong found himself standing on the balcony of his residence, contemplating the future. The city below was illuminated with lanterns and laughter, and the festivities showed no signs of slowing down. It was a beautiful sight, and he took a moment to appreciate the happiness he had brought to so many.

With a determined expression, Zhang Dong turned from the balcony and made his way back to the celebration. The night was young, and there was still much to do. The path ahead was uncertain, but he was ready to face whatever challenges lay in wait. The Golden City had risen, and he would do everything in his power to ensure it shone brightly and for his loved ones to prosper…

Chapter 738

“Hah, are you sure about this? You still have time to bow your head and surrender before you get hurt~”

“Why would I bow my head? This time you are going down!”

“Did little Jun’er finally grow a pair? I hope you’ll do better than last time.”

“I’ll have you eat those words and stop calling me little!”

“Make me then!”

Two young fighters were staring at each other. One was a beautiful young girl with light pink hair that stood out of the crowd. Her hair was a delicate shade of pink, reminiscent of cherry blossoms in full bloom, and it cascaded down to her shoulders with a silky, radiant sheen. Her skin had a slightly tan complexion, giving her a healthy and sun-kissed appearance.

Her opponent was a young man of around the same age who looked to be in his later teenage years. His white hair and striking figure gave him a somewhat otherworldly charm that enticed the onlooking ladies to cheer him on. His hair was long and flowed loosely around his shoulders, moving like a soft waterfall of silk.

“Young Master Jun, we believe in you!”

“Young Lady Xiu, take it easy on the young master, we all know that you are the best!”

The young lady, Zhang Xiu, was known for her exceptional martial skills, which had earned her the admiration and respect of many in Spirit Spring City. She was often considered the most promising disciple of the United Element Sect. Her mastery of elemental control was unparalleled, and she had a natural affinity for water and wind, which allowed her to perform incredible feats of rapid water manipulation. Her water-based martial arts were graceful and mesmerizing, yet deadly in their precision. She was a splitting image of her mother, Zhang Liena.

On the other hand, Zhang Jun, Zhang Dong's son was more similar to his father and proficient in both lightning and holy elemental attacks. He had been diligently practicing martial arts under the guidance of his father and the sect's most skilled warriors. Although he had come a long way, he was still considered an underdog compared to Xiu. The crowd watched with bated breath as the two young warriors squared off, ready to witness a thrilling contest.

They both were standing on a large circular arena that had risen up into the air. It was much larger than a standard football field at around ten times the size. It was encased in a grand translucent barrier that allowed the onlookers to peek inside. Then to make things even clearer there were massive screens floating in the background and close to the stands the viewers were residing in.

The battle began with an explosion of energy as Xiu lunged forward with a graceful, fluid motion. Her control over water was truly a sight to behold, as she sent torrents of water spiraling towards Zhang Jun, who barely managed to evade by creating an electrical barrier around himself.

The crowd cheered as the two young warriors clashed, each displaying their unique skills. Xiu danced like a water nymph, her movements flowing like a river, while Zhang Jun moved with the agility and precision of a lightning tiger. Sparks of electricity crackled around him as he deftly avoided Xiu's watery attacks.

The battle raged on, with neither giving an inch. Xiu continued to use her water manipulation to her advantage, creating intricate patterns and deadly strikes, while Zhang Jun countered with swift lightning bolts that danced around the arena. Their elemental powers clashed and intertwined, creating a breathtaking display of beauty and power.

As the battle continued, it was clear that Zhang Jun had improved significantly since their last encounter. He was more agile and had a better understanding of his elemental abilities. The audience watched in amazement as he executed a complex lightning and holy elemental combination attack, creating a dazzling display of power that left Xiu momentarily stunned.

But Xiu was not one to be underestimated. With a determined look in her eyes, she summoned a massive water dragon that surged towards Zhang Jun, threatening to engulf him. However, Zhang Jun was not to be outdone. He unleashed a powerful burst of holy energy that encased him in a radiant glow. The technique allowed him to enhance his power several times as he pushed the water dragon back.

“They are improving each day but…”

“Yes, Jun is being a bit too hasty, he isn’t conserving his spiritual energy enough and also has less of it than Xiu.”

While the two youths were fighting their parents and other members of the sect looked on from afar. Some years had passed since the creation of the new Golden Empire that this sect now resided over. Their father Zhang Dong along with his lovely wife Liena were looking at their children who were competing with each other. The older sister still remained superior but her brother was quickly catching up.

As the battle between Zhang Xiu and Zhang Jun continued, their parents, Zhang Dong and Zhang Liena, couldn't help but feel a sense of pride and nostalgia. Watching their children grow and develop their elemental abilities brought back memories of their own journeys and struggles. Zhang Dong, the Patriarch of the United Element Sect and the Emperor of the Golden Empire, looked at his wife with a fond smile.

"Our children have come a long way, haven't they? It seems like just yesterday when they were still in their early training stages."

Liena chuckled while nodding.

"Yes, they have. It's incredible to see how much they've grown, their progress is also staggering. I was nowhere near this level at this age they might soon reach the nascent stage if this continues!”

“Yes, I bet the two will boast about how they were able to reach it before their parents did.”

“Haha, let them. They have earned it!”

Liena continued to fawn over her children while Dong worried about their future. The couple watched as Xiu and Jun continued their fierce but friendly competition. The battle was a testament to their dedication and hard work, as well as the guidance and training they had received from their parents and the sect.

Zhang Dong couldn't help but think about the future. He knew that one day, he would have to pass on the leadership of the sect and the empire to the next generation. Seeing the potential in his children, he believed that they were more than capable of carrying on his legacy but there was one elephant in the room, their ages.

Both their parents were still relatively young and outshone their children in every aspect. The two of them were now twenty and seventy years of age, and the age gap between them and their parents wasn't particularly significant. The true future leaders of this Golden Dynasty would emerge more than five hundred years from now, as Zhang Dong's reign was destined for at least another six hundred years. That is, if he decided to remain in this world for that amount of time.

Considerable time had elapsed since the last major incident, and at this point, he was confident they were in the epilogue of the story. There was nothing left but for him to enjoy his happy ending and ride off into the sunset. His status as the new emperor had already been secured, and his path to ascension was clearly defined. With each passing day, he accumulated spirit points that he could utilize to further enhance his cultivation. The rate at which they accrued was so staggering that he couldn't help but wonder if this was the intended amount his hidden adversaries had in mind.

It wouldn't be unusual for him to ascend to the immortal realm in a relatively short span of time, but he wasn't sure if he should. There was a significant decision he needed to make, something he had been postponing while watching his children grow. As the two engaged in their dispute, he couldn't help but reminisce about their childhood appearances and how soon they would become full-grown adults, a process he couldn't halt.

There was still time to make the decision, and he would wait until the very last moment. After finding happiness in this world with his wife, he wanted to indulge in a bit of selfishness. The time he spent with his wife, children, and friends was what he treasured the most, and eventually, it would all come to an end. He stood before two choices, neither of which he had fully committed to yet.

One choice would lead him towards an early death at a thousand years of age. He would live out a full life in this world and ensure that his children prosper for many generations to come. With Bob by his side, there was a possibility of transferring into other devices that could aid his people if they ever encountered a new system holder. Perhaps it was possible to make this world truly safe and prepare people to defeat future system holders who decided to follow an evil path.

The second option was to ascend and depart from this place. He would follow the scenario created by whoever had designed this world and prepare accordingly. There were still many years left for him to live out. He could slowly make preparations for the occasion, but he would need to shorten his stay in this world. His predecessor had chosen to wait until they were on their deathbed, but he wasn't sure if that was the right path leading to victory.

The available data did not provide enough information about what awaited him. One thing that could enhance his chances of survival was a youthful body and mind. Eventually, his cultivator body, which couldn't progress any further, would start deteriorating, and his power would diminish. Becoming an immortal at a younger age was likely better than doing so at a later stage. As in the tales of old, the younger a cultivator appeared, the more powerful they were as they achieved higher realms at younger ages.

As Zhang Dong pondered these choices, the battle between Zhang Xiu and Zhang Jun continued, each moment bringing them closer to the realization of their potential. The crowd roared with excitement as they witnessed the clash between these two exceptional young warriors.

But amidst the cheers and the spectacle, Zhang Dong knew that the true challenges and mysteries lay ahead. The enigmatic puppeteer who had manipulated the scenarios in this world still eluded him. As an Emperor and the Patriarch of the United Element Sect, he had a responsibility not only to his family but to the people of the entire new Golden Empire.

He couldn't afford to be complacent. The path he chose would not only affect his future but the future of this world. With the knowledge and experiences he had gained over the years, he was determined to make the right decisions and prepare his people for the unknown challenges that lay ahead. However, for now, he would continue to revel in the joy of this moment, watching his children grow and thrive, and basking in the love and companionship of his family…

Chapter 739

“Hey, hurry up! We are going to miss it!”

“Calm down little one, we will be there in time… Look, the parade has only started.”

“It’s the golden elders!”

As the grandfather and his grandson watched the cultivators soaring through the sky, the sight was truly breathtaking. The golden robes of the cultivators glistened in the sunlight, and the flags they carried waved majestically in the wind. The characters on the flags, displaying the names of various sects, created a beautiful mosaic of unity within the world of cultivation.

The larger character in the middle, "United Sects of the Golden Empire," spoke of a powerful alliance, where different sects joined forces for a common purpose. It hinted at a time of harmony and cooperation among these groups, which was a rare and remarkable sight in the often competitive and hierarchical world of cultivation.

The grandfather and grandson watched in awe, knowing that they were witnessing a significant moment in the history of their martial world, where sects came together under a common banner, united for a greater cause. It was a scene that would be etched in their memories for years to come.

“Look, it’s the Great Emperor!”

“Haha, yes there he is, I didn’t think I would live enough to see this day… I hope this peace lasts forever.”

As the child cheered on in the parade, the old man started to reminisce about the old days. He was a Core Formation cultivator who was approaching the age of four hundred years. The man had not been much of a cultivator when the old Azure Empire fell, but he could recall that ancient, bloody war that shook everything.

The memories of that old, bloody war haunted him. It had been a time when the entire world of cultivation had been in turmoil. The Azure Empire, once a powerful and revered force, had crumbled under the weight of conflict and chaos. The battles had been fierce, and the loss of life immense. Friends and comrades he had known had perished, and the world had changed forever.

He had seen the skies darkened by the smoke of burning cities and the earth soaked with the blood of cultivators and ordinary people alike. It had been a time of profound loss and sacrifice, a memory etched deeply in his heart. However, that was a time long forgotten. The lands once scarred by conflict had transformed into a peaceful and harmonious realm where travelers could journey without fear. The Golden Emperor's wisdom and benevolence had extended to all, and his rule had brought stability and security to the entire empire.

It was a time when the people, regardless of their background or cultivation level, could pursue their dreams and aspirations without the constant threat of war and chaos. The Golden Emperor's legacy was not just one of strength and power but also of compassion and a commitment to the well-being of his subjects.
While the parade continued, the old man couldn't help but feel a sense of gratitude for the peace and prosperity that had come to define this new empire. It was a world where his grandson could grow up in safety and pursue his own cultivation journey, free from the horrors of the past. However, unbeknownst to the cheerful atmosphere in the crowd, the one who was responsible for it all was examining everything with a solemn expression.

Zhang Dong's wife gazed at him with concern, her eyes filled with a mix of love and understanding. She had been his constant companion for more than three centuries, and she could sense when something troubled him.

"Dear, is something wrong? You have been looking down lately?"

She inquired gently, her voice filled with warmth and care.

"Are you worried about Jun'er taking over your responsibilities? We could always postpone it for later."

Zhang Dong took a deep breath and smiled at his beloved wife, her presence was a constant source of strength and solace. He could see the love in her gaze that did not waver one bit even after more than three hundred years of being together.

"No, that's not it, I'm fine. Jun is more than suited for the role of Emperor, he'll be fine."

While he put on a brave face for her, there was still a hint of sadness in his eyes. The world had continued to turn and he had postponed his decision for many years but now time was quickly running out. What he was worried about was not how well his son would do as the sect head but when he was gone. His decision to ascend was drawing near and he wasn’t sure that he would be strong enough to leave his family behind.

“Ah, is it then about that other issue?”

“Yes…”

Liena had always been the one person in whom Zhang Dong confided his deepest secrets and his connection to the system was no different. Over the years, he had gradually revealed more and more of the intricate details, including his carefully thought-out plan for the future ascension.

To Zhang Dong's relief, Liena had taken the revelations remarkably well. Her support and understanding had been unwavering, and she had encouraged him to follow his heart and convictions. She understood the immense burden of responsibility he carried and the risks that lay ahead.

In Liena's eyes, they had already accomplished so much in their lifetimes, and they had a legacy of peace and unity to be proud of. She was willing to allow him to take whatever risks were necessary to protect their family and their vision for the empire's future. Her unwavering support and her belief in his decisions gave him the strength and determination to face the challenges that lay ahead with confidence.
“But that’s for then, let us enjoy the current moment, this is a big day for our little Jun… but I guess he isn’t that little anymore.”

“Haha, that’s true, he has become quite the responsible adult, probably more than his old man ever was.”

Zhang Dong couldn't help but smile with pride as he watched his son, a young man who had grown into a remarkable leader. The resemblance between father and son was uncanny, with the same distinctive snow-white hair and a chiseled chin that marked them as members of the same lineage. While there were subtle differences in their appearances, it was clear that he was his flesh and blood.

As his son delivered a grand speech, addressing not only the millions gathered before him but also the billions across different cities, Zhang Dong marveled at how the legacy of their family continued to thrive. His son's eyes, even sharper than his own, reflected a resolute and visionary spirit that had been passed down.

Zhang Dong felt a sense of fulfillment and reassurance in knowing that his son had the qualities needed to carry on their mission and lead the empire into a bright and prosperous future. The torch of leadership had been successfully passed, and it was now his son's turn to guide the empire with the same dedication. He could safely leave it up to him and his grandchildren that had been multiplying with time.

As the generations passed and new cultivators arose, Zhang Jun, like many others, reached a significant milestone in his life. He decided to take the step of getting married. However, his path to marriage was different from his father’s who did it early. It was marked by his unwavering commitment to training and his dedication to his responsibilities. Only after more than a hundred years did it finally come about.

His choice of a spouse, someone from outside the three great clans, had raised eyebrows and sparked some controversy. Many beauties from the powerful clans had hoped to win his heart, and there had been rumors of infighting and competition among them. Ultimately, Zhang Jun followed his heart and found the love of his life in someone not affiliated with the Zhang, Huo, or Feng clans.

One of his foremost concerns was whether his chosen spouse had been tampered with by the Overseer, a figure that had vanished since the last great war. For Zhang Dong, ensuring that his son wouldn’t be influenced like the last emperor was paramount. As of now, he had found no evidence to suggest any interference, allowing him to focus on other things like new grandchildren.

Zhang Dong's perspective was more in tune with the cultivators of this world. He had finally achieved the freedom to live his life without the constant threat of external dangers. The time he had been granted was dedicated to establishing peace and uniting an empire that had once been divided into thousands of smaller factions.

Instead of consolidating his own power in a single location, as his predecessors had done, he opted to distribute resources and elevate everyone to a certain standard. While no one could challenge the main sect's authority, people now enjoyed longer lives and cultivated with greater ease than ever before.

As life expectancy grew and the population increased, the empire experienced a significant transformation. People lived longer, healthier lives, and the extended years brought about a more adventurous spirit among its inhabitants. With newfound vigor, they sought to explore the uncharted territories beyond the well-established city-states led by clans or sects.

In this empire, most regions were divided into small city-states, each governed by powerful clans or sects. These city-states were relatively safe and prosperous. However, the smaller towns and remote areas that fell outside the protection of these powerful entities remained dangerous and untamed.

These less-regulated regions were fraught with dangers, from savage beasts roaming the wilderness to ruthless bandits preying on unsuspecting travelers. The life of a cultivator or adventurer often led them to these remote and wild areas in search of resources, secrets, and challenges, knowing that the risk was commensurate with the potential rewards.

With the unification of the lands, travel had become significantly more accessible, and life continued to thrive. There were still many uncharted regions that people were eager to explore, populate, and establish as new, expansive settlements and their own kingdoms. It was indeed a genuine era of exploration and growth, one that was likely to persist for thousands of years. Something that he wished to witness but the time for action was now and he had done all that he could to make everyone prosper.

His time needed to be used to explore what was outside this confined empire, he wanted to ascend while his body and mind were still strong and willing to fight for the future that he had created…

Chapter 740

“Most things are ready… Bob, let us go over the inventory and defenses again, make sure that we are prepared for that Overseer!”

“Affirmative.”

Zhang Dong stood within the old sacred ground that marked the beginning of his adventure. This was where his predecessor had ascended, and it was now his turn to take the plunge into the unknown. Over three hundred years had passed since his arrival in this world, and a choice needed to be made. As Bob calculated away, Zhang Dong pondered his options, each with its own merits.

First, he could choose to remain here, living out his life with his family until he succumbed to old age. Currently, there didn't seem to be any danger from the Overseer, which had been dormant since the fall of the Azure Capital. It made sense to believe that for the seven or six hundred years he had left, he could enjoy this world to the fullest.

Zhang Dong, originally named Matt, didn't have any grand aspirations. In a way, he had already achieved what he had hoped for by having a large family and a loving wife. There wasn't really anything more he wished for, and letting things end naturally didn't seem like a bad outcome.

In the world he came from, a person's life expectancy wasn't very high; at most, he could have pushed to a hundred years. Here, he had already lived through three lifetimes and was in his fourth. It wouldn't be bad to go when surrounded by people who cherished him. However, there was one problem - he had become responsible for these people's lives, and he couldn't just let it all end without knowing what was out there.

Zhang Dong found himself inclined towards the second or third option. He could wait until he was close to a thousand years old and then make his move. At that point, he would have nothing to lose and would have lived life to its fullest. However, this option came with a drawback - his aged body would likely be much weaker than it was now.

Zhang Dong had not noticed it for the first three hundred years, but he was beginning to age slowly. By the time he reached five hundred years old, his body would resemble that of a forty-year-old, and by eight hundred, it would be like that of a seventy-year-old. Going up against enemies with a body constrained by aging and lacking vigor would be unwise. So, the last option made the most sense – advancing when his body was at its peak, which was now.

‘There is not much more that I can gain from remaining here, everything that I could discover has already made its way into my library, contemplating more Dao is an option but it probably won’t help me against what is out there…’

Over the years, Zhang Dong had accumulated an unfathomable number of spirit points, totaling well over trillions. He had used a significant portion of these points to nurture and enhance his cultivation seed, bringing it close to the point of bursting. This process had concluded more than a hundred years ago, but he continued to save up additional points, knowing that whenever he initiated the transformation, it could potentially activate the Overseer.

This is why he found himself in this place - a secret hiding spot known only to him, concealed even from his own family. Over the years, he had diligently uncovered the enigmatic remnants left behind by the previous owner. Now, the moment of decision had at last arrived. The Empire was under the new leadership of his son, Zhang Jun, while his daughter had embarked on a journey of cultivation with a Daoist partner after her brother assumed leadership.

Zhang Dong's decision to step back from his position as the Patriarch was a strategic move. He embraced the role of an ancestral elder, a designation reserved for the most powerful and experienced members of a sect. Ancestral elders often operated discreetly in the background and were called upon in times of crisis. It was a role he had seen during his adventurous youth, and now he found himself a part of it. This change allowed him to enjoy newfound freedom as his input was no longer required in the day-to-day affairs of the sect.

Another individual who had embraced a similar position was Zhang Jin. His grandfather had reached the nascent soul level a bit later in life, which had caused his aging to progress slightly faster. This accelerated aging made it challenging for him to support multiple wives, ultimately leading to his retirement from active leadership to preserve his power and extend his longevity.

However, Zhang Jin was not someone who would easily succumb to the effects of aging. It was expected that he would reach the impressive age of nine hundred, demonstrating his enduring strength and wisdom as an ancestral elder. The combined knowledge and experience of figures like Zhang Dong and Zhang Jin were valuable assets to the sect, ensuring that their legacy would continue to thrive even as they embraced a more behind-the-scenes role.

As the old Golden Emperor, Zhang Dong understood the enduring power of his legacy. His name would live on in history, a symbol of authority and stability that few would dare to challenge. His legend would cast a long shadow, ensuring the safety and prosperity of his sect and empire for many years to come.

He had laid the groundwork for another seven hundred years of stability, during which his sect could thrive without fear of revolt. But even with the best preparations, time was an unstoppable force, and an age of turmoil would eventually arrive. Zhang Dong had taken extensive measures to prepare for such an occasion.

His children were well-prepared to carry on his legacy, and the sect's leadership was poised to endure even in his absence. His vision was to ensure that his sect remained in power until the time came for a new system holder to be chosen.

With his affairs in order and his preparations extensive, there was no reason for hesitation. Zhang Dong was ready to step back, confident that his legacy would endure and his sect would continue to prosper, even in the face of the inevitable challenges brought by the passage of time.

Zhang Dong's desire to see his family, including his children and grandchildren, continue to prosper was a powerful and heartfelt sentiment. His family had grown over the three hundred years, and the bonds he shared with them were deep and meaningful. Moving on from his current role was a difficult decision, and he found himself torn by various worries and uncertainties.

The safety of his loved ones was not a primary concern, as his extensive preparations had already taken that into account. Instead, he was more anxious about the potential consequences of initiating his scheme. He feared that it might bring about unexpected challenges and even lead to death and destruction for those he held dear. It was a heavy burden to carry and if he caused everyone to suffer was his biggest fear.

He had witnessed another world with an Overseer and after its defeat not much had changed. This brought him a measure of comfort as he prepared to make his decision. Even with the automaton's absence, the world wouldn't come to an end. However, this didn't guarantee that external forces wouldn’t be drawn to this anomaly. He had no means to check on the world he had left behind and the people he had encountered there. All he could do was hope that they had lived out their lives in peace.

‘Scan complete, everything is in order for the mission ‘Ascension’ ‘

“I see… so there is nothing holding me back than my own emotions…”

His contemplation was interrupted by a notification sound in his mind. Bob had successfully completed the scan, and everything appeared to be in order. This place would serve as the location where he would attain the immortal stage or something akin to it. He had to consider the likelihood that the seed within him might produce a cultivation realm that deviated from the creator of this world's intentions.

It was highly probable that in the midst of this process, he would face opposition from the Overseer or what was often referred to as the will of the world. Ascending to immortality was seen as defying nature itself, something that shouldn't be achievable. The world adhered to a set of rules, and surpassing a certain life threshold contradicted these established rules. Undoubtedly, there would be forces attempting to prevent him from crossing that threshold, and for that, he had spent centuries preparing.

The path of ascension to the immortal stage was a mysterious and seldom-traveled one. The only individuals who had successfully achieved this level were former system holders, and their journeys were shrouded in secrecy. There were few comprehensive records documenting their experiences, and the accounts that did exist were mostly second or third-hand, often vague and incomplete.

This lack of detailed information left Zhang Dong in a state of uncertainty about what to anticipate on his own journey toward immortality. The one consistent detail that seemed to emerge from the limited accounts was the recurring mention of lightning tribulations. It was said that as cultivators sought to ascend, the heavens themselves would unleash formidable tribulations in an attempt to thwart their progress.
“I didn’t think that saying goodbye would be this hard…”

All the preparations were in place, and he had firmly resolved to proceed with this plan, driven by a burning curiosity to explore what lay beyond this world. He couldn't simply live out his life in peace, knowing that the people who depended on him would eventually face destruction. He wondered about the god-like being responsible for it all and the reasons behind the creation of these scenarios for people like him.

In his previous life, he had been a bored gamer with little hope for the future. The same seemed to apply to Wang Long, who, upon closer investigation, appeared to have led a similar lifestyle. This suggested a particular type of person was being targeted for these alternate worlds - individuals who lacked direction in their lives and yearned for fame, glory, and recognition from others. When presented with a fairytale fantasy world like this and a system to handhold them, there was no way of them turning back.

“I guess, I should say my farewells to everyone before going…’

With a subtle motion of his finger, he conjured a teleportation gate and disappeared into it. He felt a sense of responsibility towards the people he had been associated with, believing they deserved a farewell and an explanation about his destination. However, he also hoped they wouldn't attempt to dissuade him, as he wasn't sure if his heart could bear their pleas if they tried to hold him back from his decision…

Chapter 741

‘There he is… He looks busy…’

As Zhang Dong observed the gathering, his gaze settled on a particular individual who bore an uncanny resemblance to himself, both in terms of facial features and height. The man was dressed in attire nearly identical to his own. It was none other than his son, who had now ascended to the role of the new Golden Emperor and Patriarch of the United Element Sect.

A profound sense of pride and accomplishment welled up within Zhang Dong as he watched his son assume the mantle of leadership. The legacy he had worked so diligently to establish had been passed on to the next generation, and he had every confidence that his son would carry it forward with wisdom and dedication.

While looking at his son, he found comfort in the knowledge that he could indeed move on, secure in the future of his family and the sect he had built. Yet, leaving his son behind was far from easy. In his mind, he still saw him not just as a full-grown adult and leader but also as the scared and curious five-year-old boy he had once crafted toys for.

Time had worked its magic, and now Zhang Jun had his own family, with three children of his own and even more grandchildren on the horizon. There were multiple generations, stretching back to the very roots of the family tree he had planted, and new babies were soon to be born, further extending its branches. The legacy he had established had flourished and grown, evolving into something more extensive and profound than he could have ever imagined.

His legacy extended beyond the empire he had united; it lived on in the flourishing family he had nurtured, with generations poised to carry forward the carefully cultivated heritage. In order for them to thrive and prosper even more, he had to depart. Acknowledging the possibility that he might not return, he felt compelled to bid his farewells and his son was the first person on his list.

‘Hm… he is really busy, should I come later?’

To his dismay, the new Emperor found himself swamped with an immense workload, and he was someone who was deeply involved in every aspect of the empire. Despite the fact that the Empire had been unified, smaller pockets of adversaries continued to emerge from time to time. These challenges included demonic cultivators, wild beasts, and environmental disasters. While it wasn't strictly necessary, Jun appeared determined to personally engage in protecting the empire that had been entrusted to him by his father.

“... That will be all, report if there are any changes with this issue.”

“As you wish, Emperor, we shall take our leave.”

While for some people, waiting for half an hour in a corner might seem tedious and unproductive, for Zhang Dong, it held a special significance. His plans and responsibilities could be temporarily set aside, and simply watching his son, Zhang Jun, act like a capable adult was a refreshing and meaningful experience.

As he observed his son, he couldn't help but feel a deep sense of pride and admiration. Zhang Jun had not only taken on the role of the new Golden Emperor and Patriarch but also proven himself to be a natural leader. Zhang Jun's leadership qualities were evident, and his strength was comparable to that of the previous Azure Emperor, a figure that also went down as a legend just for the wrong reasons. As a father, it was heartening for Zhang Dong to witness his son's growth and success in carrying on the legacy he had worked so hard to establish.

“Dear, you must take a break.”

“I must take care of this issue, a new cult is growing and I will snuff it out before it takes any more lives.”

“Hah…”

The only individual who stayed behind was the current Empress, a woman who had compelled the sect and the elderly cultivators to adapt their traditions. To them, she was nothing extraordinary, merely someone his son had rescued approximately two hundred years ago.

Their love story was one of gradual evolution and transformation, an intriguing narrative in itself. The Empress had not started as a figure of great significance, but through the years, her connection with Zhang Jun had grown, leading to the development of their unique and powerful bond.

Naturally, many of the senior elders had initially been opposed to the idea of mingling with individuals who were not part of the main sect or the original clans. These distinctions had been significant to them. However, Zhang Dong's more modern approach was instrumental in bridging those gaps and fostering understanding, allowing his son and the Empress to find love and acceptance within the sect.

As this event unfolded, a growing number of people began to examine the traditional methods of forming families. There was a genuine movement to move away from bonds solely based on connections and instead focus on love and chemistry. Although this shift was gradual and still in progress, he held out hope that it would ultimately usher in some significant changes. It was evident that when parents lacked genuine love for each other, the ones who primarily suffered were their children.

“Why don’t you take a break? It’s just the two of us here so…”

“You mean?”

“Yes~”

‘Oh no…’

Zhang Dong remained in the meeting room, which was now empty except for his son and his wife. Their relationship mirrored his own with Liena, often filled with playful banter even in their later years. His concealment technique was beyond anyone's comprehension in this world, and an awkward scene was beginning to play out before him. The two of them were on the verge of embracing, and he could anticipate what was about to transpire. Thus, before he could witness whether his son was skilled in lovemaking, he decided to reveal his presence.

“Uh…”

“Who?”

“What?”

The two lovebirds swiftly separated, their fists raised in the direction of the sound. Being high-level cultivators, they instantly detected the surge in spiritual energy when Zhang Dong revealed himself. Zhang Dong, with a grin on his face, slowly stepped out of the shadows.

"I didn't mean to interrupt anything. It's heartwarming to see that the flame of love still burns brightly in your hearts after all these years, you’re just like me and your mother!"

Zhang Jun, his face turning slightly red, laughed nervously.

"Father, you certainly have a way of timing your appearances…"

Equally embarrassed, the Empress distanced herself from her husband. While Jun nonchalantly brushed it off, she respectfully bowed before the man who had once been known as the original Golden Emperor. Although Zhang Dong preferred a more informal approach when it came to family matters, it was challenging to alter the deeply ingrained personality of this woman.

"It's always a surprise when you drop by unannounced, great Lord Ancestor.”

“Again with that ancestor stuff, just call me father.”

“I must not!”

Zhang Dong chuckled, his eyes filled with warmth as he looked at the woman who had become an integral part of their family.

"Well, I've seen enough to know you're doing a fantastic job as Empress. And, if I may say, Jun, your mother and I are immensely proud of you. You've grown into a remarkable leader."

The Empress nodded in agreement but didn’t voice her own feelings about the issue. She still held onto some of the old ways and when an old ancestral elder who was once the emperor was present, she was not allowed to speak out.

“I’m glad that you think so father, but why did you come here? Is there something wrong? Could demonic cultists have appeared? Did the remnants of the Long Clan finally make their move!”

“Haha, you do have an active imagination my boy, nothing as drastic.”

Zhang Dong couldn't help but laugh at his son, who had become an elder just like him. His adventurous and kindhearted nature had played a significant role in ensuring the empire's control and the formation of the sect alliance went so smoothly. Many times, his father had simply needed to watch as everything fell neatly into place.

“...but, it is something that we need to discuss as a family.”

Zhang Dong's tone turned more serious, and a sense of gravity settled over the room. Zhang Jun and the Empress exchanged concerned glances, their curiosity piqued.

“I haven’t been very active lately, which you probably have already noticed.”

“Yes Father, a lot of the old elders hoped for you to lead the empire for a couple hundred years more...”

Zhang Jun responded with a touch of concern in his voice. Zhang Dong was well aware that some individuals didn't welcome the transition of leadership. In their view, Jun wasn't truly the leader while his father remained stronger and at full power. They believed it would have been better for Zhang Dong to retain his position as the leader, and only then pass it on to someone younger. His son was conscious of this dynamic, and it was likely one of the reasons he continued to strive for more, to demonstrate to everyone that he was indeed worthy.

“Don’t listen to those old farts, you are more than worthy of your position and far better at it than I ever was!”

Zhang Dong gave his son a pat on the back while laughing. His wife that was standing not far off just nodded in agreement.

“But this is not why I’m here, I need your help to gather everyone, I have an announcement to make and I want you to help me set up the venue.”

“An announcement?”

“Mhm, we will only invite our closest family members, I have something to discuss with all of you…”

“I see… I think that arranging it won’t be that hard just…”

“Is there a problem?”

“Well, I’m not sure where Xiu is, finding her might be troublesome…”
“Your sister? Don’t worry about that, I’ll go get her and drag her back here if I have to… She really didn’t take that loss well, did she?”

“Yeah…”

Zhang Jun chuckled weakly, acknowledging that his relationship with his older sister hadn't been the warmest lately. His father, on the other hand, simply smiled and activated his system window. No one within his faction could hide from him, and locating his children was a simple task. In an instant, a teleportation gate materialized out of nowhere, and he reached through it.

“There we go…”

“GAH! Who dares!”

“I dare!”

A bewildered woman rubbed her head that was bonked by a fatherly fist. Soon after more people were sucked in through the portal to end up on top of her in surprise.

“F-father?”

The woman asked in bewilderment only to get a pat on the head that had previously been smacked gently.

“Well, I’ll leave the rest up to you Jun, get everyone together. Also, participation is mandatory!”

Soon he vanished from this room where a bunch of people were forced into. Jun could do nothing more but sigh at what his father got him into. His older sister and him had a little feud with each other many years ago and now they were stuck together…

Chapter 742

‘There are a lot of them… To think that someone like me would have had such a big family circle…’

Zhang Dong's thoughts transported him back to a time before he had arrived in this world. Before that strange email had changed the course of his life, he was just an ordinary person leading a solitary existence, stuck in a dead-end job. His previous family had been something he felt he didn't quite belong to.

During those family get-togethers, he often found himself on the outskirts, trying to avoid confrontation and blending into the background. He would sit in a quiet corner, speaking very little, or he'd linger over his food, using it as a way to deflect conversations and uncomfortable interactions. The sense of alienation and disconnection from his previous life had been palpable.

His journey to this world had transformed him in many ways, providing him with a new sense of purpose, a loving family, and a profound impact on the world itself. The contrast between his past and present was striking, and he couldn't help but reflect on the incredible journey that had brought him to where he was today.

At times, he couldn't help but wonder if his original family was still out there somewhere. Even though more than three hundred years had passed in this alternate world, it didn't necessarily mean the same amount of time had passed in his original world. His experience when visiting the world where Beatrice resided was a clear example - upon his return, five years had already elapsed in this realm. It was even possible that when he ascended from this world, he might simply return to his old world as if nothing had occurred.

An outcome like that would indeed be quite unfortunate, but the possibility that all of this was just an elaborate illusion crossed his mind. Nevertheless, this place felt far too authentic to be a mere illusion, and its abrupt dissolution upon his ascension would raise suspicions. Before he embarked on his journey, he felt compelled to bid farewell to everyone who had gathered here.

“Welcome, I’m glad that you have managed to arrive at such short notice!”

Family members gradually gathered within the Zhang Dong family villa, an expansive estate that had served as the home for generations of the Zhang family. Everyone in this place was a part of his closest family circle, direct descendants of himself as the family head. Although he had only produced two children, each of his own children had three, and their descendants continued to multiply.

The entire villa now housed nearly a hundred individuals who were directly connected to him as the oldest member. Only one person was older, that being Zhang Jin who he also owed an explanation of what he was about to do. Liu and Xue who were his disciples, were also here but their own families were not part of this celebration.

“My dearest family, gathered here today, I've called upon you for a specific reason. As you may have noticed, I've been less active in recent years. Some of you still disagree with my decision of stepping down from my position as Emperor but I had a good reason for it, which I will now explain.”

Zhang Dong paused for a moment, looking at the faces of his family members, each with a mix of anticipation and curiosity. Some of the children present were already dozing off while their family members were pinching their cheeks which brought a smile onto his face. To some of them he was a scary cultivator but to others just a strange grandfather.

"First, I want to express my deep pride and gratitude for each and every one of you. You have all played a significant role in the growth and prosperity of our family and the sect. Without your dedication and hard work, we wouldn't be where we are today. But now, it's time for me to move on to the next step… I will be making preparations to go through the ascension…”

Zhang Dong stopped for a moment as he saw shocked expressions on some of his family member's faces. Most of them knew what he was talking about but none of them believed that it was actually possible to reach another realm.

“Dong’er… you know how to reach the Immortal realm? But the knowledge has been forgotten for thousands of years…”

“Yes gramps, I have the knowledge to reach it and I’m almost certain that I can.”

“You can? By the heavens, I knew that you were talented but not to this extent…”

Zhang Dong chuckled at his grandfather's astonishment and glanced at his son, Zhang Jun, whose mouth was agape. He wasn't disclosing the full truth, a fact only known to his wife, Liena, but in a way, it was still the truth. He would indeed be progressing to a new stage and eventually departing from this world. He pondered explaining everything but opted not to reveal the intricacies of the outer worlds, as there was a large chance he might never return here again. Leaving his children to live out their lives without the burden of wondering about their father's travels through different realms seemed like the better course of action.

Without the system on their side, ascending would remain an impossible challenge. Those born into these worlds were inherently bound to them and could never defy the heavens that had created them. He worried that if he disclosed too much information, his son or daughter might recklessly pursue their own destruction.

"Reaching the Immortal realm is no easy feat, and I must undergo rigorous preparations and training. The path ahead is fraught with challenges and uncertainties. I wanted to gather all of you here to let you know that this will be a long process, and it might be the last time that I will be able to speak to you again. I’m sure that you’ve heard of the legends and of what happens to anyone who has ascended before.”

“Whoever ascends must leave this realm…”

Zhang Jun muttered to himself while looking over at his sister who did the same. Both of them realized what their father was telling them. Zhang Dong nodded, his gaze filled with a mixture of sadness and resolve.

"That's right. Ascending means leaving this world behind, possibly forever. It's a decision I've thought long and hard about, and I understand the implications. But it's a journey I must undertake, not only for my own growth but for the knowledge and experience I can bring back to our family."

The room fell into a contemplative silence. The family members were processing this profound revelation. They knew the legends of ascension, but it was one thing to hear them and another to face the reality of a loved one preparing to embark on such a journey.

"Dong’er, you've accomplished incredible feats, and we've all benefited from your wisdom and strength. But this... this is a path that none of us have walked. Are you certain it's the right choice? To my knowledge none of the immortals have ever returned back, what if its impossible?"

Zhang Dong met his grandfather's gaze.

"I can't be completely certain, but I believe it's the path I must follow. The potential for growth, for discovering new realms and bringing back knowledge that could benefit our family, is too great to ignore. It's a risk I'm willing to take."

His wife, Liena, reached out and took his hand. Both of them looked at each other with love in their eyes as they nodded. They had this conversation before and his ascension could not be halted anymore.

"We've faced countless challenges together, and we've always emerged stronger. I have faith in my husband, and I'll be waiting for the day that he returns to us and to me.”

Zhang Jun and his sister exchanged glances. While it was difficult for them to accept their father's departure, they also understood the importance of his decision. All of the people here were cultivators and would probably choose to go through the ascension if they were given the opportunity. Growing stronger and wiser while improving their martial arts was ingrained into their very souls.

"Father, I'll support your decision, as difficult as it is for me. Just promise me that you'll come back, no matter how long it takes."

Xiu on the other hand frowned at the revelation. It didn’t seem that she was too convinced or glad about this information but also knew that stopping her father would be impossible.

“Dad, just make sure to not over do it, okay?”

“Haha, you know me, safety first!”

She rolled her eyes at the response and soon the whole place was filled with laughter. The family members nodded, their initial shock giving way to a sense of unity and determination. They were a family that had faced numerous challenges and thrived, and they would face this one together.

“That’s about everything that I wanted to discuss, I’m not sure when my ascension will take place… So before that, I wanted to share this feast with all of you! Now come, let us eat!”

With their concerns and questions addressed, the family embraced the idea of unity and celebration. They moved to the grand dining hall, where a sumptuous feast had been prepared in honor of this special occasion. Zhang Dong's ascension might have been on the horizon, but for now, it was a time for togetherness and joy.

The dining hall buzzed with laughter and conversation as family members from different generations and walks of life shared stories, caught up on each other's lives, and relished the delicious dishes. It was a heartwarming sight, as even the youngest children seemed to understand the significance of this gathering.

As the evening unfolded, Zhang Dong found himself surrounded by his loved ones, old and young, basking in the warmth of their presence. He shared anecdotes, offered guidance, and made cherished memories with his family, all the while feeling immense gratitude for the life he had built in this world.

The celebration continued into the night, with music and dancing, reflecting the deep bonds that connected them all. It was a reminder of the legacy he had built, not just as a powerful cultivator but as a loving father and grandfather.

The night eventually grew late, and the family members began to disperse to their respective quarters, reflecting on the day's events. For Zhang Dong, it was a reminder that despite the challenges and uncertainties of his ascension, he had the support and love of his family.

As he retired to his own chamber, Zhang Dong couldn't help but feel a sense of happiness. He knew that his journey forward would be fraught with trials and tribulations, but he was prepared to face them head-on. With the love and unity of his family as his source of strength, he was ready to embrace the unknown...

Chapter 743

“Is there no way that I can help?”

"Unfortunately not, we will have to part here. At most, you can watch what transpires through the spirit screen. It would be too dangerous for you to be there; I don't know what will happen. The tribulations might descend on your body, or my enemy could show up and use you against me..."

"... I understand."

The two looked at each other with love in their eyes. There was not much left to say; everything had already been discussed. Zhang Dong had made a decision, and his wife had given him permission to go through with his plan. She knew about the other worlds and about the Overseer, who continued to be a looming threat.

With one final, heartfelt embrace, Zhang Dong and his wife parted ways, and he vanished into a portal that would take him on his journey. A few days had passed since the emotional family get-together, and each member had already gone their separate ways, continuing with their lives.

As Zhang Dong reappeared above the city that he had played a pivotal role in creating, a sense of pride filled his chest. He gazed upon the grand structures that had risen under his guidance, symbols of his enduring legacy. The city stood as a testament to his hard work and the positive impact he had made on the world.

‘I hope I did a good job…’

Even as many years had passed and people had moved on with their lives, Zhang Dong continued to worry about his citizens and sect members. Like a caring father, he carried the weight of their well-being and happiness on his shoulders. His deep sense of responsibility toward them had not diminished over time.

His journey had been filled with both triumphs and challenges, and now he found himself on the precipice of a new adventure. He hoped that the people he cared about would cherish his memory, even if he were to fail in his next journey.

With a sense of resolution, Zhang Dong realized it was time to stop stalling and face what lay ahead. He created another teleportation portal that transported him to the secret grounds where he had been meticulously making preparations for his ascension. This place was filled with various countermeasures and tools intended to aid him in crossing the threshold and reaching the immortal stage. The moment of truth had arrived, and Zhang Dong was ready to embrace it.

He had spent years studying ancient texts, delving into esoteric knowledge, and refining his cultivation techniques to prepare for this moment. Everything he had done had led him to this point. All possible relics that he could find were here and even past records of old immortals painted him a picture of what was supposed to happen. The hard part was not really getting into the immortal stage but ascending with the help of this mutated seed that he had within him.
‘Well Bob, keep a lookout for that Overseer they will probably show themselves eventually. You’ll have to keep them busy as long as you can.’

‘Affirmative.’

Zhang Dong wasn't entirely alone in his momentous endeavor. While only his wife was watching from within the city, Bob, the AI program, was there with him. Over the years, their partnership had proved to be invaluable. Both Zhang Dong and Bob had continued to evolve and improve, enhancing their capabilities and knowledge to face the challenges ahead. This AI program had continued to be his best bet against his current predicament.

“Let us get to it then…”

After a firm nod, Zhang Dong descended into a more desolate area of this secret ground. This place had become something like a second home and now would be his way forward. The place he would start was devoid of any life that had previously been created by his predecessors. The goblins and other creatures that had been present in the past had been removed after he took full control over everything here. The energy used to keep everything running could be shifted elsewhere to help him through this new step.

First, Zhang Dong removed a certain item from his belongings that used to belong to the Cerulean Empress. It contained the Dao of Water, which he had refrained from absorbing for all these years. Secondly, he brought out a piece of memorabilia from his late older brother, Long Qing. It was a blue dagger that contained a higher form of flame Dao, which he also refrained from absorbing to avoid arousing the suspicion of the Overseer.

His plan had seemingly worked, giving him three hundred years to improve himself in other ways. He focused all of his time on perfecting his other skills, knowing that learning multiple Daos was the path to victory. The more he could learn and perfect, the stronger he would become in the end.

Throughout the years, Zhang Dong had honed not only his mental skills but also his combat abilities. He noticed early on that many cultivators could not effectively engage in conventional combat. Most of them relied on overpowering techniques and wide-range attacks. It was often a battle of spiritual energy rather than skill. Thus, for a certain amount of years, he had sealed away all of those techniques to focus on practicing the fundamentals of kicks, punches, and submissions. He aimed to become a combat expert who didn't rely on flashy energy attacks.

‘Even though I’ve already decided, this is quite stressful…’

He began by placing the various cultivation resources down on the ground before him. The entire secret ground was cleared of any living creatures, but he left all the plants untouched. The location where he sat was a wide meadow, very similar to the one where he had first arrived in this world. The central tree was now replaced by numerous diagrams and strange characters etched into the ground. Several layers of formations were placed everywhere, each inscribed by hand to ensure that everything would be perfect for this moment.

Zhang Dong took a deep breath, his heart pounding with anticipation. He had calculated every step meticulously, ensuring that every element was in place for this pivotal moment. He started out by using the Cerulean Empress sea shell as the medium for absorbing the Dao of water. As he did, he felt a rush of energy surging through his body, the power of water flowing within him. It was a sensation like no other, as if he were becoming one with the very essence of water itself.

With this Dao now integrating into his being, Zhang Dong moved on to the blue dagger, a piece of his late brother's legacy. He closed his eyes and focused on the dagger, allowing the higher form of flame Dao within it to merge with his own cultivation. Fire and water, two opposing elements, fused within him, creating a harmonious balance that he had never thought possible. The intense heat of the flame and the soothing coolness of the water coexisted, giving him a unique sensation of power.

While not much time had been spent on the infusion of those two Daos, he could feel his seed on the brink of germination. He was hastily absorbing all the power and swallowing pills to halt the process. If he could extend his time by even a few seconds, it could prove valuable for his ascension. However, the seed that he had nurtured for three hundred years was reaching its limit. All those spirit points from running a prosperous Empire were overflowing, and he wouldn't be able to stop the progress anymore.

‘It’s time, Bob be sure to watch out for you know who…’

Sweat beaded on his forehead as he channeled his energy into the seed, his entire body trembling with the effort. The ground beneath him quivered, and the diagrams etched into the earth began to glow with a soft, otherworldly light. The air crackled with energy as Zhang Dong delved deep within himself, seeking the connection to the seed's ancient and unknown power.

As Zhang Dong focused on the seed within him, he could feel its immense power surging. It was as if he had tapped into the very core of the universe, and the energy within him continued to build. The ground trembled, and the diagrams around him glowed even brighter. The process had taken on a life of its own. Bob at this time continued to diligently scan the surroundings for any noteworthy changes, if a shift in the Dao of time was discovered he would immediately forward this information and even be ready to initiate some defensive measures if they were required.

During a crucial moment of cultivation, the person undergoing it could not be disturbed. If they couldn't fully focus on the matter at hand, there was a significant risk of suffering a backlash in their cultivation. It was a moment of vulnerability, and the best time to strike if someone wished to dispose of a powerful master. They would be weakened as the process was taking place, and even gentle movements could ruin hundreds of years of preparation.

Normally, a person like him would be surrounded by masters from all sides, creating impenetrable defensive arrays and spiritual shields to keep everyone away. Even a fly would not make it through. However, when facing someone who could alter time and arrive unnoticed, these defenses would be just a hindrance.

His senses were heightened as he continued to channel energy into the seed, feeling the immense power building within him. As he delved deeper into his cultivation, he began to experience a profound connection with the seed. It was as if he could hear the whispers of countless ancient souls, guiding him on this journey. The energy within him was in a state of constant flux, merging, and melding, evolving into something greater than the sum of its parts.

He could sense the seed's potential, its desire to sprout and break through the confines of his current state. Time seemed to stretch and contract as he continued his cultivation. Minutes felt like hours, and hours like mere moments. He lost track of the world around him, fully immersed in the transformative process.

Outside of the secluded meadow, in the vast expanse of the secret grounds, an eerie stillness prevailed. The natural world seemed to hold its breath as the fusion of Dao energies continued. Not a leaf rustled, not a bird sang, and even the air itself seemed to hang in suspense.

The tension in the air was palpable, and the moment of ascension drew closer with each passing second. Zhang Dong's heart raced as he felt the seed within him reaching its breaking point. He had pushed his cultivation to its limits, and there was no turning back now. It was a point of no return, and he braced himself for what lay ahead.

Suddenly, as Zhang Dong's energy reached its peak, a disturbance in the fabric of reality itself rippled through the meadow. The diagrams etched into the ground flickered, and the air quivered with an otherworldly energy. Bob's sensors detected the anomaly, and he immediately alerted Zhang Dong to the impending danger…

Chapter 744

Zhang Dong could feel it - the white seed that he had nurtured for three hundred years was finally cracking. From within these cracks, a strange aura that he didn't fully understand began to radiate as something slowly emerged. A tiny white sprout started to emerge, taking root inside his very soul. It was really small, but the spiritual force that it generated was unlike anything found within this world.

As the sprout continued to grow, the meadow around Zhang Dong seemed to come alive. The ground quivered, and the diagrams etched into the earth glowed with a brilliant, otherworldly light. The air itself seemed to tremble with the power of this newfound energy. Zhang Dong's senses were overwhelmed as he felt the ancient and profound Dao of the sprout merging with his own cultivation.

His connection to the sprout deepened, and he could sense that it held the key to his ascension. It was as if the sprout were a bridge to a higher realm, and with each passing moment, he felt himself getting closer to breaking through the limits of his current state. It was an exhilarating and terrifying experience, which his body was having trouble contending with.

Zhang Dong's body was covered in a faint sheen of sweat, and his breathing was heavy as he channeled all of his energy into the growing sprout. It was a delicate process, one that required the utmost concentration and control. Any misstep could lead to disaster, and he was acutely aware of the risks involved. He knew that this little thing could kill him and destroy his soul if he wasn’t careful. However, taking things slowly might not have been a possibility as his enemies had realized that something strange was happening.

Outside the meadow, Bob's sensors continued to detect the anomaly, and he transmitted a message to Zhang Dong. Without presenting him with a system window he gave his warning in a softer tone than usual just so that he wouldn’t potentially hinder the ascension to the new realm.

"User, there's a distortion in close proximity to the secret ground. Be on high alert. The Overseer is approaching.”

“Just follow the plan, let them come…”

Zhang Dong knew that the Overseer would appear and might do so before he could ascend into a higher realm. While his seed was germinating inside his very soul and sprouting roots in his body, the transformation wouldn't take hold at a moment's notice. He wasn't sure what his enemy would do, but he had to assume that it would notice the mutated cultivation realm that didn't fit within the parameters of this world.

What came after that was the true question. Would this being just allow him to go through with it, or would it attack, as the demon lord did in that other world he visited? Zhang Dong was inclined to believe the latter, and he was prepared for a battle if necessary. However, it wasn't as easy as just defeating this puppet. There could be different consequences after he managed to slay this entity, and for that reason, he had been preparing for hundreds of years.

Finally, the moment of confrontation was upon him, and it was initiated by time halting around him, just as he had expected. The Overseer had access to several travel points in this world, and had arrived through a dimensional door not far away from his location.

Zhang Dong's heart raced as time froze around him, a palpable silence descended upon the meadow. He could feel the Overseer's presence, an otherworldly force that defied the natural laws of this realm. The air seemed to ripple with a sense of foreboding, and the diagrams etched into the ground paled in response to the time-stopping powers this creature possessed.

As he sat in the traditional lotus position, a figure materialized before him. It looked just the same as the last time he had laid eyes upon it. The Overseer didn't take a new form or intrude on his sect like it did with the Long Clan. He knew this well and was sure that this being would only start acting after he was gone from this world. It probably only resumed its work to prepare the scenarios for a new system holder, and so the cycle would repeat itself.

There were a few paths going forward for him now. He could defeat the puppet before him, just as in the other world. It didn't seem to affect it at that point in time, and perhaps it wouldn't here either. Only one thing was keeping him from following through with this easiest solution, and that was his family. If the Overseer vanished and he was unable to conquer whatever was out there, it could possibly lead to the erasure of everything he held dear to him.

This was not the optimal path he could follow. What he needed to do would be a lot more troublesome. He had spent hundreds of years running simulations and working on the technology in his secret ground. His puppet technology and insights into their creations were something he had focused on for quite a while. What he needed to do was to take control of this automaton and bring it to his side. Only then would he have a lifeline into this world and something that could help him rescue the people who were here if something went wrong.

‘Here it comes, did it notice or not?’

Just like the time before, he didn't move or give away that he was conscious of what was happening. The automaton remained silent, and even with his increased cultivation, he could not feel an inkling of a soul within this creature. It was an artificial being, more similar to Bob. It was trying to assess the situation with the help of its own scanning devices before engaging, and during that small window, the trap needed to be sprung.

‘Do it Bob, activate the formation!’

As the technique of controlling time was applied, the world remained in a state of stasis, but with the order given, the formations and symbols started to shine with energy. They covered the whole meadow in an array of symbols that quickly conjured up a prison made out of light particles, with the Overseer puppet right in the middle.

The Overseer puppet froze in place, its inscrutable form held captive by the intricate prison of light. The symbols of the formation pulsed with an ethereal glow, locking the puppet in a state of suspended animation. Its attempts to break free were met with resistance, as if the very fabric of space and time conspired to keep it imprisoned.

He had kept improving his own Dao of time throughout the years to counter whatever this being could do. However, this would not quite be enough, as this automaton possessed a cultivation base above that of the nascent soul level. Only after he had some time to begin his ascension would he have enough spiritual energy to balance things out. In the state that he was currently in, he had already pushed through the first layer of the barrier and entered the realm above the nascent soul.

While this realm was just a stopping point and only the beginning, the amount of power he could produce was a hundred times more than when he was a nascent soul master. It was probably a state that other masters could previously access before it was taken away. This stage was something between the realm of mortals and immortals, and his seed that was growing would push him even further.

But even with his newfound power, holding the automaton in place wasn't easy. Instead of progressing with his own ascension, he needed to focus on dealing with this enemy. Before the automaton could counter-attack, he needed to have Bob merge with its systems. In an attempt to gain a true ally, he intended to transfer all of his AI into this automaton so that it could be controlled.

‘Transferring data… 23%... 24% ...’

This plan was the result of their consensus. In most simulations, either Zhang Dong ended up dead or the Overseer. It wouldn't be just a copy but almost a full transfer of all of Bob's systems. With his new cultivation realm, Zhang Dong didn't require Bob's assistance with the system anymore, and the connection between them would remain open, with his AI receiving a proper body.

The battle of wills continued, as the Overseer puppet strained against the prison of light, desperately trying to break free from its confinement. It was a creature of immense power and it wouldn't be subdued easily. Its form flickered and wavered as it fought against the powerful formation that held it captive.

While the struggle raged on, Bob's data transfer was proceeding, and Zhang Dong could feel the AI merging with the automaton's systems. It was a complex process, and every percentage point counted. Time was of the essence, and they had to complete the transfer before the Overseer figured out a way to break free.

"Transferring data… 58%... 59%..."

Bob's calm voice continued to update Zhang Dong on the progress while he continued to concentrate. It wasn’t easy to focus both on holding his cultivation from going berserk and suppressing this puppet in the grand trapping formation that he created here. The whole secret ground was shaking and outside the landscape was being torn apart.

The power being exerted by Zhang Dong on the puppet was causing significant strain on this place. It was originally created by his predecessor using robust materials, but now that he was approaching the immortal realm, the very foundations of the location were being destroyed. The Overseer continued to resist, and its body began to convulse. The arms, which initially resembled a wooden puppet, transformed into sickles and were aimed directly at Zhang Dong's head.

"Transferring data… 78%... 79%..."

“Still not done yet… I guess it won’t go down without a fight…”

Zhang Dong had set up a back door years ago, which allowed him to track the Overseer's presence and prepare Bob for the transferring process. However, the percentages were not increasing as quickly as he hoped. Until it reached one hundred, Bob could not effectively take control of the puppet. It appeared that Zhang Dong would need to use his semi-immortal state to keep the monster occupied and hope that he wouldn't experience any cultivation deviations during this critical moment.

Chapter 745

The strain on Zhang Dong was immense. With each passing moment, the Overseer puppet's resistance grew stronger, its form warping and changing in desperate attempts to break free. Its sickle-like appendages thrashed about, aiming to strike at Zhang Dong, who was doing his best to fend off the attacks while maintaining the delicate balance of his own cultivation.

The meadow quaked as the puppet tried to free itself from the hold. The intricate formations glowed brightly, struggling to contain the otherworldly power of the Overseer. The air crackled with energy, and the very ground beneath Zhang Dong's feet trembled as he fought to keep the puppet at bay. The transference of data to get Bob in there had slowed down as the strange being was trying to halt the spread of the corruption. Even though more than 70% of Bob had been uploaded, it was about to break free.

“Shit… I guess we need to go with plan B. Bob, continue with the transfer while I keep this thing busy!”

Zhang Dong gritted his teeth as he forced himself to rise from the lotus position. Though he had successfully unlocked the seed and transcended the boundaries of this realm, he had yet to ascend to the immortal stage. His power was immense, but whether it would prove sufficient to contend with the puppet before him remained uncertain.

Anticipating such a scenario, Zhang Dong had readied a set of countermeasures. Even if the smaller formation encircling the meadow were to be obliterated, Bob could proceed with the upload unabated. The entire hidden ground had been reshaped, ensuring that as long as this powerful creature remained here, the transfer could persist. Thus, he needed to delay the monster's progress for as long as it was humanly possible.

Harnessing the recently acquired spiritual energy, he endured the surging pain that coursed through his body. In his current, incomplete state, he needed to momentarily suspend the germination process to concentrate on the battle at hand. The tiny seed had already evolved into a sprout of sorts, an entity eager to grow further. Deep within his soul, a primal urge urged him to grow stronger, to ascend to new heights, but he resolutely suppressed it to prevent his body from entering a suspended state. He was well aware that allowing it to progress unhindered would render him immobilized, leaving him vulnerable to the Overseer puppet's impending assault.

Instead, he thrust his palm forward at the foe capable of time manipulation. With his newfound power, he managed to move within the frozen landscape. The flailing puppet, struggling to break free from its temporal restraints, was forcibly propelled backward by a colossal golden palm. It soared several kilometers into the distance, colliding with numerous trees and massive boulders before becoming lodged in the side of a mountain.

“Bob, how are we doing on the transfer?”

"Transferring data... 74%...74,1%...”

“Still going slow huh? Try to increase the rate, I don’t think I will last too long in this state!”

Zhang Dong ascended into the air and extended his hand towards his adversary. His opponent had succeeded in freeing itself, but the grip on the world appeared to falter. The frozen landscape began to shift, indicating that its control over the Dao of time was not an enduring capability. This was understandable, considering that the puppet was not a genuine immortal, and its cultivation realm existed in a realm similar to the stage he currently occupied.

A barrage of spiritual blasts erupted from his outstretched hand, surging in the direction the puppet had been flung. Zhang Dong's aim wasn't necessarily to win the battle, but rather to prevent himself from suffering severe injuries. As long as he could keep the puppet occupied, victory would eventually be within his grasp.

The puppet, though momentarily immobilized, was still far from vanquished. It writhed and twisted, persistently striving to extricate itself from the mountainside. Once it emerged from its entrapment, a deluge of golden energy rays rained down upon its body. However, now that the puppet had regained its freedom, it was no longer such an easy target.

The Overseer puppet responded with speed and tenacity. It morphed and adapted, forming a crystalline shield that absorbed Zhang Dong's golden energy blasts. The ground beneath it shifted as it received all of the golden blasts that were intended for the Overseer. Even though thousands of rays descended from afar, none of them could break through the shield made of a strange crystal substance.

He did not relent as his attempt was not to defeat but to hinder. However, his enemy didn’t seem perturbed by this form of range attack and started pushing forth while encased in the strange crystalline formation. To stop him he decided to use a more concentrated attack that he conjured up through his finger tip.

Raising his hand, a colossal surge of spiritual energy burst forth from his fingertip. Instead of a scattered array of blasts, it manifested as a single, intense concentrated beam of energy. It streaked forward, colliding with the shield erected by the monster. Upon impact, the beam splintered into smaller beams that scattered throughout the environment. Some of these beams struck the ground, while others ricocheted upward, puncturing the ceiling.

The hidden secret ground had been concealed deep underground, shielded by an intricate network of ancient formations that kept it concealed from prying eyes. However, even these formidable ancient barriers were now unable to contain the sheer power of Zhang Dong's energy beams, which exceeded the capacity of this world to endure. As they erupted, they wreaked havoc, obliterating the surroundings and any creatures that ventured too close.

‘It was a good idea to move all the cities away from this location, there are no humans within a thousand kilometers…’

He had not squandered the three hundred years of meticulous planning. Zhang Dong was determined to render this place inaccessible to all, going to great lengths to infuse the land with demonic energies that would deter anyone from venturing near. These noxious fumes and corrupt forces prevented the formation of any sizable settlements, ensuring the land remained uninhabitable.

Only daring demonic cultivators and beasts risked using this place as a hideout, and now they were likely regretting their decision. The long-range battle between Zhang Dong and the Overseer was wreaking havoc, uprooting vegetation and continually reshaping the terrain. Nothing and no one above the secret ground would be able to endure the clash between these semi-immortal beings.

As the intense battle continued, Zhang Dong's concentrated energy beam was proving effective in slowing down the Overseer puppet's progress. The crystalline shield surrounding the puppet began to show cracks, and the creature struggled to maintain its forward momentum. Nevertheless, despite his success in momentarily repelling the monster, before he could further escalate the output to shatter the shield completely, Zhang Dong was struck by an intense, stabbing pain in his chest.

His cultivation realm went haywire as he exerted excessive energy. The seed within his soul began to pulse and even wither as he attempted to prolong the battle. If this continued, his body would remain trapped in this intermediate realm, or worse, he could potentially jeopardize his own soul and confine himself to this world without defeating the Overseer.

"Transferring data... 89,6%...89,7%...”

Zhang Dong gritted his teeth and clenched his fists. The pain was excruciating, but he couldn't afford to stop now. Bob's upload was at a critical point, and if he faltered, all their efforts would be in vain. With renewed determination, he channeled the energy from his surroundings, allowing it to flow through him without straining his own cultivation. The formations in this place along with the vegetation had been specifically created to aid him during this occasion.

The concentrated energy beam intensified, and the cracks in the Overseer puppet's crystalline shield grew wider. The creature let out a piercing, otherworldly screech as it struggled to maintain its charge. The Overseer was evidently bent on eliminating him by any means necessary. Bob's intrusion had diminished some of its mental capacity, fortunately keeping it engrossed in the battle rather than making an escape. If the puppet were to decide to flee, the entire plan would be in jeopardy.

The strain on Zhang Dong was immense, both physically and mentally. The body that had evolved from absorbing treasures was starting to crack and the very soul that he tempered was evaporating. The battle had reached a critical point, and the Overseer puppet, while severely hindered, was continuing to come. His efforts to stall the puppet and ensure Bob's complete upload were taking a toll and he didn’t know if he would last for more than a minute in this state.

A sudden surge of energy erupted from the Overseer. The shield, on the brink of collapse, flared and reformed, much stronger than before. Zhang Dong’s heart sank. The Overseer, despite its previous setbacks, had tapped into an unknown reserve of power, reconstituting its defense in a last, desperate stand. The shield now radiated an ominous, pulsating glow, repelling Zhang Dong's attacks and surging forth, encroaching upon his position with menacing speed.
"Bob, you better get that transfer going or we both are going to die!”

His mind raced as he couldn’t even hear Bob’s response. The transfer process must have been close to finishing and perhaps a minute was all that he needed. He roused all the treasures that he had gathered throughout the years. Swords, axes, spears, and glaves started floating up and quickly tossed themselves at the approaching puppet.

While they battered against that shield various beasts and monstrosities formed from within the secret ground to act as meat shields against the monster’s approach. All the formations were brought to a state of overloading and even the plants stretched out their branches and roots in a struggle to gain more time.

The puppet kept coming while he kept clutching the left side of his chest. His breathing was erratic as the seed within him could not progress further and was bent on destroying even his soul to continue growing. Instead of using his own spiritual energy, he just threw the entire secret ground onto his foe who was fast approaching. To halt himself from crumbling or blowing up he was forced to concentrate on the growing seed that was close to ripping his entire being apart.

However, his adversary showed no signs of relenting. Every defense that had been erected proved futile against a semi-immortal entity. It relentlessly charged toward Zhang Dong, hurtling on a collision course with the intent of severing his head. The puppet's arms, transformed into razor-sharp blades, were already poised for the attack that would spell the end for their foe.

Zhang Dong could see the blade millimeters before his face but he was unable to move. His whole body was in a catastrophic state close to cultivation deviation. It seemed that he would be not making it out alive but before the blade collided with his neck he heard a strange dinging sound, similar to the ones used by ovens. The blade then instantly stopped while grazing his neck, the puppet’s movement halted and he finally heard words of assurance that he was waiting for.

"Transferring data at 100%...”

Chapter 746

“Bob… are you in there?”

“... Assuming control of the autonomous overseer puppet designation number 52384… “

“I guess I got my answer, is everything proceeding well? Or do we have to move on to plan C?”

“Processing, please wait…”

“How reassuring…”

Zhang Dong gave out a big sigh while moving his neck away from the sharp blade-like arm. His blood was staining the appendage but luckily it had not reached his jugular. As Bob assumed control of the autonomous Overseer puppet, a wave of relief washed over Zhang Dong. He knew that their mission was teetering on a razor's edge, and the completion of the data transfer was their only hope for survival. The Overseer puppet, now under Bob's influence, stood frozen in place as if awaiting new orders.

One thing that remained unfrozen was the environment surrounding them. With the puppet's influence no longer at play, time resumed its course. The entire landscape in this hidden underground area had been ravaged, and during their battle, even the ceiling above them was crumbling. It wouldn't be long before the entire place would collapse, but in a moment like this, such concerns no longer held importance. The Overseer that had haunted his dreams was vanquished, and now it was becoming integrated into his own system.

“Is it safe? I can’t hold on for much longer…”

While he was gazing at his system window, excruciating pain coursed through his entire body. Even though the Overseer had ceased its assault, the internal transformation continued relentlessly. The white seed within him sought to sprout and expand, and he had been tirelessly suppressing it. Waiting any longer might risk his body's integrity. Fortunately, a faint chime and the appearance of a new tab provided him with some relief.

The system he had been granted had evolved in tandem with his own development. When it was no longer able to supply him with spiritual energy through the act of killing others, it adapted by offering faction rewards. It appeared to be deeply intertwined with the very essence of the system holder, and it appeared to be in a state of constant evolution to cater to the user's requirements. Whenever he conceived a sensible addition to the system, it would respond by providing him with something akin to his idea. It was almost as if his very existence was shaping it, and the system was adjusting itself to suggest a potential new path forward.

While he was cautious about becoming overly dependent on his system, it had been instrumental in providing him with answers and guiding him to this pivotal juncture. In the past, he had harbored concerns that excessive reliance on it might be his Achilles' heel, but he now recognized that it could also be his greatest asset.

He had a strong suspicion that the entity that granted him this system could potentially revoke it at any moment, a belief that had held true in the past. Nevertheless, in the present, it seemed likely that the system had become an integral part of his very essence and was no longer a power that could be taken away by an external force. It had transformed into something entirely unique, and perhaps it held the key to liberating not only himself but also everyone else from these enigmatic predicaments.

This tool had been bestowed upon him by some form of supreme being, and it was plausible that it held a concealed Dao or truth that could steer him in his forthcoming pursuits. If he could unravel its secrets regarding the manipulation of reality through spiritual energy, he might ascend to the level of this mystical entity. Nevertheless, before such a transformation could occur, he had to enter this new realm and avert the impending threat of the sprouting white seed that could potentially end his life.

With a renewed sense of urgency, he swiftly navigated through the new tab that displayed the Overseer. The puppet was depicted as a new servant, with the potential for augmentation and monitoring through the system. However, most of the options remained non-clickable at the moment, as his AI was still in the process of relocating the old data. Once the hostile takeover was completed, he issued Bob the command to archive all the knowledge possessed by this puppet while erasing any elements that could facilitate its escape or exploitation by external forces.

This entity had likely been operational across multiple system holder cycles. It held the potential to furnish him with numerous insights into what he might encounter in the upper realm, a term often employed by cultivators to describe the immortal realm. It was a widely acknowledged concept and a common theme in many fictional works he had come across in the past. Now, he was poised to ascend to this realm as well, and with a measure of fortune, he might even attain a feat greater than mere immortal ascension.

Zhang Dong felt the strain on his body increasing. The white seed within him was on the verge of sprouting, and the pain was becoming unbearable. He needed to complete his ascension process and he needed to do it now. Without hesitating anymore he went down into the lotus position with the Overseer puppet still standing in front of him. Even though it still had its arm raised it was not a problem anymore.

He delved deep into his own soul, tapping into the ancient formations that still lingered within the vicinity. An array of symbols and runes drew near and encircled him as he initiated a genuine breakthrough. The seed within his dantian, devoid of any resistance, finally began to germinate and transformed into a burgeoning sproutling that continued to expand and grow in size. It grew and grew, becoming larger within his very being.

As the symbols and runes danced around him, the air seemed to crackle with a newfound energy, and a sense of profound serenity washed over him. He had spent years studying the ancient arts, mastering the lost knowledge of the ancestors, and now, at this moment, he was witnessing the culmination of all his efforts.

The burgeoning sproutling within his dantian was a manifestation of his inner power, a power that had lain dormant for far too long. It pulsed with an otherworldly light, and as it grew, it sent ripples of power surging through his body. He felt a connection to the very earth beneath him, as if the roots of the world itself were intertwining with his spirit.

All at once, everything began to quake as a torrent of white energy erupted from his body, enveloping everything in its vicinity and coalescing into a colossal pillar of light. This pillar ascended, piercing through the crumbling ceiling and forcefully pushing aside any obstacles in its path. It traveled vast distances, ultimately reaching the heavens and encountering what appeared to be an imperceptible barrier, barring passage to what lay beyond.

The heavens were rending asunder, and even those at great distances could sense and witness this peculiar phenomenon unfolding. Every cultivator in this world felt an enigmatic power resonating with them, and all living beings within this realm of existence could perceive that something momentous was unfolding. As one, they all shifted their gaze toward the radiant pillar of light, which bathed everything in its illuminating glow.

However, the heavens that had been previously illuminated started to darken, engulfing the whole world in a deep dark veil of night. Lightning strikes surged forth to strike the pillar of light, each increasing in power and magnitude.

The lightning strikes clashed against the colossal pillar of light, causing a cacophony of thunderous booms that reverberated throughout the land. It was as though the very elements were rebelling against this transcendent ascension. Zhang Dong, deep in his meditative state, didn’t remain oblivious to the chaos that was unfolding around him. With each hit of the lightning, he could feel pain rush through his soul, the heavens were sending down tribulations to halt his progress just as he had anticipated.

With steady determination, Zhang Dong continued to meditate and channel his inner power. The pain from the lightning strikes was excruciating, but he refused to be deterred. He knew that this was a crucial moment in his journey, a make-or-break point that would determine whether he could ascend to the upper realm or be consumed by the power within.

As the lightning strikes intensified, the pillar of light grew more resplendent, and Zhang Dong's body began to undergo a profound transformation. His skin glowed with an ethereal radiance, and his eyes shimmered with newfound wisdom. It was as though he was becoming a being of pure energy, transcending the limitations of his mortal form.

The battle between the pillar of light and the celestial tribulations raged on, with each lightning strike becoming more powerful and relentless. It was a test of endurance, a test of will, and Zhang Dong was determined to prevail. On the outside, the landscape was changing and everything within a hundred kilometers was being destroyed by the tribulation lightning that was trying to destroy him.

A multitude of onlookers gathered outside, their expressions awash with sheer horror as they bore witness to this apocalyptic spectacle. Ancestral-level cultivators abandoned their cultivation chambers, drawn by the irresistible allure of the phenomenon that was unfolding. It had become evident to all in attendance that a new immortal was in the process of ascending.

The entire world plunged into darkness, with the distant pillar of light becoming the sole beacon in the obsidian void. The thunder and lightning continued their relentless assault, sending shockwaves reverberating throughout the entire empire. In the wake of this chaos, cataclysmic events unfolded one after another. Floods caught some cities off guard, while dormant volcanoes, silent for millennia, erupted, spewing molten lava across the land.

Amidst the chaos, as the world seemed on the brink of collapse, Zhang Dong remained resolute. He continued to meditate, his body now a luminous silhouette within the colossal pillar of light. The power within him surged, and he could feel the white seed in his dantian undergoing a profound transformation. It was no longer a mere seed; it had grown into a radiant tree, its branches reaching out to the heavens.

As the heavenly tribulations intensified, Zhang Dong's connection to the world deepened. He felt the heartbeat of the earth beneath him and the whispers of the wind. It was as though he had become one with the very fabric of the universe, a conduit for the energy of creation itself…

Chapter 747

“W-what is that?”

“By the ancestors, is the world ending?”

“If it was ending then it would have ended a week ago!”

“... It looks like a big tree… “

A crowd had assembled outside, captivated by the enigmatic spectacle. It had been a full week since the appearance of the peculiar luminous tree in the Empire, and it still attracted a relentless barrage of lightning strikes. Some cultivators had attempted to get closer but anyone who attempted to bridge more than a hundred kilometers was turned to ash by the heavenly lightning strikes.

Amid the chaos, as people speculated and debated the nature of the luminous tree and the ongoing heavenly tribulations, the truth of Zhang Dong's transformation was known only to him and his family. He was locked in a battle of wills with the forces of the universe, striving to complete his ascension and become a being of incredible power. The luminous tree that had sprouted within him was a manifestation of his spiritual energy and also of the sprout inside of him.

A mirror image of this radiant tree was materializing within his very essence. It was merging with his dantian and soul, forming something resembling a miniature world contained within his own being. The Dao’s that he comprehended before felt minuscule when compared to the truths of the world that he was just realizing. It all became clearer the closer he paved his way toward this newly evolved immortal realm that he didn’t truly know how to call.

As the luminous tree within him continued to grow, the same phenomenon took place in the real world. Its roots extended deep into the spiritual energies of the world, absorbing the essence of the earth and the heavens. With each passing moment, Zhang Dong's understanding of this realm and the universe deepened. He began to grasp the profound mysteries of the energies that made up this world. His cultivation continued to skyrocket as the tribulation lightning tried to stop him from continuing.

He could feel the connection between all living beings, the ebb and flow of spiritual energy that flowed through the world. It was as if he had become a living bridge between the mortal realm and the immortal realm, a conduit for the exchange of energy and knowledge. The luminous tree within him pulsed with life, radiating an aura of power that resonated with all of creation.

All of this unfolded under the watchful eyes of his family members and Bob, who had now assumed control of the Overseer puppet. The connection between the two had deepened, and Bob's functionality had expanded well beyond the capabilities of the previous puppet. First and foremost, he discerned that the tribulation lightning was likely nothing more than a scripted reaction integrated into this world. It appeared to be designed to prevent weaker system holders from completing the ascension process, but it didn't seem intent on going to extreme measures.

The world he occupied already housed immortal-grade items, and whoever had crafted it likely had the power to bring about his demise if they so desired. However, there was probably a rationale behind why most of the responsibility was entrusted to the Overseer puppet and other abandoned automatic systems.

It seemed that the creator of this world perhaps didn't deem the system holders, like him, as a substantial threat or saw no need to intervene personally. The tribulation lightning appeared to be giving its utmost effort, but with time, it became evident that it could not obstruct his progress in the least.

Bob had received prior instructions to maintain secrecy after taking on the role of the Overseer. His task was to extract all the information contained within the puppet and repurpose it for Zhang Dong's benefit. His first action was to mask his mutated version of the immortal stage into the conventional one. For the time being, he aimed to follow in the footsteps of his predecessor without drawing undue attention. Zhang Dong understood that as long as his adversaries underestimated his capabilities, he would have more chances for survival later.

As the days passed, the luminous tree within Zhang Dong continued to grow and evolve. The heavenly tribulations that had once seemed insurmountable began to diminish in intensity. It was as if the universe itself had recognized his transcendence and had started to relent. The tribulation lightning strikes grew less frequent, and their power waned.

As soon as it became feasible to approach the tree that seemed to function like a new sun, crowds of masters began to gather. The previously overcast heavens gradually eased, and soon the sky started to clear up as the transformation reached its culmination. The colossal luminous tree was visible from every corner of the empire, but its size began to dwindle. From its core, a new radiance emerged, causing the knees of onlookers to weaken. A figure materialized, and everyone who beheld this being could discern that they were gazing upon a deity.

“I can feel it… this world is repelling my presence…”

The luminous entity uttered a few words that sent shockwaves rippling through the entire realm. Zhang Dong swiftly realized that his newfound form was immensely powerful, and even his spoken words had the potential to cause widespread destruction and harm. After keeping his eyes closed for nearly a month, he finally opened them, revealing a brand-new perspective on the world.

The moment Zhang Dong's eyes opened, a wave of energy rippled outward, creating a profound disturbance in the surrounding space. His gaze fell upon the people who had gathered to witness his transformation, and for a brief moment, they felt their souls tremble under his scrutiny. He had ascended to a level of existence beyond their comprehension.

His family members, who had been anxiously observing his journey with bated breath, now stood in awe of the radiant being that had emerged from the luminous tree. Tears welled in their eyes as they comprehended that their former patriarch had been transformed into something truly extraordinary. It was evident that the realm he had entered was far beyond the nascent soul stage that had confined all the other masters within this realm.

Upon introspection, he could sense that the small white seed had at last sprouted. The moment it transformed into a tree, he gained insight into its true nature - it was a world seed. Upon sprouting, it had given rise to a world tree within his very soul, where a miniature universe was already taking shape, one that he could rule over as a bona fide deity. In its initial stages, it was relatively small, but it was likely that as he continued to grow, the world within him would expand in proportion.

It was a truly peculiar experience; he was simultaneously perceiving the universe within himself and the outer world and realm in which he found himself. His perception had transformed into something unique, allowing him to exist in multiple places simultaneously. Even without directing his attention, he could hear his family members, like Zhang Jin and his wife, conversing amongst themselves, uncertain of whether they should approach or begin to bow. His current form closely resembled his previous one, with the distinction that his snow-white hair now radiated a constant white glow.

‘The system is still there and then there is that pull…’

One of the first things he became aware of was the persistent force attempting to displace him from this realm. Similar to the fate of previous system holders who had reached the immortal realm, he too was experiencing rejection from this so-called lower realm. This appeared to be a fundamental law established by the entity responsible for creating this place, a decree that forbade beings of such immense power from coexisting with mortals. However, despite the powerful pull, it seemed incapable of expelling him from this realm entirely, a testament to his newfound strength.

He had already surpassed his predecessors, as the historical records indicated they were quickly expelled following their ascension. In contrast, he had completed his ascension days ago and continued to invest time in fortifying his new cultivation level. The specifics of his current cultivation stage remained unknown to him, but it was evidently linked to the world tree he had sprouted.

Perhaps the being that was above also had one of these as it was able to create many realms with people living in them just like this one. It was possible that with him earning this world tree he had become his own man and was not tied to the being that created everything. However, he only had one world within himself and was up against something that could create countless ones.

There were things that he still didn’t fully understand and thus it was better to gather more information. Leaving this place would be a requirement as even though the force couldn’t pull him away, it was strong enough to sap his spiritual energy away. If he continued to resist then eventually he would run out of it or perhaps be discovered due to the strange phenomenon taking place.

“Husband, is that truly you?”

“Ahh, my apologies, I’m still taking it in… This change is something else but I think I’m getting the hang of it.”

From a distance, Zhang Liena called out, and he effortlessly responded. Even though they were separated by ten kilometers, their words were distinctly audible to each other. His voice could traverse vast distances, just as he could. With a single swift step, he appeared before his wife, requiring no teleportation device, as his power had now reached an immense level.

“It is really you… but you feel different.”

“Different? I guess, this body has transcended the mortal realm and become close to immortal.”

He could feel that his lifespan had been boosted tremendously. It would be strange if he was an actual immortal or could at least live for a million years. But this was not the time to give his family such information as they all gathered around him. Even though he wanted to remain here, Bob was informing him otherwise. If the information that he had apprehended from the Overseer was true then he needed to quickly make his way out of here before being spotted. Thus instead he reached out to touch his wife's hand as to for one last time feel the warmth that she always gave him.

"It's me, Liena. I may have changed a bit, but my love for you and our children will never be broken. I wish all of you a life of happiness but now… I must depart.”

With a gentle smile, Zhang Dong extended his hand toward the area where the radiant tree had formed. There was a connection there that would lead him to the next realm or at least the place where the other system holders were being led to. Now that he knew some of the truth he needed to continue to release everyone from this eternal cycle…

Chapter 748

‘I guess this is it, no looking back anymore but before that…’

Zhang Dong heaved a sigh as he observed the path leading to the next realm unfolding before him. It was a significant leap that he still hesitated to take. Fortunately, he had gained insight into some of the truths of the world he resided in, courtesy of absorbing the tree of knowledge that had flourished within him. Additionally, Bob had secured control over the Overseer, a puppet that at this juncture posed no threat to his well-being, providing him with new information.

To validate some of the newly acquired knowledge, he resolved to ascend into the clouds, a realm previously prohibited to him. A familiar wind, which would have previously torn him apart, obstructed his way, but his current cultivation level left him with nothing to fear. With ease, he passed through the invisible barrier that had previously confined him, granting him access to the true world beyond.

“So this is it…”

For a moment, he experienced the sensation of being a deity, gazing down at the entire empire that filled his entire field of view. Yet, there was more to behold, as he ascended even higher, allowing him to survey the entirety of the world and planet on which he had resided for over three centuries.

“That’s probably the Emerald Phoenix Empire… and that must be the great wide sea the Cerulean Empress came from…”

From this elevated perspective, he could take in the grand scope of it all. Even from a high vantage point, the entire planet remained vast. It resembled a huge sphere that closely matched the size of the sun around which his old planet had orbited. However, one thing became evident shortly after leaving the atmosphere and ascending to this height: this world was perhaps not intended to be observed from such a distant viewpoint.

“There really isn’t anything out there, this whole place is just a miniaturized universe…”

The planet he had lived on was not part of a larger cosmos; it was the entire cosmos itself, contained within a self-contained bubble of existence. The sun, the moon, the stars, and the galaxies were all nothing more than celestial ornaments within this constructed reality. It just confirmed some of his older theories that all of this was a setup for something and that soon he would probably discover what it was all for.

His senses had now been heightened to the point where he could peer into the void and discern that there was not as much empty space as he had initially assumed. He accelerated his pace and reached one of the apparent celestial bodies that actually orbited their planet. It was not the only one, for it appeared that each Empire had its own version, resembling nothing more than phantoms suspended in an intricate pattern above the sky. These celestial bodies were akin to glowing lightbulbs that emitted minimal heat on their own. It became apparent that the entire planet was held together by spiritual energy that simulated everything.

Everything appeared illusory - the moon resembled a hologram that mimicked the real celestial body, much smaller than he had anticipated. Attempting to stand on it proved futile, as his feet simply passed through as if it were insubstantial. The other stars above were nothing more than sizable luminous dots against a dark, shadowy canvas radiating the Dao of darkness. As he approached it, he could glimpse beyond, leading to a truly astonishing revelation.

“There is nothing there… just an empty void…”

Beyond this canvas, there was an absolute void - no other stars, galaxies, or planets. It was a barren expanse devoid of life, where even spiritual energy failed to penetrate beyond the shroud of darkness. Even his efforts to perceive anything were met with an impenetrable barrier, which likely marked the boundary of this realm. There was nothing out there; the entire world was an isolated planet with nothing else surrounding it.

While this knowledge wasn’t truly new, he had at least hoped that there was something more out there. He couldn't help but think about the countless lives that existed within this constructed world, each living their own stories, pursuing their own dreams, and facing their own challenges. The thought that all of them were part of an experiment or some grand design left a heavy weight on his heart.

Even more so when he realized that his whole family was stuck here and just like this fake world was established, it could probably be eradicated easily. With his current cultivation level, he felt that it would be possible for him to bring this planet to its doom. If he focused all of his energies together, it would probably be enough to create a cataclastic event to end all life on this planet filled with trillions of lives.

“It was a good idea to take over that puppet instead of destroying it. I should probably return and continue with the plan.”

Bob was waiting for him down on the surface of this world for an order. He had been tasked with trying to block out any signals to outside beings that would normally be transmitted during an ascension event. This approach enabled him to progress steadily through the transition of cultivation realms without raising suspicions as an anomaly. Without this strategy, he would have had to expedite the process, moving quickly to advance to the next stage without being detected.

In his current state, he knew how to depart from this realm, yet there were multiple routes to exit. With the Overseer under his control and all its knowledge at his disposal, he decided to make his way to what appeared to be the central command center. Similar to other such locations, it was concealed behind a hidden door that could transport him into a parallel dimension.

It became increasingly apparent that there might be no actual transcendence to upper realms; rather, it seemed to be an event that transported a system holder once they reached the immortal stage. Upon achieving this milestone, they were forcibly moved to the subsequent stage of the scenario. This mechanism likely served to prevent them from seeing the world outside the planet, as doing so would have easily revealed the artificial nature of their existence.

He was presently experiencing the influence of this mechanism, which tugged at his very essence and attempted to draw him away from this realm. Its strength intensified the farther he ventured from the planet. However, although he could follow this compelling sensation and allow it to carry him away, his intention was to utilize the alternative method.

The Overseer possessed a connection to the creator of this realm and access to all the hidden doors within it. There had to be one leading out of this place, and he just needed to pinpoint it. When he arrived back on the ground, Bob was already waiting before the door that would lead him inside. Without the Overseer puppet present, he wouldn’t be able to go inside without force.

“Hm, could you turn to something different or are you locked in that form?”

Zhang Dong asked Bob who still had sharp blades for his arms. After he posed the question his AI started shifting around to take the appearance of an old acquaintance, the Azure Empress.

“It is possible to shift into forms the Overseer had previously absorbed, is this form satisfactory, or should this unit change again?”

“... I guess that’s fine. I didn’t really talk with her much… better than Long Qing I guess…”

While it was a bit distasteful to have the puppet assume a person that had died he didn’t want Bob to circle through everyone the Overseer had killed. With Bob now in a more familiar guise, Zhang Dong approached the hidden door that led to the central command center. The door looked a bit more robust and metallic than the others that he had witnessed but it was easily opened with Bob’s help.

What greeted them was a familiar-looking tunnel, very similar to the one that he encountered when he was out adventuring with Liena, Huo Qiang, and Zhang Zhi. It led to other rooms that were labeled and probably connected to various junctures in this world. With his currently enhanced spiritual sense, he could just instantly read the labels to discover that some of them even led to other empires.

“I guess these are some types of persistent teleportation spots, everything is connected but it’s also abandoned…”

The further he went, the more he realized that this central tunnel was a hub for control, monitoring, and management of this entire artificial universe. They passed rooms with elaborate machinery and vast screens displaying the lives and events of the people living in this world. It was a surreal experience, seeing the lives of countless beings played out like scenes in a movie.

It was probable that the puppet normally wandered through these corridors and continued to monitor the beings to push them into a certain direction. Perhaps when he arrived into this world this being was already watching. Maybe it was the thing that triggered his first boss encounter or left it there for him to discover. There were a lot of questions that were being answered and soon he arrived at a small chamber that seemed to not have been used for a while.

“This should be it, the back door that should take me there…”

This was his way out of here and it was somewhat unique and outdated. The other corridors were very sterile and modern looking while this place even had a wooden floor that seemed to have been handcrafted and not just copy-pasted with the help of some creation technique.

“Instead of the door, it’s a mirror huh? Is it going to be a mirrored dimension or is this where I’m currently in the mirror world?”

Zhang Dong approached the ornate mirror with caution. It was unlike anything he had encountered in this artificial world. As he stood before it, he noticed his reflection shimmering, but something about it was different. The reflection seemed more vibrant, more real, as if it were a gateway to another world.

Taking a deep breath, he reached out and touched the mirror's surface. His hand passed through the cool glass, and he felt a strange sensation as if he were being drawn into it. Instinctively he pulled back his hand just to see the surface of the mirror ripple around like the surface of water. When looking at it he could see that his reflection had disappeared and instead, he could see another area behind it.

“I guess this is it…”

It was time to move on beyond the threshold. Thus he initiated one of his techniques to hide his presence. After giving Bob some orders he finally stepped through into the unknown…

Chapter 749

“Hm, so this is it? The place that the system holders get sent to? It doesn't look much different from an old office building... Am I in a storage closet or an unused office?"

Zhang Dong had just stepped through a large mirror, which was supposed to be a back entrance to the destination where cultivators ascended. The moment he passed through it, he felt the pulling at his soul had vanished, and he was truly in a higher realm that wasn't trying to reject him anymore.

His arrival here was met with silence, and after remaining in the room for a few minutes, it didn't seem like he had triggered any alarms. The mirror was just an advanced portal that quickly extinguished after he passed through it. He was now in uncharted territory, not found on the planet where he had previously lived. Perhaps soon he would be able to discover why these fake realms were created and what happened to people who completed their scenarios.

“Thanks to Bob, they should still think that a system holder is alive in that realm, but this place…”

One thing became clear almost instantly: the rules that governed this place were a bit different than what he was accustomed to. The laws he was familiar with were slightly altered, and time flowed in a strange way. It felt like sometimes it would move faster, then stop, and even revert back. Some strange forces were at play here, but luckily, the room he found himself in was nothing special.

The only thing that really worried him was the passage of time. It was possible that time was moving faster in the world he left behind, and when he tried to return, everything he had left behind would be gone. This was a fact he had come to terms with and had also informed his wife about. It wouldn't be strange if he never saw anyone he knew ever again, but he had made the decision to discover the truth behind his adventure and perhaps, through it, find a way to prolong the lives of his loved ones.

It was unnatural for them not to be able to ascend. If he could lift that barrier and change the laws that governed that realm, then perhaps they could reach higher realms, just like he was able to. If that was not possible, then maybe he could find a place to transfer them to, or even move them into the small universe that had been established within his very soul. He had become something close to an immortal being, so as long as he lived, so would they.

However, a significant amount of time would need to pass before any living being could move into the realm that was being created within his body. It was a slowly growing cosmos devoid of any life and would probably grow with him. One way to hasten the process would be to reach another higher cultivation realm, but at this point, he wasn't even sure if that would be possible.

‘I shouldn’t be getting ahead of myself, first I have to get more information…’

It didn't seem that anyone had visited this room in a while, which made it a good hiding place to take note of. There was a single lightbulb that could be turned on by pulling on the string attached to it, but for now, he left it be. Turning on the light could potentially give away his position, and thanks to his Dao's abilities, seeing inside dark places wasn't at all difficult.

There was a lone door at the other end, directly opposite to the mirror that he had used. Some light was shining through that door on the bottom and when he listened in he could hear some type of noise akin to clicking and tapping.

‘Could I be in some arcade or internet cafe?’

While he couldn't hear any chatter, there were distinct clicks that sounded like people typing. He moved forward cautiously, and before stepping through the door, he also noticed something to the sides. There were other mirrors similar to the one he had stepped through. All of them were covered by cloth, and some were lying on the floor.

‘Do all of these lead to other worlds? Some of them are broken…’

He mumbled to himself while examining the mirrors that weren't showing anything but his reflection. Even if they worked the same way as the one he had stepped through, they seemed to only activate from the other side. His own way back was still available, thanks to Bob taking over the Overseer. Their connection was still working through the system, which didn't seem to have been affected by the change of scenery.

“Whoever made this clearly doesn't care about these worlds…”

This revelation was a good one, as it meant that whoever he was facing didn't care enough about the intrusion. Underestimating one's capabilities often made it easier to confront others. However, upon examining the broken mirrors, concern crept in. The material from which these items were made was of immortal grade. The destruction of these mirrors suggested that the worlds they connected to might no longer exist. It was possible that all the mirrors in the room had been abandoned to some extent.

He moved cautiously toward the door from which light shone through the bottom. Uncertainty loomed, and he wasn't sure what to expect. His adventure could be short-lived, so he remained cautious. In the distance, he could hear something and sense the presence of strange beings. They were indeed peculiar; he couldn't accurately identify their power or cultivation level.

Encounters like this often occurred when a cultivator was weaker than the target they were trying to identify. His system wasn't providing him with any reliable readings either. Even though it was still operational, the numbers it displayed were corrupted. It was evident that the system hadn't been designed with this place in mind or that it had some form of programming preventing it from identifying the items he was looking at.

“Think this is a job for you Bahamut, come out.”

Before him, a wisp of golden light materialized and transformed into a miniature version of his trusted dragon companion. Bahamuth’s power had increased alongside his, and he had gained additional abilities, one of which allowed him to shrink to the size of a fly. Bahamut and Zhang Dong shared a profound connection with each other. They could both share their vision, and at this moment, he needed Bahamut to peer beyond the door before he opened it.

“Go and be careful.”

The tiny dragon-fly squeezed through the crack under the door to venture outside, while Zhang Dong patiently waited. His mind remained connected to the diminutive Bahamut, who was greeted by a white corridor beyond. Just as he expected, it looked like they were in some kind of office building. As Bahamut continued to fly further, he even came across a copy machine that appeared to have been unused for a while.

‘It looks like it’s a real office building but it doesn’t look like most of these rooms are being used by anyone?’

Finally, after a moment, they discovered living beings - or at least people who resembled them. There was something peculiar about these individuals; they all had identical appearances and were dressed in business attire. Each had the same face and wore matching glasses to complement their inexpensive work suits. Bahamut remained attached to the ceiling, observing as a few of them passed through the outside corridor.

‘They don’t seem to possess the capabilities to discover me at least… an expert would have probably noticed Bahamut by now.’

Initially, he thought that they might be patrolling the building, but he soon realized that these beings were more akin to the Overseer puppet he had taken over than actual living people. They moved like robots, devoid of conversation, and their behavior was peculiar. It was as if they had been programmed to act as if they were busy at work but were not actually engaged in anything meaningful. Additionally, they completely ignored one another, which gave him an idea of how to proceed.

‘I guess it’s now or never…’

He remained concealed in a single room for an entire day, observing the movement patterns of these office workers. It became evident that one of them consistently passed by the room he occupied every hour, almost like clockwork. This led him to suspect that they were following a peculiar pattern. Thanks to their predictable movements, he executed his next plan with ease.

With Bahamut stationed outside, he knew exactly when to strike. The door was unlocked and easy to open. In less than a second, he executed his attack by swiftly seizing one of the men and pulling him into a room filled with mirrors. After the initial contact, he became confident in his victory, as this individual proved to be significantly weaker than the Overseer he had confronted earlier. Subduing him with just a fraction of his true Qi proved quite straightforward.

He managed to instantaneously immobilize the puppet, reverting it to its original automaton form. The human-like facade dissolved, revealing a crude wooden doll resembling a crash test dummy, with a long wooden nose in place of a face.

“They appear relatively weak, but I mustn't underestimate them. There might be some defenses against intruders, and this individual could be just a worker.”

Swiftly, he assumed the appearance of the puppet, transforming into a typical salaryman with slick hair and glasses. With this disguise, he aimed to move through the area unnoticed. He finally decided to step through the door, joining Bahamut outside. Despite his best efforts, a lingering chill ran down his spine.

The surroundings seemed ordinary, but he knew it was all an illusion. Multiple rooms, each filled with mirrors like the one he had entered, were spread throughout. In one room, the damage to the mirrors appeared particularly severe, with broken shards strewn about. He cautiously navigated the corridors, attempting to blend in. Thankfully, the other puppets he passed paid him no attention; his disguise had been successful.

“Good, everything is clear... now I need to head toward the source of all that noise. I might find some answers there.”

Chapter 750

As Zhang Dong made his way through the office building filled with these peculiar puppets, he couldn't shake the feeling of unease. The ambient noise of typing and clicking continued, and the relentless repetition of tasks by these automatons felt eerie. He wondered who or what had created this bizarre world and for what purpose.

Following the sound of typing and clicking, he eventually arrived at a room where the noise was the most pronounced. When he pushed open the door, he was met with an astonishing sight. The room was vast, stretching as far as the eye could see. It was filled with rows upon rows of computer workstations, each occupied by a puppet-like figure typing away at keyboards. Each workstation was divided, all of these puppets were working within their own cubicle.

The room was bathed in an eerie, cold light, and the air felt strangely sterile. Numerous entrances and corridors led out of this expansive space, seemingly extending into infinity. He wasn't certain about the nature of this place, but fortunately, everything appeared to be numbered. The puppet he had disabled bore an identification number, likely corresponding to one of the cubicles in this complex; he just needed to locate it. To avoid standing out, he continued to follow one of the designated pathways along the sides. These artificial human beings were simply going about their business, oblivious to anything unusual, and he needed to ensure it stayed that way.

Zhang Dong carefully weaved his way through the rows of cubicles, each one identical to the last. The repetition was mind-numbing, and he couldn't help but wonder if this was some sort of purgatory for lost souls or a bizarre experiment by some advanced civilization. The puppet-like figures continued to type away, completely absorbed in their tasks, as if they had no awareness of the world beyond their computer screens.

Eventually, he located the cubicle that corresponded to the identification number from the subdued puppet. It was situated in the far reaches of the room, nestled within the maze of workstations. For a moment, he observed the other puppets mechanically going through their motions, their posture somewhat hunched, and their multiple screens casting reflections on their glasses. Occasionally, they would take a sip from a self-replenishing drink, whether it was tea or juice, powered by some peculiar technique that exuded energy.

Upon entering the cubicle, he discovered that a spatial technique was in use, expanding the apparent size of the area. It was a peculiar sight, as from the outside, it had appeared far more confined. Only upon stepping inside did the full workstation reveal itself, featuring even more monitor screens than he had previously observed.

‘Let me see…’

His first task was to power up the personal computer. It resembled a typical office computer, devoid of most labels. After pressing the button, the fans inside the case whirred to life, and the drive lights blinked. It was a recreation of old technology, which he assumed the creator of this world was familiar with. The operating system that appeared was also something he recognized, as it was the same one in use back on Earth, the world he had come from.

‘It’s all in basic English…’
To his surprise, the language being used here was from his original world. Typically, other worlds had developed their own language systems with unique writing and phonetics. The system also had a built-in translation tool, but he didn't need to use it in this case, as everything was easily understandable. This further affirmed his earlier assumption that the individual who had created this system was somehow connected to the ‘real’ world he came from.

‘Did this person create all of this or did they just take it over?’

Zhang Dong considered a few initial possibilities. Either the creator of all this came from the same world and then designed this peculiar system, or his world was being used as the host world for system holders. There were variations of these possibilities, but it wasn't the time to dwell on them. Instead, he needed to concentrate on these monitors and uncover what the puppet-like businessmen were engaged in at this location.

Shortly after the computer powered on, he was presented with a desktop featuring only a few icons. It reminded him of his old gaming setup from before he was transported to become a cultivator. However, there were no games on this computer. Instead, there was a peculiar program with an icon that resembled the infinity symbol. After a moment of preparation, he finally clicked on the icon, causing a window to pop up.

‘These are… other worlds and their stats?’

As Zhang Dong studied the window that had appeared on the screen, he realized that he was looking at a vast array of information about different worlds. Each world was represented by a small icon, and beside it, there were statistics that seemed to describe various aspects of those worlds. Some of the statistics included the world's population, technological advancement, cultural development, and even a strange indicator labeled ‘System Power.’

The list seemed endless, and he couldn't help but be awed by the sheer diversity of these other worlds. Some appeared to be futuristic, with advanced technology, while others seemed to be medieval or even ancient in nature. It was as if he was peering into a multiverse of countless parallel realities.

Curiosity drove him to click on one of the world icons, and as he did, a new window opened up, displaying detailed information about that particular world. It was like a database of parallel universes. He learned about the inhabitants, their history, and the unique characteristics of each world. Some of them had magical systems, while others had advanced scientific principles governing their reality. There were worlds with mythical creatures, and supernatural abilities, and even some resembled his own.

Upon selecting one of the worlds, he was presented with a planet that had two moons orbiting it. There were various options he could explore. Population density and size were among them. He could even view the types of factions that governed this world and the different kingdoms. When he clicked on one of the continents, the entire map began to zoom in, providing him with even more statistics and data.

‘This arrow here? Does it represent the system holder?’

As Zhang Dong delved deeper into the information on the screen, he discovered an arrow icon that seemed to represent the system holder for each world. It was like a marker, designated for individuals just like himself. Within a few clicks, he was able to bring up a status window to represent this particular system holder. It included quite a lot of information and he probably had his own page somewhere.

Original Name:

|

Johan Schneider

Current Name:

|

Ivaran Eldermoon

Race:

|

Dark Elf

System Type:

|

Leveling Type

System Advantage:

|

Superior Experience Gain

There was an abundance of information to sift through. It appeared that each person had their own version of the system, and not everyone's was like his. Some systems were more limited, such as this leveling type that transformed the world into an RPG-like game. The individual named Ivaran had been granted a cheat that enabled him to earn experience points at a much faster rate than the inhabitants of this world. This, coupled with the longevity of the elven race, likely constituted their main advantage as a system holder.

The more he delved into this information window, the more it sent a shiver down his spine. It contained everything, from the man's accomplishments to his relationships. A complex web of relationships was displayed, detailing the people with whom he had interacted and their approval ratings. Every action and interaction of this person in that world was meticulously recorded and presented here.

‘My system was hacked after a few months so they shouldn’t have the information… but what is this star for?’

Upon further investigation, he found that each system holder had a star rating assigned to them. They began at one and went up further, but after searching, he couldn't find anyone with a rating higher than three stars. Normally, these types of systems would go up to five, but he couldn't be certain. One thing was clear, though: all of these people had some kind of rating assigned to them, and some of them were evidently more significant to the system than others.

As he went through the worlds, he only confirmed what he had already suspected - everything had been falsified. What he needed was a way to free himself from this situation or at least figure out the fate of those who completed their scenarios. He began clicking through various options in search of something important, like a list of previous system holders. He decided to use his own name in the search function. From the system's perspective, he was a deceased system holder replaced by Wang Long.

"Hmm... nothing. Wang Long's name also doesn't work," he muttered in frustration.

He then attempted to input the names of the people he had interacted with in the other world, but still, he couldn't discover any useful information. After contemplating the issue, he arrived at a conclusion: this PC was limited to a certain number of worlds. The puppets likely only monitored a restricted number of system holders, and the one that had his world was at a different cubicle.

‘I probably won’t be able to find the right workstation in this huge space.’

Zhang Dong realized that searching for the specific cubicle and puppet within it would be like searching for a needle in a haystack. The workspace extended into infinity, and he couldn't afford to get lost or waste too much time in this strange environment. The only way for him to find the right one would be either through hacking or finding a part with higher privileges. If he saw these puppets as moderators then perhaps there was an administrator inside of this building.

He continued to go through this computer to see if it had some other information than keeping track of the system holders. All of this didn’t really help him with his pursuit of truth. He needed to find out about what happened to the other system holders. While clicking through he also discovered a section with the emails, one of which he had received during his transfer.

‘They even have an extensive list of new potential system holders, some have higher stars than others. I guess they want to keep the ball rolling…’

Some of the questions had been answered but he still needed more. His best bet would be to find the administrative room where he could probably access the entire database. However, to do that he needed to leave this cubicle and start roaming this strange office building some more.

Chapter 751

Zhang Dong persisted in navigating through the computer, extracting as much information as possible. He stumbled upon a few intriguing details, including the responsibilities of these moderators. They were primarily tasked with system-holder scouting, recruitment, and monitoring. Furthermore, they had the ability to adjust the stakes of the scenario, making things more challenging or easier with a few clicks.

According to his findings, individuals with higher star ratings were granted more options. There were packages rated from bronze to platinum. With a superior package, the system would offer better features, such as weakening opponents or influencing the probability of success in various endeavors.

The moderators had access to an extensive list of human beings, involving millions of individuals whom they contacted and observed. There appeared to be intriguing criteria that they emphasized. The system-holder candidates were typically loners with a chip on their shoulder, individuals with few ties to their original world or even harboring a hatred for it. Many of these candidates were outright shut-ins who had experienced bullying or simply didn't fit in with the rest.

This was a familiar concept for him, as he had been a loner himself before being spirited away. Wang Long appeared to harbor lots of animosity toward his original world, which he vented on the people in the new one. It didn't seem that having a moral compass was a requirement, considering both Wang Long and Zhang Dong couldn't have been more different in that regard.

It all felt surreal, and he couldn't shake the suspicion that the reason he had nearly died when confronting his first real foe was due to one of these moderators playing around with the statistics. If he hadn't obtained the hacked system and freed himself, he might have met a different, perhaps fatal, fate. It appeared that individuals with a higher moral compass, like him, were rated slightly lower than the rest. This could be the reason why he was left to face death without much assistance.

‘There isn't really more that I can learn here. This DSP thing is also an unknown factor.’

He thought, having gone through everything and discovered a strange number labeled as 'DSP'. There was no explanation for what it was, but each system holder had this number assigned to them, constantly increasing. It seemed to be another rating distinct from the star system, but he couldn't find an explanation for its significance.

The clicking of the puppets resonated throughout the office area as he stepped out of the cubicle he had been occupying. Once inside, all noise had been canceled out, likely to maintain focus among the puppets on their work. Thanks to this phenomenon, the other puppets wouldn't really notice that his workstation was empty.

For now, it seemed that there weren't any defensive measures or security protocols in place. It was evident to him that whoever created this place wasn't concerned about people snooping around. They were either very confident that no one would reach this place or simply didn't care. Either way, his new opponent seemed to be underestimating potential threats, which worked in his favor.
The endless rows of cubicles extended as far as he could see, but there was an end to them on the sides. Other corridors and rooms likely led to various points of interest. Outside these confines, he might find the administrator. If the administrator was also a weak puppet, gathering more information could be relatively straightforward. With this in mind, he set out to explore further while maintaining the appearance of a puppet.

While other system holders were leaving their worlds and heading elsewhere, he couldn't spot any of them here. It was conceivable that the backdoor he used brought him into an entirely new dimension or realm. There was still a possibility that these individuals weren't truly his enemies and the entire scenario was crafted for the system holders to have a thrilling time. They were granted a fantastic adventure where they could be heroes or villains if they chose. Yet, that DSP number was causing him concern. It was as if they were compelled to earn something that the entity behind all this required or desired.

It took him some time but he managed to slip away from this large section to start exploring. Thanks to his mapping system he was able to keep himself from getting lost in this strange yellow business building. As Zhang Dong moved through the labyrinthine corridors, he came across different sections of the building. Some rooms seemed to be dedicated to specific tasks, while others housed more mysterious equipment and machinery. One thing was clear though, most of them were never intended for use and had been placed to simulate an office requirement.

‘Could the person that created this have been some type of disgruntled businessman, stuck in a cubicle for most of his life?’

This was his best guess regarding the nature of this place. Typically, people created things based on their memories, and perhaps the creator of this place had one in a similar setting. It gave him some hope that he was confronting another human being and not some interdimensional, godlike being that could erase him from existence at any moment. As long as this entity wasn't omniscient or omnipresent, he felt he had a fighting chance. Otherwise, nothing really mattered, and his entire journey could come to an abrupt end at any moment.

He swiftly navigated through the corridors, hoping to find something of substance. The building was incredibly vast, and even after wandering through it for more than a week, there seemed to be no end in sight. While there were windows on the side, they only revealed an empty void. Going outside wasn't an easy task, as there was nothing to open the windows with. The place was also reinforced, so the only way outside would be by blasting through with force - a method he wanted to avoid unless he was under attack.

His map had rapidly filled up with the three-dimensional depiction of the office building. One revelation he made was that it wasn't actually flat; it took the shape of a spiral winding up into what seemed like infinity. The further he ventured, the tighter the spiral became, giving him the impression that he was heading in the right direction. With a bit of luck, he might discover a new section, perhaps even the room with the administrator. So, he pressed on, and after another week of searching, he finally reached something new: the building had begun transforming into what resembled a hospital.

He felt like he had entered a new biome, the switch being somewhat abrupt. The yellow paint that covered most of the walls was abruptly cut off by the white walls. Everything started shifting, and even the doors were different. The ones he was looking at now were double doors with rectangular glass windows through which he could see inside. To no surprise, there were no salarymen in there anymore; they were replaced by two different puppet types.

‘So, a nurse or a doctor, which should I go with?’

Zhang Dong contemplated while peeking through, observing a long corridor with what seemed like a lounge area at the end. A few nurses were behind a counter, engrossed in some task, moving around and feigning work. Similar to the businessmen, he needed to alter his appearance. Fortunately, the women here also looked the same, and examining them from his vantage point was straightforward. On the other hand, there was a doctor in a long white coat facing the other way, making it challenging to copy his appearance.

‘I guess, for now, I’ll have to be a nurse…’

At first, it might have seemed like it was better to change into the persona with more authority like the doctor but the nurses were far more active. He could still move through every area without being discovered so he quickly shifted into the image of a blond nurse that was wearing a somewhat reduced uniform.

‘Why do they have to wear high heels in a hospital… I hope it’s not one of those hospitals… I should really get a look at one of those doctors.’

Now in his new guise, Zhang Dong cautiously pushed open the double doors and stepped into the hospital section. The atmosphere was different here; instead of the sterile office environment, the air carried the faint scent of antiseptic. The low hum of medical equipment replaced the constant clicking and typing sounds of the previous area.

As he strolled down the corridor, he noticed that the puppets in this section were engaged in different activities. Some were pushing empty gurneys, while others were reading medical charts or typing on computers. The puppet nurses moved with purpose, attending to tasks that seemed as repetitive and monotonous as those in the office.

Zhang Dong mimicked their movements, trying to blend in seamlessly. He knew that any deviation from the norm might draw attention. As he walked, he observed the different rooms and departments of the hospital. There were operating rooms, examination rooms, and even a pharmacy area. The attention to detail in recreating these spaces was remarkable.

Yet, something made him stop as he noticed that something was actually going on here. While the rooms for the patients were empty the puppets were actually talking to each other. Curiosity compelled Zhang Dong to approach one of the puppet nurses engaged in conversation with another. Their exchange was mundane at first, discussing the routine tasks of the day, but as he got closer, he began to overhear a peculiar detail.

“... The new patients will be arriving soon, the doctor asked us to proceed to room 237.”
‘A patient?’

This was not something that he expected but this was a hospital section and it wouldn’t really be one if there were no patients. Was it possible that other puppets played the role of patients and it wouldn’t lead to nothing or could there be something more to it? Without giving himself away he followed after the group of nurses that numbered well above ten.

‘This is quite the group of nurses just to see one patient, what could this really be about?’

As he trailed after them, the group continued to grow, all heading in a specific direction. Staying towards the back, he maintained a position where he could escape at any given moment. Soon enough, he got an answer to the question of where they were going.

“What are you doing!? This is all wrong!”

‘Huh? Whose voice is that? It doesn't sound like a puppet.’

The nurses opened a large set of doors, and he heard a man's voice that didn't match any of the doctors he had seen so far. It seemed like an event was unfolding that might finally shed some light on what was happening in this place.

Chapter 752

Zhang Dong cautiously approached the source of the disturbance. Peeking through the partially opened doors, he witnessed a scene that both intrigued and puzzled him. In a room labeled 237, a man was strapped to a hospital bed, struggling against his restraints. He was dressed in patient attire, and it was evident that he wasn't a puppet like the others.

Standing beside the bed was a puppet doctor, holding a clipboard and seemingly unfazed by the man's protests. The nurses were arranging various medical instruments and preparing for a procedure. It was a bizarre sight, especially considering the man's distressed pleas.

"You can't do this! I demand to know what's happening! Do you know who I am? I will have all of you executed! Why can’t I move? “

The man continued to struggle around while being held on a strange medical table. The bindings that the medical staff was using didn't seem that strong, yet the man was unable to budge them at all. He looked a bit older, but his body was in good shape and reinforced through some strange means. With the help of his own system, he was able to identify the man, and the results were interesting.

Original Name:

|

Stefan Pudziankowski

Current Name:

|

Erik Avison

Race:

|

Evolved Human

Affiliation:

|

Emperor of the Galactic Empire

System Type:

|

Achievement Type

System Advantage:

|

AI Chip Helper

He was obviously a system holder who came from some type of scientific world. Zhang Dong deduced that this person had probably reached the end of his storyline, becoming an Emperor of a whole galactic empire. His body was somewhat peculiar; he looked like a human but had various implants and cybernetics hidden within. It was clear that he was some type of evolved human with his own set of advantages. If he had to judge his strength, then the man would be around early core formation level, which meant that his world’s power level was a lot lower than the cultivation world he was from.

‘He should be able to break those bonds with that advanced body of his but… for some reason something is keeping them in place, did these puppets do something to him?’

It was a strange spectacle, the man was barely able to move as if some outside force was holding him in place. The sight before him raised more questions than answers. Why would a powerful figure like this Emperor of the Galactic Empire, be subjected to such treatment in this bizarre place?

‘How did he even get here? How do non-cultivators leave their realms if they don’t ascend?’

There were a lot of questions on his mind, and this seemed like one of the places to get answers. It was clear that this person was a system holder who, by the looks of things, was quite confused. His maddened shouts weren't revealing much of the truth besides the fact that the puppets could successfully pacify him without much trouble.

'If this person is here… could there be more around?'

Zhang Dong was disguised as one of the nurses, but it didn't seem that any of the puppets here cared. They were huddled around the screaming man while the doctor focused on his clipboard. After some time had passed, they pulled out a regular-sized syringe and inserted some sort of sedative into the man's arm to calm him down. Within a few moments, he looked out of it and became unresponsive, but he was still alive.

“His DSP rating is fairly low, send him out to processing plant C.”

The doctor spoke in a monotone voice before leaving the room. The nurses here started moving the man onto another table, equipped with wheels, and quickly pushed him out of the room. Zhang Dong followed after them to see what this was all about, with an interest in the DSP rating that had been mentioned. This strange stat had been featured inside the workstation he previously went through, and perhaps, if he followed after them, the secret of what it was would reveal itself to him.

As the sedated man was being rolled out, Zhang Dong also noticed another creepy fact: there were other similar scenes playing out all around this strange hospital. Passing other hospital rooms, he could see people of varying genders, races, and some even looked like alien creatures, tossing and turning while being bound. All of them were being handled by a whole team of nurses that gathered around one doctor.

The sight sent a shiver down Zhang Dong's spine. It wasn't just one or two isolated incidents; it seemed like a systematic operation. It was probable that if he hadn’t used the back door to enter this strange place, he would be one of these people getting sedated. After examining them like the other man, he confirmed that they were all system holders who had probably completed their journey. All of them had high positions similar to emperors and empresses. There were even other cultivators like him who had attained the sought-after immortal realm, which wasn't enough to counteract this strange hospital either.

His curiosity grew, fueled by a mix of concern for these captives and a desire to uncover the mysteries of this place. It was a hard thing to gaze at and not help. They were like lambs being led to slaughter but he couldn’t do anything about it. If he attempted to free them without gaining more knowledge about this situation, his whole plan could be ruined. Even though he felt bad about these people, there were more pressing matters. There was a lot at stake here, if he could uncover all of the mysteries here then perhaps he could actually save all of them and then also the people that came after.

Thus while hiding Zhang Dong continued to follow the nurses and the sedated man, navigating through the hospital's winding corridors. The wheels of the gurney made a soft creaking sound as they moved along the sterile floors. The strange hospital environment continued to baffle him; each section seemed meticulously designed to mimic a real-world scenario.

After a while, the hospital started changing into something else. The corridors expanded further, and other sedated individuals joined them on the way towards this so-called processing plant. They all looked different and carried their own story with them. The number was also quite eye-opening, and by the time they arrived at a door marked ‘Processing Plant C’, there were tens of them there.

The doors to Processing Plant C swung open, revealing a vast, dimly lit space filled with rows of metallic tables and strange machinery. The nurses efficiently rolled the gurney carrying the sedated Emperor into the room, following a routine that seemed eerily well-rehearsed.

Zhang Dong hesitated for a moment, glancing around the room. The other system holders, still unconscious, were being placed on similar tables, each surrounded by a team of nurses. The atmosphere in Processing Plant C was different from the hospital section. It felt more ominous, none of them uttered a word while removing them from the gurneys.

These new tables were made out of thick steel, and the moment a person was placed on one, strange mechanical-looking appendages sprung up to limit their movements. They looked like tentacles created from stainless steel, wrapping themselves around the bodies of these system holders, leaving only their heads free.

Zhang Dong's heart raced as he observed the unfolding scene. The tentacle-like restraints seemed to have a purpose beyond mere immobilization. They were equipped with various sensors and connectors, linking up to the strange machinery in the room. A low hum emanated from the equipment, creating an eerie ambiance.

The nurses, now devoid of their previous animated movements, operated in a synchronized manner. They connected the system holders to the machinery, ensuring a secure and efficient process. Zhang Dong couldn't comprehend the purpose of this operation but his eyes focused on a new type of puppet, this one looking like a mad scientist.

The puppet scientist moved around the room, checking the connections and adjusting the settings on the machinery. He seemed to be in control of the entire operation, occasionally consulting a tablet filled with data. The atmosphere was tense, and Zhang Dong's instincts told him that whatever was happening in Processing Plant C was crucial to understanding the nature of this strange realm.

“These ones are ready for processing, activate the extractor! Pull the switch!”

When glancing to the back, he could see another person that looked like a stereotypical hunched-over evil scientist assistant. The moment the scientist-looking man gave the order, the switch was flipped, and a lightshow above them started. A strange-looking contraption started sliding down, consisting of a plethora of wires, flashing lights, and strange transistors.

From within this monstrosity of metal and cables, multiple large tubes started to emerge. They could move freely through the ceiling and fixated on the sedated system holders. All of them came to a stop before their faces and only then the truth of this extraction process was revealed. The metallic tubes resembling a vacuum started to suction away something from the system holders, something that Zhang Dong could somewhat perceive.

‘It’s… absorbing their essence? It’s not going for their soul or life force… what is it pulling out of them?’

As Zhang Dong continued to observe, he noticed a peculiar substance being extracted from the system holders. It wasn't their life force or soul, but rather, it seemed to be a radiant, ethereal energy. The tubes were siphoning off a shimmering light that emanated from each captive. Each person’s energy had a different shine to it and they also varied by colors.

While the extraction progressed, the system holders' appearances became increasingly haggard. Their once vibrant and powerful auras dimmed, leaving behind a hollow shell of their former selves. It was as if the essence being drained from them held the very essence of their achievements, experiences, and power.

‘The systems that they held are being removed along with everything that they provided them with?’

The puppet scientist monitored the process with a cold and detached expression, focusing on the data displayed on his tablet. The room filled with the sound of machinery and the soft hum of the extraction process, creating an unsettling symphony. Zhang Dong watched on with horror but could at least feel that these people were not being killed, instead they were being drained of something more intangible.

‘Is this the DSP rating? Is it their experiences and memories that they gained during their adventure?’

He had no way of knowing what a person would need something like this for but it would be akin to sucking away all the DAOs that he had learned. One piece of the puzzle revealed itself to him but the real question was still left unanswered….

Chapter 753

Who or what was behind this mysterious extraction process, and for what purpose were these unique energies being harvested? Zhang Dong, concealed among the nurses, knew he needed more information before he could make any move to intervene or understand the grander scheme at play.

He wanted to do nothing more than to stop this strange phenomenon, but the fear of failing his current mission held him back. The young man who would jump to save everyone had been changed. If he let his emotions cloud his judgment, then a lot of other lives were at stake - the ones that relied on him back in his own world but also these system holders. For the time being, he needed to keep wandering around to get a clear picture of what to do. No one would be saved if he were captured.

As the extraction continued, the puppet scientist's tablet beeped, and he glanced at the data with a nod of satisfaction. The ethereal energies flowed through the tubes into a large, central container, pulsating with an otherworldly glow. Zhang Dong couldn't help but feel a surge of anger at his helplessness in this situation. The only solace he could take from his decision was that seemingly the people were not being drained of their souls or lives.

The process lasted for just a few minutes and the squirming patients were left on the tables, now devoid of the radiant energy that once defined them. The puppet nurses efficiently disconnected the system holders from the machinery, their limp bodies carried away on gurneys to an unknown destination. He had a choice to make, he could either stay here and examine this strange facility or follow after the limp system holders.

‘The nurses are leaving, so it would be better to keep blending in…’

After the suctioning was finished, the energy made its way into the large machine. It started sliding back into the ceiling that it came from, and perhaps it was taken to some kind of large battery or something else entirely. His mind raced with ideas, one depicting an Eldritch elder god just consuming all of this essence while the puppets fed it more and more of it. Was this what everything was made for, to harvest the system holders like him for their essences?

Zhang Dong decided to continue his exploration of the facility, following the nurses as they wheeled the drained system holders to their next destination. They moved the limp bodies through a series of winding hallways, eventually arriving at a set of heavy, metallic doors labeled "Recycling." The doors opened with a hiss, revealing a room filled with large, futuristic-looking capsules. Each capsule held a system holder, suspended in a translucent liquid that seemed to pulse with a faint glow.

This was not something that he expected. First, they removed what made these system holders, and then they were healing them? At first, it seemed that way at least, but the moment he looked at the capsules that were further in the back, he realized something - the system holders in those were a lot smaller and younger.

‘They are reversing their age?’

The sight before Zhang Dong was perplexing. The capsules in the back held system holders who looked much younger than when they were first brought into Processing Plant C. It wasn't just healing; it was more like a reversal of time, a strange process that defied the laws of nature.

As he observed, the puppet nurses carefully placed the drained system holders into the capsules, ensuring they were fully submerged in the glowing liquid. The lids of the capsules closed with a soft hiss, sealing the rejuvenation process within. Tubes connected to the capsules seemed to provide sustenance to the suspended figures, maintaining their life functions as the strange liquid worked its wonders.

The puppet doctor overseeing the process muttered to himself, checking a series of monitors displaying data on each capsule. Zhang Dong, still disguised among the nurses, listened intently.

"Excellent. The extraction process was successful, and the reversal phase has begun. Everything is proceeding well, move the rejuvenated specimens to the transferal chamber immediately and send them on their way.”

The term "rejuvenated specimens" sent a chill down Zhang Dong's spine. It became clear that the mysterious facility was not only harvesting the unique energies from these system holders but also somehow reverting them to a younger state. For what purpose this was done was unknown, to him, it didn’t really make sense. Why did they bother with reverting the people back to a newborn instead of just disposing of them afterward?

‘They are on the move again…’

He was stunned for a moment as everything that was happening here didn’t make much sense. The fact that he was only sent out to be harvested for parts was a hard pill to swallow. His whole life was there to be drained of his essence and then reverted back to the start. The babies that were being carried out of the pods were blank slates; they clearly had all of their memories removed, and he could tell through their souls. These were wiped clean and returned to their base; in a sense, the people that they once were didn’t exist anymore.

His mind was racing as he continued to follow after to see this until the end. The babies that were once system holders like him were transported to the last chamber, a place that seemed to be the final stage of this bizarre process. The room was dimly lit, with a large, circular platform in the middle that was generating most of the light.

He watched as the puppets placed the sleeping babies onto this platform, in which they started floating. After a certain threshold was filled, the sleeping newborns started glowing, reverting to what seemed to be their soul forms. Then, before he could blink, they shot up into the ceiling through what looked to be a portal.

Zhang Dong was left standing there, perplexed and disturbed by the entire spectacle he had just witnessed. The portal closed behind the ascending souls, leaving him alone in the dimly lit chamber. He took a moment to collect his thoughts and process the information he had gathered.

The system holders, once powerful figures in their respective worlds, were reduced to a state of infancy, their memories and experiences erased. The essence drained from them was used for some mysterious purpose, and the rejuvenated souls were sent through a portal, presumably to another destination.

‘What is the purpose of all this? What kind of entity or organization is orchestrating such a complex and bizarre operation?’

His thoughts were interrupted by the sound of approaching footsteps. While he was baffled by it all, the process continued without being stopped. More infants passed by him and were on their way to being transported. More system holders were drained of their experiences, and he was not sure what he should do about it. If he wasn't fortunate enough to have dislodged himself from the system, then he would have been turned into a soul as well.

‘I need to think… What should I do?’

After seeing the truth, the first thing he wanted to attempt was to set all the system holders free. There were a few ways that he could go about this problem, and the best one would be through Bob’s involvement. After seeing it all, it was clear that these people were being held back by the same systems that gave them power. It was an inside job from the beginning, and by using the system to grant them power, they were powerless here.

‘I probably need to find that administrator room before attempting anything, maybe they never expected anyone to reach this place but that doesn’t mean that they will not notice if I start moving around people.’

There were two ways he could do this, by either forcing his way and just engaging the hordes of puppets. Even though the place was huge, he wasn’t sure if the forces he was facing were truly infinite. The second option would be through more subtle and strategic ways. Zhang Dong knew that a direct confrontation could jeopardize not only his mission but also the lives of the system holders still trapped in this strange facility.

The key, he believed, lay in taking over the facility with the help of his AI helper and his own understanding of the system. His current cultivation level compared to his previous one was quite godlike. His understanding of the forces in the universe far exceeded his past self, and he could somewhat understand how the system was functioning. It might have seemed like an omnipotent tool that granted every wish, but there were certain limitations on it. Through these limitations, he felt that his opponent was not truly a fully established god just yet.

His new cultivation realm allowed him to house a whole universe within himself, which also gave him insight into his new enemy. Even though it was all within him, it wasn’t that easy to focus on things that were happening inside it. His mental capacity didn’t increase to the point that he could spread out his attention through the vast amounts of empty space and blossoming planets. If it was like that for him, then the person that created this plethora of worlds could probably not find him unless he revealed himself to some extent.

The more he thought about it, the more it made sense that this godlike being was limited to some extent. If it was all-powerful then there would be no reason to create fake worlds that didn’t have a proper galaxy like the one that he came from. It seemed that this being still wanted to conserve their power, it was not infinite and gave him hope for the future.

With determination in his eyes, Zhang Dong decided to first locate the administrator room. If he could gain control over the system or at least disrupt its operations, he might be able to free the system holders and understand the true nature of the mysterious force behind this facility.

He continued to navigate through the labyrinthine corridors of the strange hospital, blending in with the puppet nurses as he searched for any signs or clues that would lead him to the administrator room. The air was tense, and every step he took felt like a gamble. The stakes were high, and the lives of countless system holders depended on his ability to uncover the secrets of this place. However, now that his hope had been restored he was reinvigorated, if there was a way to win it, then he would find it.

Chapter 754

‘Why does this place have to be this big? It’s like looking for a needle shot out into the void…’

Zhang Dong sat in one of the numerous vacant rooms within this peculiar place. The puppet humans, an odd bunch, never ventured into any of these chambers. Strangely, dust seemed absent in these spaces. It defied reason but considering that they were in a strange separate dimension or realm, it did make sense. There were no spiders to make cobwebs or skin follicles to create dusty rooms as the inhabitants were just automatons made up of a silicon-like substance. On the outside, they looked real but when taken under a magnifying glass it was easy to tell.

‘Bob, is the connection still holding?’

‘Affirmative, connection holding, no errors discovered.’

‘Good.’

The fact that he could still connect with Bob in his own world eased some of his stress. If he chose to, he could likely go back to his previous world and abandon the current mission. The only requirement would be to seal his present cultivation to prevent it from forcing him out. In his current state, the duration of his life was uncertain. Perhaps he could become a true ancestor, safeguarding his people for hundreds or even millions of years.

‘Kind of hard to come back after seeing what has been happening with these system holders…’

As he gazed at the map of the peculiar location, he pondered. Another week had elapsed since his arrival. He identified another point of interest - the location where system holders arrived which was a waiting lounge that accommodated only one person at a time. It seemed designed to prevent system holders from conversing with each other before the nurses disabled them through their system.

The waiting lounge seized Zhang Dong's focus. If it served as the entry point for system holders into the facility, it could also be a potential vulnerability. Contemplating the limitations of his adversary's power, he wondered if he could manipulate this entry point to block system holders from entering. Yet, the repercussions of abruptly halting their arrival remained uncertain, especially considering the unpredictable reactions of the puppet humans. Perhaps, he could utilize these individuals to aid him in future confrontations.

'What if I initiated a resistance, brought them all to my world, and trained them?'

While this plan promised relative safety, it would demand time. After exploring the moderator's workstation, Zhang Dong realized that a majority of these system holders leaned more towards immoral tendencies, akin to Wang Long rather than himself. The demise of such individuals wouldn't trouble him, but he also recognized the presence of good people among them - individuals he could potentially save while allowing others to perpetuate the cycle.

‘I could hack their systems and perhaps connect them to my own instead, then they would be able to further their power through cultivation and potentially reach the same realm as me now…’

The idea had merit, assuming he could avoid detection. His ability to freely roam the halls without triggering any significant reactions suggested that the puppet humans required a large event to provoke a response. This mirrored his experience of being left alone for years on his home planet, even after Wang Long's defeat. The Overseer, after it appeared, was easily deceived. It seemed that the system holders were underestimated and treated as lower-class entities by the creator of this entire operation.

While the plan wasn't without merit, it had its drawbacks. Operating within the confines of his own world exposed the risk of discovery by the orchestrator behind everything. Zhang Dong's primary goal was to protect his family, not endanger them by potentially triggering their creator's wrath. Additionally, relying on other system holders posed a significant challenge.

He couldn't guarantee their obedience or loyalty when faced with the choice between following his orders or pursuing a peaceful life within the existing world order. They remained autonomous individuals with their own motivations, making it difficult to count on their unwavering support in critical moments. They were still humans and the things that he saw could drive some of them to madness.

‘It would be better to go with a less investment-heavy plan, maybe I should get to it then…’

This was just one of the options available to him. Before making a decision, Zhang Dong knew he had to delve deeper into the mysteries of this place. Over the course of two weeks, he navigated through different puppets, even trapping some within his own miniature universe. Now, his focus shifted towards locating the administrator's room, determined to unravel more about the intricacies of this enigmatic space.

‘It is hidden somewhere and this is probably where it is…’

Analyzing the map he had meticulously crafted through his exploration, Zhang Dong discerned a semblance of order amid the apparent chaos. The entire place resembled the haphazard creation of a careless child toying with a strategy game. Given the omnipresence of systems, it occurred to him that the godly being might have employed a creation system to build this intricate environment. The revelation told him that everything was constructed from modular building blocks that were interconnected.

‘Everything has a beginning and this area looks like where it all began…’

In the vast expanse of this constructed world, one region stood out as notably more well-maintained than the others. It appeared as though the creator had invested more effort into this particular area before losing interest as the environment expanded infinitely. It struck Zhang Dong as plausible that the architect had employed an automated building system after establishing the core that housed the main structures. On the map, a specific area marked the convergence of all biomes, indicating that this was likely the origin point where the entire creation began.

Zhang Dong set his sights on this central convergence point. Navigating through the intricate corridors and bypassing puppet nurses and others, he carefully made his way toward the heart of the facility. As he approached, the surroundings became more pristine, indicating a departure from the chaotic design of the rest of the space. The air felt different here and the deeper he ventured in, the more handcrafted everything became.

‘There has to be a hidden passage somewhere here…’

Despite having explored this location before, Zhang Dong returned once more. This time, after several days of wandering, he found no substantial clues. Yet, when examining his map, he noticed a previously undiscovered empty space. Its dimensions suggested it could indeed be the starting point, possibly the hiding place of the administrator he sought. Determined, he ventured into this uncharted territory, eager to unveil the secrets it held.

‘Try examining the walls Bob, there might be a hidden passage somewhere here.’

Bob's virtual presence within Zhang Dong's mind began to analyze the walls of the empty space. After a few moments, he reported.

‘I've detected irregularities in the structure of the walls. There might be a hidden passage here, but it's heavily encrypted. Do you want me to decrypt the security measures in place?’

‘Go ahead and don’t force it, if we get discovered then it’s all over.’

As Bob worked on deciphering the encryption, Zhang Dong carefully examined the walls. He ran his fingers along the seemingly seamless surface, searching for any subtle clues or mechanisms that might reveal the concealed entrance. After what felt like an eternity, Bob's voice echoed in Zhang Dong's mind.

‘The encryption has been cracked. There's a concealed door on the northern wall.’

‘Northern wall? So here…’

Zhang Dong received an overlay that revealed the precise location of the hidden opening. As he concentrated his senses on the designated spot, a distinct sensation enveloped him. Protective formations, magical runes, and an array of technological concealment techniques formed layers of defense. It became evident that whoever designed this opening intended it to remain hidden, even from the scrutiny of an immortal-level cultivator. Only by combining his intellectual acumen with the capabilities of his AI was Zhang Dong able to perceive the intricate layers of concealment that shrouded the entrance.

‘Now that I can perceive it, I can actually open it… a strange method.’

The layers of protective formations didn’t really keep anyone from opening the door, it only kept them from perceiving that they were there. Without being able to tell, no one would be inclined to approach or reach for the door handle, it was as if it didn’t even exist so there was nothing to open.

With caution, Zhang Dong approached the concealed door. He extended his hand toward the northern wall, feeling the subtle energies and runes that disguised the entrance. As he touched the invisible interface, the layers of concealment yielded to his newfound understanding of the system. The door materialized before him, revealing a dark passage that led into the heart of the facility.

‘Great, barely lit passage leading to god knows where… I guess it’s time to do this, let's see what secrets you're hiding.’

He whispered to himself as he stepped through the threshold. The passage was dimly lit by a soft, eerie glow and just as many times before, the space inside was larger than what it seemed from the outside. His form was quickly concealed by several layers of hiding techniques and he faded into the shadows. It didn’t take that long for him to arrive at a point of interest, an open room in which flickering lights could be seen along with another phenomenon.

‘Is someone eating chips in there?’

Uncertain of what to anticipate, encountering another living person in this surreal place felt oddly out of place. As he stealthily advanced, Zhang Dong stumbled upon a room adorned with numerous monitors, where an individual sat in front of what appeared to be a gaming PC. The room was aglow with an array of RGB lights, explaining the flashing illumination he had observed earlier.

The person, engrossed in a bag of chips, seemed oblivious to Zhang Dong's presence, affording him a clear view of this supposed 'administrator.' The individual appeared somewhat lanky, with a pot belly likely attributed to poor posture and a penchant for junk food.

Zhang Dong observed the scene, slightly taken aback by the unexpected sight. The administrator, or at least the one who seemed to be in charge of this entire operation, was engrossed in a video game. The screens displayed various charts, data, and surveillance footage of the entire facility. It was clear that this person, or entity, had been overseeing the activities of the puppet nurses and the extraction processes.

‘Is this some kind of sick joke?’

The administrator continued munching on chips, seemingly oblivious to Zhang Dong's presence. He couldn't help but feel a mix of frustration and disbelief. Was this person responsible for bringing Wang Long into his world or tormenting the other system holders in the adjacent chambers? One certainty emerged - the administrator was not a puppet but a being comprised of flesh and blood just like him.

Chapter 755

“There is nothing good ever on… should I watch a stream or watch a show?”

In a dimly lit room, a lone man sat surrounded by monitors, absentmindedly scratching his armpits. The table before him was cluttered with plastic cups, each containing a half-filled soft drink, some appearing to have been there for weeks. The lanky man intermittently took sips while munching on nearby chips. Unbeknownst to him, another person lingered in the shadows, remaining hidden.

"Is this really the administrator? He looks like a balding gamer with no job. Is this some kind of joke?"

Zhang Dong asked himself, pondering whether he had unwittingly fallen into his enemy's intricate trap. He half-expected the true owner of the place to suddenly appear and mock him, yet nothing of the sort occurred. The man continued to sit there, not doing much. Occasionally, a message would pop up, and he would mumble something before clicking his mouse and keyboard.

The room was cluttered with numerous screens, some hanging from the ceiling on wires, displaying camera footage of the puppets working outside. Zhang Dong could even witness the entire system-holder recycling process, which didn't sit well with his morals. It was evident that this person wasn't the same as those autonomous humans; he was made up of flesh and blood. There was something peculiar about him, as his body wasn't normal - it closely resembled that of a cultivator's.

His cultivation level appeared to surpass the limits of the world he originated from, yet it fell below what he was capable of manifesting. There was no world forming within his being, and perhaps this was the reason he remained undiscovered. It seemed that this person possessed something akin to a pseudo-immortal realm. He was powerful, but this power was granted and not something he had worked for.

‘I guess if we are within a realm or cosmos created by a powerful cultivator, they would be able to grant people power to some extent…’

Various theories floated inside Zhang Dong's head, slowly connecting the elements as he spent more time in this place. It didn't appear that this person posed too much of a threat, so perhaps he could answer some of Zhang Dong's questions. However, it was a tricky endeavor; he was unsure whether anyone in this location was paying attention to the administrator. This man could be an essential cog in the machine that would instantly reveal his position. Nevertheless, Zhang Dong realized that he couldn't wait forever; perhaps this was his only chance to uncover the real truth.

As Zhang Dong contemplated his next move, he observed the administrator engrossed in a heated online debate about the latest gaming trends. The man's attention seemed so consumed by the virtual world that he appeared oblivious to the real one around him. This also begged the question, who was this person interacting with, in the first place? Did he just pick one of the many worlds that were more modern to pass the time, or was he focused on something more specific? There was only one way to find out, moving in closer and checking it out directly.
Silently, he manipulated the ambient shadows with his technique, making himself practically invisible. Moving cautiously, he approached the cluttered gaming station, maintaining a safe distance from the administrator. Then the moment his target seemed to be most distracted, he moved in like a flash.

With his current cultivation, Zhang Dong was more than just a superhuman; it took less than a fraction of a second for him to be behind the man. This was a delicate moment - the man possessed a body similar to that of a legendary immortal. It was possible that he wouldn't go down easily, and using a chokehold from behind would be pointless. Beings of such might had long been able to sustain themselves without the need for air. Thus, Zhang Dong quickly concentrated his lightning energies to deliver a palm strike to the side of this lanky man's head.

“GUEGH!.”

“Guegh?”

The moment Zhang Dong's palm collided with the side of the man's head, he sensed that something was off. Zhang Dong was adept at judging his opponents' strength; it didn't take more than a few hits for him to get a good reading. As his hand made contact, he realized that this being was actually quite weak. The man's body flew to the side and collided with the nearby wall, though he instantly went through it.

‘How can he be so weak? His body is that of an immortal…’

Zhang Dong quickly examined the hole in the wall and chased after the man he had flung. The opening led further inside, revealing other rooms. When he reached the end, he found the administrator passed out on the floor. The man had ended up in what looked like a dirty bathroom, with water gushing onto him in a damaged bathtub. His face was dented on the side where he was struck, and blood was spilling out.

‘Did I actually kill him with one blow?’

Zhang Dong's face went pale with worry as he prepared himself for the possibility of being discovered after making such a ruckus. To his surprise, no retaliation came - there were no warning signals, and he couldn't sense any disturbances throughout the facility. In the weeks he had spent there, he had become attuned to the forces and could tell that the puppets were just moving around as usual. It seemed that this place lacked any countermeasures against intruders, and this worked in his favor.

“I guess that I’m safe… but is this guy dead?”

The lanky individual he hit looked as if the right side of his face had been caved in by a collision with a truck. Zhang Dong had assumed that the man would be a formidable foe, so he didn't hold back as much. Only during the collision did he manage to pull back and lower his force. This administrator, who was supposed to be his informant, now had only half a mouth to talk.

“Wait… I can feel something… there is a heartbeat!”

The sound was weak but this person was still alive. Even though he had a body of an immortal being at a base he was still just a human. Relieved that he hadn't unintentionally murdered his only informant, Zhang Dong hesitated for a moment, contemplating his next move. It was clear that this administrator knew something and could possibly explain the world order. His body was slowly healing and before that, he needed to prepare the stage for questioning.

“I should probably tie him up, but the ropes and shackles I have are only at the nascent soul level…”

While looking around, Zhang Dong noticed something - a gray hairdryer with a long cable attached to it. Upon taking this bathroom utensil, he realized something odd - it was an item at the immortal level. Quickly, he started scanning everything with his system and spiritual senses. What he realized was mind-boggling and hard to understand for a cultivator like himself.

“Even the toothbrush is an immortal level item… I would be able to defeat the Azure Emperor with this thing and even the Overseer…”

Every small item or tool was of the immortal grade; the only reason any of it was damaged was because Zhang Dong had reached a realm above these items. This was the first time he had attempted to utilize his power in a combat setting, and breaking the walls that were also made from superior materials was now possible. With everything being of this caliber, he was able to quickly find enough wires and cords to tie the administrator up.

Zhang Dong had truly become a force to be reckoned with, but his system was unable to identify the realm that he had reached. Inside him, a massive tree stood at the center of what looked like a new solar system. Everything originated from it, and numerous celestial bodies were continuously being born, creating something that resembled a new galaxy.

At first, he considered naming it the Dao Tree realm or Dao Tree Creation realm. However, after paying more attention to it, he was more inclined to call it the Dao Galaxy stage. It wasn't quite a universe or a cosmos yet, but a mass of stars and planets from which he gained his power. Zhang Dong was absorbing all that solar energy, reinforcing his power, and as time passed, more stars appeared within his body.

Ever since he entered this strange dimension, the inside of Zhang Dong's galaxy had been growing at an increased rate. There was something in this place that was making him stronger. His new body was primed to absorb energies from the outside, and the small universe inside him continued to grow with time. It was possible that he was near someone of a similar realm, and it was giving his own a boost.

His attention moved back to his prisoner as he was starting to wake up. The administrator groaned and slowly regained consciousness, finding himself bound and at the mercy of the person who had assaulted him. As his eyes focused, panic along with confusion flashed across his face, and he struggled against the makeshift restraints.

“Who are you? Where did you come from?”

He stammered, his voice strained. Zhang Dong remained silent for a moment, studying the man before him. The administrator's eyes widened as he took in Zhang Dong's appearance. The man didn’t look like an all-powerful being that towered over countless worlds but instead like a scared animal. He was sweating, his eyes were darting all over the place and he couldn’t keep eye contact at all, it was clear that he was afraid for his life.

“Hey, I don’t have any money on me! Just take what you want and leave, please!”

“Hey, be quiet for a moment.”

To test out his theory he decided to speak in a more intimidating fashion which seemed to work. The man flinched as if there was no courage inside of his lanky body. He was stunned with fear which continued to give Zhang Dong a strange feeling. However, this could be a chance, if this person was so afraid of him then he just needed to play into it.

As Zhang Dong explored the place, he stumbled upon a few interesting items in the kitchen. The knives there were also of immortal grade, easily capable of cutting the administrator into ribbons. He dragged the man back into the main room with all the monitors, and on the gaming desk, he placed a few knives, now playing around with them. The administrator's eyes widened with terror at the sight of the immortal-grade knives. He swallowed hard, his throat audibly clicking as he tried to find the courage to speak.

“Please, I-I don't know what you want! Take everything, just don’t harm me!”

“Well, that depends on you, I hope that you are good at answering questions because I’ve got a lot of them…”

Chapter 757

In a dimly lit room, colorful lights danced around to the sound of a gaming computer. The previous owner of this space was tied up and passed out in a bathtub while Zhang Dong, who had taken over, contemplated his newest scheme. His eyes darted through the various monitors as he tried to find one specific location.

“Here it is, Sector 42069 … I was subject number 80082, it shows me as being deceased …, replaced with subject number 80089, system name Wang Long. Good that I had Bob hack the system at that time; it thinks that I’m him now…”

He was able to access the information of his own world along with the whole sector. It was one among many within the office area of this floating station. Through this main console, he had access to everything and wouldn’t need to return there. He could actually alter all the input of the moderators and even disable or make the Overseers act as his minions.

His AI helper had been slowly integrating himself into the system and taking over everything. While he wanted to bring an end to the cycle, he wasn’t able to quite yet. It was clear that this place was sending out some type of energy to one location, and this place was just a fraction of a bigger undertaking. What he needed to do was to slowly take over everything without being noticed.

This was quite the task for one person, but he wasn’t planning on tackling everything by himself anymore. With the help of the console, he was able to find the world that he fought his adventures in, and it was filled with nothing more than allies. While normally they would be too weak to be of use outside here, there were ways of enhancing their power, and that was through the system.

His planet was under his supervision and the Overseer puppet as well. There was no one watching over his shoulder so he could easily carry out his plan of integrating systems into the people that he trusted. They were the tool that would allow them to reach heights above the limitations of that world. Reaching stages above the nascent soul level was a possibility and he already had a good way of training them.

‘That’s the gist of it but something like that won’t be easy, I hope there is enough time left…’

The biggest question had not been answered yet. Probably the only way of finding out what this was all about was to go towards the center of this strange universe where Prime Earth was situated. The other planets and these stations were all automated, so as long as he didn’t do something stupid, no one would be alerted to his existence.

‘I guess it’s better to keep this guy alive; killing an administrator might give away my position.’

The lanky individual that he incapacitated was luckily an immortal who didn’t really require any food or sustenance. It was possible for him to disable him by inducing a dream state. In his mind, he would be having the best time in his life, but outside, he would be bound inside of a bathtub.

“Good, I need to get the others on board… but leaving this space unattended might not be wise.”

Zhang Dong glanced around the administrative chamber, his eyes scanning the intricate setup of the gaming consoles and monitors. He needed a plan to maintain control without arousing suspicion from whatever higher power might be overseeing this entire operation. It was possible for something unforeseen to happen while he was away. He needed to play the role of the administrator, and also, this place was filled with miraculous energies. The longer he remained, the stronger he became.

“I could probably reroute some of these energies into myself for another boost. It would be better to remain here than go back… I guess I’ll need some help this time around… and what better help than myself!”

There were various techniques that he knew, and after interfacing with the administrator console, he had unlocked access to the old system store that he had lost before. There were various immortal-grade techniques there that he had access to, and through them, he would carry out his plan. Being in two places was not impossible if one could split their soul into smaller ones.

‘It will probably be strange but let’s make some clones!’

With a determined expression, Zhang Dong began the intricate process of splitting his soul to create clones. Utilizing the immortal-grade techniques from the system store, he carefully crafted duplicates of himself, each containing a portion of his essence and consciousness. It was a delicate operation, but with his heightened abilities and superior cultivation, he managed to create five clones, each boasting a cultivation realm similar to that of the immortal realm.

As the clones materialized, they looked like mirror images of Zhang Dong, each possessing the same features, skills, and memories. They were fully-fledged bearings that could make decisions for themselves but at the same time, they were all the same person. It was a strange feeling as they shared one hive mind with each other. Information between this group of Zhang Dongs could be sent out immediately, they were like one being with multiple brains with the main him as the core.

"Now, let's assign some tasks! Number one will go down to the cultivation world and help everyone reach higher realms.”

“Yes! Haha!”

“Damn, I wanted to go there!”

“Don’t worry number two, I’ll take care of Liena!”

“Hmm…”

Zhang Dong raised his eyebrow as he realized that his clones were a lot more individualistic than he expected. Even though they shared the same soul, it seemed that some of the other clones were jealous of the first one that was allowed to return to their family. Perhaps with time, they would develop in some ways, but for now, this would have to suffice.

“Stop squabbling.”

“Yes, Supreme Dong!”

“... Don’t call me that.”

“Hehe.”

The five clones started laughing and he couldn’t help but smile a bit too. It seemed that they knew his sense of humor and also things that would set him off.

“Now next, number two, you’ll be responsible for the system holders here, we will save the promising ones, having more allies with a hacked system could aid us later.”

“Are you sure? Can we really trust them to do the right thing when we are up against the wall?”

“You bring up a good point, hmm…”

It was strange to talk to himself but he was kind of naturally doing it instead of thinking out loud now.

“Alright, number two, you’ll save them and bring them down to another cultivation world. You’ll gather more information and understand their motives, we’ll need to see how they will react to the information first before deciding if they are trustworthy.”

“Understood.”

After passing into this realm and taking over the console he was now able to move freely within the sectors this space station managed. His clones would be able to use the mirrors stored within to move into other worlds freely.

“Number three, you’ll go check up on our young friend Beatrice, she is someone that we can trust. Passing on some better spells to her along with a hacked system should be easy.”

“Got it.”

“Four and Five, you’ll both go to the other administrative satellites, examine them carefully, and if you can, take over the administrative chambers.”

“More exploring sounds like fun!”

“I’ll remain here and gather more energy, with time I’ll probably be able to make more immortal clones to send out, is everyone ready?”

“Ready when you are!”

With the tasks assigned, the clones dispersed, each going about their designated responsibilities. He could see them going through the corridors through the monitors. Thanks to being the new administrator he was able to make the puppets non-reactive to them. Even if they bumped into one of his clones, they wouldn’t even know that someone was there. This made the task of rescuing some of the system holders a lot easier.

Number One, the clone assigned to the cultivation world, made his way back with a big grin on his face. It was a chance to reunite back with his long ones that he was afraid that would never come after going into the strange upper realm. He made his way through the mirror that the original Zhang Dong appeared through and quickly flew back towards Spirit Spring City to give everyone a surprise.

Number Two, dealing with the system holders, faced some challenges as a lot of people were skeptical and others even paranoid. They found it hard to cope with all of their adventures being lies to get to their essence and explaining himself took up quite some time. Soon he was on his way to transport them to a safer location where they had some time to cool their heads and nerves.

Number Three eventually located Beatrice and, after a heartfelt reunion, shared the truth about their world and the strange system. Beatrice, being the quick-witted person she was, immediately grasped the situation. Some time had passed since his old adventure with her and she had grown up into a respectful adult and mage. With determination, she joined forces with Number Three to spread awareness among some of the more trusted people and prepared for the impending conflict.

Numbers Four and Five had the toughest assignment of them all. They needed to infiltrate the other satellites from outside. There were only two ways of getting there, one would be to just fly through the endless void of this world or to hitch a ride to a closer side realm. After using one of the mirrors they escaped that world's atmosphere and made their way to infiltrate their enemy's territory.

As the clones carried out their missions, the main Zhang Dong continued to absorb the energies in the administrative chamber. His power grew exponentially and also at a rapid pace. However, this was not an amount that he felt comfortable with; it would probably take a lot more for him to clash with whoever was responsible for it all. When the time came for that confrontation he would not be alone. With the help of his family and the allies that he gained over the years of his adventures, they would be victorious and break the shackles of this existence.

Chapter 758

“Haha, I made it back! … Only partially though!”

Zhang Dong's clone celebrated upon returning to his previous world, relieved to find his family alive and well. Time seemed to flow differently between the two realms, with only a small discrepancy. While several months had elapsed in the realm he had just left, here, only a month had passed. The time differential was advantageous, especially considering he had gained thousands of years of longevity. This exchange granted him additional time to adequately prepare for the future.

The previously persistent pull was now absent, and Zhang Dong attributed it to his original self sitting at the administrative desk. Through some research, they discovered that this pull was a feature that could be deactivated. It forcefully yanked a system holder out of any world, directing them through a teleportation gate and into a waiting area where they would be disabled by medical professionals. The recycling process would then commence. To evade this fate, Zhang Dong had chosen to return.

'I wonder how everyone will react when I tell them the truth. Will they believe me?'

As Zhang Dong flew through the sky, he pondered while leisurely taking in the breathtaking scenery. Although he could create a gate to transport himself directly to his family, he opted to savor his time in the current location. The sights from the upper realm were still overwhelming, and he was uncertain if his endeavors would prove successful. There lingered the possibility that the godly being he sought to confront might swat him like a mere fly, even if he grew stronger. Everything could potentially be in vain, but he felt compelled to try - for his own sake and for the well-being of every living being in the world he had come to love.

The once vast world now felt remarkably small. Despite merely flying, Zhang Dong's speed exceeded what he had as a nascent soul master by several times. He effortlessly pushed through the atmosphere without repulsion and even landed on one of the moons. The view from up there was breathtaking, with everything appearing diminutive. He could even discern the other empires and, from this height, observe the artificially crafted divide, which, if he wished, he could pass through or even disable.

‘I’m not sure any of the other empires will be of much help. I should probably focus on my sect, for now, taking them to that trial tower will probably be the best way for their progression.’

Zhang Dong had a well-thought-out plan to enhance everyone's progress, starting with the removal of the nascent soul limit. While there were several approaches to address this issue, he opted for a localized solution. The ideal location for this transformative change was the grand tower with multiple levels, where he and his companions had once confronted an elusive immortal. This place was already devoid of limitations, and Zhang Dong intended to expand this effect further, enabling his people to progress more easily. As the administrator of this world, he possessed the authority to implement any desired changes. Additionally, resources were abundant, allowing him to infuse greater amounts of spiritual energy into the world.

‘There she is, as beautiful as ever… I wonder how she will react…’

Satiated with the picturesque view, Zhang Dong honed in on a specific spiritual signature, identifying it as that of his wife. He materialized in a familiar location, one of the summer resorts they frequently visited. The climate here maintained a perpetual warmth, and the crystal-clear water added to the inviting atmosphere.

Zhang Dong found Liena sitting by the edge of a tranquil lake, engrossed in a book. The soft rustling of leaves and the occasional chirping of birds created a serene ambiance. As he approached, Zhang Dong couldn't help but marvel at the beauty and resilience of his wife. Despite the trials and tribulations they had faced, Liena radiated an inner peace that resonated with the world around her.

“Hey there…”

Zhang Dong said, a warm smile spreading across his face. Liena looked up from her book, her eyes widening with surprise and disbelief. For a moment, she simply stared at him, the book slipping from her hands and into the grass. Then, as realization dawned, her expression transformed into a mix of joy and disbelief.

"Zhang Dong? Is that really you?"

She asked, her voice a mixture of excitement and uncertainty. Zhang Dong nodded, his heart swelling with emotions. He extended his hand, helping her up from her seated position. The sensation of their hands meeting brought an overwhelming sense of familiarity and comfort.

“It’s me, Liena. I’m back…”

The two embraced each other tightly, her arms wrapping around him as if she feared he might vanish if she let go. Tears of joy streamed down her face but soon after her arms pushed away. Her expression shifted to a somewhat stern one as she posed a question.

“...There is something off about you… are you really my husband?”

“Haha, I guess you have noticed it? Quite the feat for a nascent soul master!”

Taken aback by the peculiar response, she instinctively took a step back. Although Zhang Dong's clone possessed the same memories, mannerisms, and expressions, it wasn't quite the genuine article. The soul of this clone was smaller, making it generally difficult to discern, but for some reason, Liena could sense that something wasn't quite right.

“Let me explain, I am Zhang Dong but I’m also not Zhang Dong.”

“You’re not really making sense…”

“I am a Dao Clone of him, we share everything with each other and in a sense are the same being but we can function as individuals as well.”
Liena raised an eyebrow, clearly trying to wrap her head around the concept of a Dao Clone. While clones existed in this cultivation as well, they weren’t as perfect as this one before her. Even as she realized that something was off, the way this clone talked, his whole vibe was that of her husband. If he denied the claim previously she would have probably ignored it. Zhang Dong chuckled and decided to simplify the explanation.

“Think of it this way: I've split a part of myself to handle different tasks and responsibilities. We share the same essence, memories, and consciousness, but we can act independently when needed. The main body, let us call him Zhang Dong Prime, is still in the upper realm and he is fine so don’t you worry!”

Liena nodded slowly, still absorbing the information. It was a lot to take in, but she had been through enough with Zhang Dong to accept such a thing as normal. Her ears perked up the moment he mentioned the Prime version and also the upper realm. It was clear that something was afoot there as her husband would probably not send his clone here just to keep her company.

“So, what brings you back? And why in this form?”

“Glad that you asked, you should sit down as this might be a lot to take in, but you already know about the system and my true origin, so I’ll just talk about what happened in the ‘upper realm’.”

“Please do…”

Zhang Dong explained the situation, detailing the bizarre world he stepped into after walking through that mirror. He explained about system-holders in more detail and how they were people from his original world. Liena was having a hard time processing the information but she continued to nod as he told her about how he became the administrator of this current system. As he was finishing up the tale, he could see that his wife wasn’t fully convinced about the tale but he could probably just show her part of the trick.

“I see that you don’t fully believe me but that’s fine, how about I just show you the big lie that we all have been living under?”

“The big lie?”

He nodded and took her hand, the best way of explaining was to show her how the world above looked. While he couldn’t bring her through the window he could still show her the fake planet they were living on.

“Now hold on tight, this might feel a bit strange.”

Even in clone form his cultivation level was identical to that of an immortal. He could easily leave the atmosphere by surrounding himself and Liena with a transparent barrier. Soon the two were blasting off into the heavens.

As they ascended, the scenery changed dramatically. The illusion of a vast, thriving world below gave way to the cold reality of a fabricated sphere suspended in an endless void. The stars were not distant suns but mere pinpricks of light embedded in the artificial backdrop.

Everything on the surface was real, but anything above had been fabricated. With a sweep of his hand, he lifted the veil before her eyes, exposing the fakes. He demonstrated that even the star providing them with light was nothing more than a creation crafted using the Dao of Light.

Liena gasped in disbelief as the truth unfolded before her eyes. It was as if the entire world she had known was nothing more than an elaborate stage set for some cosmic joke. Everyone in the world below was convinced that there was more to everything but this was quite different.

“This... this is all fake?”

“Yes, it's an illusion created by the system. The real world is beyond this facade, and that's where I came from.”

“So someone created this illusion for people like you? The System-holders?”

“Yes, and there is no happy end. I saw other people like me be drained of their essence, all of their experiences and memories before being sent out back to the world they came from. They were able to keep their soul but in a sense, they were erased at their core…”

In Zhang Dong’s mind, memories and experiences were what made a person what they were. Even if the core which was the soul remained in place, it was wiped clean and would never be the same.

Liena's eyes widened in horror as she comprehended the magnitude of the deception. The world she had known, the people, the landscapes, all of it was a grand illusion created by an external force. It was a bitter pill to swallow, the revelation casting a shadow over the once picturesque scene. Her body began to shake in indignation but Zhang Dong was there to hug her close.

“Who would do such a thing? Create this illusion… create us?”

‘I don’t know, but I will find out, no we will find out together with everyone and put a stop to it!”

Both of them nodded at each other, it was time to start a rebellion and first, they needed to get everyone else informed about this situation…

Chapter 759

‘I need to gather the sect elders and those closest to us. They deserve to know the truth’

Zhang Dong muttered aloud while his wife nodded a few times. The two had decided to start their plan with the main sect. They needed to awaken everyone to this truth and then empower them. The plan was straightforward: bring more people into the immortal realm, provide them with a simplified system, and enlist their help to take over the other stations alongside the other Zhang Dong clones.

At this juncture, Zhang Dong didn't feel confident enough in his current realm to pursue the truth. His power fell short compared to the godlike being that created all of this. He could only hope that whoever made this would remain preoccupied with other matters and not shorten his life. Nothing indicated that he was on the verge of being discovered by anything or anyone. Perhaps creating such a vast multiverse of small worlds had its drawbacks, and the person responsible was unable to govern it fully.

“Should I go get little Xiu?”

“Hah, she hates when you call her that but sure, I’ll have a word with our little Jun. Has he been doing well lately?”

“I’m not sure, after you left he had been working hard to keep the peace in the empire.”

“Were there some troubles?”

“Oh you know, the usual things that happen after a grand ancestor leaves.”

“I see…”

Zhang Dong smiled at his wife, who gave him one last hug. He could sense her distance, likely still apprehensive about the fact that he was a clone of her husband. Though this saddened him somewhat, he comprehended the peculiarity of their situation. Nevertheless, he needed to be strong and overcome the decrease in affection from his wife. Soon, he departed in the direction of his son, who was surprisingly not within the confines of any city.

‘I guess, there has been some trouble?’

His speed was tremendous, so it would only take him a few minutes if he pushed himself to reach the distant location where his son was situated. Even from afar, he could sense some commotion. As he drew closer, he discovered that his son was at the helm of their sect's armada, poised to clash with a large group of cultivators. The assembly was a mixed bag of individuals, including some demonic cultivators who had nearly been hunted to extinction.

‘I see, so these idiots think that after I’m gone, they can bully my sect and children into submission?’

Zhang Dong observed the situation from a distance, his eyes narrowing as he perceived the imbalance of power. Despite the odds seemingly stacked against his son and their sect, Jun stood confidently at the forefront, his eyes ablaze with determination. He presented himself with grace and looked like a proper Emperor.

‘Hah, my son sure is a sneaky little guy… he is pretending to be weaker, did he set this up to get rid of possible revolts in the future?’

Initially, it might have seemed like the opposing group held a certain superiority. They boasted more nascent soul masters in the great circle of the nascent soul and had effectively encircled the armada of ships belonging to his sect. The ambush was evident, and there was a suspicion that it was orchestrated, perhaps even by his own son. It was one of the oldest tricks in the book - appearing weak while, in reality, remaining the most powerful cultivator in the vicinity.

‘Should I let it play out? Even if Jun is probably going to win, some of our people will still die…’

His senses surpassed anyone else's, allowing him to discern all the formations and hidden soldiers strategically positioned. The other group unwittingly walked into a trap, despite their considerable numbers. Despite the meticulous preparations, it was likely that some of their sect members would end up dead or gravely injured. While he would have appreciated giving his son a moment of glory, this minor battle paled in significance compared to the real stakes at hand.

“Without that monster protecting you, there is nothing to fear from you Zhang Jun. Surrender and we will guarantee you a painless death!”

“Mmm, how magnanimous of you… but I’ll have to refuse, lay down your weapons and you might walk away with a severed dantian.”

“Hah, damn welp! Without your father you are nothing!”

As he surveyed the scene, a conversation between his son and the coalition of some sects was unfolding. Among the group, he identified members from the old Long Clan and also some from the Heavenly Crane Sect. These two giants of the past seemed intent on reliving their glory days and establishing a new rule. After his sect took over, they were stripped of most of their power and became their vassals.

Zhang Dong couldn't help but find the situation amusing. It seemed like some remnants of the old power structure were attempting to rise again in his absence. It seemed a bit strange that they had already forgotten the grandeur of his ascension. However, this forgetfulness was also a part of the system governing this planet. It generated conflict whenever there wasn't much to gain, and after spending time on the administrative console, he realized that it was an integral part of the lives of the people here. There was nothing he could do for those who were already born, but he discerned that it was possible to disable this effect for newborns.

He decided to intervene before the conflict escalated any further. The two armies were starting up their spirit cannons and the attacking formations were primed for carnage. With a thought, he appeared in the midst of the battlefield, standing between the two opposing forces. With a wave of his hand, he disabled every formation and cannon in the vicinity. The spiritual bolts that had already been fired simply vanished into nothingness.

His sudden appearance silenced the commotion, and all eyes turned towards him. The shock and awe on their faces were palpable as they recognized the man who had once ruled over this world. The form that he took was exactly the same as always and the power that he radiated was that of a true immortal being, something that these people here could not go against.

“Father!”

Zhang Jun's eyes widened, as a mix of surprise and relief washed over his face. Zhang Dong knew his son well, even if he was playing his role of the Emperor well, his true character was different. It was clear that he disliked fighting and conquest. The only reason he was out here was for the greater good as if the enemies of the sect continued without being stopped, many innocent lives would probably be lost.

Zhang Dong's gaze swept over the assembled cultivators. There was a mixture of fear, awe, and confusion in their eyes. He raised an eyebrow at the representatives of the Long Clan and the Heavenly Crane Sect, two factions that seemed to be leading this rebellion. Some of them were men that he even interacted with from three hundred years ago, now they were trembling in fear after he appeared.

“Well, well. It seems like some people didn't get the memo that my sect is not to be trifled with. What's the meaning of this rebellion?”

He asked, his voice carrying the weight of authority. The representatives from the opposing factions exchanged uneasy glances. One of them, a middle-aged man with a Long Clan insignia, stepped forward, trying to maintain a facade of confidence.

“Um… G-great Ancestor, we w-were merely testing the strength of your sect in your absence. We had no intention of rebellion. We're loyal servants of the Golden Empire and The Emperor!”

Zhang Dong's eyes narrowed, and a smirk played on his lips. He could hear them whispering with each other to get down on their knees and beg for forgiveness. Their lies were apparent and somewhat amusing to a being of his current power.

“Testing, huh? Seems like a rather aggressive way to test someone's loyalty. I'm quite disappointed in you. I thought you had learned your lesson. But alas… there is no time for this, surrender yourselves, your lives will be spared but your cultivation will be lessened.”

To no surprise, some of the old masters didn’t like that trade. To a lot of them, having their cultivation stripped or restrained was akin to dying. Zhang Dong was floating close to the flagship of the enemy army and suddenly a group of cultivators charged at him.

“Don’t let them fool you, Zhang Dong has passed on to the other realm! This is probably some elaborate ruse, a fake! Attack with me brothers and sisters, we will rule the Empire, it is our time!”

A group of around fifteen great circle nascent soul masters charged at him. Behind them an explosion of spirit bullets and other elemental attacks. Zhang Dong sighed inwardly. It seemed that the rebellion was more deeply rooted than he initially thought. These cultivators were willing to risk everything for a chance at power, even if it meant going against the man who had once united the entire world under the banner of the Golden Empire.

With a wave of his hand, a powerful gust of wind emanated from him, extinguishing the approaching attacks like candles in a storm. The rebels were sent flying backward, their bodies battered and bruised. The fear in their eyes intensified as they realized the futility of their resistance.

“Enough of this foolishness!”

He declared, his voice resonating with authority.

“I have returned, and any attempts at defiance will be met with consequences. Surrender now, and perhaps you'll be given a chance at redemption.”

The rebel cultivators, now lying on the ground and nursing their wounds, exchanged glances. The reality of their situation had sunk in, and the allure of rebellion had faded in the face of overwhelming power. After a moment of tense silence, the leaders of the rebellion gritted their teeth and reluctantly dropped to their knees.

“We surrender, Great Ancestor. We were misled, and we beg for your mercy.”

There was no way of fighting overwhelming power and he disliked the fact that he was forced to act. The trembling men and women below didn’t bring him joy but just saddened him instead. None of them was aware of the bigger picture and all of them continued to murder each other for a little bit more prestige. He hoped to finally be able to break this cycle.

“My son you did well but we must have a few words, we will be returning to the main sect, I want you to assemble our most trusted sect members, there is something that I need to show all of you…”

The battle was over but a new war was on the horizon. Zhang Jun looked quite confused but he nodded.

“Yes, Father!”

Chapter 760

“Matriarch, are you sure?”

“Yes, stop bringing this up; he can wipe his own ass!”

“Of course, please forgive my impudence, Matriarch!”

A woman bowed before a beautiful lady seated on a large chair within the palace. Behind her were characters representing the word ‘victory’. Many other individuals within this expansive palace were adorned in extravagant white cultivator robes, with the same words embroidered onto their backs.

“I will not let the lives of my Victory Sect be thrown out in vain.”

The person that was bowing started removing themselves from the throne room while whispering with one of the people they had arrived with.

“Is the Matriarch still angered about that issue?”

“I think that could be the case, she hasn’t been able to win against her brother ever since for at least a hundred years now…”

“But it’s her brother and the current Emperor, there is no shame in …”

Before the two could continue with their talk they felt a massive spike in spiritual energy pushing them down to their knees. The Matriarch that they were talking about had overheard their whispers and focused some of that rage onto them.

“What are you two whispering about?! Are you badmouthing your Matriarch!”

“N-no no such thing!”

“If you don’t stop blabbering, I’ll reduce your salaries by fifty percent!”

“No, anything but that! M-my cousin is getting married soon, I need that for her gift! Please show mercy!”

Everyone within the chamber began narrowing their eyes and scrutinizing. Their Matriarch was a peculiar person who typically punished her sect juniors by stripping them of resources or playing strange pranks on them. Initially, it seemed preferable to physical punishment, but after a while, they realized that these punishments were far more insidious in the long run.

“Yeah, I bet you are! Now choose! Either your spirit stones get halved, or you spend two months out in the glacial fields!”

“N-not the fields!”

The two people who were previously whispering collapsed onto the ground. The choice was between hard labor or having their wages lowered by quite a significant amount. However, before the two could make a choice and plead more, another person burst into the chamber.

“Matriarch, I bring important news!”

“Hm? Speak!”

“The battle between the rebels and the Emperor’s army has ended!”

“It ended already?”

The Matriarch, along with the other people in the room, was shocked by this revelation. Their informants looked on from a distance, relaying the information to their sect. It was an order from their leader, who was evidently concerned in her own way about her younger brother. Despite her claim that they wouldn’t be providing assistance, their forces were on standby, and the teleportation gate was ready to be activated at any moment.

“Even if it’s the Emperor… they shouldn’t be able to defeat such a large army this quickly, did the rebels surrender instantly?”

One of the elders spoke out, as they had been previously discussing the whole issue among themselves. All eyes turned towards the messenger, who quickly responded to the inquiry.

“No, someone appeared before the battle started, they drove back the rebels in a show of unfathomable power!”

“Someone? Who could it have been?”

“It was…”

Before this person could continue, a blue light in the form of a compact teleportation gate appeared in the middle of the throne room. Through it, they could see a lone person coming through. He was a handsome man with long snow-white hair and the demeanor of a mighty cultivator.

“Oh, sorry to interrupt your meeting, but I’ll have to borrow my daughter for a bit.

“Is that you, Dad?”

“Indeed, it is me, but we’ll talk along the way Xiu’er”

Everyone was confused about the great ancestor's arrival. He was supposed to have moved on to the higher realm like a few other individuals from legends. They could feel that his power was tremendous and that any resistance was futile. Soon their Matriarch was getting sucked into the teleportation gate along with her throne and withing a second the two were gone.

“Did the ancestor take out Matriarch away?”

“It does seem so…”

The room went silent as everyone just stared at the space that the portal had been previously. No one knew what to do as they could only try to contact the old United Element Sect or someone that knew the Golden Emperor to explain this matter to them.

…

“There we go, you’re the last one!”

“Welcome, Xiu’er”

“Grandpa? … and you two?”

Zhang Jin along with Zhang Jun greeted Xiu with many other people around them gathered on a large circular platform. They were all high above ground and soon they all started floating upwards, passing through the atmosphere that revealed the oval planet to them all.

Zhang Dong observed the confused expressions on the faces of his family, friends, and followers. Flying up to such heights was considered impossible, even for a nascent soul master. In their perception, the world was mostly a flat expanse of land extending up to the borders of the empire - borders they could now see. Soon, they reached their destination, where the artificial nature of their surroundings became apparent.

“Impossible, so it was all a lie? There is no greater realm outside? It’s nothing more than an illusion?”

“Regretfully so gramps, as you can see, everything here is fake and everything outside this sphere is nothing but an empty void.”

“Nothing but empty space? But surely if you flew long enough then…”

“You are mistaken, it doesn’t even go on for that far, within a few days of flight you’d reach the end, a barrier of this dimension. While we can’t consider it small, it pales when compared to a true boundless universe.”

“How could this be…”

“Grandfather? Are you well?”

Zhang Xue, one of his disciples, offered Zhang Jin a shoulder to lean on after he collapsed onto his knees. To simplify matters, he decided to bring his most trusted family members and advisors beyond the bounds of the planet. They could all witness the fake planet and the absence of anything beyond.

The primary group included his disciples, children, and most trusted elders. Huo Qiang, Zhang Zhi, Feng Maling, Zhang Kuo, and Zhang Ya were all present. Revealing the truth was a heavy burden, but he understood its necessity for their comprehension of the world they inhabited.

Without this realization, it would be impossible to expedite the plan involving all of them, including the elderly. While some among them, like his grandfather, were at an advanced age, they could potentially prolong their lives by reaching a higher realm. With a concentrated effort, many of them could likely ascend to the stage of an immortal, and then the real work would begin.

“This will be enough, let us head back, I can now explain to you all what we are facing and what my plans are.”

Everyone was visibly shaken by this revelation, but some remained composed. They all reconvened in one of the old meeting chambers of their sect. The room was filled with a diverse group of people, ranging from young adults who were his grandchildren to old elders he recognized from the past wars they had endured. The gathering totaled around fifty people, a loyal group to whom he could safely explain everything.

Zhang Dong took a deep breath, gathering himself before addressing the group. He spoke of the system, the upper realm, and the mysterious force behind the illusion they had been living in. The revelation was met with a mix of disbelief, shock, and anger.

“So, what you're saying is that everything we’ve known is a lie? Our world, our lives, our struggles… all part of some cosmic game?”

Asked Feng Maling who still had a hard time processing all of this information.

“Yes, but we are not powerless. We have the opportunity to fight back, to break free from this illusion, and confront the force behind it. I brought you all here because I trust you, and together, we can forge our own destiny.”

He explained his plan to empower everyone, remove the limitations imposed by the system, and prepare for the looming confrontation with the enigmatic being in the upper realm. His words resonated with determination and it installed the people here with a newfound purpose. However, a lot of them still remain skeptical of this revelation. Their power was limited and most of them could not fathom becoming strong enough to challenge a foe their great ancestor could not defeat.

“But father, how will we tackle this foe that not even you, an immortal cultivator could hope to battle?”

Zhang Jun posed the question that was on everyone's mind. This was the crux of the problem. The people here had been conditioned to think that the Nascent Soul realm was the limit for them. Zhang Dong knew that it would take some time to convince them otherwise but the fastest way would be to present them with a path forward. After one of them gained a new realm, the others would follow suit and for that, they just needed to be granted a simplified system.

“While one immortal realm cultivator might not be able to, what if there were many immortal realm cultivators?”

“Many?”

“Yes, all of you will be the first to reach a new stage, one above the Nascent Soul realm and I will guarantee it!’

The whispers within this hidden chamber started. Some of them were shocked, others were intrigued and some didn’t believe it.

"I know it's hard to believe, but this limit on your cultivation realms had been artificially created. After I lift those limitations, some of you will naturally break through to the next stage, I won’t even need to help you with that as you had already grasped one lesser Dao to make that jump!”

“One lesser Dao? W-what is the next realm after the Nascent Soul stage, Patriarch?”

Zhang Zhi was the one to speak out. His realm had been at the Great Circle of nascent soul for quite some time now. Even if he tried pushing his body and soul further, he could just not progress anymore. It was the same for all the other older cultivators who had been stuck for hundreds of years at what seemed to be the end of their cultivation journey.

“I had to fiddle around with the options a bit, but the first realm after the nascent soul realm, is called the Dao Foundation realm!”

“Dao Foundation realm?”

“Yes, you will have to grasp one Dao to its fullest before you can hope to ascend and the quality of this Dao will dictate your future but, before all of you can start with your journey, we need to prepare some things.”

Zhang Dong waved his hand to create another portal, this one would take them all towards the new training area where they all would probably spend many years training.

Chapter 761

“Well then, I’ll guide you all through the process and we’ll start… with Liena.”

“Hey… that’s not fair, senior brother… I’m stronger than her!”

Zhang Liena smirked while glancing at the pouting Huo Qiang. Following his announcement, Zhang Dong transferred everyone to the old Tower of Trials, which boasted a hundred floors. In the past, he and his friends had only managed to clear up to the 50th floor, but now, Zhang Dong intended for them to conquer the entire tower. The place was designed to test system holders, and soon everyone would have one of their own.

With his current administrative powers, he could influence this structure in ways he previously couldn't. He had the ability to adjust the difficulty and even shut everything down if someone was close to dying. This tool was designed to aid his people in achieving greatness in a more natural way, and he fully intended to utilize it. While it was possible for him to artificially raise everyone's understanding, he recognized that such a method would impede their future progress. Gaining insight into their Dao through rigorous training and self-reflection was the only genuine path to reaching the immortal realm.

Fortunately, time was now under his control. People could spend years in this realm, and only a few hours would pass in the outside world and in the higher realm. Interestingly, the higher the realm and the more potent the spiritual energy, the more challenging it was to control time. Training weaker individuals from a lower realm was straightforward, but it became significantly harder after they experienced a cultivation breakthrough. With an immortal’s body, time would not affect them as much, allowing them to peer through the veil.

The place he brought them to looked like a gym building, with a row of seats that some of his family members could occupy. This trial tower was a marvel of pocket dimensions and an amalgamation of architecture. The main area looked like a large five-star hotel while the rooms could lead to places like this or even forest biomes. Zhang Dong turned to Zhang Liena, who was grinning in anticipation.

“Liena, you have exceptional talent and have reached the limits of the nascent soul realm. I believe you are ready to break through to the Dao Foundation realm. Remember, this is not just about strength but also about understanding and embodying a Dao. Choose a Dao that resonates with you, and let it guide you to new heights.”

Liena nodded, her eyes sparkling with determination. She stepped forward, and the air around her seemed to ripple with energy. She closed her eyes, focusing on the innermost essence of her being. After a moment, she opened her eyes, revealing a newfound clarity.

“Then I will choose, the Dao of Wind! ”

She declared and almost instantly, a gust of wind surrounded her, swirling and dancing in response to her will. It was as if the very air acknowledged her choice. Zhang Dong nodded approvingly.

“Well chosen, Liena. Now, let the Dao of Wind be the basis for your Dao Foundation. It is one of the greater Daos and will be perfect for your foundation. Now, relax and focus on this Dao, let it fuel your essence. I will help you.”

As Zhang Dong spoke, a radiant light enveloped Zhang Liena. She closed her eyes, and her body started to undergo a subtle transformation. Her aura expanded, and the wind around her intensified. It was a mesmerizing sight, as if she had become one with the very essence of the Dao she had chosen.

The spectators, including Zhang Jin and the others, watched in awe. They could sense the profound changes occurring within Zhang Liena. It was not just a simple advancement in strength but a deep connection with a fundamental force of nature. The entire gym was filled with wind energy that seemingly danced around producing a gentle warm wind.

After a while, the wind subsided, and Zhang Liena opened her eyes. They gleamed with newfound wisdom and power. She smiled confidently, and the wind that surrounded her responded, creating an ethereal dance. Green energy surrounded the whole place and started blowing in all directions. The nascent soul masters felt suppressed by this energy and were unable to move, it was obvious that she had reached a height above everyone in this chamber.

“I feel... different. Stronger and with more energy…”

Zhang Dong nodded at his wife's words and responded.

“You have successfully stepped into the Dao Foundation realm. Embrace the changes within you and continue to cultivate the Dao of Wind. This is only the beginning of your journey. Thanks to mastering a greater elemental Dao, you will be able to swiftly progress to the next realm.”

“The next realm? What is the next realm?”

“The way towards the immortal realm is paved by mastering multiple paths. After the Dao Foundation realm, you will have access to the Dao Gathering realm, you will achieve it by truly mastering your main Dao and all the lesser paths that it branches away to. Only after pushing it to the very limit will you break through. After that, you will gather more paths, even ones that might be at odds with your current one…”

The revelation left the onlookers in awe, realizing that the path towards immortality was not a straightforward one but a complex web of interconnected Dao. Zhang Liena, now in the Dao Foundation realm, could sense the possibilities opening up before her. Her journey had just begun, and she was determined to explore the depths of the Dao of Wind.

Zhang Dong turned his attention to the others in the room, each of whom was eager to embark on their own path. The atmosphere in the chamber was charged with anticipation as they witnessed the transformation of their fellow cultivator.

“Who’s next?”
Zhang Dong asked, scanning the room and Huo Qiang quickly stepped forward, his eyes were gleaming with determination but mostly anticipation. He could feel the power emanating from Liena who could not control it well. The pressure was truly immense and something that he wished to grasp as well.

“I’ll go next, Senior Brother.”

“I’m not sure if that is a good idea, the idiot might crush out juniors under his flames.”

“You think that I won’t be able to control my power?”

“Yes!”

Zhang Dong started rubbing his chin while looking at the two fighting already. It brought a smile to his face to see them bickering as in the old days. However, now there was a tiny difference as Huo Qiang found himself getting pressed into the floor by his wife.

“Hey, this is unfair!”

“Down where you belong!”

Liena’s cultivation level was now above the nascent soul and she was many times stronger than before. Even without training much, she was able to easily suppress the second strongest man from the United Element’s Sect. He was lucky that Zhang Dong was even stronger, with a little application of his immortal realm the suppressive Qi was gone instantly.

“While I would love for you two to argue more, we don’t have the leisure.”

“Thank you Senior Brother!”

Huo Qiang smirked at Liena, as if claiming victory by securing help from Zhang Dong. This provoked a frown on her face, but after a brief shoulder rub from her husband, she returned to a good mood.

“Good, come Qiang, Choose your Dao and let us start.”

Huo Qiang took a moment to contemplate, but there was just one answer that he could go with.

“I choose the Dao of Fire!”

Flames erupted around him, swirling and dancing in response to his choice. The air crackled with heat, and the temperature in the room soared. Zhang Dong nodded approvingly, recognizing the affinity Huo Qiang had with the Dao of Fire.

“Good choice. Let the flames be the foundation of your Dao. Now, focus on it, let the essence of fire become a part of you.”

As with Liena, a radiant light enveloped Huo Qiang as he closed his eyes in concentration. The flames around him intensified, and the spectators could feel the scorching heat emanating from his presence. The process seemed both intense and beautiful, as if a fusion was taking place between the cultivator and the elemental force he had chosen.

After some time, the flames subsided, and Huo Qiang opened his eyes. They now held a fiery glow, reflecting the profound changes that had occurred within him. The air carried a warm, comforting heat which felt like it could erupt at any moment

“I feel... alive, as if the flames have become a part of my very being.”

Huo Qiang exclaimed as an eruption of flame energy shot out in all directions. Liena pointed out with disdain as what she said came to be true, only thanks to Zhang Dong’s overwhelming might did the onlooking family members not get swallowed up by this bursting inferno.

“See, I said so! The idiot can’t control his flames!”

Zhang Dong nodded.

“Yes, that is true. The elemental Daos have a mind of their own and when not fully mastered can affect the user’s emotions. Fire likes to burn, it’s a very passionate element known for its outbursts.”

Huo Qiang blushed a bit as he was reprimanded by his senior brother. However, his joy outweighed the shame that he was feeling. The boost in power was tremendous and he couldn’t wait to test his newfound power on something or someone. His gaze turned to Liena who was the only person at the same realm as him and Zhang Dong noticed.

“Calm down you two, first meditate on your new realms, you just stepped into them, your foundation is still weak and if you strain it too much, it could break.”

The stern tone from Zhang Dong sobered the atmosphere in the room. Both Liena and Huo Qiang, despite their excitement, understood the importance of consolidating their newfound power. Zhang Dong turned to the rest of the group that was filled with anticipation and eagerness to progress further.

"Who's next?"

He inquired, his gaze sweeping across the room. Several hands shot up, each eager to be the next to undergo the transformative process. This brought a smile onto his face as he pointed onto the next person. It already took half a day to help these two with their new realm and time was of the essence. Only after everyone had progressed further on, could they delve into the trial tower to truly start their new journey.